OST: 'Long Gone'
♪ I want those moments back, those memories of you... ♪
♪ An ounce of respite, that's all I ask of you... ♪
♪ You're the same, I'm the same; helpless, all the same, ♪
♪ Unsure how long we can bear this pain... ♪
♪ My heart longs for a new dawn ♪
♪ Lit up by a sun long gone ♪
♪ To ashes of sweet words holding on ♪
♪ Lit up by the love long gone... ♪
♪ Are you coming back, or will I die in the dark, alone? ♪
♪ When would you hear my helpless moan? ♪
♪ There's something different about our last tiff - ♪
♪ Something distant, something cold, something stiff... ♪
Rakshi!
♪ Something that tells me I'm losing you, ♪
♪ Someone else you've taken to... ♪
♪ My heart longs for a new dawn ♪
♪ Lit up by a sun long gone ♪
♪ To ashes of sweet words holding on ♪
Rakshi!
♪ Lit up by the love long gone... ♪
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ARY TV
♪ A new dawn... ♪
♪ Yea, a new dawn... ♪
♪ My heart longs for a new dawn ♪
♪ Lit up by a sun long gone ♪
♪ To ashes of sweet words holding on ♪
♪ Lit up by the love long gone... ♪