♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 3 - 'Something in the Wreckage'
... Lt Col Anand Rastogi and his squad are reportedly killed in action.
The nation takes pride in its heroes who are willing to make the ultimate sacrifice for its sake, and their families who stand strong in their sorrow.
In other news...
Remember Mukesh?
-Pakistan has resorted to unprovoked firing yet again...
Pakistan has resorted to unprovoked firing yet again...
That's his Dad...
-Two of our heroes lost their lives in the dastardly attack...
Two of our heroes lost their lives in the dastardly attack...
The Pakistani Special Forces reportedly mutilated the bodies beyond recognition...
One wonders if this is the fine generalship and military discipline that Pakistan takes so much pride in...
The fallen heroes' funeral will be held on...
In the ensuing skirmish with India, we have reports that Major Iosef Abidi, Captain Khurram, and Lieutenant Niaz Mohammad lost their lives...
I repeat, we're getting reports that Major Iosef Abidi, Captain Khurram, and Lieutenant Niaz Mohammad lost their lives in the skirmish with India...
Remember Hamid Abidi?
That's his son...
And so we bid farewell to Col M. N. Roy, who embraced death in the line of duty in Kashmir...
But not before setting an example that will live on after him. The final farewells from his daughter and the Gorkha Regiment brought us all to tears...
Hail India!
-Hail India!
Long
Long live
Long live India!
-Again!
Again!
-Long
-Long live
Again!
-Long live India!
Long live India!
-Again!
Again!
-Long
-Long live
Again!
-Long live India!
Sergeant Khalid Mehmood's sacrifice will not be forgotten...
Heroes like him will forever give us hope and remind our enemies that death does not scare us...
Age shall not weary them, nor the years condemn...
At the going down of the sun and in the morning...
We will remember them...
Gotta have a heart of stone to get in the army, eh?
-Perhaps... But not a cruel one.
Serving eight months a year in distant lands, I'm not mad to start a row with my wife in my four months here!
I've got a lot to learn... Got to be brave.
-Of course. Like a soldier's wife.
No less a soldier herself.
Vishal!
Granny?
Pari and Laxmi haven't gone to school for so long...
Ask Sunanda to send them. Get them back up to full speed.
Why don't you talk to Mum?
I've told her so many times...
No idea...
How I'm gonna say it...
We haven't talked in ages...
How do I convince her?
Why don't you try?
Major Iosef Abidi's heroism in the face of impossible odds set an example for our nation. We've got with us his widow and mother...
Sarah... Just change the channel, will you? And get me my pills, my BP's shooting up...
-Are you alright, Granny?
-Who, with a glowing and a glistening eye...
It's nothing...
Just... Missing Sherali...
This kind of news...
Anything...
Just opens old wounds...
I know...
What his mother feels like...
I mean...
She'd just got Iosef married last year...
She sent sweets for us just a few days back...
When he had a son...
And these heartless journalists...
Want to ask her...
How she feels!
C'mon, school time! Let's go!
-No, we're enjoying ourselves here.
Don't you wanna enjoy with your friends?
I've got none.
They ain't the fun sort...
As if you go to school to have fun. Don't you think you should learn something for a change?
-I don't want to.
-I wanna stay at home...
Why?
I'm afraid...
No idea.
She's lying. She's just waiting for Dad.
When's Dad coming back? Tell him we can see through his trick!
C'mon, now.
What happened?
No idea what's wrong with my legs...
I can't get up.
C'mon, try again.
C'mon.
No...
My legs... Feel lifeless...
Amna!
Sarah!
Get here quickly! Your Grandpa can't get up!
What happened?
-Dad?
Grandpa?
Just... Can't get up... My legs feel weak...
Call the unit. Get someone. We need to see a doctor!
Hey, mate.
-Hey.
You comin' on the school trip?
-There's a school trip?
Yeah?
I'm sorry, I can't...
-Why?
I thought you always wanted to.
-I can't... Not now...
Everyone's gonna need me at home.
We've planned some proper fun this time... Hunting...
And the music show!
-Aye, shindy in the spinney! Bands in the woodlands!
Okay.
-Bye.
He led the fight. Like a true hero...
-I feel sad for Mukesh though...
Don't be. I'm sure he's as proud as the rest of us.
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
It hasn't even been a month and you're here playing your guitar?
He was my husband. Your Dad!
But all you seem to care about is your blimmin' guitar!
D'you feel anything for your Dad at all? Like ever?
Vishal!
Open the door!
Vishal?
What happened?
Vishal!
Vishal?
It's time for your pills...
Just a second...
Has Dad turned in?
Yeah... But he's too restless...
He's broken...
Ever since your Dad...
He's also restless because he won't have a home...
He'll be better once your Aunt's here... Just a few more days...
The unit asked for some papers... No idea where I've kept them...
Anyway, go get some rest...
Six months already?
First time I'm seeing my little Sarah...
There, now... You're crying?
No... Just... Delighted...
Seeing my little girl after months at the border... Just...
Makes me realise how beautiful this world can be...
A soldier's life ain't easy...
Time never heals some wounds...
Hello
Probably for someone else...
Why'd he want to talk to me?
T --
There?
Why in Heaven's name?
What's he thinking?
How are you???
n
no
not
not w
not we
not wel
not well
Same
Same here
The day everything changed forever...
Wonder what happened to him... But...
Why should I ask him?
She didn't even ask me...
Why would she?
But...
What was I thinking? Saying any of this...
What'd she care?
What was I thinking? Replying to him...
I hate the sound of his name!
But he messaged me...
I wonder why...
Mum... You up?
Hmm?
What is it?
Parents' evening... At Pari and Laxmi's school...
Aren't you going?
Why don't you?
Are you alright?
Yeah...
As much as I can be...
Don't skive off school again, okay?
Ready?
Yeah.
C'mon.
Is Mum ready?
No. I'm going with you.
As if you're Dad!
Get ready...
We're getting late...
Again? Remember what I told you?
What's wrong with you, Nadir? I've told you a hundred times!
I don't wanna do this... You're always yelling!
Well give me reason not to! Your notebook's a mess!
I don't need your help. You can just yell. I'll go ask Dad...
Dad!
What?
Back to work!
Lemme have a look...
Where's your mother?
She's not well... But she'll be here next time...
Oh, sorry...
I can understand how you feel... Please give her my condolences...
Pari, Laxmi... It's time you two got back up to full speed. Exams start next week. You've been absent for two weeks...
Please make sure they're regular.
Of course.
Who helps them with their schoolwork?
Mum... But I've taken over for now...
Okay. Don't worry. Here's my number. You can contact me anytime.
I'll be glad to help in any way I can.
Thank you.
Alright then, you may leave for your classes.
I don't wanna go to class, Vishal...
I want to go home...
Yeah, take us back...
You got to go to class.
Don't worry, I'll take them...
Thank you.
Your bag...
She beat me bad!
He's lying!
I just scolded you!
For the mess he's made of his notebook! See for yourself! No wonder why he's failing!
Easy there...
You didn't really need to!
D'you want me to help him or not?
-Not like this!
Don't worry. Mum's gonna help you.
-Fair enough. Up to you to fix him your way.
Calm down...
It's okay...
I remember this one...
-And this one...
From the birthday party...
That's you...
Remember how much he'd to bother you?
Aye... But he was the only one who cared... Helped me with everything... Took me over to friends'...
Remember how he'd pull my ponytails?
Like, all the time!
He said he hated how they look...
Alright...
I can't go on...
I'll go check on Dad... No idea what happened to him. How can we go on?
The doctors said he's fine...
Excuse me...
That's how he is when he gets worried...
That's how he felt...
When Sherali left for the Siachen frontier...
Three years ago...
You got to be brave... Strong...
But...
How... Just how?
What with endless worries...
Badar wants Amna to move to Karachi with the kids...
And -- What about the two of you?
That's what I'm worried about...
We can't live with her brother...
Nasir says...
One of us should live with you...
And the other with Ayesha...
There's a few things we need to sort out for it... Besides, we'd need to talk to his wife... At the office...
How long will it take? A couple of days?
-No.
There are so many pending claims...
But Dad's a martyr... A hero...
Indeed. The Colonel was one of our finest.
We'll try our best to get it done quickly.
Okay.
They want us to file a claim, right?
Yes.
And... All sorts of red tape... Forms, paperwork, and more...
Aye, red tape. That's it.
That's how it was back in your Grandpa's time...
But he'd retired from duty...
Who's gonna do it all? Mum...
Take Sunanda to a doctor.
Who?
You think I'm yampy?
What 'appened?
What'd you tell Vishal? What did you tell him? I need therapy?
No, Sunanda, I dedn't -- I joehst said...
Don't even start...
I heard everything!
Well dat's because I care fahr you!
-Oh you do?
Aye.
-When'd that happen?
You've always tried to drive a wedge between me and Vijay!
Where'd it get you?
Where'd it get us?
Everything's gone...
Finished...
But now...
You're targeting Vishal!
Why'd I even think?
He's your son. My grandson...
No!
You want to drive a wedge between us!
Because that's what you've always done!
You've taken away everything I ever held dear!
But not again! Get it? Mum!
-What happened, Mum? Everything alright?
Alright?
Of course not! Not when she's -- What's wrong with you?
-It's okay, Mum... Come...
Vishal... I won't let her snatch you!
-You need rest, Mum... Come...
Between your Mum and Granny, tell me you're always gonna pick your Mum! TELL ME!
-C'mon... Get some rest...
Why d'you want to pick a fight with Granny? Is it that hard to bury the hatchet?
Why not? She's telling you I need therapy! You think I'm yampy?
-That's not what she -- No...
You're just... Depressed...
You are depressed.
'Depressed'...
For the last 20 years, yes...
Ever since I fell for your Dad... And got married...
D'you have any idea what your Granny's done all these years?
What, you want to settle the scores? Now? When she's just as helpless?
She's never helpless!
She's been a pain in my neck for half my life!
She didn't let me move in with Vijay for five years after our marriage!
Five long years, we'd see each other in secret...
Because...
Your Granny didn't like it! Because she didn't know about it...
She ruined the first five years of our marriage...
And...
After we moved in... Whenever she paid a visit...
She'd treat me like a lowly animal!
And Vijay would just tell me to stay quiet...
'She's my Mum... My Dad's Queen'...
'Can't argue with her'. You get it.
And now she's turning you against me!
-What are you talking about?
No one can turn me against you.
You're my Mum... I'm your son...
That's what I'm telling you! I'm your Mum, so as my son, you shouldn't listen to anyone else!
Vijay couldn't choose between the two women in his life...
But you...
You've just got me, get it?
I get it, Mum -- I get it... But could you please step out of this room for a change?
How long d'you want to stay locked in here?
Laxmi and Pari need you...
They all need me...
But the one I need...
Is no longer with us...
Granny... Do you, like... Know what Mum's going through?
You do, don't you? Yet...
Yet what?
Does it hurt her any more?
-No.
I only had him...
My only son...
I'm his mother...
Wasn't he someone to his mother? Or is it just his wife who...
Of course not... We know how you feel...
But what can I do?
I say something to her and she tells me off. I say something to you and you tell me off.
I wish I could die right now...
At least I'd fend sahme peace...
Is it so easy?
You know how one death wracked our hearts with grief...
What'd anyone care if I live or die?
I lost my only son...
And all my daughter cares about is my estate...
While my daughter-in-law would rather not see me again!
Give me good reasahn to live.
Aye?
You gotta live, Granny...
For me...
You're all I have left, my boy...
My only hope...
Never leave me, Vishal...
Never...
Granny...
How'd you even think?
I'll be right here... For you.
Never leave me alone, okay, dear?
Vishal...
We're gonna need your help... Yeah, the usual red tape... Go there, do that, go there, do that...
I'll need a week to sort a few things out...
Why don't you sort things out over there? About coming over and all...
I'm coming there just once... To sort out Sherali's compensation and take you along...
I'm gonna need time...
We're in mourning... And I gotta think of something for Mum and Dad...
Why don't you talk to your sisters-in-law? Let them decide who stays with who. Their visas are all sorted out.
Okay. We'll talk about it when you're here...
Okay. I'll get back to you. Got a few things to do.
Bye.
Mum told me your brother wants you to move to Karachi with him?
Yeah...
Because of the kids... And because I haven't got a job...
He's the only one who can help us...
That's why he wanted us to move to Karachi. He says we can live upstairs.
Don't even think about it. Don't leave for anywhere... It just won't be home...
Besides, the Army's gonna give you housing and all... You don't need to live with your brother.
Yeah.
But...
We've lost the man of the house...
Nadir's a kid... And you've seen Dad...
Don't forget Sherali's Unit. They'll be there if you need anything. Don't worry.
You don't live here... You don't know...
This isn't the United States.
It ain't easy for a young woman to live all alone... Plus, Sarah's coming of age... And when Noria...
And... What about Mum and Dad? What d'you think?
Badar says they can live with you... Or Ayesha...
They can't live at our place... Not before my kids start college... That should free a room...
As for Ayesha... You know just how well she gets along with her in-laws!
But what's it to you? You're not thinking about them... You're just thinking of yourself.
No...
I've always cared for them... Sherali's parents have been like my own...
We wouldn't be talking about this if that were true.
Okay... I'll talk to Badar.
Maybe they can move to his place with us?
Don't leave your place, Amna...
You don't need to live with your brother!
Because... I've sorted things out for Sarah...
How?
-I mean...
Zuber's started college. Once he graduates and gets a job, we can get him and Sarah married.
That's one of your responsibilities taken care of. So please... Live here with Mum and Dad... Don't leave this place.
Sarah's too young... I haven't even thought about it...
Just give me your word... That's all I need...
All we need to sort this out.
I've talked to my husband and Zuber already. They're fine with it.
We can talk to Badar when he's here.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5