♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 16 - 'Beholden to Borders'
Right now, you're the only one who can stop Vishal from joining the Army...
Please... Stop him...
What? He's joining the Army?
No -- He got into Engineering... Didn't he?
Who told you?
-He and his Granny.
They lied to you.
He's been selected in the Army.
You told her?
You didn't tell her?
♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
Sarah...
Have your breakfast...
I'm getting late... Take care...
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
For you, Vishal...
Say whatever you want...
Get angry all you want...
Hit me all you want...
Do whatever you want, but please...
Don't give me that look, okay?
What's it matter?
It does...
Why'd you lie to me?
Why'd you make promises you can never keep?
Look... Life forces you into things you never want to do...
Don't throw another cheesy film dialogue at me...
I've got no excuses... I've got no reasons... I had no choice...
Your Mum never forced you... Is it your Granny?
It's my helplessness...
My country forced me into this...
My family - four women who look up to me, who I can't protect, can't do anything for... They forced me...
I'm a woman too... I've got women in my family too... I've never been so helpless...
You're brave... Strong...
Stronger than me...
And you?
You're not weak...
You're a coward...
What d'you call it there?
You're a funk!
You're too much of a funk to fight...
And?
Nothing...
Nothing's left now...
Whatever it was between us...
Ends...
Right now...
♪ There's two shores divided by the abyss, ♪
♪ Gone their ways, gone amiss, ♪
♪ In estrangement trying to find bliss... ♪
♪ I stand eager here ♪
♪ And you over there, ♪
♪ To meet in the darkness down there... ♪
♪ May the Lord hear our prayer, ♪
♪ And let our love judge us fair... ♪
♪ Let our love judge us fair, O Lord... ♪
♪ But there's this wall, ♪
♪ There's this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ Yea, there's this wall, ♪
♪ There's this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Mum...
Tell them I accept Cüneyt's proposal...
But why?
It's a good match...
And... I like Cüneyt...
But you sa --
-I don't mind marrying this soldier...
I've got no words, Sarah...
You've left me speechless...
You don't need to say anything.
I always thought...
I've got a long road ahead of me...
A long wait...
I hastened my decision...
Let's just say someone...
Helped me decide...
Who?
A friend.
My deepest thanks to your 'friend'!
It's okay...
You won't regret making this decision...
You have my word.
It's a soldier's oath...
To live and die by.
Vishal's fine now, Dr Sunanda.
He just had a nervous breakdown... Of sorts...
He's stressed.
But don't worry.
He's alright now.
You can take him home tomorrow.
Thank you, Do --
-Welcome, Dr Sunanda.
Yer nu waaat 'e's stressed aboyt...
Don't yer?
I'm so sorry, Vishal...
For what?
For stopping you from joining the Army...
Pressuring you...
I won't stop you.
I'll be happy with what you want...
Do whatever you want... Just -- Don't be like this...
C'mon, we're neighbours...
We live next to each other.
She won't have any problem visiting you...
Our place's been so lonely after Meliha got married...
Cüneyt ain't around too... We'd like his wife to give us some company...
Sarah's just started college...
I'm not sure she can manage both her studies and household chores...
Kids know these days...
Meliha's been doing both her jobs just fine!
You don't need to worry about Sarah's studies. We'll take care of everything.
Totally agreed with you...
Your choice...
She's all yours...
She can go to your place anyday you pick.
On that note, how 'bout some sweets?
Sure. Why not?
Amna... Get us some sweets. And a nice cuppa.
Congratulations!
-Congratulations!
-Thank you.
-Thanks!
God protect you...
Take care, okay?
Got everything you need?
-'Course.
Bye...
Bye.
They want to get you two married as soon as possible.
You're engaged already...
We'd have a man in the family...
If you got married...
He may be able to protect us...
No one's been able to fill the void...
Your Dad left in our lives...
Perhaps Cüneyt...?
Do what you see fit...
I have no problem with it.
Sarah!!
I couldn't keep my word and enlisted in the Army.....
I'm very sorry....
Could you.... Forgive my first lie....?
Vishal.
The weather's changing...
What do we do with the plants outside?
Remind me in the morning, okay?
For now, could you wash these dishes?
Sarah!
Love...
Could I talk to Vishal's Granny?
Why?
Aren't they invited to your wedding?
What are you saying? Why in the world would we invite them?
Why not? We're exchanging sweets already, what's the big deal?
It's not like they're actually gonna come!
Sorry Oi 'enny talked ter yer in a while...
De kids don't let me call yer...
Oi literally 'ad ter cadge Amna ter call yer the-day...
Pure kind av yer...
Vishal's not raun...
An' Sunanda's at work al' day...
Oi tart I'd call yer...
But Vishal's de wan who alwus 'elped me wi' dees things...
Oi gotta learn ter do it meself...
Sarah's not gonna be 'ere forever... Canny go an' ask 'er every time, can Oi?
Waaat do yer mean?
Where's she 'eadin'?
She's gettin' married!
We've fixed de date too...
An' you're invited!
Be the 'oly, that's gran'...
Congratulashuns!
Wonder why Vishal never towl me...
-What? He didn't?
I'm sure he jist forgot...
Anyway... We didn't... You're invited!
No way Oi'm takin' a 'no'... Yer gotta cum see Pakistan!
Sure...
I've alwus wanted ter visit Pakistan...
I'll talk ter Sunanda an' Vishal aboyt it...
By de way...
Who's 'e? 'Er man.
The neighbour's lad.
A Captain, naw less!
A gran' fella. Upright. Simple.
Okay, that's enough...
-Have some more. Yeah, finish it...
Blimey, you look so weak...
The Army ain't no joke...
Know what...
I could barely recognise Vijay when he came back from the Academy...
He'd lost 10 kgs!
Not me... I mean -- Barely had any weight to begin with... Nothin' to lose...
I miss you so much... Why don't you call us?
Between studying and getting some rest... I barely get the time...
I'm not on my phone all day now...
Aye...
No other way he could miss finding out about Sarah's wedding, yes?
Sarah...
Sarah's wedding?
Aye...
She's gotten engaged...
Didn't she tell you? Oh wait... You don't get to call her either, do you?
Speakin' av whaich...
Cos they've invited us...
Why don't we send a gift or somethin'?
Yeah?
What happened?
Was it something I said?
Hello?
Hello...
Getting married?
Yeah...
Congratulations...
You didn't tell me...
Thank you...
You know everything about me...
You found this out too...
You didn't want me to join the Army... But now, you've gotten engaged to a soldier...
You started it...
And I know you're gonna end it...
How's the training?
Oh, just the usual...
My life, though... Not so much...
You could wait until you graduated, you know?
And?
What's the difference?
I would've married Cüneyt...
Either way...
I...
Told him about you...
What'd you tell him?
I said...
I've got a friend...
On the other side...
That makes me his enemy.
That's what he said, too...
He was kidding...
I'm not.
You won't be fighting all day, every day...
Right...?
After you're married...
We won't be able to talk to each other...
-Aye...
Aye...
We won't...
Like we couldn't all these months...
You were busy...
Now, it's my turn...
That's it about life...
Always something... Someone...
Like Cüneyt between us right now?
We had a border between us...
A wall of thorns...
There's a lot more...
♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
And...
What if I said...
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
I wanted to make it over this wall?
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
Can you?
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
If you want...
I can try...
Sarah...
Y -- You there?
I can't hear you...
But... If you can hear me...
Take care...
See you in a better world...
♪ There's two shores divided by the abyss, ♪
♪ Gone their ways, gone amiss, ♪
♪ In estrangement trying to find bliss... ♪
♪ I stand eager here ♪
♪ And you over there, ♪
♪ To meet in the darkness down there... ♪
♪ May the Lord hear our prayer, ♪
♪ And let our love judge us fair, O Lord... ♪
♪ But there's this wall, ♪
♪ There's this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb Â© ZEE5
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5