♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 2 - 'Dust and Echoes'
I never knew this side of you... The brave son...
It's nothing...
I was reading your row on Facebook with Sarah Sherali all night.
You cut her down to size! She couldn't say a word! I dare imagine how it was between her Dad and yours...
Vishal...
We're all very proud of you... You've shown the world you're ready to pick up the baton.
Well done, m'lad.
Who is it this time?
They want to interview Miss Sarah.
Sarah?
But why?
Well...
She had a row with Col Vijay Malhotra's son on Facebook...
I hear you had a row...
With someone on Facebook?
What happened?
A bunch of reporters are here... They say they're covering the row between you and the son of... Col Vijay Malhotra, yes...
They want to talk to you.
I'd like to thank the people of Pakistan for supporting me on social media...
And standing by me after the... Threats and all... And liking my comments...
We'd all like to know... How'd it start?
Well... I saw this video on Facebook about the Indian Government decorating Col Vijay Malhotra...
For 'routing the enemy'... That'd be my father... Who, as you know... Stopped the enemy in their tracks!
Why does she have to say any of this to the media? I don't like it one bit!
Agreed. I'll talk to her Grandpa...
Would you like to tell us how you feel?
-No idea why she's got to be all soppy!
No idea why she's got to be all soppy!
-We don't know a greater hero than Dad. I'm very proud of him. We all are.
We don't know a greater hero than Dad. I'm very proud of him. We all are.
And -- We're not grieving or something...
The entire nation's watching you, Vishal. I'm sure you're proud of how we've all stood by you as you showed our enemy's girl her place on that thread!
The nation salutes your father's courage.
To see the entire nation rally behind me... It was almost overwhelming... But it gave me strength...
It gave us all strength that my countrymen stood by us and paid their tributes to my father... I don't think I could've faced all the abuses thrown my way without their support.
Of course. But is there anything you'd like Sarah Sherali to hear?
No.
Because my Dad said everything we've got to say to Sarah Sherali's Dad.
We're ready to sever the heads of those who dare look at us the wrong way.
My family stands as one, united... Proud that the nation salutes my father's sacrifice.
We end this programme on that note. We'll be back with another debate after the break. Hail India!
They pay him anything for it?
Why?
Why not?
Everyone gets paid to be interviewed on these shows.
Except him, I guess?
Well... The mother of one of his friends works for the channel...
Oh, hell...
Exploitation... All over the blasted place!
Here's a tip... Before any of you goes for the next interview... Just... Sort out your deal, okay?
I can sort out everything else.
I know these dratted journalists inside out...
I know just what goes on behind the scenes...
That was bang-on brilliant, sir! With a bit of skillful presentation (I'll take care of that!), your granddaughter's high-octane interview will flummox India proper!
Now... It's up to you to make 'em all cry... Put on 'We'll Meet Again' or 'Keep the Home Fires Burning' in the background... Anything. I want to see tears, and I want to see a lot of them!
It'd be all the better if...
We could talk to the Colonel's younger daughter and son.
Gotta say, you're quite the orator! You cut the Paki down to size!
Just lovely!
Yeah! I could almost hear the Pakis scream throughout the programme!
We've got so many messages...!
-Wonderful...
I'm thinking of inviting you again... But you gotta give me your word you're not gonna talk to any other channel... Keep this exclusive, okay, Vishal?
Very important!
Okay? And, Arun... I think you should work on his contract... Sign him up for a few features and programmes...
Work on his Facebook and Instagram pages...
And you've got to find every pic with your Dad that you can...
Send them to us, and we're gonna share them. Try to find the most sentimental ones... The ones that make you cry, okay? Okay...
Well done.
Thank you.
-Yeah...
Where's Daddie?
-Martyred...
Martyred?
-In a war...
Fighting who?
No one...
Cut! Not right...
Let's start again. When I ask you that one, you got to say... 'Indians'!
Who?
-Indians...
Actually... Better yet, say... 'The Indian Colonel'. Again, who?
The Indian Colonel...
-Lovely.
Alright, we're ready.
I'm gonna start with that question, and you're gonna say...?
'The Indian Colonel'.
-Aye.
Next, I'm gonna ask what he used to kill him, and you're gonna say, 'His gun', okay?
'His gun'...
-Again?
Again?
-'His gun'.
Okay. Ready?
Okay.
Fighting who?
The Indian Colonel...
Your Dad killed the Pakistani Colonel. What's he gonna get for it?
-A medal.
Here we have Pari and Laxmi... Young, but not too young to appreciate their father's courage that earned him the Victoria Cross.
They know he's not coming back, but they know he's done something that makes their family and their nation proud.
This was Noran Bhaskar reporting from Col Vijay Malhotra's place... Keep watching AS News.
Cut!
So... How was it?
C'mon, pack everything. We gotta go.
Tell the crew we're leaving.
Excuse me...
Who's the producer?
Yours truly.
Okay...
Anurag. Vijay Malhotra's brother-in-law.
Nice to meet you.
-Likewise.
So... How're y'alls payin' us?
Paying? For what?
Laxmi and Pari's interview, of course? And Mum's. Don't tell me you're not...
We're just covering this story... For all of India and the world to watch...
Aye, so?
You're getting your views, aren't you?
I'm from Canada, and they pay 'em for these kinds of shows there.
You're in India, sir... That's not how it is here.
Well, then, why don't you start a tradition here? Such a popular channel... Helping a family in need...
Besides...
We've talked to dozens of channels by now. I think it's about time y'alls valued our time.
Don't you think martyrs' families shouldn't be saying that?
Vijay martyred himself.
We've got our lives...
Needs...
I think y'alls should work on these things before you interview any of us. That's how it is everywhere.
This is not fair.
Careful! The trophy's fragile!
Yeah, we're careful...
Ridiculous!
Why'd you have to create a scene?
Why'd he have to say his Dad was a hero? We all know Dad was the real hero.
Let him believe what he wants to! The world knows better. You don't need to prove your Dad's heroism with this vaudeville!
I can't take it...
-Your Dad's no more...
And you've started disobeying me ever since! I can't take it anymore!
Who told you to sign the contract?
She just wanted me to agree to talk only to their channel. I didn't think it was a big deal...
-Please, Vishal, we don't want to sell our grief! We don't want any ratings!
Just call and tell them you're not creating this Facebook page...
But Mum --
-No!
Or running this Instagram campaign!
Yeah, we do nothing while that Paki Colonel's girl can do whatever the devil she wants!
-Yeah. Nothing.
Because this isn't a war you can't get out of, Vishal.
Enough...
You're not talking to the press ever again.
What's the big deal, Mum?
Dad gave his life for this nation!
It's the least we could do to honour his legacy... His sacrifice!
As if screaming your guts out on Facebook and Instagram could help!
'Not sorry, Indians, but Col Vijay Malhotra was no brave man.'
-'My father embraced death, fighting the good fight. What can you Indian wretches do except yap online?'
-'Miss Sarah Sherali... Your manners show the character of your country. Cowards! That's what you are. What you've always been. I'm Vishal Malhotra... The son of Col Vijay Malhotra... Who died fighting to protect his country... But not before proving his mettle and crushing your army... For which, in just a few days, he will be awarded the Victoria Cross. You are most welcome to believe it. Or would you rather want an official invitation?'
'Miss Sarah Sherali... Your manners show the character of your country. Cowards! That's what you are. What you've always been. I'm Vishal Malhotra... The son of Col Vijay Malhotra... Who died fighting to protect his country... But not before proving his mettle and crushing your army... For which, in just a few days, he will be awarded the Victoria Cross. You are most welcome to believe it. Or would you rather want an official invitation?'
-'Mr Vishal Mahotra... Admittedly, I feel sorry for your loss... But it appears you've lost your sanity between your grief, which is why you can do no better than shoot your mouth off here!'
-'No amount of chest-thumping or gibbering here's gonna prove how brave you are.'
'I'd like to see you bring your old man's regiment here so we can sort it out in a fair fight!'
'Oh, please, just admit we've given you the frights... It's a lot easier... Your old man died a coward's death!'
-'That's only because we're ready to fight... And die for our nation. Were it up to you, you would've killed all the minorities in yours!'
Doesn't he look like your Dad?
As elegant and handsome as Dad...
When your Dad passed away...
He told me...
'Never grieve that I'm gone'...
'For Vijay will always be there with you'...
But Vijay... Didn't even get a chance to say...
Mum...
The more you look at this, the more you'll miss him...
And the more you miss him, the more you'll cry...
Just think...
That he's a hero...
Heroes never die --
-They do!
Who told you they don't?
Ask one's mother...
And she'll correct you...
There, now, Mum...
Get up...
Come.
Have you booked your ticket?
Yeah. I leave on the 20th.
But I'll be back in two months.
Mum...
There's something I wanted to ask...
Yeah?
Go on.
Anurag said... If we could get a part of the estate... We could get a better place in Canada.
The estate?
I've rented it out.
You also get Dad's pension.
Waaat aboyt Vijay's kids?
-He's a martyr, Mum...
They're entitled to welfare.
Anurag said they can get housing too.
We didn't talk about it earlier because you used to live there...
But you'd be living with Sunanda now...
-No...!
I want to live at my place.
You should be with Sunanda and Vishal.
Surely you'd rather not live all alone at this age?
Besides... As I've told you...
We'd need it...
Anyway, think over it...
No hurries...
We can talk again when I'm back.
Anurag's brother can help you out.
He'll get you a good price for it.
Get some rest. You need it.
Good night.
Amna...
What d'you think?
About what?
Your life...
Nothing...
The kids... Mum and Dad...
How can I look after everyone?
That's why I'm asking you to think about it.
I've talked to Nazia...
And we think it's best...
That you come over to our place in Karachi.
Me?
Yeah.
You and the kids.
As for your parents, their daughters can take them to London or the US.
How'd you, Sarah, and the kids live here all alone?
We don't know anyone around here.
That's why I thought you should come over...
We can rent the place the army gives you out...
Together with your pension, it should take care of everything.
I can't think of anything.
Well, when you can... Think over it.
Give yourself some time...
But in a few months... You've got to.
I mean...
Sarah's coming of age too...
It's best that you have a man in the family.
Your father's ageing, and Nadir's just a boy.
You know what I mean, don't you?
I get it, but Mum won't let me.
-What d'you mean?
You've signed a contract with us!
-Yeah... But I didn't ask Mum about it...
She says I shouldn't have signed it.
-I'm coming over in the evening.
We'll sort it out.
You're making your Dad proud.
D'you understand you're fighting for a good cause?
His sacrifice and your patriotism inspire the youth.
Fine by me. But Mum...
If it's fine by you, I'm coming over in the evening to convince your Mum.
Okay.
-Bye.
Bye.
Mum...
We're not going anywhere.
Who told you we're going anywhere?
I heard you and Uncle.
It just won't be home...
Yeah...
But we can't stay here, Sarah...
-Why not?
They all support us here... The TV, the media, the neighbours, the unit...
We don't need Uncle's help.
This won't go on for much longer...
They'll all get back to their lives...
And forget us...
No way.
Dad gave his life for us all. We're his family.
How can they forget a martyr? And us?
A third-world martyr...
What does it matter?
It does.
I can't tell you everything...
But you'll find out soon enough...
Whatever...
I can't leave my home.
I want to stay here.
I know how you feel, Sunanda...
But the best thing is that you've still got Vishal.
You've got someone to keep Vijay's memory alive.
I don't think there's anything more powerful than social media these days.
That's why I asked Vishal to --
-Vishal... Go...
Ankita...
I don't want Vishal to waste his time on social media.
He's under a lot of pressure.
-Of course, I understand it.
I don't want him to waste a second either.
But I've got a team of managers... For his pages and content. His response to Sarah.
Let's just end it here. Please.
I don't want Vishal to fight a war on social media everyday... Not least the war that claimed his father's life.
It may be a job for you, but it's not for Vishal. He's still studying!
I want him to stay away from this mess!
I talked to Anurag.
And he was so excited about the prospects!
And he said h --
-My son's not gonna make a fortune out of his Dad's death.
So I'm sorry... Please go and make it clear to Anurag too.
What happened?
I was worried where Sarah may be...
But turns out she's right here!
Amna!
Sarah's here with us!
Come here.
C'mon, now...
Yeah?
What is it?
Won't you tell Granny?
I don't want to go to Uncle's.
Who's sending you there?
-Uncle was talking to Mum about it.
He says we should live with him in Karachi... And you should live with Aunt in the US... Or England.
Granny...
I don't want to go there...
I hate his kids!
Please tell him...
I don't want to go there...
No way I'm going there...
I'll ask Vishal to drop you at the airport.
-He said it himself.
Take care.
And take care of Mum.
She's just got you and Vishal...
C'mon... I'll see Anurag off too.
I'll be back in two months...
Got a few things to sort out.
Bye.
Take care.
Sunanda...
Anurag wants me to sell my estate...
And give him his share.
Your estate?
My estate... My home...
What d'you say?
Whatever suits you.
Don't talk to the journalists before striking a deal with them, okay?
Okay.
You don't know it, but we've seen the world. We know how they make money.
Feel free to get back to us if you need anything. I can talk to them for you.
Okay.
Vishal...
What are your plans after A-Levels?
I haven't really thought about it... But maybe computer engineering?
Aye, good. You can come over to Canada. Study at a good university. With your excellent grades, it should be a doddle.
Why? I mean -- He doesn't really have to come all the way and all... You've got many good options here...
Besides, your family need you. Mum, Granny, Pari and Laxmi...
You're responsible for all of them.
You're the man in the house.
'Bout time you got over your friends and all, by the way.
Aye.
Amna...
Yeah?
We...
Need to talk...
Alright?
Yeah.
Just the usual...
We can only live as long as we're destined to...
Anyway...
I heard you're going over to Badar's with the kids?
Who told you?
Sarah.
Well...
He said the kids are young... And Sarah's coming of age, so...
Sarah's Grandpa said...
He'd do his best...
To do his duty as the man in the house.
It's nothing like that, Mum... He's done so much for us, but...
My dear...
At this age...
We can't think of going to England...
The US, or anywhere...
Because...
We want to be around Sherali's kids...
As, I'm sure, they'd want us around...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5
Hello? Sarah? You there?
Yes...
What is it?
Just missing Dad...
The misery, the problems... We are the same...
You think I'm yampy?
-No... Just... Depressed.
But why are we talking about it? Why am I telling you any of it? We're enemies, aren't we?
So we are.