Every promise, every vow, every oath,
Everything just snapped...
Heart and soul mine, cry both,
In this life, trapped...
I'm whiling away sleepless nights
And restless days,
Searching for you in the dark anights,
Hoping to see you through the haze...
Who's gonna stop these tears from falling?
There's just this wall,
Just this wall,
That's betwixt us,
That's betwixt us, standing tall...
There's just this wall,
Just this wall,
That's betwixt us,
That's betwixt us, standing tall...
Episode 8 - 'My Friend, My Compeer'
Something wrong?
Why?
Granny and Grandpa didn't say anything when I greeted them.
Something you said? Or Uncle?
Your Grandpa heard you talking to Vishal last night.
He asked me, and I told him about him.
Who wouldn't be furious? Don't say I didn't warn you.
I'll sort it out.
-How?
What're you gonna say? 'You can't stop me from talking to the boy whose father --'
-Please, Mum... He's something else too... Something much more...
He's lost his father too...
Aye, that's why they don't want to talk to us either.
But you're outta your minds, you two.
Don't think you can sing a duet on social media and win hearts all over... We've shed each other's blood.
I know...
We've both shed blood... Both lost... And hurt...
That's why we talk...
Hurt? What d'you want to say?
You think your Dad's heroism is something that hurts us?
Doesn't it?
Don't you dare say that to your Grandpa and Granny.
I'm sure Vishal doesn't dare either. Remember the slap he earned for talking to you?
I do...
His Mum wants to talk to us. You and me.
Us?
Why?
She wants to help.
Are you out to lunch?
Why'd she want to help us?
Who asked for her help?
Me...
What is it that you want from them?
Mum...
Nadir's teacher told me -- the other day...
That he's got a learning disability... Probably dyslexia...
I couldn't figure it out, so I talked to Vishal... He said his Mum's a psychiatrist who's worked with SEND kids...
What's the big deal if I talked to him about it?
You should've talked to me...
You should've told me what his teacher said.
But you're looking for help in India... As if we haven't got anyone who can help here! And -- Did you have to ask him of all the people?
-Mum -- I was too troubled to think! I didn't want to trouble you!
I didn't even know if she was right about what she said...
Could you - any of you - not get up my nose for a change, like, ever?
My brother doesn't want to talk to me because of you...
I've never stepped out of the house, but I've got no end of things to do out there!
Who d'you think we've got who can help us? But you had to create another mess!
For Christ's sake... Just spare me! Please!
Yes, it's Mrs Brigadier Malhotra, Colonel Vijay Malhotra's mother...
Thank you...
I thought if you could help me...
I'd rented the place my husband got after his retirement out...
Yeah...
The tenant doesn't want to leave...
I'll give you all the details...
But he's very rude... Almost threatening...
I want him out this month. Because I want to sell it right away.
Okay. Thank you.
Mum...
Granny's talking to someone from the Unit...
I'm going to see them tomorrow...
I'm sure the Army can kick them out.
They can't do nothing... Even the Army's powerless before the sort your Granny's rented that place to...
Your Dad tried to stop her, but when does she listen to reason?
It's all just... Brahmin sentiment to her... Thought it'd be nice if someone her class... From the party she's always rooting for... Could stay there... Yet here we are...
Mum...
They're nothing before the Army...
I'm a hero's son... I'm sure they'd show some respect...
'Respect'...
There's millions like you in the billion people here... A bunch of them lose their lives everyday... How many d'you think they'd respect?
Why're you so bitter?
I'm not bitter. Just realistic.
Here...
They've made an order to show cause...
For my 'long and unexplained leave'.
They know everything...
Well, just tell them?
I'm trying to... I'm writing my reply...
I'm the late Colonel Vijay Malhotra's widow...
I'm sorry I couldn't attend to my duties because of my husband's sudden and unexpected demise.
The nation wants sacrifices...
Not excuses...
That's all it asks of its people...
So...
Say something, will ya?
What?
What is it?
How d'you know?
I can hear it in your voice.
I know you're troubled.
What is it this time?
Dad shouldn't have left us...
Not like this... Not so soon...
That's what I'm thinking too... We needed him here...
Grandma's estate... The one Aunt wants a share in...
Has been taken over by the tenants.
What?
Aye. We gotta do something. And do it quick. Aunt's coming in two days. No way she's gonna take this nicely.
Why don't you talk to the Unit? They'll throw them out in a moment.
I did... But nothing happens in a moment...
They told me I have to file an application...
Which I did... Let's see...
Anyway, did you talk to Mum... About that... Thing?
Grandpa's found out I talk to you.
That why you're worried?
No one wants to talk to me...
Suddenly, I'm the traitor...
Is that... You telling me you can't talk to me anymore?
I can't talk to anyone like I talk to you... But when I talk to you...
It hurts everyone.
They think I'm talking to the son of the man who --
Well, so am I. Talking to the girl whose father killed mine...
Anyway, how long d'you want to keep at it? I need to know when I should come back on Facebook.
Sarah?
Yeah?
Can I... See you on Skype?
Nah, I get it... Fraidy-cat ain't gonna show me her face.
You'd be stupid to think I'm so stupid.
D'you think I'd do all you want...
When you want it?
In your dreams, perhaps, but never for real...
I'm a soldier's daughter, but I'm smart.
You're weird... Really.
The different sort...
The memorable sort...
Hello?
You there?
Did I stick around too long?
Did you mind it? Me saying that...
Sorry, I didn't hear you.
(What now...?)
Sarah...
You know, I --
I think you're very...
Actually...
What I want to say is --
-Anyway, I'm honestly sleepy...
Gotta get some rest. Bye.
Okay, good night...
The stars and the heavens above...
See you in another part of the world...
Every promise, every vow, every oath,
Everything just snapped...
Heart and soul mine, cry both,
In this life, trapped...
I can't be too sure, but... I think he's dyslexic.
That's why I asked your daughter to consult a psychologist.
We've never even heard of it before.
What is his problem, exactly?
It's just a learning disability. Many kids have one. It can be managed if addressed on time...
But -- He never had any problems before...
I think Nadir's just disturbed and upset... After my husband's death...
I'm sure he's upset... But that's got nothing to do with this.
I'm sure he had this problem before... Perhaps no one could identify it...
I did when I started taking his classes a few months back.
I couldn't talk to you about it before, but now that you're here, I think we should do something about it.
Would you happen to know any psychiatrist or psychologist? He can sort this out.
I don't know any myself, but I'll see what I can do.
I'll try to find someone who can treat him.
Could you give me your number?
Dad...
Nadir will be fine, won't he?
- Of course.
The teacher said he'll be fine.
It's just a learning disability.
We'll get him treated before it's too late.
He's my only son...
If he couldn't do well...
Amna...
Don't worry.
I'll do my best.
I'll look for someone. Do something for him. Sort this out.
Who d'you think did all of this when wee Sherali fell ill?
I could manage something back then... I sure can now...
Never forget...
Age cannot wear my will.
Don't worry.
Our worries don't seem to end...
There's always something...
C'mon...
I'll call Badr... He may be able to help.
Sure.
He's in Karachi. I'm sure he'd know someone in the city...
I'll talk to Rabia and Ayesha...
The doctors in the UK and the States can treat anything...
Besides, I'm sure they'll do anything they can for their brother's son...
They'd care for him...
Hello?
Hello...
Yeah?
How are you?
-Fine.
Something's come up --
-Why am I not surprised?
Otherwise, why'd you think of me?
I'm sorry but I don't have the time...
But don't worry... I'm sure your in-laws can help...
Why d'you want to talk to Rabia? She left us in a fit of rage!
Who else have I got?
Amna's brother doesn't seem to care!
I'm sure it's the same with Rabia...
And Ayesha?
You're the stuff of...
Sweet dreams, you are...
By me in my thoughts though far,
Okay...
You're the stuff --
Sorry... Lemme try that again...
You're the stuff of sweet dreams, you are,
By me in my thoughts though far,
Like the priceless gift that you are...
You're the thirst I crave for, you are,
Following me around like the pole star,
A feeling, unexpressed by words, you are...
You, yeah you, you've got beauty that can kill,
That draws me closer and closer still,
Chasin' my lovely daffodil,
That's who you are...
The stuff of sweet dreams, you are...
You're the stuff --
Sorry... Lemme try that again...
You're the stuff of sweet dreams, you are,
By me in my thoughts though far,
Like the priceless gift that you are...
You're the thirst I crave for, you are,
Following me around like the pole star,
A feeling, unexp --
You're back?
Yeah...
You said Vishal's mother can help?
Let me know when I can talk to her.
Okay?
You, yeah you, you've got beauty that can kill,
That draws me closer and closer still,
Chasin' my lovely daffodil...
She listened to it but didn't reply...
I mean, I ain't that bad...
Or maybe, she's so mesmerised!
Nah, I ain't that good either...
How 'bout asking her -- Nope, sounds cheap...
Nah, forget it...
You're angry?
You know everything.
It's not like I talk to him in secret...
Mum knows about him.
-Never thought you'd be so shameless!
You say that like you've known him for ages! You know who they are, right?
Yeah...
But don't we talk to millions of others?
People of every country... Every religion... How are they any different?
Only because they don't think that way!
Have you ever seen how proudly they act?
How they talk about us?
Remember everything they said when you had a row with Vishal online?
Remember everything you used to tell me?
But most of all... Remember everything he said on TV?
It -- It was silly... Stupid of us...
Only those who fight pay the price... The rest of us just... Cheer on, make noise, and -- Enjoy the circus!
Sarah!
Why d'you have to talk to Vishal?
We've got enough on our hands already.
Okay...
I won't talk to him if you say...
But I just talk to him! Just talk...
You've never made friends with a boy before...
And --
-It's not like I'm friends with him.
We talk because we're enemies. Sworn enemies at that.
Grandpa...
Ever since he lost his Dad... They're going through the same mess as us... Living through the same hell...
But what hurts me...
Is you doubting me...
It hurts me a lot...
Where's she disappeared?
Is it my song...
... Or her family?
You, yeah you, you've got beauty that can kill,
That draws me closer and closer still,
Chasin' my lovely daffodil...
Hello?
Mrs Malhotra?
Yeah, who's it?
Your tenant.
Narain Saxena.
Yes?
I hear you've filed a complaint against me...
You forced me to...
You shouldn't have done that...
But don't worry...
I'm right here... At your place...
Throw me out if you can...
Don't forget...
The sacrifice of your son...
Save your grandson while there's time...
Your bloodline risks...
Extinction...
Long live India...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5
I never knew you've got such a lovely voice.
You noticed it just now? We talk - like - everyday.
Never paid attention to it...
So... How was the shocker? My song?
-A pleasant shock...
Can't believe you care so much about them that you're worried about her Mum more than your studies!
Call them when it's okay. I'll talk to them.
-How about right now?