♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 6 - 'Cold-Blooded Blood Ties'
I'm sure Sherali would've thought differently...
Of course...
I'm sure if Sherali were with us...
We wouldn't be talking about any of this...
I've got no shortage of matches for my son.
I just wanted to ease my sister's burden...
Sarah's no burden!
Unlike you, I'm not doing anyone here a favour...
It's my duty to help them.
I want my brother's daughter for my son.
We've got a right over our brother's kids before you.
-Look who's talking about rights...
Someone who - unlike me - couldn't care less about the responsibilities that come with it.
Someone who'll never bother to take them up.
Who asked you to do anything?
Why are you even here?
I can call Atif to help them with all the paperwork. But you took it upon yourself because you wanted to.
You couldn't even be here for Sherali's funeral!
I took care of everything here.
When Uncle and all the others were grieving.
Sherali's Unit took care of everything. The Army arranged for his funeral. What'd you do?
I don't want to talk to you.
I don't want to argue with you... Not after Sherali...
But let me be clear...
Sarah's not marrying anyone other than my son.
Not one of your sons!
You can't order around like that here!
I'm not ordering you around. Just... Telling what I want and asking for it...
I couldn't tell you but... I intend to take Amna and the kids along anyway.
D'you hear that, Amna? D'you hear what he's saying?
Who gave him the right to decide for you and the kids? Who the dickens is he when we're here?
Why are you acting like the kids've got no one but their Uncle? We're still here.
Uncle's here because they needed him. He has no interest poking his nose where it doesn't belong.
And, if Amna has a problem with his help and proposal, he will leave.
We're not coming with you. I'm not marrying your son. Period.
Sarah! Back to your room.
Why are you shutting her up? She knows what's best for her.
And she just said what she wants. She'd rather choose Rabia's son --
-I'm not marrying your blimmin' son either!
I'm not marrying your blimmin' son either!
Nor yours!
I will take up all responsibilities myself. We don't need your sympathies and pity!
We can manage something. Take care of ourselves.
And -- Why are you even here? Go back where you're needed! Out!
Gorblimey! Hear what she's saying? Is that what you've taught her? She's kicking us out!
I've been doing all the paperwork like mad, but it appears you've grown up! You're all independent! You don't need your Uncles, Aunts, or anyone now, do --
Yeah. We don't.
We've got enough problems without you lot starting a bloody riot!
Mind your tongue! They're your elders!
-Well they better behave like it!
All I see is a bunch of filthy rabble-rousers, all wrapped up in their blasted selves!
Who told you to say anything?
Who told any of them to come here and start plotting against us all day?
Your mother's a widow.
You're orphans.
Your Uncle and Aunts are the only family we've got!
Can't you see we need them?
-We're not orphans...
No...
Dad's a martyr... A hero...
A martyr's wife...
Is as much a widow...
His children, as much orphans...
Just... Go. Right now.
Go back where you've come from. Go to Britain, America, or Timbuc-blasted-too!
We've got all we need in our lives here.
Thank you too, sir.
I'll take your leave.
♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's two shores divided by the abyss, ♪
♪ Gone their ways, gone amiss, ♪
♪ In estrangement trying to find bliss... ♪
♪ I stand eager here ♪
♪ And you over there, ♪
♪ To meet in the darkness down there... ♪
♪ May the Lord hear our prayer, ♪
♪ And let our love judge us fair... ♪
♪ Let our love judge us fair, O Lord... ♪
♪ But there's this wall, ♪
♪ There's this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Who's having breakfast so early?
Mr Badar. He had a flight to catch.
Where's he off to?
Didn't he tell you? He left.
Could you make something for me too?
Hey! Where are you off to?
My brother-in-law's here for me. I'm staying with him and leaving from his place.
But you're only jus --
-I've stayed here long enough.
I'd be off my head to stay here after everything Mum and Dad said yesterday.
-What is it that we said?
What is it that we said?
That you're oh-so-hurt about? But if that's what you want...
Have it your way...
Okay.
Without my brother to side with me... You can do as you want.
And Amna and her family can say whatever they want.
I'll get get going. I'm getting late.
Bye.
But -- Wait -- Stop her --
-Don't stop her! Let her go!
It's best if she leave!
But how? I'm sure she'll listen to Ayesha... I'll go get h --
She's gone.
Where?
To her sister-in-law. She said she's staying there. She leaves the day after tomorrow.
But -- Couldn't she tell us?
Someone's got a problem with me... And someone's got a problem with Sarah!
She can say sorry. We'll talk to h --
No one's talking to her!
No one's stopping them!
What's happened...
Is enough!
Where's the other plates?
Everyone else left, ma'am...
Who?
Your Uncle...
Mmes Rabia and Ayesha...
Where?
No idea. They all just... Packed their things and left... One-by-one...
So everyone's gone!
Everyone's here... Everyone else is gone...
Peace at last!
I'm starving! Get me everything you've got! Call Mum, Grandpa, and Granny...
This calls for a proper feast!
I'm honestly delighted they're all gone.
Mhm... Same here.
I hate Uncle... He makes Mum cry all the time...
Well, so does Aunt...
Which one?
-The younger one.
I feel like roughing up anyone who makes Mum cry.
And I hate it when anyone comes here...
I want to get out of this place... With Mum...
Gopi!
Ma'am?
How many ages has it been since you cleaned this room?
I couldn't get the time... Not with all the guests --
-No, thank you... I can do it myself...
Ma'am...
CoUldN'T gET thE TimE...
You never get the time when no one's watching, do you?
No... No...!
Gently this time, Nadir! Or I'm hitting it hard!
-Give her your best shot!
Aww...
Catch!
-Not out!
Everyone's left because of her, but look at how happy she is! I mean, she's not a kid!
She's a kid... Never let her grow up.
-Get the ball!
I can't stop her...
But everyone in my family and yours would be cursing her...
Who cares?
What's the worst they can do?
What could they do when we suffered our worst?
Nothing.
They'll just say a few things for a few days and move on...
-You're too slow for me!
All I care about...
Is being with my Sherali's kids...
Amna...
-Out!
We're all together... All in this together...
-Careful! Don't aim for my face again!
-Back off a bit...
Come over here! Aye...
Waaat tuk 'imself so long?
Took you long enough!
Good day, Granny!
It's okay... I was working on an assignment, okay? Why are you worried? Did you need me?
No.
Jist a bit worried...
Don't be out for so long...
Granny... I don't do it on purpose...
C'mon...
-But I get worried!
Why'd you give up your morning walk?
Huh?
No idea...
I gave up on a lot since last month...
I'm sure you're starving.
-Actually, no... I had my lunch at the University...
But Oi'm starvin'...
I've been waiting for you...
Granny...
Please don't starve yourself waiting for me...
That's what Dad always said, remember?
Please, have something...
I will... Sure...
Naw wan gives up on food...
Back at last?
-Aye.
Seeing you do the chores after a loooong while... Delighted!
D'you see how you've kept your room? It's a complete mess! Had to do something about it...
You're not a kid, Vishal...
What are you saying?
I'm still a kid... Here...
Take a look...
Adulting suits you...
Not this... Okay?
Besides, we need an adult in the family...
Not a kid...
I see grey hair!
Aye, they've been this way for a while... More and more turn grey everyday...
Dye them. Like before?
What good is it?
Black or grey... Who's gonna care? Who's gonna bother to look?
Anyway... I've arranged the clothes in your cupboard. Everything's organised perfectly. Don't make a complete haymes of it, okay?
Okay.
Clear?
Mum...
When are you getting back to work?
Soon.
About time... I got a letter... They can only let me take so many leaves...
Don't scatter everything everywhere!
I'm sorry about what Sarah said... But you shouldn't have gone like that... Without telling anyone...
Aye, I should've stayed there... So you, your kids, and your in-laws could insult me more!
And hear that I'm doing this for the money...
He said it in a fit of rage... You know how much we respect you...
Aye... I know only too well how much they...
And you and your kids respect me...
I always shut my wife up...
But now I think she was right all this time.
But --
I'm sure the Unit will take good care of you and your kids.
I don't want your insults!
Hello?
Hear that? Your Uncle doesn't even want to talk to me!
Why do you want to talk to him?
Why d'you want him to come here?
He doesn't want to talk? Fine by us.
How can we live all alone?
-Is it any better with him?
We're more lonely with him than without...
At least... We're together... All of us...
Oi got me ticket ter A. R. Rahman's concert. Want ter cum wi' me?
-You're going to Mumbai?
Without a ticket?
Vishal! Why didn't yer git yers? Oi tart yer alwus wanted ter be dare live!
-So I did...
But not now... Not Mumbai, sure...
Step oyt av yisser gaff for a day or two... Can't believe you're the guy who couldn't stay at his place!
So I was...
But not now... Got no choice... But I'm happy for you.
Vishal...
We want to have some ice cream...
-Okay, go. I'll come in a sec...
-No, we wanna go right now!
Guess I'll... See you tomorrow?
-Okay.
-Sure.
-Bye.
What's the matter, Granny? You move it around all the time!
Yer got a problem? It isn't dat 'eavy!
You'd know if you were lifting it... When do I keep it back?
Go... I'll call you when I need you...
I have to leave the kitchen for this...
Look... Don't ask anything of me when I'm with my friends.
Why?
What's with all the whys all the time?
-Dad used to take us whenever we asked him... He never said anything like that...
Well, I'm not Dad...
-I know...
Sorry... How 'bout another one? C'mon!
You're good... But Dad was better...
Enjoy yourselves...
How many more times will your younger days come back to me?
Oi never tart...
I'd 'av nathin' else ter go on wi'...
Whaen it al' ended...
Oi cud never even imagine...
Good that you're out somewhere after long... How does it feel?
Here.
Thank you.
-Ma'am.
How say you order something?
Order what you like... Please.
Okay...
Shoot! 1-10, 1-10! Shoot! Goal! Got it!
Gee, you're louder than all of them... Combined!
But look at that fantastic goal!
Lovely, aye...
You're so boring... Remember how you react when Sachin hits a six? It's that kinda goal! The whole Premiership depends on it!
Okay... But please... Let me work...
As if I'm a kid!
Here.
-Treat yourself!
Grumpy as always, eh?
Well done!
Sunanda...
What happened?
Easy there...
Sunanda?
Hello.
-Hello.
Why isn't Mum taking my calls?
No idea.
-She's not been online. Not checked her WhatsApp. Stopped taking my calls.
What's up?
What do I know?
-Give the phone to her.
'Sec...
Just a minute...
Granny... It's Aunt.
Hello?
-Yeah?
She turned in...
She doesn't turn in this early!
You can talk to her when I'm back from University tomorrow... I'd hate to wake her up right now...
Okay.
Don't forget it, okay?
Okay. Bye.
Bye.
What's up?
Why don't you want to talk to her?
Oi'm weary, Vishal...
Oi'm weary av it al'...
Jist wan tin' on 'er mind...
The estate...
The money...
Her share...
Well, then, give her her share and sort it out forever.
Wan...
One last memory of your Grandpa... That's what it is to me...
I've lived there for so long...
Easy for them to say, 'Sell it'!
Tell me...
Can you sell something you're so attached to... So quickly?
Can yer?
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5
Don't talk to Sarah Sherali ever again! Never forget we're enemies!
No way I can forget that... Not with you saying it every waking moment to remind me!
They hate us.
We don't talk about our friends as much as we talk about one enemy.
I don't know what our elders want. Do they want to see each other or not, be friends or enemies, talk to each other or not... I mean... They're so confused!
Well, so are we...!