♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 11 - 'Hate or Love?'
When'd you remember you had a daughter?
How could I forget her?
I love her so much.
You do? Funny I didn't see it when you kicked me out.
I didn't kick you out. You picked a row and left.
Just forget it and give her the good news!
Aye, forget it... I just called...
To give you the news...
That Sarah's got her result.
Straight A*s!
She'll get into medical college.
Congratulations.
Turns out you didn't miss me at all...
You just wanted to share the news about your granddaughter.
She's your niece too! I just called so you could, maybe, congratulate her yourself?
That insolent girl? Don't even think about it.
I ain't congratulating anyone.
What happened? Lost the signal?
She hung up.
What?
Hello?
Rabia?
Good day, sir. This Sarah Sherali's place?
-Good day.
Of course.
-Sweets for her.
Sweets?
-Yeah.
From where?
India.
Could you sign this here?
Here.
Thank you.
What's that?
Sweets for your sweet little granddaughter!
Ah, the sweet smell of success!
Who sent it?
Pretty sure it's her Uncle Badar.
No!
It's from India!
Vishal sent this!
Why'd you receive it? You could've just returned it.
You wanted me to tell that to the delivery boy? I don't want to create a scene!
What's up, Dad? What happened?
I'll tell you what's up. I told you to talk it straight with Sarah.
But no... Now they're exchanging sweets! What's next?
By the way...
How'd they find out about Sarah's result?
I told his Mum.
-You?
You talked to her again?
We've hurt each other every way we can.
What's left?
It's just some sweets. Big deal. We even exchange sweets with enemies...
Besides...
You know we ain't getting anything from our families...
We'll get even...
Send them something when it's time...
There will be no dues... No favours...
Right... Left... Right... Left... Right... That's good. C'mon.
Just a minute, Vishal... I forgot my handbag.
-We'll be waiting in the car.
They're coming with us?
Yeah. Gotta get some things for them on the way...
We can get it later...
I told you I won't enjoy with the kids around...
And I told you I can't leave them home while I show you places...
So, we're gonna be waiting in the car. Let us know if you're coming, okay?
Let's go!
What?
Balloons! Vishal! Stop here!
-Yeah, get me one!
-Aye...
Okay, just lemme park the car...
If we keep stopping like this every other minute, we're done sightseeing...
This is gonna be quite a sight to see!
Need some help?
-No, I'm done...
I don't usually enter the kitchen with Gopi around...
When's he coming back?
A couple of days, at the most...
Did Mum say anything to you?
No?
About Vishal and Neha, I mean...
Vishal and Neha?
Their marriage.
Are you serious?
He's just a kid, Pratibha!
He ain't a kid anymore... He's 18!
I found someone good, so I thought I'd do something for my nephew.
She's a Canadian nationality holder. You know how influential her family is.
You don't get matches that good that easily. He can study if he wants... Or start a family...
Vishal's my only son. Who'd be here with us if he left for Canada?
D'you think we can manage without him? Mum, me, Pari, and Laxmi?
I don't want him to leave you either...
I just meant he could think about his future... And take you along...
Besides, you've got so many problems here...
Aye, but we're used to 'em.
Anurag asked me to talk to you about it...
I can't tell him you told me what you did...
He said we won't need our share of the estate if Vishal accepts this proposal...
Please, Pratibha...
How long has it been since your brother's death? And you're talking about Vishal's marriage?
Take your time. We're not in a hurry.
They make a good couple. It's a good match.
That's what Mum thinks too... I think Vishal's interested too...
Oh, please...
What's up with Grandpa and Granny?
What'd they say?
Nothing.
I just saw it on their faces...
What's this?
It's for you.
Me?
Grandpa received it.
I didn't ask him to send anything...
Did you tell him about your result?
Vishal... How 'bout a picture?
Sure.
'With my Handsome Hunk'?
'Neha Sharma is with Vishal Malhotra at Urban Market'?
He never mentioned her...
'Neha Sharma is with Vishal Malhotra at Urban Market'
Why didn't he tell me?
And that place smelled like butter! Did you notice?
Whoa... Looks like you two visited all of Amritsar!
Aye.
-Hardly... Vishal couldn't leave Pari and Laxmi for a moment...
You didn't have to take the kids along... I mean, it's so hot! Enjoyed anything?
So, Vishal... When are you taking her to Mumbai?
Mum --
Mum -- Bai?
Aye. And then... Agra. Right, Neha?
I gotta have a bath... Getting all sweaty in the heat...
-Sure...
Show me what you've got.
-C'mon, you two gotta change...
Indian dresses! Isn't that a nice colour?
-C'mon.
Blimey, it's so pretty. Was it on sale?
-Of course. Everything was. I got everything I could!
It's so nice... Lemme see...
Nawab always stays at his place a week longer than he's supposed to...
I talked to Vishal's Mum...
When?
Last night...
And?
She's nice.
Warm. Humble.
Don't say I didn't tell you. What'd you talk about?
What else? She told me about Vishal's Dad... I told her about yours...
We gotta talk again today...
She sent a few things on WhatsApp... Teaching techniques for dyslexic kids...
Vishal sent the numbers of two psychologists... Did you get an appointment?
Aye. One of 'em's not in Pakistan right now. The other isn't free for 90 days.
We can visit him in Lahore... Or Karachi...
I can go to Karachi...
Your Uncle's there too...
Did you tell him about my result?
Yeah.
And?
He congratulated me...
Before saying he's busy...
Your Grandpa and Granny have had some...
I've given some to Nadir and Noria...
So...
Forget where it's from and have it...
After all... It's for your result.
What happened?
I would've felt like celebrating if Dad were here...
I've been calling for ages. Where've you been?
I called you too. Where've you been?
What, you settlin' scores now?
Why would I?
I mean --
Nothing... I just... Took my Aunt shopping and all... Sightseeing, you know?
Just your Aunt?
Aye.
I got your sweets. Why'd you send me?
Who asks that?
You didn't have to spend a couple thousand...
Big deal. I just wanted to share my happiness...
Aren't you happy?
It wasn't necessary, this... Politesse...
-Polit -- What?
Oh, nothing much... Something unnecessary, really...
Something wrong?
No. What could be wrong with me?
Did you mind it? Me sending you sweets...
Why'd I mind it?
First and only box of sweets I got for my admission...
Anyway, I gotta go... Dinner time... Bye.
-Hey --
Why'd you lie to me?
Gee, I literally bought everything I could see! I was worried Vishal would say something, but he's so nice...
It's nothing...
I mean -- Nothing... I just... Took my Aunt shopping and all... Sightseeing, you know?
-He got me everything I wanted.
-What else did you do?
I mean -- Nothing... I just... Took my Aunt shopping and all... Sightseeing, you know?
-Shopping, shopping, and more shopping!
Just your Aunt?
-Really?
Yeah, we went to the Haat...
-Get anything for me?
Of course, I did! Shoes, dresses, you name it! Everything!
We could go on, but Vishal said he had to get back...
I lied to you
I
I k
I kn
I kno
I know
How d'you know I lied to you
You didn't tell me about Neha
Hello?
What, you a crystal gazer now?
Why?
How d'you know about Neha?
Go and check your timeline...
She's my Uncle's niece...
Here from Canada on a tour of India...
Why did you hide it from me?
What's the worst I could've said?
Nothing, aye... I'm sorry... Shouldn't have done it...
That why you're angry?
It's your personal matter... Why'd I be angry?
You saw all her pics?
Aye. All your selfies with her.
Lovely.
That's not what I -- She's a bonehead, that cow!
Oh?
She thinks you're a handsome hunk. You think she's a bonehead. Yet you're there, happily taking selfies with her all day.
Hy
Hypo
Hypocrite.
Jaysus -- She's crazy about these selfies and stuff -- Not me!
She doesn't even care what my family's going through!
All she cares about is her long list of PlAcES tO gO and tHInGs To bUy!
Okay, enough with the explanations...
Who else can I tell?
D'you mind her going out with me?
Why'd I mind it?
But I do mind you lying to me...
The least I can expect as a friend is you telling me the truth...
Okay...
I won't lie again... I'm really sorry...
Please...
Want me to sing your anger to sleep?
What d'you mean?
Don't try anything cheap.
No need to sing anything for me or my anger...
Wait... Just a sec...
♪ Sarah... You are so pretty... ♪
♪ And me Granny doesn't like that Neha one bit, yeah Granny... ♪
♪ So, Sarah, please don't be mad... ♪
♪ Or India and Pakistan will be very sad... ♪
♪ Sarah, Sarah, Sarah... ♪
♪ You're so pretty... ♪
♪ Sarah...! ♪
♪ Sarah! ♪
You gotta try... How can you convince Vishal and Sunanda if you don't talk to them?
'Tis their life, Anurag... Oi canny force dem.
Who's forcing anyone? It's for their best...
Vishal's all set for life if he got married to Neha.
Why don't you get it?
I've been trying to tell her for ages...
But who knows what's going on in her mind?
No one in my place would've cared so much about you...
But... You're family... I'm doing what's best for you...
Sorry if I disturbed you! I'll be back...
-Nah, Oi ain't jammers at al'...
Aye, we're talking about you. It's best if you heard it.
About me?
Hey.
How are you?
Great. You?
Not so much. Thanks to your Granny and Aunt.
Why? What happened?
Why don't you tell him, Mum?
Vishal...
Anurag an' yisser Aunt...
Want ter git yer married ter Neha...
Aye. She's a good match for you. Smart, stylish... Your type.
She just got into college... She's the type they all want...
A nationality holder too... You'll be all set for life...
Anurag's found the best match for you...
Without Vijay around... We've gotta think about all these things...
Your career... Your life... Your life-partner...
Aye...
Thank you so much...
But... I don't want to get married or anything...
Not just yet...
Not anytime soon...
Besides... I don't think I'm going to Canada anytime soon... I'm fine here, Aunt...
Well...
Looks like they don't care about it after all...
Get your share and come back.
And if you can't...
Just send Neha back...
You won't rest until you've ruined my marriage, will you?
You only care about yourself... Not your daughter...
What's wrong with you?
I'm ruining your marriage? My daughter's marriage?
Have some sense...
Before you speak...
Anurag's said enoof guff already... Don't yer start nigh...
What's wrong with what he said?
Just accept this proposal...
Or give me my share...
You know...
He won't let me in unless I've got my share...
Hey, Vishal!
Where're we going today?
Umm...
Look... I can't marry you, Neha...
Just... Make it clear to Uncle Anurag, okay?
Sarah's the only one I'll ever love...
So... If I ever decided to get married... She'll be the one...
You... Heard it?
Mum?
How dare you even think about it?
You love Sarah? You gonna marry her?
-No way...
I wanted to say something else -- It just -- Slipped out...
Big mistake...
You'd do well to remember that!
You can never love her...
She can never be yours! I hope you're clear about that!
Of course...
It's not like I love her or something...
It's just -- Plain impossible!
I just needed something to get rid of Neha...
How could I love her?
And -- Just why?
Look into my eyes and say that again, Vishal!
You shouldn't have to ask me!
How could you love Sarah?
Yeah?
And why?
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5