♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 7 - 'A Bond of Grief'
Could you go to Nadir's school? His teacher's been asking me... Something about his result maybe...
Okay, I'll leave early...
I could've gone if I were not in mourning...
I could send Dad... But he may not get what she says...
But I'm sure... You will...
Okay...
How's Vishal's Mum?
I didn't talk to him after you told me not to...
Good.
I don't know what to tell you... It would've been better if your mother had come...
Of course but... She can't come right now...
-But this is important. We can't ignore it.
You can tell me. Dad and I used to help him with his work.
Just me now...
Nadir's result has been very bad...
I'm sure you can understand... The tragedy we're living...
The school has tried everything. I have tried everything. I think it's something else...
What?
The school psychologist had a session with Nadir.
He has a learning disability.
Learning disability?
I don't get it...
That's why I wanted to talk to your mother. I'm sure she'd know...
You're too young to get this, maybe, but...
Nadir needs therapy for this...
30%... 40%... Can't believe it...
The teacher says he needs to work harder...
And?
Nothing?
Just... Talked about his exams... Results...
But he's never scored so low...
His grades are falling everyday... What's the matter?
Nadir's our only hope...
If he didn't study hard...
No... I'm sure you don't teach him well enough...
I'm getting him a tutor.
If you wanted to have something, yer could've jist asked me...
It's just noodles... Almost done...
By the way... Aunt's been calling... What do I tell her?
What d'you mean?
How long do I have to ignore her?
As long as you can.
Hello
i
i know
i know you're
i know you're online...
why don't you say something ?
Because I want to forget you...
It's easy now...
But not for long...
Excuse me...
Good day.
-Good day.
D'you have a card?
-Of course.
Please wait with the martyrs' families.
They're all martyrs' families?
Yeah.
Looks like... This'll take a while...
Just wait for this patient... You're next.
But I go next.
They go first.
Please, come with me.
How many patients have we got?
Your messages last night
Your messages last night kinda caught
Your messages last night kinda caught me
Your messages last night kinda caught me .... by surprise
Vishal...
If you've got time, we can go the-morra.
Go where?
Your Grandpa's estate, of course...
That we've rented out.
Why?
Blimey...
We didn't get the rent last month.
Plus, Pratibha's gonna be 'ere anyday...
Oi don't nu waaat ter do... But aye...
She called yisser Mamai ter tell 'er we don't take 'er calls...
Just sell the estate... Or she'll keep bothering you...
You've got us.
Sometimes...
That's what I think too...
You can't hold on to everything forever...
Sometimes, you gotta decide...
When to hold on...
And when to let go...
So... Come with me tomorrow, okay?
Okay, Granny, as --
It's... Uhh...
One of my friends... I'll be back in a sec...
Hello?
You've got one for theatrics, I give you that!
-Theatrics?
'Caught me by surprise'? 'Not sure what to do'? D'you really think I'll buy any of that?
You're angry?
-Nah, I'm enjoying it thoroughly.
Obviously, I'm furious!
Too often, aye...
Don't you think?
-So?
How many times've you told me we're not talking again? Only to call me later yourself...
Mum was asking how your Mum's doing.
Like... My Mum? For real?
Aye... Told me not to talk to you... And then asked about your Mum...
That's very kind of her.
Weird is more like it.
Why?
I don't know what our elders want. Do they want to see each other or not, be friends or enemies, talk to each other or not...
I mean... They're so confused!
Well, so are we...!
I'm... So worried...
What is it?
Nadir's dyslexic... His teacher says he needs therapy.
Dyslexic?
Can't you know it early on?
How'd you miss it?
He was always a slow learner... With minor learning disabilities...
Dad used to help him with it... And then me... But he's changed...
I Googled around but I don't get much...
He's the man of the house... What if something happened to him?
Don't worry, Sarah...
If the teacher says he needs therapy, why d'you assume he's dyslexic?
I'm talking to you because -- I don't know what to do...
I'm so sorry...
If I knew you're so worried --
-You wouldn't have sugarcoated your ego as 'surprise'... Innit?
There's nothing left of my ego here...
I'm the only man looking after four women...
What'd happen to them if I started caring about my ego?
I'll -- Try something... Actually, you know what, Mum's taught SEND children for a while... Including dyslexics.
She's a psychiatrist.
She's a psychiatrist?
A psychiatrist who can't handle her own depression?
It's always easy to solve others' problems...
But when it's your time... You know...
I have no idea what to do...
I'll talk to Mum...
What'll you tell her?
Everything. I've been talking to Col Sherali's daughter... And I want to help his son...
I mea --
-Who're you talking to again?
Col Sherali's daughter? Did I get that right?
Y -- Yeah... Mum...
You know everything...
I don't know what to say...
You're talking to Sarah Sherali?
-She's a soldier's daughter...
Someone like me...
The least two forces can do is answer a call for help...
It's called humanity.
'Humanity'...!
Don't ever preach your 'humanity' here again!
Get it?
What've I done to earn that slap?
You've got no idea, have you?
♪ There's two shores divided by the abyss, ♪
♪ Gone their ways, gone amiss, ♪
♪ In estrangement trying to find bliss... ♪
♪ I stand eager here ♪
♪ And you over there, ♪
♪ To meet in the darkness down there... ♪
♪ May the Lord hear our prayer, ♪
♪ And let our love judge us fair... ♪
♪ Let our love judge us fair, O Lord... ♪
♪ But there's this wall, ♪
♪ There's this wall, ♪
And 2kg flour...
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
2kg?
-I got a discount last time...
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Yeah.
This here tastes lovely.
Got it?
Here. Like this.
-What's up with you?
Nothing?
What is it?
N -- Nothing...
I -- Don't exactly remember why I came here...
Someone needs to eat more almonds to keep their memory young!
Yeah, write that down too...
-And almonds...
Sarah...
What happened?
Nothing.
No, there's something... Tell me...
I talked to Vishal...
Hardly surprising, now, is it?
And then?
His Mum came when he was talking...
And...
She heard everything... She knows we talk to each other...
She slapped him...
I heard everything because I was on the phone.
Why are you so worried?
Why not?
We're enemies, Sarah.
What d'you care for them?
That's why I always said you shouldn't be talking to him...
Why does it hurt you if his Mum slapped him?
They hate us.
All of them.
Mum's got a point...
What's it to me?
What do I care about Vishal?
Vishal...
C'mon. Dinner time.
Ain't you coming?
Not hungry.
What?
You're not hungry?
Can't believe it...
Sunanda said the same thing...
Guess Oi'm de odd wan oyt...
Guess Oi'm... Too cowl...
Granny...
Granny!
What's up with you?
I'm having dinner...
Oi didn't ask if you're 'avin' bill skinner...
Oi'm askin' what's de matter witcha?
You just asked why I'm not having dinner... And when I am, you're asking what's the matter with me...
I'm just a bit worried about this... Test I've got...
I've never seen you worried about your exams before...
I've -- We've never lived through any of this before...
We've never had enemies in our lives before...
Who's yers?
Never mind... Let's enjoy our dinner...
Heard you haven't had dinner.
I've slapped you after years...
It killed something in me...
Make it a habit...
So it doesn't hurt either of us.
I thought...
You'd be upset...
Nah... You've always got the right to do that...
How could I be upset?
Okay...
Just don't talk to Sarah Sherali again, okay?
You know...
Her Dad is responsible for everything we're going through.
And my Dad's responsible for everything she's going through...
Can't believe you're saying that.
They're going through a lot.
You've got me.
They've just got a girl of 19. She's got to take care of everything.
Why d'you feel so much for her?
What do we care what she's going through?
Back when you were depressed... I talked to her. She said I should talk to your friend.
Her Mum doesn't want her talking to 'that Indian lad' either.
Why are you telling me? And why'd you tell her anything that should've stayed between the two of us?
Jaysus, Mum -- I dunno why I told her... It just...
Felt like...
She's the only one who can understand my pain... Because she's going through the same...
She told me her Mum's been asking about you.
Never forget we're enemies!
No way I can forget that... Not with you saying it every waking moment to remind me!
We don't talk about our friends as much as we talk about one enemy.
They're not living through the same upheavals as us... Not even remotely...
We lost everything. You know everything.
They're responsible for everything!
I mean -- Just look at your Aunt...
Mum...
They've got nothing but problems...
Her seven-year-old brother's dyslexic.
His teacher just told her. She hasn't told her Mum yet.
She's got her Granny... Grandpa... And others in the family who only care about their shares...
Her Mum's been a housewife all this time.
Totally dependent.
She doesn't have a clue either.
We're hardly any better off...
It hurts them the same as us.
The same as I miss Dad or you miss your husband...
If your Granny found out... She won't spare you...
You know how the thinks... If she could nearly ostracise me for my low birth...
-Aye...
If she found out you're making friends with her son's killers...
You're right, Mum...
I'll talk to her myself...
Just...
Don't get all worked-up over it, okay?
But you won't budge?
No, Mum... Gimme a sec...
She helped me once...
I want to too... Get even?
I don't want any favours...
After that... I promise I won't talk to her again...
Hello?
Is everything okay ??
Yeah, why? What happened
Can I call you on Skype?
Can I call you on skype????
Yeah offcource
What's your skype ID ?
Hello?
Hello. Can you hear me?
Yeah. Can you?
Aye... But I can't see you...
Perfect. I ain't video calling.
What's the point of using Skype if you're not video calling?
Facebook Messenger garbled your voice too often. So, plan B: Skype!
You've seen me, I've seen you... Hardly any point in video chatting now, is there?
Aye...
You've seen me, I've seen you... Hardly any point in video chatting...
Your Mum must be angry... Because of this...
She slapped you?
How d'you know?
You forgot to hang up.
I -- Heard everything...
Everything?
Everything.
She hates us, doesn't she?
Just like your Mum hates us, aye...
Not like it's unfair...
Is it?
No.
It's only fair...
But why were you standing by me?
Siding with me?
You could've saved yourself the misery...
If I knew you were listening, I wouldn't have said any of that.
You're a good man, Vishal...
Not really as bad as on the telly.
You're not as bad as I thought either.
Your Mum doesn't want you talking to me, yes? Just like my Mum...
Not exactly...
I mean, yeah, she did try... But I didn't give in...
I ain't as cowardly as you.
I'm a lot of things, but cowardly is not one of them.
I'm a fallen hero's daughter.
Easy there... It's the same here...
Anyway... Before I forget it... What've you thought about Nadir?
Nothing. No idea what to do.
How do I tell Mum? She's so worried... She'd panic if she heard it!
I just spent another day Googling around...
I'll try to connect you to someone who can help...
Who knows, Mum may talk to you in person.
Your Mum? She'd never...
No way... I can't talk to her...
How can I talk to her? What do I say to her?
The same as she'd talk to you?
No -- Don't -- I'll manage something...
I'll talk to Nadir's teacher... She can help.
Don't you want my help? And -- Mum's not as bad as you think...
She's a very...
Kind woman... Very kind and polite...
I'm sure she's just like that...
Very kind... Caring... For everyone around you.
But we're Pakistanis. Soldiers. Colonel Sherali's family, no less.
We ain't so lucky.
So...
What d'you think about me?
I'm an Indian too...
Colonel Vijay Malhotra's son...
I'm very kind to you... And I want to help you out...
Who are you to me?
Can you tell me?
Someone who shares your grief.
Because it's as much his own...
That you, Amna?
You gave us a fright!
-Yeah, it's me.
What happened?
I thought someone's trying to pry open the door from outside. Thought I'd check...
I check the doors when Nawab's not around...
I locked the main door myself.
I lock all the doors and windows myself ever since Nawab left.
It's the least I can do.
Don't worry. Get some rest.
Sofia and I are used to it... We can't get a moment's sleep...
We can check the doors all we want.
I can't get a moment's sleep either...
No idea what's wrong...
You know how I used to sleep without a care in the world...
You'd get furious over it too...
But now...
Nothing ages a woman more than being widowed...
Mum!
Ready?
Just a minute...
Gimme a moment to do my hair...
What're you looking at?
Nothing...
Just... Seeing you so lively and fresh after ages... I love it...
I'm sure there's a ton of work waiting for me...
All those patients...
You can leave if you're getting late... Another day maybe?
No. It's your first day back at work... No way I'm not dropping you. Not today.
Okay?
Aye, c'mon.
And...
-Hmm?
Don't forget the dyslexia case you told me about...
Get all the details. I'll see what I can do.
Whoa, Mum...
-I know a few useful websites...
I know a few useful websites...
But the kid needs counselling. That's what matters more.
You want to talk to Sarah or her Mum yourself?
-I don't think I need to... You can tell them everything yourself.
Granny...
Mum's going back to work... Lovely, innit?
Don't you think you should change?
What?
-You're a widow.
It's barely been a month.
What with these fancy clothes --
-No, seriously, Granny -- I'm sure Mum --
No, seriously, Granny -- I'm sure Mum --
-No...
No...
She's right...
How'd I forget?
Just -- How?
I'm a widow...
These...
Colours... Don't suit me anymore...
Just a second... I'll go change...
Wait here, okay?
Mum...?
People say al' sorts av things, Vishal!
Your Mum's young... Beautiful...
Out there, they're gonna say all sorts of things, and none of us... None of us can shut them or our ears up!
So, which one d'you like?
You must be the only soldier's wife who doesn't care about the time one bit!
So hurry up and tell me! I need to go change!
Anything but black and white, hun... You don't need to ask.
As if you ever let me buy anything black and white...
Oh, I never will...
By the way, I don't know what's taking you so long...
I mean, mate...
Can you see something better than this?
-Oh, not again!
And again, and again! Because this looks lovely on you!
-My cupboard's full of colours... Can't you pick another, like, ever?
No way, ma'am...
Because these reds...
Stoke the flames of love...!
-Gimme a moment and I'm gonna light up the sky!
♪ Let's strike a match, my dear! Oh my dear! ♪
Mum...
Aye...?
I...
Thought I'd come check...
I haven't got anything I can wear... Everything's so... Colourful...
All thanks to your Dad...
Hey...
Come shopping with me today...
Why?
Dis one's gonna suit yer!
-No... I don't think this will do...
-But what's wrong wi' it?
I'd like something plain and simple... In black or white...
You know... The type that'd suit a widow?
Gran' so, jist a sec...
'Ere.
This looks fine...
I'd like four or five like these...
Gran'.
Okay...
Will any of it ever change?
Never...
♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
Mum's widowed...
Everything's drained of colour for her now...
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
Hello?
Just... Feeling terrible...
Why? Your Mum said something again?
No... Not this time...
So?
-We went shopping today...
Mum needed plain white dresses...
Why?
Oh wait...
Widows there... Can't wear anything else, right?
Sorry...
I thought maybe because you're educated... You wouldn't care about these... Things...
Nah, we're Brahmins... The ones who made these rules... Would be a shame if we didn't uphold them...
I'm sure your Mum's got to wear white too...
No.
We don't have to wear white...
Anything plain. That's all.
Isn't that what they show in your plays? Everyone wears white in mourning.
Yeah, thanks to you lot. Our directors started making 'em all wear white because everyone in your films and dramas wears white in mourning... For the rest of us... It's catching on...
Your Mum's lucky...
There's colours in her life...
Not in mine's...
Break free.
Big deal! Let her wear colours if that's what she wants.
That's all she likes...
Red...
Maroon...
And shocking pink!
But never white...
-Mum gave everything colourful she had to the maid...
Why?
You just said she can wear them...
She can, but...
I don't know...
First time the very thought of conflict has repulsed me...
Is it?
Mine was when I saw Dad's coffin...
Getting killed in action...
I always thought that's a glory... A privilege... But now, I realise...
It comes at a great price...
If I could give everything I had to get Dad back...
I wouldn't think for a moment.
Glory... Heroism...
Everything...
Me too...
He was deployed in our city just once... Before he was sent to the frontline...
Dad and Mum were always in different cities...
Life couldn't be more unpredictable.
I've started writing everything I can remember about Dad in my diary...
You keep a diary?
-Mhm...
Me too.
Really?
We've got a lot in common...
Besides our grief, I mean...
Well then, doesn't that make it easier to be friends?
Or enemies...
Just look at our nations...
Anyway, I'll get back to you tomorrow, Vishal...
Gotta study...
If you need any help...
You know you've got me.
I need to learn to do these things myself...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5