♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 13 - 'Bridging the Gap'
The Unit sent someone...
That's why...
They got hold of me...
Beat me -- And threatened never to complai --
-No...
We're not filing any complaint...
Just --
Forget the estate...
What's it matter?
I warned you, Mum...
You're risking my son's life for it!
Tell Pratibha she can have all of it... If she can throw them out!
She can call Anurag or anyone else she wants... Just -- Keep my son out of it.
Mum...
We don't give up like that...
I don't want anything...
I can give up anything...
But...
Not my boy...
Hear that?
I don't care about anything else...
Mum...
Hmm?
When'd you gather the courage to say no to Aunt?
Stop embarrassing me already...
What's embarrassing about it? You've been brave...
I just did as someone told me...
Whoa...
Wonder who it is you listen to so much.
Vishal's Mum.
She said I should not give them anything... Because it's all yours...
You told her about it?
She's the only one who could understand...
I thought you'd never talk to her again...
No, I do... Quite often, actually.
What d'you talk about?
You all...
And those...
We've lost...
Our lives...
That have become...
Unrecognisable...
Tell your Mum I said thanks.
For?
Doing us a great favour.
Mum refused to give Aunt the money... We didn't have to say a thing.
Funny thing she isn't nearly this brave herself.
Your Mum's very brave. Braver than mine. And strong.
She's my Mum...
I know her strengths...
And weaknesses.
What happened?
You sound worried...
Something going on over there... With your Aunt?
Some folks...
Abducted me...
Today...
Vishal...
If you're having a Turkish... Lemme tell you it sounds cheap.
I'm not havin' a Turkish...
The bloke staying at Granny's estate... He sent them...
They beat me real bad...
And released me...
Does it hurt?
Not my body...
As much as...
The Army esteem and all...
You were crying the other day...
When someone harassed you...
You said how they could do that...
To a hero's daughter...
Between the punches...
That's what I thought too...
My father died protecting them...
Can we talk on Skype?
You don't call me on Skype... Why today?
Just felt like it...
Jaysus, Pratibha...
Don't try it with me...
I'm serious...
They got Vishal for real...
They beat him real bad and left him here...
You know how it is with the politicians here...
Your brother was a soldier...
Isn't the Army gonna do anything for his family?
No idea...
Mum talked to the Unit. Then this happened.
I won't take this bullshit.
I'm suing her if she doesn't give you your share.
What about me?
What am I gonna do?
Get a lawyer.
Send her a notice.
I'll book you a ticket...
When you send me a copy.
Take a good look.
It ain't that bad.
That's what you wanted to see, yes?
-It looks bad...
It looks bad...
They've beat you real bad...
I'll be fine.
Don't worry.
Did you tell the police?
What good is it?
-They could be worse next time.
What about your family? Your Mum? Care to think?
When they tore my shirt...
Punched and pushed me around...
It...
Punched a hole...
In my love for the nation...
I was wondering...
Why we fight for them...
When this is how they reward us...
I wish I could do something for you...
Like what?
Anything that'd ease your pain...
I ain't a doctor yet, but... I would've tried...
Alright...
I'm sending you a text...
I hope you won't mind it...
After what you've gone through...
I wouldn't dare... Not today...
'Wow, you're lovely'
'And you're very... Average,
And aye... I'mlovely. So ??'
Calm down, Parbhu...
Be patient...
And wait a while...
I knew you ain't gonna give me my share just like that...
But... 'They've taken over the estate?' Wow, that's a new low! Way to ruin my marriage!
What are you saying, Aunt?
It's Granny's estate. You can have all of it if that's what she wants. We won't mind.
Why'd she give me all of it? Aye?
You're the only one who matters to her... She's gonna treat you like a king.
This is unacceptable Mum... I'm going straight to a lawyer... He's gonna sort you out!
Lemme see how long you can hold on to your Aunt's share!
Canny believe...
Me own daughter...
Is threatenin' me wi' a lawsuit!
And -- He's your martyred brother's son!
Cut the emotional blackmail already...
I'm sick of it!
I'll make an example of you! Anurag's got friends in the media...
I'll tell the world how you've usurped my share!
Thank goodness you're here, Sunanda...
What's this?
What's this cheque?
Your share.
Go and ask Anurag to do the numbers if you don't trust us.
Now... You've got no right over it...
I've called my lawyer...
He'll be here with the papers...
For your signatures...
C'mon, Vishal...
She's the only one who cares! I knew it!
That's all I ever asked for! Big deal!
Vishal?
Well, I guess everything's sorted out...
Mum?
We thought we'd come here the moment we found out Colonel Sherali's family lives next door!
It is a great honour indeed.
Of course...
To live in the company of heroes...
Is a great honour indeed...
Is he in the Army too? Your son.
Aye, he's a Captain.
On his second assignment here.
How many kids d'you have?
Cüneyt and his younger sister...
She's gotten engaged by the way.
Hey...
Hello...
My daughter, Sarah.
Bless her...
She's lovely.
She's the eldest...
She just got into medical college.
Come here, will you?
Sure.
My daughter's in medical college too.
She's doing her House Job.
Great. Where?
Fatima Jinnah Medical College.
That's where I study too!
Meet our new neighbours.
I saw them when they got here...
You gotta attend my daughter's wedding.
I'll be waiting.
Sure.
Why not?
-We'll be there.
You know, it's such a pleasure to finally meet you...
Yeah?
I followed you on social media.
Back when your father lost his life... And you stood your ground against the Indian Colonel's kid... You may've missed it, but I was right there by your side, supporting you.
Well...
It was very childish, to be honest... But thank you...
Childish? Not at all.
In fact, whatever you said made quite a lot of sense.
I mean, he was making such a moron of himself.
He didn't seem to have anything to say, really.
You're a soldier?
Aye.
How'd you guess?
The way you talk...
I thought it's my haircut.
Your haircut ain't nearly as big a giveaway.
Well, what else d'you expect from a military man?
I think...
I'll get going...
See you soon?
Good. At least no one's gonna claim the estate for himself.
Hmm...
I was sick of it...
Wanted to get rid of it...
I mean, what if something happened to Vishal?
Good. That's one thing sorted out. Let's move on to the next...
Please, Raj... I told you already!
You know I won't give up. I'll keep waiting.
How long d'you want me to wait?
I don't know. Can't say. No idea.
I've got little kids... A young son...
And you're proposing to me?
I've got a son too.
-You're a man...
Your morals won't be policed like mine.
You really disappoint me, mate...
No idea why but... I feel so weak... After Vijay...
I can make you strong again.
Aye?
Yeah, Granny?
You busy?
Aye...
Applying to a few Universities...
Vishal...
Yeah?
Why don't you apply to the Army?
But -- Didn't you never want me to join the Army?
I've changed my mind.
But -- I don't want to join the Army...
Never wanted to. You know it.
So...
Your grandfather...
Chose the Army life for himself...
As did your father...
They...
Didn't need to...
But you...
Yer nade ter choose dis Army life... For yerself... An' for us...
A uniform...
Makes lions of men...
Life in this part of the world...
Is difficult...
Without a lion around...
The last few months...
'Av killed any love Oi 'ad for dis nashun...
First time...
First time Ah've felt...
A love for their nashun...
Isn't de only tin' dat makes soldiers...
Ah've been blind...
Ter everythin' else dat pushes tren...
But...
No longer...
After your father died...
Vishal...
At my age...
I'm not sure how much life there is left in me...
But you...
You've got responsibility... Pari, Laxmi... And Sunanda... They need you...
They need you to forget everything else...
I --
What if --
I'll tell Sunanda.
Apply to the Army.
We'll tell Sunanda...
Once you're selected...
You're late...
I went --
For lunch -- With this friend...
Sunanda...
Thank you.
You've done me a 'uge favour.
It wasn't a favour...
It was my duty.
That's weird...
Telling me never to do it, but giving your SIL the money right away?
The situation was completely different, Amna...
She was asking for a loan... And she just wanted her share.
Hardly different...
You gave her the compensation you got.
Every penny of it.
Vijay...
Was very attached to the estate...
Every brick is a walk down the memory lane.
Vijay's gone... I couldn't do anything about it...
What'd be left of him for Vishal if we lost the estate?
I just saved his memory... For Vishal...
Vishal and his Granny must've been thankful...
Aye... First time she seemed worried that I was late...
But, to be honest... These things hardly matter now...
I understand...
But who cares if it 'matters'?
Someone's...
Proposed to me...
You?
Yeah. I don't know why I'm telling you, but...
Who?
An old friend...
From college...
But...
I was only ever interested in Vijay.
He left for America. Got married.
He's back now that he's divorced... Saw me a few days back...
That's when he proposed...
What are you thinking?
-What d'you think?
I've got three kids! Including a young lad!
How long's it been since Vijay left us?
How can I even think of it?
You refused?
Again and again...
But he's been calling again and again... And saying the same thing...
I guess there's nothing wrong in thinking about it.
What'd you do in my place?
It's no use.
We're all in our own set of circumstances... We face different choices...
If you think it can work out well, you should give it a thought.
It ain't as easy as you think...
I know...
But...
We're different, you and I...
You're an independent working woman... Unlike me...
What about my son? He's a young man now!
And he'll be lost in his own world very soon...
You'll be all alone once he starts college...
I'll still have Pari and Laxmi.
In your place... I'd still give it a thought...
Especially...
After everything I've gone through in the last few months...
Everything's changed...
Feels like...
I'm...
All alone...
You don't always need a companion who can take someone's place...
Just one...
Who can fill the void...
Who you're not alone with...
Did Aunt call?
After she left for Canada?
Why'd she call us nigh?
She wanted 'er share...
She got it.
End av scayle.
I've applied to the Army, by the way.
Aren't you happy?
Sarah?
Can I talk to her?
Gotta apologise ter someone... Mind?
Aye...
You got back so quickly, Nawab...
Told you about the wedding...
You remember everything after you get there, don't you? Repairs, wedding, and all...
Could you give me the spoon?
Blend these nicely, okay? I'll be back...
Hello?
Hello.
Sorry I didn't call you. Thought you'd be busy.
I'm making a cake!
Uh...
Granny wants to talk...
Your Granny?
Why?
No idea. Find out yourself. Here...
Hello?
Hello...
-Sarah...
How are you, love?
Great... And you?
I -- I'm fine, dear...
I...
I wanted to say sorry...
Oi said a lot Oi shouldn't 'av...
It's okay... I get it... My Granny and Grandpa react the same way too, sometimes...
Would you like to talk to Granny?
Why not?
Vishal's Granny... Wants to talk to you...
Why?
What've you done this time?
Why does she want to talk to me? She in the mood to pick another row?
-Just -- Talk to her once?
Just -- Talk to her once?
Aye?
-Hello...
Hello...
I...
Wanted to say sorry...
For everything...
I said that day...
Aye...
That's what I told Sarah's Grandpa...
We said a lot we shouldn't have...
They're kids...
Big deal...
But we should know better than act like kids!
Absolutely...
Me emoshuns got de better av me...
Oi'm sure yer understan'... Losin' Vijay 'as been most painful...
Aye...
You're telling me...
Sherali left us all grieving...
They lef...
Too young...
If anyone should've gone, 'tis us...
Aye...
That's what I think too... May God never make parents live to see the deaths of their children...
Me warrld feels... Empty...
Nothing's ever felt de seem...
Since Vijay's death...
Of course... He was at the border...
But we knew...
He was there... He was alright...
Even as he put his life on the line...
Where in Pakistan are you from, by the way?
Me?
I'm from Lahore.
Sarah's Grandpa's from Amritsar though.
Amritsar?
Bli
Blimey...
That's wha we are!
Mum, Da... Everyone lived in Amritsar...
In dat case, Oi gotta ask 'imself! An' Vishal's Grandpa?
Me 'usban' wus from Pakistan... Jhelum, aye...
That's wha 'e wus from...
'E 'ad family dare too... Mamai, Da, Uncles, Aunts...
Blimey... Me Grandpa lived dare too...
Waaat wus yisser 'ouse number?
I'll 'av ter git 'is diary...
'E used ter write everythin' in 'is diary... Oi'm sure 'e'd 'av de address written somewhere...
Me in-laws used ter talk aboyt Amritsar as if they went dare everyday...
Same 'ere... They talked aboyt Jhelum loike they still lived dare...
Yer ever come 'ere?
-No...
'E never 'ad de time... Typical military man things, yer nu...
Mum an' Da alwus wanted ter visit Jhelum...
Any way they cud...
-Ma'am...
We need eggs for the cake...
-Naw, Oi doubt anything's gonna change...
Naw, Oi doubt anything's gonna change...
-The call's gonna use all my balance!
You're using up all my balance!
-Shut up!
Oi want ter 'ear everythin' she's got ter say aboyt Jhelum! So jist shut yer bake, gran'?
Aye, waaat were yer sayin'?
Wud yer luk at de kids the-day... She's 'ere sayin' 'tis enoof for nigh!
She wants 'er dag an' bone back! Naw words for 'er, really!
Back in our day, kids wouldn't even dare tink av commandin' their elders loike dat!
Yeah, roi... Oi never dared say a ward meself! Naw idea what's de craic wi' kids the-day...
Jhelum awaits yer wi' open arms...
Cum 'ere sometime?
-Aye.
Ah've alwus wanted ter...
Alwus wanted ter see de place Ah've only 'eard av...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5