♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 18 - 'The Wall'
Waiting for your go, sir!
Where's Arez?
-I'll find him...
Hands behind your head!
I said something! Quick!
You've entered Pakistan. How many men've you got with you?
-No one... I'm just a straggler! I got here by mistake!
You make these mistakes only too often, don't you?
Bloody fools!
Get up...
And keep your hands behind your head!
Vishal Malhotra?
Cüneyt Ensar?
How d'you know me?
Same way you know me.
Sarah...
What happened?
Tripped and fell...
Got hurt.
Couldn't keep up...
How many men were with you?
Two.
What happens now?
Other end of the river, it's Occupied Kashmir.
You're in the Liberated Kashmir.
First time in two months we've had a ceasefire here...
I'd love to take you with me, or shoot you...
But we'd hate to break the ceasefire in just three days...
What d'you want?
Eh?
In your place...
I'd shoot.
You're Sarah's friend.
I can't shoot you.
Congratulations.
Sarah sent your son's pic.
Gotta say, he's cute...
Get up.
On your feet!
Turn around and get back where you came from. Don't look this way again.
You've got ten seconds...
If you ain't outta my sights, I won't think again before filling you with lead!
You're lying.
You wanna play cat and mouse?
You want me to turn...
Run for it...
And you want to shoot me in the back...
I've got what it takes to die fighting.
One bullet can send us to war again... You've got ten seconds to avoid it.
I've been here, collecting the bodies of my fallen brothers... And civvies...
Men and women... Young and old...
Kids... Including one newborn baby...
I've been doing the same.
Why d'you only see your dead?
Don't we all see only our dead?
If I shot you...
It'd add one more...
And I'll get promoted for it... Perhaps even a medal...
But the flames which seem to settle...
Will rage again...
The count would keep increasing...
We're soldiers...
We sign up for this. We're ready to die fighting.
But know what, I've realised something since the birth of my son...
Not everyone's born to die like this...
So, you've got ten seconds...
Run for your life.
Unbelievable...
A Pakistani soldier with a heart...
A Pakistani soldier with a heart... Sparing me?
Sparing the enemy?
Even when you know me and Sarah --
-Sarah told me you're the man of the house... The only son...
Sarah told me you're the man of the house... The only son...
You've only got women in your family...
Life's hard for women. Here and there.
I care for Sarah. That's why.
I'm sure you care for your mother and sisters...
So... Run for them.
Go.
Ten!
Soldier!
NINE!
EIGHT!
SEVEN!
He's in our sights, sir... We got him.
Just clear the way and I'll put a bullet in his head.
If you don't, he's gonna get away through the woods!
Okay.
Was he not the best?
No doubt!
SIX!
First time in two months we've had a ceasefire here...
One bullet can send us to war again... You've got ten seconds to avoid it.
Cüneyt!
Our sniper's got you in his sights!
He's gonna shoot you...
Stay right behind me and get out of here!
Go!
Stop firing, damn it!
♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Vishal sent me his picture...
He's got your eyes...
Your face...
These things change...
That's what they all say...
I think he's taken after Cüneyt.
You know, Vishal once told me...
'Mum'...
'Don't wear white again'...
'It doesn't suit you'...
His Dad didn't like it either...
They don't have it there, do they?
White for widows...
What's it matter?
Everything's dark - black - after Cüneyt...
You love him so much...
You didn't even mention Vishal's name...
Cüneyt's the only one you talk about...
I can't bring myself to say his name...
Or hear it... Please don't mention him...
I can't do it...
I'm his mother...
I thought I'd see you...
Somewhere else...
We can't go to each other's countries...
Until...
This Kartarpore Accord...
I didn't expect to see you here...
How could I turn you down?
Because... I'm Vishal's Mum...
That's who...
I'm here to see...
Give me your hand.
C'mon.
I'd kept this for my daughter-in-law...
Sarah...
When Vishal found out...
You're getting married...
I can't live without her, Mum...
He came to me...
-I don't mind converting... If that's all, I don't...
I don't mind converting... If that's all, I don't...
It ain't just about religion...
It's about our countries... There's this wall... Of sunshine...
That just refuses to come down! So I'm sorry, Vishal...
I lost her when I enlisted, Mum...
Just -- Let me stop her -- Talk to her once...
I know she's waiting for me... She'll be mine if she saw me --
-No...
No... Don't even think about it...
Your 'love'... It's nothing! Nations... Religion... Whatever... It can never be!
I hear these things at the Academy all day! Please don't start it here!
Please!
Why can't you say love is greater than everything?
All these walls come down when love strikes them...
And when they do... Everyone wins...
But in war... Everyone loses...
Just once, Mum --
-No, Vishal... Don't call her... Don't give her hope...
Don't make a promise you can't keep... For my sake, Vishal...
-Please, Mum...
Just... Forget her...
Just... Think she never existed...
He was right...
I was waiting...
He only had to call out my name...
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
'Soldiers' families grieve... Not celebrate!'
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
'War orphans here and there'
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
'No one loses in peace'
♪ My Lord, hear me pray, ♪
♪ Just this once, let me have a say, ♪
'No one wins in war'
♪ Save these hearts pining away, ♪
♪ Isn't it, for You, but child's play? ♪
♪ The unease gives me frights ♪
♪ Even as my mind prays, ♪
'War widows here and there'
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5
♪ There's two shores divided by the abyss, ♪
♪ Gone their ways, gone amiss, ♪
♪ In estrangement trying to find bliss... ♪
♪ I stand eager here ♪
♪ And you over there, ♪
♪ To meet in the darkness down there... ♪
♪ May the Lord hear our prayer, ♪
♪ And let our love judge us fair, O Lord... ♪
♪ But there's this wall, ♪
♪ There's this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ Yea, there's this wall, ♪
♪ There's this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪