♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 12 - 'A Hate for War'
Why am I always thinking of Neha?
Why do I care who he's with?
We grieve together...
As friends...
But...
Nothing else...
Innit?
♪ There's two shores divided by the abyss, ♪
♪ Gone their ways, gone amiss, ♪
♪ In estrangement trying to find bliss... ♪
♪ I stand eager here ♪
♪ And you over there, ♪
♪ To meet in the darkness down there... ♪
♪ May the Lord hear our prayer, ♪
♪ And let our love judge us fair... ♪
♪ Let our love judge us fair, O Lord... ♪
Don't you think you're being too sentimental? Slow down...
It's about my self-respect!
I ain't your ordinary Indian woman who'd do everything to please her man.
Vishal's not even interested in me... He's interested in Sarah!
He's not interested in her... Where does she come in?
Boys make friends with girls... But that doesn't mean they love them...
Maybe...
But I curse the girl who goes after a boy who's made it clear that he loves someone else!
Your Uncle's gonna pull me up for this...
Just do as he says... Take your share and jet off to Canada...
Mum said Neha's going back?
Aye.
She felt too insulted here...
We've got so many matches for her... All his loss...
I'm sorry if it's something he said...
You don't need to say sorry, Aunt... It's just... Vishal ain't my type... He doesn't see things our way...
But I don't blame him for it... It's just...
What with the whole family serving in the Army and all...
Ticket confirmed!
Anyway... There's a world beyond patriotism...
Could you please tell Vishal?
Hello!
Yeah?
-Need your number, lydy.
Wanna see my shoe number?
-Oh, I wouldn't Chinese Blind!
I'm Colonel Sherali's daughter...
The late Colonel.
-Aye, so wot?
What?
-I asked for your number, lydy... Not your old man's rank, or if 'e's even jack's...
I asked for your number, lydy... Not your old man's rank, or if 'e's even jack's...
'Ey! Wait!
Not so fast!
Sla daahhhn! 'Ey!
I just wanna Rabbit and Pork!
-Grandpa!
Wait!
Grandpa!
-'Ey!
He's been bothering me, Grandpa...
Who are you?
How dare you come here?
Gr --
Stop pokin' your fireman's hose where it doesn't belong, pot and pan... In'cha gettin' cilla black for Left in the bleedin' Lurch or summit?
He's gone, Grandpa...
I never thought...
They'd reward a hero's daughter like that...
Everyone knows my son's name... His rank...
But --
-It's okay...
Just -- Don't tell Mum or Granny, okay? They'll get all worked up...
Don't go out again okay?
Don't go out alone...
I'll talk to the Unit...
I saw his number plate...
I've been missing you again, Dad...
We need you in our lives...
All of us...
Even as the nation seems to forgot your sacrifice...
They don't even remember your name...
Or that I'm your daughter... A hero's daughter...
I lose courage with each day...
It's too much for me to bear...
Hello?
Could you check your email?
Mum sent you some exercises. Print them and give them to Aunt...
I didn't see it...
I'll tell Mum when I check it...
Have you got the flu?
No?
You crying, then?
No... It's the flu...
No, you're crying...
What happened?
First time someone dared harass me...
I'm missing Dad so much...
It means nothing...
Nothing... 'Dying for the nation'... 'Protecting our borders'...
The nation doesn't care...
A hero's daughter is hardly different from any other girl for them.
None of it matters to anyone...
I've never felt more unsafe...
Stop pokin' your fireman's hose where it doesn't belong, pot and pan... In'cha gettin' cilla black for Left in the bleedin' Lurch or summit?
What is it?
Why are you still up?
Nothing, really...
Just not sleepy...
But...
Why?
No idea...
I ain't just worried about me...
I'm worried about Noria too...
And Mum...
Grandpa can't fight the world for us...
The Unit can't save us from them all...
If Dad were here...
None of them would dare look at us the wrong way...
What happened? You still up?
Uhh...
Nothing...
Just...
Sitting here...
Mum...
Mum, I --
Wanted to know...
-Hmm...
If someone's... Bothering you...
No. What d'you mean?
-I mean, anyone --
Harassing you?
Of course not...
But why d'you ask?
Just... Asking...
But if anyone does, just lemme know.
What can you do about it?
You'll see.
Gives me all the more reason to not tell you.
What, you don't want me to protect you?
I can protect myself, thank you!
Who d'you think protected me all these years when your Dad was not around?
Tell Sarah I know how to deal with that lot, okay?
Sarah? Where does she come in?
Someone's bothering her, yes?
How d'you know?
You ain't that upset for no reason.
Tell her to stop crying and face them. Life's got its unpleasant moments, but you gotta face them.
Mum!
-Hmm?
Well...
I --
I don't want --
Pari and Laxmi to face any of it...
They're too young...
I know... But they won't always be, yes?
The Indian Army... Live a life that's extraordinary.
I fire hard.
But I fire strong.
I like solving problems.
Facing an enemy on higher ground? Problem.
Being two points down? Problem.
But the bigger the problem, the sweeter the victory.
What do I like more? Going to battle, or firing my pistol?
I like the fact that I do both, my dear...
We're India's most exciting workplace, and we're making you an offer.
The Indian Army. Live a life th --
I really like cars, so just two weeks into the job, they gave me a company car.
A big one at that! With fourteen wheels and quite the ground clearance.
It can go pretty much anywhere! But it's not the easiest thing to p --
Never enlist in the army...
I won't.
No idea why I told you any of it the other day...
That's what I'm thinking... Why'd I tell you anything?
Has your sister-in-law left?
-Nah, she's still here...
Her niece left though.
They wanted to get her married to Vishal, but he refused...
They'd be fuming...
How d'you know?
My sisters-in-law got here for Sherali's funeral... From the UK and America...
The elder one wanted Sarah to marry her son...
My brother wanted her married to his...
Sarah refused, and they left, fuming.
I always thought I'm unlucky I don't have siblings.
But looking at Pratibha's greed...
I feel I'm quite fortunate indeed.
Or... They'd be here to bother us too...
Mind if I asked something?
-Hmm?
What if someone asked for some money?
Just refuse!
What if it's Sherali's dearest sister?
What if she told you she's helpless?
Refuse more clearly.
She's got her husband, yes?
Yes.
She doesn't need your help.
She ain't more helpless than you.
Don't waste the money that's your kids'.
You there?
Aye...
I'm thinking...
How I can turn her down...
We're trying our best, but you know they're members of the ruling party...
I told you I want the house vacated ASAP.
You can file a complaint against them.
Who's gonna help with all the legal paperwork?
I'm sure the Colonel's son will help you.
He's a kid...
A student...
He's got to focus on his studies, not get involved in this feud...
As you see fit, ma'am... We're doing our best. I'll keep you posted. Thank you.
Thank you...
Anurag's not taking my call...
He's not texting back...
He won't talk to me until I've got my share...
You got me in this mess, Mum...
Oi jist talked ter de Unit...
They want me to file a complaint...
It's gonna take some time...
No idea how I can make you understand...
Canny Anurag wait a wee!?
How long can I stay here?
Why don't you think about me?
I say, just get Vishal and Ne --
-Shut up!
End this chapter right now.
Get it?
You want your share? You'll get it.
So just -- Shut up!
Over there, yeah.
-Alright.
Careful!
Are they new here?
Yes ma'am. Just got here.
Careful...
Alright, next one...
Hey!
Geroff me!
Just lemme go! Hey!
Good day, ma'am.
Can't believe my eyes!
Good to see you again, Gopi...
Hope everything's good.
No...
Nothing ain't good after my brother...
Your sister-in-law and her kids?
She ain't my SIL now.
What?
Wife.
What d'you mean?
We said our I-dos!
I mean, there she was... Alone with her kids...
Good.
But...
Why the hurry?
C'mon, she was a young widow... With kids!
Plus, the Army stopped paying her his pension...
They want to 'investigate' him!
She needed someone to support her...
How'd she agree so easily?
How couldn't she?
She had no choice.
Didn't she love your brother?
Perhaps she did, perhaps she didn't...
But love stands no chance...
When you're struggling to make ends meet...
And your stomach starts growling...
She was in dire need, yes, she was...
It's getting late... Where's Vishal?
I'll have a look...
Congratulations on Sarah's admission.
Sherali's dream is coming true!
The Lord has been kind...
Sarah's worked hard, despite everyth --
You've worked hard too.
After Sherali's death... In her place, most girls won't even be able to sit an exam...
Aye... Just pray things go on fine...
I always pray for you...
You're the only ones with Mum and Dad...
Amna...
I asked for something...
Zafar's been asking me about it...
Ayesha...
I'm sorry...
For what?
I can't help you... Sorry...
I --
I thought about it a lot...
This money... Is for my kids... And --
It's not like we said it's ours.
We don't have a right over it... We're just borrowing it in times of need...
I understand, Ayesha...
But...
I can't give you any of it...
Why? You're the only one who can give it away...
Yes... I can...
But I won't...
Did you tell Mum and Dad?
Yes.
And -- They're with you on this?
No.
I'm turning you down myself...
As the mother of Sherali's kids...
Ayesha...
You were and always will be their Aunt...
But I think...
Sherali helped you all he could while he was here...
But...
No longer...
Vishal here yet?
No.
Vishal!
What happened?
Vishal?
Vishal!
Hey!
Vishal! Wait!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5
Wow, you're lovely...
And you're... Average...
And aye... I'm lovely. So?
Why don't you apply to the Army?
I don't want to marry a soldier, Vishal...
Because I don't want to die everyday like your Mum and mine...
A uniform makes lions of men...