Every promise, every vow, every oath,
Everything just snapped...
Heart and soul mine, cry both,
In this life, trapped...
I'm whiling away sleepless nights
And restless days,
Searching for you in the dark anights,
Hoping to see you through the haze...
Who's gonna stop these tears from falling?
There's just this wall,
Just this wall,
That's betwixt us,
That's betwixt us, standing tall...
There's just this wall,
Just this wall,
That's betwixt us,
That's betwixt us, standing tall...
Episode 10 - 'Blurred Borders'
When'd you get back?
Two weeks ago?
And how's the family?
Out of my life... I got divorced...
Really? But Shilpa was so nice!
Aye, the women are always nice... We're the nasty ones...
Stop it, Raj... You haven't changed one bit from your college days, have you?
Do you remember those days?
Can't forget them...
I've made it through all these years thanks to the memories...
You know about Vijay...
He's always been deployed in conflict zones...
And I used to tease you for it... Vijay's been cruel to me... Claimed you for himself...
But honestly...
I really feel sad for you... You made a great couple...
Aye...
He was my world...
I miss him every living moment...
I can understand...
How's Vishal?
-Great. He's doing his A-Levels...
Last year of school... About time he started planning things...
Really? I thought he'd be sitting for GCSEs this year...
And your daughters?
-They're just eight...
And your son -- What's his name?
-Vipin.
Aye, right... How's he?
He's with Shilpa... I talk to him now and then... Talk to her too...
Bitter divorce...
Bitter divorce?
She had an affair, and it wasn't easy for me, but I asked for it myself...
She's remarried now...
Hmm...
Aye... I'm sure it hurts...
She hit me where it hurts...
Vipin left for University... And I got transferred back to India...
I can't stay anywhere long.
Just trying to reconnect with old friends since I got here...
Just trying to cope with my depression, you could say...
It was a heartbreak... But not as big as when Vijay made you his.
Please, Raj...
Sunanda...
What if I proposed to you again?
You're the only one who can help...
I wouldn't have had to ask you if Sherali were here...
You know how much he loved me...
I need some time to think... But don't worry... I'll do something...
You're the only one I've got now, Amna...
Anyway... I'll get back to you, okay?
Okay.
Give my regards to Mum and Dad... Tell the kids I said hi.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Who was it?
Aunt Ayesha...
What is it this time?
Her husband's suffered a big loss...
She was asking if we could lend her... 6 or 7 million-ish...
6 or 7 million-ish?
But how? And why is she asking you?
She's found out about the compensation for your Dad's death...
I hope you turned her down.
I said... I need some time...
You need time?
Remember everything she said when she left! But now, she has the guts to ask for our 'help'!
I've lost count how many times Dad's lent Uncle something... Has he ever returned a penny?
I know... But I can't just turn her down like that...
You know how much your Dad loved her.
-He did...
But did she love us?
If she did, she'd know we've got no source of income...
She'd know we can't give away everything we've got left like that.
I know, but I can't say it to her face...
I said I'll talk to your Grandpa.
He'd be happy to help his dearest daughters...
Who doesn't love his daughters?
Neha is Anurag's niece. She wanted to visit India, so I thought I'd bring her along. Yeah?
Yeah.
Let's turn up the music, shall we? Unless... You don't like it?
Sure...
That beauty is none but my sweetheart!
Blimey, that's some horrible traffic!
Aye, it ain't nothing like Canada!
Whoa! Are you okay? You sure you don't want that seat belt?
Aye, sorry, I just forgot...
Get used to forgetting in this part of the world...
-Okay...
I called Zafar Mehmood too...
Not sure if he told Ayesha, but...
He told me if he didn't get the money...
He'd lose his property...
I tried to explain it to him...
But he thinks I've struck gold or something.
So... What do we do?
We've got the compensation...
But we've got duties...
He's been asking for a few months... I'm sure he'll pay us back...
What if he didn't?
We can't ask for it...
They've borrowed from Sherali before...
Yeah, from their brother...
But they've got to return it to his wife.
They know what's going on in your life...
Okay... As you say...
I'd never have said it if it were not my own daughter...
You know her in-laws very well...
And, thanks to your daughter and son-in-law... I can't even look my daughter-in-law in the eye.
Parbhu...
How long are you staying here?
Can't believe you're asking that the day I'm here.
Naw...
Just... Thinking...
I mean...
I'm sure you've -- Got other things to take care of, yes?
Get it?
Granny... I'm here because I wanted to see every place in India I can, and Aunt told me Vishal's gonna show me!
Vishal?
Aye. Once he's done with his exams, why not?
I've made a list.
Shopping, tourist attractions, and then there's this concert... So many things to do!
Neha's a lovely girl... Very friendly and fun-loving. She's just started college, by the way.
Wow. What are you studying?
Art and theatre, but I've got a thing for music too.
Vishal's got a thing for music too. He's quite the singer himself!
So you told me... You've told me a lot about him...
Gotta say, this is delicious!
-Have some more!
Mum?
Hmm?
You've got to... Talk to Sarah's Mum, remember?
Not now, Vishal... Not in front of Pratibha!
Everyone's gonna find out... Say things about you and me...
But you've got to say sorry to them.
I will!
-Just do it!
Actually -- It's a bit embarrassing for me too...
-Don't you care too much for them?
I just needed a drink.
-It's in the fridge...
Nah, not this one...
But...
I guess this will do!
You've mixed your coursebooks with Dad's books...
We shouldn't be lending anything to Aunt. You're making a big mistake.
Back to work, Sarah... Don't get on my wick...
I'm not a kid anymore... I can tell you what I think...
Vishal says you're making a mistake too.
Why d'you need to tell him about everything?
Do you need to tell him about everything in our lives?
It's our problem, aye... But you're making a big mistake... Mark my words, they're not gonna return a penny!
I can't turn your Granny and Grandpa down like that.
-They're just thinking of their daughters.
Why do they want our money? D'you think they'd give us a penny if we needed anything?
Sarah's right...
We don't need to give Ayesha and Zafar a penny...
It's all for Sherali's family...
His kids...
Mum...
Mum! Wait!
Shut up the kids, and stop listening to a mature voice of reason! What's next?
Where were you all day?
Too busy...
Honestly knackered...
What happened? Your Aunt back?
Aye... How d'you know?
I just do...
There's your Aunt...
And then there's mine...
Always something going on... Wonder why we don't empower our women so they don't get blackmailed by their in-laws into blackmailing their families.
Girls are natural blackmailers...
Could you not typecast or be so chauvinistic for a change? Like, haven't you got your Granny, your Mum or your sisters?
Thank you for including Granny there... 'Mum and sisters' sounds so stereotypical... Like they all say?
I'm anything but stereotypical... Not me, not my life...
What happened?
Oh, nothing... The same old...
She's blackmailing Mum... Grandpa and Granny haven't had anything all day... And I'm the black sheep here! No one wants to talk to me!
Look...
Whatever happens, don't give them a penny. Make it clear to your Mum, okay?
I don't know...
But I think Mum's gonna give up... She won't take up arms against them...
Ain't she a soldier's wife?
-She is...
Wives ain't nearly as used to fighting... Even soldiers' wives... They're only taught to compromise...
What about you?
Never.
I want to be strong.
Not helpless, cowardly, and dependent.
You're outta luck, mate... In Pakistan, at least.
As if it's any different in India. Don't act like you folks don't want doormats for wives.
Hardly different.
There, now... Don't embarrass me like that...
Your Mum didn't call Mum...
She will... She's got her number... Tell her to take her call, okay?
She's talked to a colleague... May be able to help find someone in Pakistan...
Anyway...
I'm positively knackered... Need some rest.
Okay... Good night...
Can't believe you said good night in a second.
You amaze me...
-How?
You said you needed some rest. So I said good night. What's wrong?
Nothing, really...
Good night.
Hello?
Hung up...
Mum!
Where's everyone?
Grandpa? Granny? Mum?
Sarah!
What happened?
-Mum!
Elena called! Just got my result!
Yeah?
-Straight A*s!
Best in the school!
-Congratulations!
Did you tell Granny and Grandpa?
-Nope. Wanted to tell you first.
Well done, Sarah.
Guess what! Straight A*s in her A-Levels!
Congratulations! When'd you get your result?
Just now!
Sherali always wanted you to be a doctor...
I know...
I'm working on making his dream a reality.
Tell your Granny yet?
Sofia!
-Mum!
Mum... I need to get some dresses stitched... Who's your tailor?
The same old...
Why don't you go with Vishal tomorrow?
Vishal's taking Neha shopping...
Besides, I ain't going to a mall or something...
Excuse me...
Congrats, Doc!
Slow down, it's my A-Level result.
Doc's gonna need a few years...
This is the first step.
Thank God...
It was Dad's one dream...
He used to call me 'Doc' like you too...
So, you off to a hostel or something?
-No.
I'll apply to a medical college in my city...
Had to change my plans...
Can't leave my family all alone here...
Yeah, I understand...
Congrats anyway. When are you sending me sweets?
Buy what you like and enjoy yourself.
We don't exchange sweets here... Except our soldiers on the border...
And our Prime Ministers when they meet...
How about you change things? Send some sweets here and... Start a trend, maybe?
Sending 'em's gonna cost more than the sweets themselves. So, have what you like... And send me, perhaps?
What about my money?
When d'you care about money? You ain't a Scrooge like me, are you?
Aye...
Anyway, mate...
I gotta go back...
Have dinner...
Bye...
Hello?
It's Vishal's mother. Sunanda.
Are you Sarah's mother?
Yeah.
It's me.
How are you?
Good...
And you?
Good.
So... You wanted to talk to me?
-So... You wanted to talk to me?
I don't know what to say...
Vishal's Granny... The other day...
Everything she said...
I'm sorry about everything...
I'm really sorry...
I'm sorry too... If anything my in-laws said... Hurt you...
That's how their generation thinks...
Yeah...
So... What d'you want me to call you?
Amna?
Uh...
Yeah, that's good...
Or Mrs Sherali...
Our wounds would bleed every time we called each other...
Mrs Sherli and Mrs Vijay Malhotra...
But Amna and Sunanda...
May be able to pour their hearts out to each other...
That's right...
Suninda...
Sunanda...
Sunenda...
Don't worry too much about Nadir, okay?
If he's got a learning disability, he can overcome it...
I've worked with SEND kids before...
He's my only son...
I want him...
To be like his father...
But...
I've got to tell my world about our problems...
I understand...
But I'm sure you can find help in Pakistan...
Someone who can show you the way...
And... You've always got me...
Feel free to talk to me about anything you need...
You've got a job...
I'm a housewife...
There's a lot that's easy for you...
That I can't even imagine...
It's not like I run the world... I'm a third world woman... Just like you...
There's a lot I can only imagine... But never do...
By the way, Vishal said Sarah got into medical college?
I forgot to congratulate you...
Thank you.
We're grieving again today...
It would've been such a happy day...
If her Dad were with us...
I can understand...
It's the same here...
Good news brings us to tears...
But, as they say, life's gotta go on...
Ups and downs...
Was he your love?
My parents' choice...
What about you?
He was...
Vijay took up arms against the whole world to marry me...
We came from different classes, different ends of the country... But his love was blind to it all...
He was poet too...
He lost his heart to me when we met at a competition...
I lost my heart to him... When I heard his poetry...
No idea why I'm telling you any of it...
It's okay... I don't mind it...
He was my parents' choice...
So to speak...
But now that he's gone...
It feels like I've lost the love of my life...
God, he's spoilt me so much...
I've been handicapped...
Ever since he's gone...
We've got everything, so to speak...
An estate, kids, my in-laws...
But there's this emptiness... That's swallowed them all...
I haven't had a good night's sleep ever since...
This bed... In my room... It's never seen him... Felt him...
I can't talk to anyone...
No one will understand...
Vijay never liked me in white...
But...
Now... All I've got is white... It's all I can wear...
When I walk past his picture in white, I feel like he's giving me that look...
Feeling sad for me...
There are things a wife only shares with her husband...
Know what...
I just loved to snuggle with him...
Being close to him...
I felt safe from the world...
When Noria and Nadir snuggle with me...
I haven't got the strength to be their Sherali...
I get chills in my feet in the winter...
Vijay would warm them with his feet when he'd be here...
His hands, his feet... They were always so warm...
They were my fireplace...
But now...
My fire's been extinguished...
They say he died a hero's death...
But I ask why he left me...
Yeah...
That's what they tell me too...
'You should be proud'...
Every promise, every vow, every oath,
I wonder...
Everything just snapped...
For what?
I've lost my husband...
Everything just snapped...
My other half...
No medal can ever complete me again...
Heart and soul mine, cry both,
In this life, trapped...
I'm whiling away sleepless nights
And restless days,
Searching for you in the dark anights,
Hoping to see you through the haze...
Who's gonna stop these tears from falling?
From where?
India.
Have it... It's for your result.
Can't believe it's gotten to a point where they're exchanging sweets!
She can never be yours! I hope you're clear about that!
-Of course...
Of course... It's not like I love her or something... It's just -- Plain impossible!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5