♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 17 - 'Another War'
Granny!
Vishal's here!
Really? Where's he?
Vishal!
How are you, dear?
M'lad!
C'mon...
This house was a lonely place without you... Look at it gladden the moment you entered...
I ain't gonna stay here too long... We're about to be redeployed...
And your Mum's gonna get back to an endless wait...
I've gotten used to it as a wife... Now I've gotta wait as a mother...
I'm gonna take you with me this time.
You're just a Lieutenant... Talk about that when you're a Captain.
Besides, who knows where you're going?
-Aye...
By the way... You're done training... Enlisted...
How 'bout I reined you in?
You mean get me married? No way...
Get engaged maybe?
-The only thing I can think of right now is food. C'mon, I'm starving!
DG ISPR told Geo News in an exclusive interview...
Here.
-DG ISPR told Geo News in an exclusive interview...
DG ISPR told Geo News in an exclusive interview...
Looks delicious!
-That the army will be surveying the Line of Control...
It's your favourite, innit?
-Alright, that's enough.
-That the army will be surveying the Line of Control...
In other news, an Indian Army convoy has been attacked in Pulwama...
-Alright, that's enough.
The attack claimed 40 lives...
India has declared it will make Pakistan pay for killing her soldiers...
The Chief of Army Staff has put the Army on high alert.
We repeat, an Indian Army convoy has been attacked in Pulwama...
God help us... It's all starting over again...
-In other news, an Indian Army convoy has been attacked in Pulwama...
-The attack claimed 40 lives...
India has declared it will make Pakistan pay for killing her soldiers...
Have your dinner.
-India has declared it will make Pakistan pay for killing her soldiers...
India has declared it will make Pakistan pay for killing her soldiers...
The Chief of Army Staff has put the Army on high alert.
Dinner, Cüneyt...
-The Chief of Army Staff has put the Army on high alert.
The Chief of Army Staff has put the Army on high alert.
The Prime Minister has ordered surgical strikes against Pakistan...
Behind the tears, the nation fumes in fury...
What now?
-Behind the tears, the nation fumes in fury...
Nothing.
-Yet another cowardly attack has claimed the lives of 40 soldiers...
We're at it again...
Pickin' a row...
-Yet another cowardly attack has claimed the lives of 40 soldiers...
The Army has been put on high alert until further orders...
You haven't even been deployed yet.
-The Army has been put on high alert until further orders...
The Army has been put on high alert until further orders...
Sir.
Okay, sir.
Hail India.
Who was it?
The Unit.
Why?
We're being redeployed...
Where?
-Where?
Jammu and Kashmir. The frontline...
Sir.
Right.
When do we move in, sir?
Affirmative.
What happened?
Who was it?
They're sending me to the frontlines.
Where?
Kashmir.
Sarah!
What happened? Sarah!
Don't worry... Besides...
It's hardly unusual... We're used to standoffs like this...
Don't leave me...
You know...
I can't do that...
How can you leave me like this?
Tell me...
If we stayed back for our wives...
Our kids...
Who's gonna stand guard at the borders?
I need to get going.
But I'll be back...
See you soon...
We have unprovoked firing from India in the Chirikot Sector...
The Indian Army unleashed automatic weapons and mortars...
Join us as we interview witnesses who can tell us more...
After failing everywhere else, the powerless Pakistan Army suffered yet another disgraceful defeat...
As the Indian Army retaliated against their cowardly attack with deadly effect.
We need to fight these terrorists...
And those who provide them refuge.
We need to tell those who give them refuge that they need to be extradited!
Fire now...
And you'll be safe from the snake...
But the snakes on the other side...
Have their guns trained on you...
I'm -- Afraid of snakes, sir...
You ain't afraid of death...
But you're afraid of this puny snake?
Terrorist attack in Razmak, North Waziristan... ISPR says the terrorists used an IED...
Six soldiers, including one officer, lost their lives...
The fallen include Captain Omar Farooq, Staff Sergeant Fayaz Ahmed...
Staff Sergeant Shakil Azad, Sergeant Jonah Khan...
Lance Corporal Mohammad Nadeem and Lance Corporal Asmatullah...
The ISPR is here with us at Geo News...
What happened?
Captain Zafar's no more.
Military Intelligence is investigating the matter...
As you can see, a sinister plot to repeat Pulwama has been thwarted...
You can see the white car loaded with about 50 kilogrammes of explosives...
I'm so sorry for your loss...
We're putting up our best fight.
I hear the Pakistan Army's suffered twice as many losses in Kashmir.
The Government says...
Our men have got hearts of iron...
They're invincible...
They'd know better if they stood guard at the border themselves...
Heroes never die.
Why don't you have breakfast?
That's the sixth we know... Gone...
Zafar was too young...
Aye, about as old as Cüneyt...
May he rest in peace...
May God help us all...
We're at it every now and then...
Why can't our nations just talk for a change?
How long can we keep fighting?
No one cares about soldiers...
Or their wives, their kids, their parents, their families... No one!
If you want war...
Fight and die in one shot!
Don't kill us every day...
Slowly...
What've wars achieved, like ever? It's all just... Chaos and destruction and death all over...
Talk about peace and we'll talk about peace...
Wage war, and we'll wage war...
The Prime Minister has sent a clear message...
We are not weaklings. We love our country to the core and we're willing to die for her.
After Pulwama, they seem to be caught between chest thumping and empty threats of war...
The Foreign Secretary wrote today...
Informing the UN about recent developments...
You didn't go to college today?
Yeah, Aunt...
Just... Worried...
Had this nightma --
-Please, Sarah...
Don't say something...
That'll make my blood pressure shoot up again...
Guess I'm just a bit under the weather... That explains the weird nightmares and all...
Of course... Because...
Why else?
Did Cüneyt call?
I've --
I've been waiting...
Don't worry... He'll call you...
May the Lord keep him safe...
May He keep every son safe...
Have your breakfast...
I'm fine!
Just... Back at the base for a few days...
For rest, yeah... I'm going back...
I pray peace prevails between our nations... I pray they call the armies back...
I'm a soldier, Mum...
I can't wish for it...
Even if I want it...
You're fine, aren't you?
Of course!
It was just a fever! That's why I came here...
Did you take a pill?
I'm just back from the hospital. Took everything I need. Don't worry.
Quickly... Let me talk ter 'imself...
-Here. Talk to Granny.
Hello?
Hey, Granny.
How are you?
-Great. What could happen?
God forbid anything happen to you...
You're who we're livin' for...
Just keep praying, and I'm sure I'll be fine!
Waaat else do yer tink... Yisser Mamai an' Granny do al' day, everyday?
Those sobs are gonna drown my morale!
Everything's fine here... Don't worry.
We've lost many lives... De people in de neighbourhud...
Mum!
Many got the bodies of their fallen yesterday...
Many more didn't... Couldn't...
'Oy are things at de border?
'Oy brutal is it?
This is the price we pay...
Whenever our countries go to war...
This is the price we make each other pay...
Just a minute... Could I talk?
Aye, Vishal...
Hello?
Today, for an attack on an unprecedented scale, the nation craves vengeance on an unprecedented scale...
An attack this deadly cannot be avenged that easily.
We've hit India where it hurts!
An eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth... Blood for blood...
Why didn't you die of disgrace?
The last time someone dared threaten us, we showed him who's the boss! We didn't spare you then, we sure as hell ain't gonna spare you now!
Okay...
Give 'em a big hand!
Actors offered their tributes to the soldiers who lost their lives in the dastardly attack...
Those responsible for this massacre will pay...
And now...
I'm fine, Sarah...
I'm right here... Talking to you.
You alright?
Can't you come back?
I can't...
Look... We've got a few minutes...
Don't lose them to these sobs...
Tell me about things there... You okay?
Yeah...
Just worried...
No idea why...
Just... Take care of yourself...
I know there's a lot of stress and hormonal imbalance, but...
I'm the doctor, Cüneyt, not you.
Aye.
That's why you gotta take care of yourself.
And the young'un...
When are you coming back?
When this ends.
Which means... No idea...
Both our armies are here...
Let's see how it goes...
I might lose the signal any second...
So... Tell Mum and Dad I said hi... And please...
Take care of yourself...
I love you.
Hello?
What was I thinking?
Stupid...
She called me after two years...
How'd she think of me?
Can't sleep until I find out...
Hello?
I know you can hear me.
Aye.
How are you?
Fine.
You?
Where are you?
I'm a soldier...
Where d'you think I could be?
Deployed at the border...
Uhh...
I've been having this nightmare for the last few days...
No idea who it's about...
But I had this feeling it's about you.
That's why I called.
-Fair enough.
You see me in your dreams. Better than nothing.
I don't even dream about you now...
Won't you ask me what it is? The dream?
Go on.
You were deployed in Kashmir...
Where your Dad and mine lost their lives...
Leepa. Did you see me?
Aye... I saw you there...
And?
Nothing...
-You don't want to tell me, do you?
Aye...
They say you don't talk about bad dreams...
Where are you?
Somewhere... I can't tell you...
Not Kashmir, surely?
No.
Thank God...
Cüneyt's in Kashmir...
Oh...
Where?
Leepa.
Everything alright?
Happily married?
Aye...
Happily married...
♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
I'm expecting...
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
Congratulations...
I'm delivering next month...
What about you?
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
On the relationship front?
Got a love interest?
You only love once...
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
Miss me these two years?
You were angry...
You used to make up to me...
-When there was no Cüneyt between us, aye...
When there was no Cüneyt between us, aye...
When there were no armies between us either, aye...
I'll send you my kid's pic...
I'll be back at the border in a few days...
So if I didn't text you or call you back...
Don't think I've forgotten you...
Take care, okay?
And...
Don't be a hero...
Save yourself...
Did you say the same to Cüneyt?
He knows his slogans and war cries, just like you...
He doesn't listen to me either...
Why d'you soldiers forget those you leave behind? How are you able to forget what we go through?
Even when we can't, Sarah...
We know there's nothing we can do...
Take care...
If fate has it, I'll get back to you...
I've given the Unit your name and number, besides my family's...
They'll let you know if something happened to me...
So your memories come back to haunt me?
No.
So you know I could never forget you...
Until my last breath...
♪ Eager to meet in the darkness down there... ♪
♪ May the Lord hear our prayer, ♪
♪ And let our love judge us fair... ♪
♪ Let our love judge us fair, O Lord... ♪
♪ But there's this wall, ♪
♪ There's this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ Yea, there's this wall, ♪
♪ There's this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5