♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 4 - 'Bitter Truths'
Sarah...
I want straight A*s from you... Not even a single A, okay?
Okay, boss...
-Good.
By the way...
Don't send her to the kitchen again. Forget this baking and stuff...
What d'you mean? She's a girl! She ought to know!
-So what?
You want her in the kitchen all day?
No. Don't waste her time.
Girls ought to know. Boys ought to know too...
But this is my lovely girl...
I want her to become a doctor... I'll send her overseas for her specialisation! Okay?
Leave the cooking to Nawab...
She's your girl. Raise her like one. She doesn't need these dreams of higher degrees and all... Not when she doesn't want to grow into a woman!
Don't listen to your Mum, okay?
Don't worry. I never do.
-Good.
Aye, very good.
♪ My Lord, hear me pray, ♪
♪ Just this once, let me have a say, ♪
Everything changed after you...
♪ Save these hearts pining away, ♪
♪ Isn't it, for You, but child's play? ♪
Why'd you leave us?
♪ The unease gives me frights ♪
♪ Even as my mind prays, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
Sometimes life becomes too hard to deal with...Isn't it?
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Yes...And I want to die...I want to commit suicide
Hay
why
what happend
Why'd she take my call?
But why am I calling her?
What am I thinking?
As if I haven't got my hands full already!
Uh... Hello?
Sarah?
You there?
Yes...
Alright?
No...
What is it?
Something bothering you?
Just missing Dad...
Same... Here...
I don't know what to say...
I don't know how I could comfort a girl... A woman...
But all I've seen since Dad passed away... Is tears... Always someone or the other!
You're laughing?
-I'm a man...
Men can't cry.
But you gotta be brave... You're the eldest...
You gotta be brave... For yourself... And your family...
How d'you know I'm the eldest kid in the family?
-I just know...
I've been reading about your family on social media for weeks...
I'm sure you've been too...
You're the eldest kid too...
-Aye.
The misery, the problems... We are the same... The eldest kids suffering...
But you're lucky. Unlike me.
-Why?
What happened to you? Girls face all the problems.
So they say...
But you'd know better if you were in my place.
I've got four women at my place... Me Mum, Granny, and twin sisters...
I've got no idea what I should tell any of them... At any time!
Suddenly, I'm supposed to be Mr Responsible.
But you're a girl. It's easy for you.
Aye, I've got it easy.
No responsibilities.
Just... Grandpa, Granny... My wee brother and sister... Mum, who's never stepped out of the house...
The only man in my family is seven. So yeah, you're right... No one expects anything of me.
That why you're crying?
-No.
I told you... Just missing Dad...
But why are we talking about it? Why am I telling you any of it? We're enemies, aren't we? My Dad... Because of your bloody old man!
Aye...
So we are. Sworn enemies...
Your old man's responsible for everything we're going through!
And -- What an idiot I am... What was I thinking, asking you why you're crying? Sympathising with you? You lot are the reason we're all crying!
In that case... Why d'you even bother to call me and ask me about my problems? I'm not begging for your sympathies!
Oh-so-kind of you to talk to me!
To the devil with her... Her tears... Sympathies...
That's why I told you... Don't expect anything from her... Or her lot...
But you had to kiss up to her!
How could I know she'd yell at Mum like that?
I would've loved to see her dare with Vijay around!
She dares because he's not around...
That's why I asked you to tell Mum to give us our share quickly... Get it?
Sunanda won't let Mum give us anything.
Besides... She's growing old...
It's easy to exploit her emotions...
I'm telling you... Vishal's gonna be Sunanda's next target!
Were it so easy...
I won't stop until I've got my share.
I'm just worried for Mum...
What if Sunanda kicked her out?
I told you...
They're gonna explot her...
I'm sure Vishal told her that... Scared her and all...
Now they're gonna sell everything without a mouse stirring!
I get what you're saying... But I'm comfused...
Why?
Your Mum's got your Dad's pension.
That's enough for her.
She can rent a place... Live as a paying guest...
She wouldn't like to...
She isn't used to it...
You're only worried for your Mum...
Not the kids...
And yeah...
Let me talk to Sunanda...
Or you're just gonna play ping-pong with her...
Sherali's Dad...
First time I've heard you call me that in years...
I thought the kids wouldn't like it.
That's why I gave up...
But now I feel...
That Sherali...
Was the only one who ever cared...
They say daughters - not sons - support their parents as they grow old...
Granted we...
Never wanted to live with them...
But...
I never thought...
They'd refuse to let us live with them.
They didn't refuse...
They've got no choice...
You know it very well.
Aye...
Daughters have no choice...
Can't complain...
Mothers have no choice but to cover up for them either...
First time I've felt...
That we're growing old...
And a burden...
Now I know...
Why we're all destined to die...
The Lord God wants the likes of us...
To find some peace in death...
And leave without burdening anyone...
Leave with respect...
And...
What about those of Sherali's age who leave?
They don't have to leave the world...
They don't burden anyone...
Don't ask me anything...
That'd make me choose between staying quiet...
And lying to you...
Get up. You're getting late for school...
Blimey, you've got a fever!
Why didn't you tell me?
I don't want to get married...
Who said anything to you?
I heard what she said...
Not right away...
Once you and Zuber have completed your studies?
I just don't want to...
I want to be here. With you. Not in another part of the world.
You can't be here all your life.
Says who?
With Dad gone...
Who else've you got?
Grandpa... Granny... Nadir... Noria... Who else've they got?
Don't worry about any of that. Just focus on your studies.
I don't want to get married. To anyone.
Would you do this if Dad were here?
A lot more would never've happened if your Dad were here...
C'mon, get up. Have your breakfast. You need to see a doctor...
Vishal... We wanna go to the park... It's playtime...
Can't you see I'm studying?
I can't. Take us to the park.
Out.
And... Don't come back until I say.
Mum said no.
You said no.
Dad's not coming back.
Who do we go out with?
Change o' plans.
Tell Laxmi to get ready.
-Laxmi! Get ready, Vishal's taking us to the park!
Mum...
-Hmm?
I'm taking Pari and Laxmi to the park... How say you come with us?
Mhm...
Just for a while...
Sit in the park... You'll feel good...
What good is it?
But...
Could you...
Get me...
These medicines...
On your way back?
I talked to Atif last night...
He said he can come here for a few days if you need help with filing for welfare and all...
I thought it's great. You don't seriously think you can bear all the red tape... Not in mourning, surely?
Badar said he's coming to help me... He'll sort it out... Atif doesn't need to come all the way...
This blind trust will hurt you, Amna...
I mean -- He's your brother, but this is about money...
The more people are involved, the less likely it is that anyone's gonna break that trust.
I don't get it.
Put plainly, 'Don't trust anyone - not even your siblings - in matters of money'.
I hear the welfare is quite a lot...
So it's best for you and kids that Atif's here with us.
I wanted Zafar to be here too...
But...
He only cares about his family.
Badar's fortunate to have everything he needs... Why'd he eye his widowed sister's welfare?
No, you're getting it wrong -- I don't mean he's eyeing the welfare...
Just... That we should involve a few more people...
As witnesses?
Call him if you want, but I don't think we're gonna need it.
Badar will do what's best for me and the kids.
Why'd he want anything less?
He cares for us just like you. We're family.
I told you...
She's honest-to-goodness.
With that blind faith, you can bet she won't even bother to ask him about anything.
Leave it... She'll find out in time...
I'll have another glass...
Dey're joehst like Vijay...
Energetic... Lively...
'E cooehldn't set fahr a mahment when 'e was deir age!
Always ready to play... In 'igh spirets...
Once more!
And when he couldn't have his way...
He'd run off from home...
He was our only son...
For many years...
He was our world...
Mine and your Grandpa's...
The best years of our lives...
Vishal...
-Hmm?
Dere's sahmethin...
Dat's messin...
In 'ere... Me 'eart...
'As lahst its reasahn to go ahn...
Mind if I say something?
-No?
That's some heavy medication, kid. Not good for you.
Did you consult a doctor?
I don't get it.
-All these pills have side-effects.
Keep taking them and you'll be addicted to cocaine and weed in a few months.
Nothing else will calm you.
You're young.
Like a son.
That's why I'm telling you.
But -- They're all antidepressants, right?
-Aye.
Aye.
But in the long run... They'll destroy you up here...
And here...
Anyway...
That'll be 3,272.
That's some heavy medication, kid. Keep taking them and you'll be addicted to cocaine and weed in a few months.
Nothing else will calm you.
You're young.
Like a son.
That's why I'm telling you.
Hello?
-Hello...
I think...
I was too rude the other day...
Could you help me?
Yeah.
Mum's on these antidepressants... And -- whatcha call them? Sedatives...
The chemist told me they're no good... She'll get addicted to it... If she isn't already...
I -- I feel very helpless -- What... What now?
Hello?
You there?
Yeah, but... Why don't you talk to her? Instead of getting her the pills...
First time she asked me to get her the pills... I had no idea what she's been taking with her sleeping pills!
-Talk to her. Tell her not to take them.
Talk to her. Tell her not to take them.
-She won't listen to me!
She won't listen to me!
-Anyone else she'd listen to?
Anyone else she'd listen to? Grandpa? Granny? An Uncle or Aunt?
Not on me Mum's side... And she ain't on the finest terms with her MIL.
A friend perhaps? Hers or of the family? Someone she'd listen to?
Aye... There's one...
Aunt Shefali...
Actually --
I'll get back to you, Sarah... Uncle's calling from Canada...
Sure... But... Please help your Mum any way you can.
Yeah... I'll do something...
Thanks...
Hi, Uncle.
-'Sup, Vishal?
Great. And you? Aunt?
Great. Could I talk to Mum?
She turned in.
No...
Ah, right...
I'll talk to Sunanda then.
Okay. Just a sec.
Mum... It's Uncle Anurag.
So?
So... He wants to talk...
About what?
Why don't you find out? I'm sure they're just checking on you...
-Alright...
Hello?
How are you?
Okay...
You?
Great.
And Pratibha?
She's great too. She says hi.
Tell her I said hello.
Sure.
Sunanda...
We need to talk...
Yeah?
About Mum's estate, you know...
Pratibha wants her share...
Why don't you talk to Mum?
We've talked to her. Not just once.
But Pratibha and I think she's a bit reluctant because of you and VIshal...
So we thought we'd talk to you.
Because of me and Vishal?
Why?
It's her estate... She can do what she wants...
Rent it out like right now or --
That's what we're saying... You're not gonna need it now...
The Government's gonna provide you housing and all...
Why'd you need her estate?
But we do...
You know how it is here...
If you could ask Mum to sell it...
What do I tell her?
It's not like she does as I say.
But I'm sure she'd listen to you.
As always.
I'm sure she'll do as you say.
By the way, why don't you take Mum with you? To Canada?
What? What are you saying?
How can she live here?
She doesn't have a visa... And even if she did, you know the houses here!
Mum can't manage it without servants.
She's happy with you... Why d'you want to kick her out?
Aye, Anurag...
She's happy with me...
Lowly me. Oh, please...
Which of you chinless wonders would be happy with lowly me?
Mum's the same as you two. She'd rather be with you.
Sunanda...
Lowly or not, I never thought you'd be so low and flat!
Excuse me!
Sunanda... Let's not start a row over it...
Why d'you want to pressure Mum when we can all get our shares peacefully?
And how dare you use Vishal to blackmail us emotionally?
I'm using Vishal to usurp your share? I'm not like you!
Don't make me start... If we started talking, it will get ugly! There will be blood!
Oh, do what you want! I'm sick of staying quiet!
I couldn't believe it until I heard it today...
But I always knew you're using Vishal to usurp Mum's estate!
You know I won't let that happen.
No way you're snatching my share from me!
I've got kids too!
You're entitled to welfare. Housing.
But we're struggling to pay back our mortgage here!
Aunt... I'll do as you say...
I'll talk to Granny...
Vishal...
How --
Can't believe she gave you the phone!
Good Heavens... Your Mum wants to drive a wedge between us!
She says Vijay's memory lives on in there... She wants you and Mum to hate me!
Vishal...
It's good that you know...
But don't worry... Nothing we can't sort out...
We're coming to India in a few weeks.
So...
Talk to Mum, okay?
Convince Sunanda too.
I'll get back to you. Bye.
Bye.
Get your hands on what you can while they live... And everything they leave behind! That's the name of the game...
-Mum...
Mum...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5
You'd have many friends...
Aye... But only one enemy.
Aye... Same here...
You're never talking to Vishal again.
We're enemies...
But don't they suffer all the same?
The war between our nations has claimed many lives...
But much more importantly... It's exposed cold-blooded blood ties.