♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 1 - 'India vs Pakistan - Who Won This?'
In the air...
That's one wicket down!
And he gets the runs!
This might go over the boundary...
Brilliant shot, innit? Can he catch it?
Another one through the air...
-Yeah!
Yes!
And he does it again!
Another one in the air!
Another brilliant shot!
Good shot...
Has he taken it?
Very comfortably!
-Ye --
-Yuck!
-No...
Woo hoo!
They can't even play decently...
Not again...
That's why I never like these matches! They're always up to something else!
Don't worry. I'm praying for Pakistan's victory...
Are you gonna pussyfoot around the whole time? C'mon, sit down.
It's okay, Mum... I know we got this one.
-Of course...
I swear I'm gonna offer all my prayers if Pakistan won this!
And I'm gonna thank Him all day, all night!
Don't worry, we've been wipin' de floor wi' dem for de last 7 matches.
-Aye.
You're jist gettin' worried, that's al'.
Alright...
Separate them out, okay?
Give them all space to grow, okay?
-Okay.
In the name of God, the Most Generous, the Most Merciful...
He - the Most Generous and Merciful, the Lord of the worlds - deserves all praise...
The Lord of the Day of Judgement...
We pray to You alone, and ask for Your help. Show us the path of righteousness...
Jesus, late again...
Breakfast for Grandma, Grandpa... The kids...
Nadir? Done yet? How long are you gonna need? You're getting late!
And how long do you need?
-Not hungry, Mum...
C'mon, have your breakfast!
-I always do... Just -- Today...
Where's my breakfast, Uncle Nawab?
-Just a second, ma'am!
(Here we go again...)
Just a sec...
Here.
Hey.
-Don't leave before you've had breakfast!
Can't you put that book down for a minute, Sarah?
-I'm getting late!
Then get up early!
At least let them --
-I'm getting late, Mum! Very late!
Take care, Granny... Don't forget to pray.
Of course, it's your last paper...
I'm talking about the match with India!
-See you.
Take care.
-See you, Mum!
-Have something in break time! See you. Don't forget anything you need!
-See you!
Quickly!
-Pray for me.
-In the car, quick!
-See you, Grandpa!
-Take care!
Bye!
Hail Lord Ganesha...
Son of God -- dess Parvati and Mahadeva...
Out!
-Not out!
-Okay...
Hail Lord Ganesha...
Calm down!
What d'you think you're doing?
Doing an Atif Aslam...?
Yer nu oi pray dis time.
But what'd you care?
Alwus interruptin' me... Be done wi' it!
-Sorry...
By the way -- Don't forget to pray, Granny -- The match...
-Yeah, oi nu.
Out!
-Gopi!
(Here... Granny needs me...) Yes?
Here.
Vijay didn't call today...
Yeah... He didn't.
Weord...
He texted he'd call me...
Just a bit late...
Anyway, I'll have my breakfast...
Okay.
Nawab!
Where's the remote? Everyone knows I watch this drama on telly...
Nawab...
-Ma'am?
Where's the remote?
I kept it here when I cleaned it... Let me have a look...
Where could it be?
Ah yes, Grandpa was watching the news... Here!
Yeah, turn it on.
-Geo News live with an exclusive...
D'you watch Pakistani plays, Shefali?
Totally love them!
-Same here! Love the plays, love the wardrobe, the acting...
I mean, check out their elegant suits!
-Aye.
Don't forget the dialogues! A real story, some content... And the performances...
I swear! Nothing like our plays!
Can't believe you're comparing them with our plays! Ridiculous stories... Just think of -- 'The Serpent'!
Enjoying 'The Serpent' again, eh?
Oh, please, not again... Why don't you have a chat with your friends or something? Lemme watch it...
Can't believe you went from reading the Holy Qur'an to watching this reincarnated soap opera in minutes.
No way you'll be forgiven for this!
There now, it's just a drama... Let me enjoy it.
Anyway, when's Vijay coming back?
-In two weeks!
Thank goodness he's done with that hardship post... I was really worried about that.
That explains the lively face...
Counting down, too, I figure!
Because why not!
I've been marking the days on the calendar...
And how's your MIL?
Don't even ask... She's never gonna change...
But with a husband like Vijay, who cares?
Anyway, I gotta go... I had no idea I've spent so much time with you!
Big day today, by the way. Everyone's feverish!
The ladies' club's showing the match. Want to come with me?
-No...
I'd rather watch at home.
India's gonna win this one.
Would you say the same if... Fawad Khan were on the Pakistani team?
'Course not.
Check out this step!
Lovely. So you were dancing to this song!
-Yeah. But Mum told me to stop and get back to studies...
Anushka's dress though!
Everything she wears suits her! She looks soooo lovely!
-I know! She's amazing!
I think it's the driver...
Yeah. C'mon.
By the way... Don't forget to pray for Pakistan's victory. If we win this one, I'm celebrating for a week! Besides, I'm done with my exams!
Don't worry. We got this one.
Really?
-Yeah.
God help us win this one...
Do we have any half-decent players left?
Yes... Quite a lot of them, this time.
We haven't lost any matches in the last few months...
That's what worries me, sir!
We can't keep at anything for more than a few months!
The Asian theatre's showing the match here. Indians and Pakistanis flock together.
Brace yerself for a proper brawl!
That's not how it is here, Mum... We enjoy it together. Congratulate each other or say 'Better luck next time'. Simple, innit?
Canny believe 'oy simply yer forgot yisser country whaen yer moved ter Canada! Yer got ter be ready ter scrap... Or die for yisser country!
We're all cogs in the machine here... Too busy with work... Working together...
In the middle of all of this, a familiar face is all you need...
'Sup, Granny! Hey, Aunt!
-M'boy!
-Hi, Vishal!
Ready for the match?
Not like you. I hear you've stockpiled fireworks!
Nah, I'm about to... Too expensive these days... But I'll find some today! I've got just... Thirteen or so?
Thirteen? I hear that right? Just -- Why? It's so unlucky!
Aye, why unlucky thirteen?
Okay, I'll get some more for luck... Bye, Aunt!
Mum!
Make sure the biryani, quorma, and fruit chat are ready for dinner.
And pakoras... Samosas... Everything!
-Gee... Sounds like someone aced her paper...
'Course... Just hope the team aces this match too!
You're at it again! I made these for Noria. Put them down.
You don't make anything for me, do you? It's always for Noria or Nadir...
That's why I miss Dad so much... He's the only one who cares for me.
It's nothing... Just... Cooking rice...
-I'm starving, Mum...
-D'you think we can win this match, ma'am?
I hope so!
Likewise.
Aye?
Oh yeah?
Okay. I'll tell Mum and be there... 4-ish? 5 at the most!
Yeah, I'll be there.
Why d'you have to go anywhere when you can watch the match with us?
This isn't just any match, Mum...
Your Grandma's never gonna let you go.
Your Dad's not here either. I can't let you go.
I'm not a kid, Mum.
Oh yeah? You better mature too. See some sense. You're gonna be out until so late!
They're friends, Mum... You know them all.
Jesus, the wretch gave me this empty box!
Look, Vishal... You're free to do as you want... But if you're asking me, I ain't letting you go. Call and ask Dad if you've got a problem.
Dad's in Kashmir! You don't seriously expect me to call him for this --
-I do.
Every single time -- Forget it...
Noria! When's the match?
Again? You just asked me five minutes ago! Can't you wait?
When do I ask again?
How 'bout... Never? Just go and see for yourself on the telly!
Noria! Don't!
Please, c'mon!
Here we go, this is Pakistan!
Yeah!
-Woo hoo!
-We've won!
Victory!
-YAYYY!!
-Victory!
Everyone here! Granny?
-Yay!
-Hooray!
-Granny!
I've been twattling on all day, but you had to watch the match here! What d'you care what I say?
Hooray!
-Win win for India!
-Yeehaw!
Woo hoo!
Pari, Laxmi... Come with me!
-Yeah, c'mon! Let's go!
I got the lighter.
-Which one goes first? Hey, not so fast!
Hey, not so fast! C'mon!
Can't believe I missed another episode of 'The Serpent' for this!
Don't you dare talk about anything Indian!
I can't believe it...
Again...?
I hate cricket!
Noria...
Go freshen up... Both of you... It's late...
What was I thinking? Preparing for a feast...
C'mon...
Nawab!
All our hopes...
Go and see who's here!
Nawab!
Nawab?
Who is it?
-Grandpa...
Who is it, Gopi?
I wanna go somewhere that's nice, Grandpa... And I wanna go right now! I've watched enough cricket for this life!
('May the holy land, stay glad' instrumental)
Another brave son of Pakistan shall be buried in her soil...
Pakistan takes pride in her bravehearts who are willing to make the ultimate sacrifice for her safety, and their families, their kinsmen they leave behind...
I seek refuge with God, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful, from the accursed Satan, and begin in His name...
He is the only One, the eternal Lord...
He was not begotten, nor did he beget... One, like no one else...
In the name of the Lord, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful... All praise to Him, the Lord of the worlds and the Day of Judgement, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful...
You alone do we pray to, and ask for help, so show us the righteous path...
The path of those who earned Your favour, not the misguided who incurred Your wrath. Amen.
Few would've brought the enemy to their knees like Col Vijay Malhotra did in Kashmir.
His funeral rites will start in a few moments.
But first, a parting tribute from the people of India to their braveheart...
('Dispenser of India's destiny' instrumental)
Was he not the best?
No doubt!
('Dispenser of India's destiny' instrumental)
Miss Sarah...
The officer wants to talk to you...
The reporters are here for you.
Tell them about your Dad... And how you're proud to be his daughter...
And... Just how big this day is for you, for us... And for our nation...
-They've lost their son, but you can see neither tears in the girl's eyes, nor shock on the father's face...
They've lost their son, but you can see neither tears in the girl's eyes, nor shock on the father's face...
All of India's watching... We ought to send a message.
What would our hero's son want to tell Pakistan?
How'd you tell them that every one of us is willing to fight and die for our motherland?
I'm -- Very proud -- of my father... Col Vijay Malhotra...
My father, Col Sherali, is the first martyr in our family... And I'm proud to be his daughter. Few are so fortunate...
My husband - Kamlesh Malhotra - was a soldier too... He did everything he could for his nation...
The nation gave him life... And in return...
He gave his life for it...
We're all... Very proud...
That Dad... Crushed our enemies... Even in his last breaths...
And... Made them suffer!
Something you'd like our enemies to hear?
Just...
Don't even dare come close to our holy land.
Our enemies would do well to remember that it won't end with one Vijay Malhotra. There's millions like him who'd gouge every eye that dares look at us the wrong way out!
We'd give our nation every last drop of our blood.
Brave girl. Just like your father.
That's the kind of courageous and selfless families our martyrs come from...
We salute the family, the mother, wife, son, and daughter...
Who take pride that Col Sherali sacrificed his life defending his homeland, fulfilling the vow he made when he joined the Pakistan Army...
Eyes ablaze, smiling wide, like a true martyr...
With that, we conclude this programme. Next up on India News... (Cut!)
Hope I didn't mess it up!
Not at all! Made me tear up!
-Rehearsed it for hours, sir...
Don't forget to play 'I Vow to Thee, My Country' in the background when you cover this tonight!
♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
M...
Mum? We're home...
Mum?
C'mon...
Grandpa?
We're home.
My legs... Feel lifeless...
Feels like...
My back's broken...
When's Dad coming back, Mum?
Quickly, Uncle Gopi! I'm starving!
It's all for you...
Just give me a minute...
C'mon.
Uncle Gopi...
Why'd they burn Dad?
Vishal...
Want to have something?
I'm sure you're starving.
No.
Grandpa...
The GOC's here.
C'mon, you can do it... Grandpa.
No longer...
Not at my age...
Not without my son to give me hope...
Of course...
We're gonna have another round of the same... Bravery... Courage...
The glories of martyrdom...
The same old condolences...
Questions... And answers...
The Indian Army will always be there for you.
It would've been great if I could meet Mrs Malhotra in person... And convey my condolences.
She's not feeling well. She took a pill and went to sleep.
Well, then... I'll take your leave.
God bless you, son.
You're still up, Mum?
The sleeping pills don't seem to be working...
Strange, innit?
Doesn't your Dad look so stunning?
He was supposed to come back in a week...
But... Not like this...
H -- Have something?
Why?
You haven't had anything all day.
Mum...
Get some rest...
You're still up?
You're up too.
I'll doze off in a moment...
Go, you need some rest.
Vishal...
Go get some rest... I feel like sitting here for a while...
♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
Easy there...
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Col Vijay Malhotra has shown the world that the Indian Army guards this nation like an iron curtain...
Impenetrable no matter how many of us you kill.
We salute the family, the mother, wife, son, and daughter, who take pride in his martyrdom even as they bid him a final goodbye.
Was he not the best?
No doubt!
What would our hero's son want to tell Pakistan?
How'd you tell them that every one of us is willing to fight and die for our motherland?
Our enemies would do well to remember that it won't end with one Vijay Malhotra. There's millions like him who'd gouge every eye that dares look at us the wrong way out, and sever every head that dares think about harming us!
That's the spirit, m'lad! We're so proud of you!
'Who do these shameless Hindus spare anyway?'
-'Aren't you ashamed of yourself Sara Sherali? Comin' here to bicker! As if your old man didn't disgrace you enough already!'
'That's what you deserve, you wretched cow!'
-'It won't end with your oul fella, Sarah! We're comin' for your entire bloody family!'
Not sorry, Indians, but Col Vijay Malhotra was no brave man.
Not even nearly as brave as my father, who's gonna be awarded the Military Medal for Gallantry for routing the enemy.
'Who the hell thought it's okay to spare the daughter?'
-'Your father did the right thing, Vishal. India thanks him and stands with your family.'
'Good one. "LoNG LiVe PaKIsTaN." For Christ's sake, you can't even shoot straight!'
'Hail India! Hope to see you finishing the fight, Vishal!'
'That's what you bloody deserve, girl!'
My father embraced death, fighting the good fight. What can you Indian wretches do except yap online?
Miss Sarah Sherali...
Your manners show the character of your country.
Cowards! That's what you are.
What you've always been.
I'm Vishal Malhotra... The son of Col Vijay Malhotra...
Who died fighting to protect his country...
But not before proving his mettle and crushing your army...
For which, in just a few days, he will be awarded the Victoria Cross.
You are most welcome to believe it. Or would you rather want an official invitation?
Mr Vishal Mahotra... Admittedly, I feel sorry for your loss...
But it appears you've lost your sanity between your grief, which is why you can do no better than shoot your mouth off here!
No amount of chest-thumping or gibbering here's gonna prove how brave you are. I'd like to see you bring your old man's regiment here so we can sort it out in a fair fight!
Oh, please, just admit we've given you the frights... It's a lot easier... Your old man died a coward's death!
That's only because we're ready to fight... And die for our nation. Were it up to you, you would've killed all the minorities in yours!
Why don't you care about your blasted failing state instead? In case you forgot what we did with East Pakistan, lemme tell you we're planning a sweet reminder for West Pakistan real soon.
Oh, I'd like to see you try!
Were it so easy, you sissies would've vanquished us long ago!
Not sorry, Indians, but Col Vijay Malhotra was no brave man.
Cowards! That's what you are.
What you've always been.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5