♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 5 - 'Hostile Sorrows'
Vishal...
Hi, Aunt Shefali...
Bless you.
Everything alright?
Well...
Sorta yes. Sorta no...
And Sunanda?
We need to talk...
Mum's on these antidepressants...
She takes sleeping pills and sleeps all day...
Everything's upside down over here... I have no idea what I can do...
She takes all of these?
-Aye.
Can't believe it...
She won't listen to anyone else...
So I thought if -- You know -- You could...
Don't worry.
I'll talk to her.
In fact, I feel guilty because I met her the other day... And I couldn't get a hint...
Don't worry.
I'll take care of it.
I'll talk to her.
Okay...
What d'you mean your sister-in-law wants your daughter's hand in marriage for her son?
Yes...
She talked about it...
Said he'd be a good match...
An American national...
Currently in University...
I was thinking of Hammad.
But it seems you'd rather do as your in-laws say.
Hammad?
-Aye. Hammad.
My wife and I talked about it.
We think it's best that Sarah marry Hammad.
She can get married in time...
And we can free you of one responsibility...
But...
Hammad's not settled into his life...
He's not a very good student either...
As if her son got into Harvard.
Hammad's in University too. He's into Media Studies.
And I've got my business...
He's always got a second option.
I don't know what to say...
-You need to look your in-laws in the eye and make it clear...
But don't worry... I'll talk to them now...
Your sisters-in-law and Sherali's parents...
They can't pressure you like this!
Not after Sherali passed away!
I don't get why your sisters-in-law are even here...
What do they want?
No one bothered to be here for Sherali's funeral.
What right do they have after all this time to come here camping and propose Sarah's marriage?
Anurag and Pratibha called last night...
Why?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe because you're being tyrannised here!
Why wouldn't she call me? After everything you've told her...
No, Sunanda... Oi didn't say anythin'!
We can go on for hours about it... But... This isn't okay!
That's all...
Just --
Just -- Go back to your place...
My place?
Oi 'av naw place oi can call 'um...
Except 'ere, wi' Vishal, Pari, an' Laxmi...
Look... I don't want your daughter calling me again...
Whining about how I'm using Vishal to blackmail you emotionally...
So I can --
Usurp your estate...
I hate it when someone reminds me of my background, my status... Including you!
I had no option but to hear everything you'd mouth...
But not now...
Enough...
It's best...
That you leave...
For my sake, for my kids' sake...
And for the sake of our peace...
And yours!
I'm not stopping you from seeing the kids...
Come here anytime you want...
But -- We want nothing to do with your estate...
C'mon... Sit...
Granny's not going anywhere, Mum.
Can't believe you'd still side with her... After everything your Aunt said last night?
What about everything she said about me?
She's at the other end of the world in Canada...
What's it matter to us what they say?
Your Granny tells her every single detail!
If we're such a bother, why doesn't she leave for somewhere she'd be happy?
And her sweet girl thinks you're so close to your Granny because you want to usurp her estate!
You're proving her right...
What's wrong with you?
That's not like you...
That's not how you think...
My Mum would never think like that!
It's okay...
No one can kick you out...
As long as I'm here...
She wants the estate?
She can have it.
Okay?
Mum...
Granny's getting old...
Where'd she go?
You know Dad couldn't live without her...
You've always held him - and her - in the highest regard...
That's what you've taught me.
Please, Vishal... I don't want to talk about it. Leave.
All I want to say --
-Please!
Just -- Go... Or I'm going...
So, what is it?
-Okay!
Okay...
Just... Don't do anything...
Wrong... Okay?
Please?
What's wrong with you?
That's not how you think...
I'm sorry if you mind my saying it, but why should Amna and the kids leave this place and live with you when the Army's gonna provide them with housing? It doesn't make sense.
Of course.
The Unit will provide them everything they need. They always do.
They don't need to move out of the city...
You're in Pakistan. There's all sorts of problems for young widows and girls living alone here... Even in a garrison.
Unless one of you can take her along to the UK or the US...
It won't be easy to arrange for the immigration of the entire family...
But I've proposed Sarah's marriage...
If she's okay with it, she can marry my son as soon as she's done with med school.
Except Amna doesn't want her daughter to marry your son.
I've talked to her about my son long ago.
She never told me!
When'd you talk to him about anything of the sort?
Not exactly --
-I talked to Sherali himself!
And he said he's fine with it... Once Sarah's done with her studies.
He didn't tell any of us. Or Mum and Dad, for that reason. Innit?
I know my brother never wanted his kids married off in haste.
Sherali never said anything of the sort.
-D'you think I'm lying?
Why'd I need to?
I mean, it's possible he didn't get the chance to tell you...
But he said to me exactly what I'm saying he did.
But what'd you care?
We're lending our family a hand... But it seems you'd much rather brand me a liar and show me the door!
See that?
There is still time... Think again.
But don't even think about going over to your brother's.
Why ye an' Anurag 'av ter say anythin' ter Sunanda?
What'd we say?
They just need an excuse to insult you!
No.
Yer don't care aboyt me insult. Yer only care aboyt de estate.
Who de divil towl yer she wants ter usurp de estate? Or dat she's usin' Vishal ter blackmail me?
You're saying what they want to hear. Yet you don't want to admit she's blackmailing you.
When'd you become so money-grubbing? Ain't yer family?
Mum...
You want to see me divorced?
All alone here in Canada?
Between grieving over my dead brother and struggling to make ends meet... Who've I got to support me?
He's not dead...
He's a hero...
A martyr...
The nation pays its respects to him... But you just say he's 'dead'?
You've always sided with Vijay...
Against me...
So you do even now!
What d'you care if Pratibha lives or dies? Your world ended with Vijay.
I came all the way from Karachi for you.
I've been running from office to office for you.
But you want to call me a liar before your in-laws?
-I couldn't let you lie about Sherali.
I wouldn't have said anything if it were about me... But --
-Your blasted in-laws...
Have got their eyes on your wealth... And this house.
I'm sure they know what the Unit's gonna give you.
Now they're just hungering for everything you're gonna get.
That's what they said about you.
You...
You dare say your brother's hungering for your wealth?
My wife was right...
Kindness never gets repaid...
It was no use coming here...
But I guess I was wrong to care for my widowed sister... Feel for her...
I was wrong to help the martyr's kids...
But... If you're so happy with your in-laws... Fine by me!
Tell them to call their husbands here so they can help you with this red tape!
If they think the Unit's gonna do everything...
Tell them this ain't London or the US of bloody A!
I'm just telling you what they said...
Well let me make it clear that I don't want to hear it from you!
And let me make it clear that Sarah's not gonna marry anyone except Hammad!
They just want to burden you with their ageing parents!
They're using every trick in the book so they don't have to look after them!
You don't get brothers willing to take care of the entire family these days... It ain't easy for anyone...
We've rented the flat upstairs out.
For fifty thousand a month.
But I'm gonna ask the tenant to leave...
But I'm gonna ask the tenant to leave... For you.
Aunt... Uncle...
They were all...
Family...
When Dad was around...
But...
I can barely recognise...
What they've become...
Dad...
I never knew how much it mattered to have you around...
I was just close to my Mum...
Hello?
-I was thinking of you... Thought I'd ask you what you'd done about your Mum.
What's wrong with everyone? Out of nowhere... We're neck-deep in problems...
You or me?
What do you mean?
-Same here.
The entire blimmin' family's set up camp here. Talking about the strangest things... Demanding the strangest things...
I always knew we didn't have many people around us...
But after Dad's gone... I've come to see how hollow they can all be...
Same here...
The war between our nations has claimed many lives...
But much more importantly...
It's exposed cold-blooded blood ties.
Aye...
Absolutely...
I talked to one of Mum's friends...
She said she'll talk to Mum... But there's a truckload of issues between Mum and Granny...
And then there's this Aunt...
Dad's sister...
Her husband wants Granny to sell her estate and give them their share.
As in where you live?
-No, this place is ours...
Granny's got an estate she's rented out.
I've got my Aunts... In the UK and the US...
And my Uncle. He wants us to move to his place.
Mum, me, and my brother and sister...
He wants Granny and Grandpa to live with my Aunts...
Who don't want to keep them.
One lives with her in-laws... And the other doesn't have enough room for them.
Same here... More or less...
My Uncle thinks we're exploiting Granny, Mum and me...
So she can give us everything...
So she can live with us. Crazy, innit?
H -- He doesn't know...
That Mum's asking Granny...
To go to her place...
And I'm the only one who's stopping her...
I don't want to be away from Granny and Grandpa either...
I can't live without them... And I'm sure they can't live without us either...
You crying?
Vishal?
C'mon...
Sarah... Your Uncle's staying in my room, so me and the kids will be here with you.
-Yeah?
Where are you off to?
-Need some water...
Same here. The entire blimmin' family's set up camp here. Talking about the strangest things... Demanding the strangest things...
The war between our nations has claimed many lives...
But much more importantly...
It's exposed cold-blooded blood ties.
Who's Vishal?
Colonel Vijay Malhotra's son.
Are you telling me you call and talk to him?
Mum...
He's very worried...
In a mess...
More than us?
You've been nattering away with our enemy and you say he's worried?
I know he's the enemy...
But is he more hostile than those we hold dear?
His Mum's on drugs...
He's distressed...
Drugs?
They're in the same mess as us...
His Mum hasn't come to terms with his Dad's death.
His Aunt wants his Granny to sell her estate and give her her share.
His Granny doesn't want to be left with nothing and no one.
Our kind of mess through and through.
But... It's his Mum he's most worried about.
She's suicidal...
Did you tell him everything going on here?
Yeah...
Who did I have?
Who'd listen to me here?
Everything's gonna be alright...
This, too, shall pass...
It will...
But its memories...
Will come back to haunt us...
You're never talking to Vishal again. Okay?
I've got boys in my class...
I'm friends with some too...
It's the same with him... Just... Friends...
What's it matter, anyway?
We're enemies...
But don't they suffer all the same?
Who told you?
Vishal.
You asked him to get you some pills.
You're a doctor.
You know what they're gonna do to you.
I do...
You can't let yourself go like that.
What else can I do?
I've got this --
Thing --
Gnawing at me...
Burning me... Killing me...
These pills...
Soothe it...
They don't.
They just make it seem like it.
They just give you the hope that it's all a nightmare...
We can only run from it so far... And anyway -- Doing drugs?
Vishal's very upset.
I should not have asked him to get the pills... Why'd I even think --
You've got to stop taking them. They're killing you!
I can't...
I've been taking them for years...
What?
For years?
Why?
Ever since Vijay was deployed in Kashmir... His hardship post, you know...
I started taking these sedatives...
Because I used to have panic attacks... Anxiety...
Every soldier's wife dies in limbo... All day... All night...
I've lived all these years, fearing the call I got that day...
Every day, I've lived dreading bad news...
Vijay's call... Could make me sleep in peace... But... Anytime...
He couldn't take my call...
It felt like...
A noose around my neck...
There was this Captain whose wife used these...
That's how I started taking them...
Many soldiers' wives take these pills...
Their husbands put their lives on the line...
While we live on the brink here...
But you never told me... Talked to me about it...
Never thought you could share it with your friend...
No...
It's my dark secret...
No one knows about it...
Not even Vijay...
He didn't have a clue...
What could he do anyway?
Worry? Get furious?
But surely not understand it...
Anyway...
What's done's done... You got to stop taking them.
You're past that fear.
-Aye.
But there's this aching wound in me...
I need something to ease it...
The memories...
All around me... Gnawing...
I want an escape...
The echoes in my ears... Especially Vijay's...
'Hun'... That's what he used to call me...
'Hun'...
Look at your kids...
Pari...
Pari... Laxmi...
Pari... Laxmi... Vishal...
Everyone...
Everyone here needs you, Sunanda...
It ain't that hard to get over it all...
You just need to take a step...
Or it'll drive you crazy!
It's already driven me crazy!
You're my friend.
My best friend.
I won't let you destroy yourself like that...
I'll get you treated...
But you need to be strong.
Let me help you.
What'd your Uncle say?
-What?
He wanted you to move to his place... In Karachi...
Did he say anything about it?
Tell Mum to take a stand for herself... And us...
We can live without them - Uncle, Aunt...
If we can live without Sherali, we can sure as heck live without their lot!
And -- Aunt wants me for her son... Uncle wants me for his... I don't want to be caught in the crossfire...
You should've turned Aunt down the first time she said it.
How could I turn her down?
Everyone thinks of old men as dimwits...
Because he's helpless...
In need...
You're not helpless...
What makes you think so?
I've spent everything I've earned on my kids...
Their studies...
Weddings...
I never saved anything for myself...
I always thought...
I've got Sherali...
To support me as I grow old...
But now that we've got to spend...
At this point of our lives...
We've come to realise...
That we've got nothing...
Me and your Granny...
Nothing...
We can't even...
Get a cramped little shack...
In the middle of nowhere... Just for the two of us...
Where we could live...
The last of our days...
In peace...
That's why I want you to take a stand.
Why are we so helpless?
We can't live without you.
The Army's gonna provide us housing. That's all we need.
Talk to Mum. She'll listen to you.
Sarah...
Your Mum...
Is a woman like no other...
I don't want her to think...
That we're self-seeking...
That we care about ourselves...
But not your lives...
Our kind of mess through and through.
But... It's his Mum he's most worried about.
She's suicidal...
Serve lunch. And check on the cleaner... Where's he?
There's something...
I wanted to ask...
Yeah?
My sister's getting married... I'd need a bit of a leave...
How many days?
A month...
I've got to arrange everything... As I told you four months back...
You know what's going on here, Nawab...
Guests and all...
It'll be like this for a while...
I've got no choice...
I didn't want to leave right now either...
But her in-laws won't settle for another date.
Okay... You may leave...
Thank you so much.
I'll be back as soon as the wedding's done.
Thank you, Aunt Shefali...
It's nothing...
I've sorted it out...
I'm taking Sunanda to a psychiatrist... I've talked to one.
She'll be fine. She wants to be fine.
Just make sure...
Yeah?
That Sunanda doesn't get stressed or worried.
I hope you'll take care of her.
I'll get going.
-Thank you.
Hello?
Hello. I hope I didn't call at the wrong time.
I'm at school... Working on a diagram for my bio practical journal...
Which one?
The human heart...
Seriously?
You're laughing?
I wonder what kind of a heart you're drawing...
You were crying the other day...
-Jesus, you girls remember everything, don't you? Always ready to continue!
Why?
When you wanted to die...
I asked you why...
Remember?
You want to get even?
-Of course. We're enemies, aren't we?
It's only fair.
How's your Mum?
Thank you.
For?
You said I should talk to one of her friends.
I did.
Things are better now.
She's ready to see a psychiatrist.
I'm happy for her.
And... Mum's found out I talk to you.
How?
She was in my room that night... When you called...
And?
-She was angry...
She asked me never to talk to you again.
What'd you say?
I promised her I'll never talk to you again...
And... That's what I wanted to tell you...
But -- What's wrong with it? We can talk, can't we?
I can't disobey Mum... Can't disappoint her...
No -- I don't mean -- But -- Can I text you? Like now and then?
It's better if you don't. You'd have many friends... You'd hardly miss me.
Many friends, aye... But only one enemy.
Aye...
Same here...
Take care of your Mum...
And Pari, and Laxmi...
And...
Yourself...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5