♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 9 - 'For Honour'
Thermal properties are those properties of a material...
'Granny'
-Which are related to its conductivity of heat.
Which are related to its conductivity of heat.
In other words...
These are the properties that are exhibited by a material...
'Granny'
-These are the properties that are exhibited by a material...
When heat is passed through it...
'In class......'
-When heat is passed through it...
'In class...... Will call later'
-Thermal properties come under the broader topic of the physical properties of materials...
Thermal properties come under the broader topic of the physical properties of materials...
'Sarah'
-Thermal properties come under the broader topic of the physical properties of materials...
-Material with a high thermal conductivity at a constant temperature will conduct heat well both ways.
Material with a high thermal conductivity at a constant temperature will conduct heat well both ways.
That's the definition... Any questions?
Sir -- Loo... May I go to the loo?
Focus! Go.
Thank you.
Alright, and what about the light? Does that bother you?
Yeah, sometimes.
And you're saying it's only frontal -- Excuse me...
-Yeah...
Yeah, Mum?
Where's Vishal?
In class?
Yeah, of course --
But -- Oi called 'imself an' he didn't answer...
I'm sure he's just busy in class...
That better be it.
What happened?
Something you're hiding?
Hello?
I hope I didn't disturb you.
-You did.
I'm skiving off physics...
-What'd you say?
The classic. Works every time.
Don't tell me you said you're going to the loo.
Aye, had to... Can't wait 40 minutes to talk to you.
You can go back if you want... I've got another free period after this one.
-No, we can talk.
No, we can talk.
Hey...
Didn't you... Like my song?
I never knew you've got such a lovely voice.
You noticed it just now? We talk - like - everyday.
Dunno why, but... Never paid attention to it...
Why am I not surprised? Anyway, how was the shocker? My song?
A pleasant shock...
You're quite the singer.
Thank you.
I was worried you took offence at it...
I've been listening to it on repeat.
It ain't that good either...
But I'll get there...
I'll be waiting!
My Mum wants to talk to your Mum.
Why?
You know... About Nadir...
Can't believe it...
He's our successor...
We can do anything for him...
What about you?
-Aren't you Indian?
You know daughters don't count in this part of the world.
Aye, the male gilleans [laddies] gotta sacrifice everything...
Come again?
Could you not butcher Gaelic like that?
I mean, the boys gotta sacrifice everything.
Oh, really?
I'm sure they do... When the family's got no daughters!
I always thought the girls in Pakistan are born mute... They don't say a word...
Oops... And I always thought the boys in Pakistan don't have brains. Now I'm pretty sure it's the same in India. Utterly brainless lot.
Just say dimwits!
Not you.
I don't think it's that dim up there...
Glad there's something you like about me!
Muck...
Felt your collar?
Good luck...
Putting the 'out' in the 'outhouse', are we?
-N -- No -- I -- Got a call from my family...
Why? What do they want?
Well, sir --
Take your time, mate... Gimme your best excuse... Your Mum fell sick? Granny?
-No...
Listen here, kid... I heard her laugh myself...
-No, sir -- it's no one... You're mistaken --
You can check my phone... Here!
'Granny'? Gotta say that's creative, young man...
Lemme tell her you're gonna be a bit busy...
-Sir... Please...
Hello? Vishal? Where are you?
Good day... Are you Vishal's grandmother?
Aye.
What happened? He alright?
More than he should be...
Anyway, did you just call him?
Aye.
Just now...
I couldn't talk to him though...
Everything alright?
Yeah.
But you better tell this young man he's gonna disgrace the family if he kept on skiving off classes for random girls.
It was Granny, sir...
I can tell the difference between your Granny and your 'Granny', or should I say, your girlfriend!
And I heard what I heard! Don't you dare lie to me again. C'mon, now, back to class!
Who told you to start any of this?
Vijay always told you not to rent the estate to those politicians.
But no...
You always thought they're like us... They think like us...
Patriots and soldiers... Bound to get along...
Who could respect us more?
Couldn't have been more wrong, could you?
Oi didn't 'av de foggiest...
Never thought they'd be so... Janus-faced...
They bowed before us in respect...
Because your son - a serving officer - was alive...
You've lost him.
We're the fallen soldier's family!
Is dis 'oy dis nashun rises ter salute us...
For my son's sacrifice?
I don't know...
All I know...
Is I'm not gonna sacrifice my son for your estate.
They pay the rent or not, they leave the estate or not... It's your problem!
Keep Vishal out of this... He's not filing any complaint, or doing anything!
Just -- Tell Pratibha to call Anurag... He can do what he wants about it...
Hmph...!
I'm honestly starving... Mum?
Mum?
Nothing... I'll get you something... Go and change...
Did you tell her?
How d'you know?
But why? You know the professor was lying!
You're talking about the girl he mentioned?
Who're you skiving off classes for?
No -- Granny...
It's just... He saw your calls...
I got out of class to take them... He thought it's my girlfriend!
But you didn't take my call.
I did text you, remember?
Waaat text?
I didn't see it.
I got out of class to talk to you, but --
C'mon.
Okay.
-Go and change first. I'll get some water.
I'm a goner!
-God forbid...
Never say that again.
I'll go change.
What will we say?
Just tell them about Nadir's problem...
They may be able to help.
But how?
Can't know until we've talked to them.
Sherali was very close to their family.
Subuk's father's my friend.
We can tell them everything.
Where are they off to?
They're going to Subuk's - Dad's friend, remember? - to talk about Nadir.
But you said you're talking to Vishal's Mum.
I did... But any help would matter right now, yes?
I still remember our little Sherali...
Everything... Every moment... As if it were just yesterday...
Aye...
And like yesterday... It's all past us...
There's no day when we don't miss him...
It's the same with all of us...
He's made our Unit proud.
Thank the Lord, who's given him such worthy children.
By the way, where's Amna?
She's... In mourning...
Sherali was a straight-A* student...
Subuk and Sherali used to vie for the best scores...
May Nadir and Bilal continue their fathers' legacy...
I pray they both - though in different years - remain straight-A* students.
Bilal's been selected...
On merit...
He's going to the top boarding school here...
Bless him.
You've worked hard.
Anything for our kids.
But Bilal's a natural genius.
Just like his Dad.
I'm sure Nadir's the same.
Intelligence is inherited, after all, innit? That's what they all say.
Why don't you get Nadir into Aitchison too? I can help.
No...
We'd need him at our place...
We've got no one else...
Don't worry, Nasir Ali...
Nadir will make you just as proud - if not more - than Sherali. Straight A*s, I tell you!
Of course... He's been doing really well too...
-Bless him...
What'd Subuk say, Dad?
What could I tell him?
I couldn't dare say a word...
They think...
Sherali's son's as intelligent as him...
I didn't think it proper to talk to them about it...
Sherali always scored better than Subuk...
Sherali always stood first...
And Subuk, second or third...
When he said his son got into Aitchison... And a scholarship...
I had to say Nadir's doing no less...
That's when I knew we couldn't discuss Nadir's problem with them...
They know everyone around here...
I was worried word may get out...
But don't worry...
I'll get him a psychologist or teacher...
It was Sarah, wasn't it?
Yeah...
But -- First time I skived off class --
Sarah's Mum wanted to talk to you... You said you would...
Can't believe you care so much about them that you're worried about her Mum more than your studies!
You said you're gonna talk to her.
Don't you always listen to me like that?
Call them when it's okay. I'll talk to them.
-How about right now?
I mean -- It's still day...
Just half an hour behind Indian time...
So... Or anytime you pick!
Call her.
Jaysus, mate, it's a 'b', not a 'd'! 'Abacus', get it?
How many times do I have to tell you?
Sarah...
Get us some tea... I'll help him.
C'mon, show me your work...
Here.
Vishal.
Make it clear I don't want him calling our Sarah again!
It's on hands-free.
Hello?
Sarah... Mum wants to talk...
I'm Vishal's mother, Sarah...
Vishal said your mother needs some help... For Nadir?
Mrs Colonel Sherali here.
Can you hear me?
Of course... It's Mrs Colonel Vijay Malhotra.
Sarah told Vishal you needed some help for Nadir?
You asked Sarah to get some help?
It's Colonel Sherali Khan's father here.
In case it's not clear, we don't need any kind of help for Nadir.
Not least from our enemies!
You better tell your son to not call Sarah again.
-Grandpa...
I don't know about you, but we hold our head high in pride.
We don't need pity. Not from any of you.
We don't need pity, Grandpa...
There's a world of difference between helping and pitying...
Me grandson doesn't nade yisser granddaughter in 'is life!
-(Mum!)
Why don't yer ask 'er why she calls 'imself?
Is dat 'oy you've raised 'er?
(Just let Mum talk!)
Look... Whoever you are...
You better know that our Sarah's character is impeccable. If someone's been raised the wrong way, it sure ain't her.
You better tell your son not to call her every other minute.
Heard that?
You didn't have to say that, Mum...
Can't believe you're saying that, Sunanda!
Canny believe you're growin' so close ter me son's killers!
No one's growing close to anyone, Granny! Just... Being human...
Human...
Oh, yes indeed...
Don't yer dare blather aboyt 'umanity ter me!
Oi nu waaat you're up ter!
Get it?
Ain't yer two ashamed av yerselves?
Doesn't look like it.
You're Colonel Vijay Malhotra's family...
But yer dare stab me son in de back!
Never thought you'd ask his family for help!
After I told you we don't need anyone's help...!
What's wrong if I asked for their help?
-What's right about it?
Did you hear what that old lady said about us... And about you?
If you still think you should be asking me what's wrong about it, I'd just say...
Think about it when you're alone!
Mum? Who was talking about me? I heard my name...
Not you, love... It was someone else... Get your bag and come with me.
Vijay...
What happened, Mum?
Nathin' much, really!
Yer don't even fale sad, eh?
What?
I don't feel sad?
I'm his wife...
His widow...
Can't believe you're doubting my grief!
Then why in God's name are you talking to his killers?
They're all killers! They killed my son!
War killed him, Mum...
As it killed their son...
It hurts them all the same!
Can't believe you feel their pain!
You, of all the people...
You feel for them now, do you?
Yeah...
I do...
Looking at Pari and Laxmi...
I think of Nadir...
And, looking at Vishal...
I think of Sarah...
Orphaned...
Helpless...
All the same...
What've we got besides these hollow medals?
Everything else... Is gone...
I'm sure Sarah's grandparents call out to their son in the middle of the night too... They tear up at the mention of his name... Just like you...
They're broken too...
And his widow...
Would hardly be different from me...
Mourning, just like me...
I don't know how I can tell you, but...
I don't feel any anger for them...
But I wonder how you...
If Sherali were here, he would never have let it happen!
No idea what Amna and her girl are up to!
Asking Vijay Malhotra's family for help!
As if there's no one left in Pakistan who can help!
Never thought they'd stoop so low...
Why don't you say anything?
What?
-Do I need to tell you?
My blood is boiling!
I mean -- Just look at what your daughter-in-law's been up to!
Sarah's been making friends with him, and she's letting her!
All I see... Is a mother trying everything for her son...
What?
She's desperate...
She's trying anyth --
-Don't...
Don't you dare jump on their bandwagon!
You disappoint me!
You're just getting ticked off for no reason...
Didn't you hear what she said?
Remember what she said about Sarah?
What can I do?
D'you want me to start a shouting match with them? Stoop down to their - and your - level?
My level?
I'm talking about our honour!
Honour!
Honour...
That's all we've got left, innit?
Us...
And them...
Honour's all that's left...
When this bloodbath's consumed everything else...
Don't take me wrong, Mum...
I'm a mother too...
How could I take you wrong?
Unlike the men here...
I know what you were thinking...
Who do I ask for help? Who can help my boy with this... Thing?
I've never stepped out of the house...
The only thing I don't like about Sherali... Is how dependent he made me...
Get whatever help you can from the Colonel's wife.
I'll take care of Nasir.
You?
I've lost my son in the war...
I can't lose his son in this warmongering...
Where's Granny?
She didn't have her breakfast...
I gotta go, I'm getting late...
Talk to her for me, okay? You know what she's up to with this hunger strike...
Okay, bye.
-Okay...
Granny...
Blimey, that's some real fury!
-Waaat do yer care?
Waaat do yer care?
-I do! That's why I'm here!
Mum cares too...
Oh, you do?
Swear by me noggin dat yer or yisser Mamai are never gonna blather ter Sherali's family again!
Granny...
What good is it? Is it gonna bring Dad back?
If it can, I swear I won't.
Waaat do we care for dem? Why do we want ter blather ter dem?
We've got enoof on our 'ands withoyt yer two botherin' aboyt whatever's 'eadin' on in their lives!
I'm sorry, Granny...
But whatever you said didn't suit you.
They're a soldier's family... Just like us!
Is that how soldiers talk to each other?
Oi don't nu why, but...
Oi jist felt furious...
Yer nu 'oy anger clouds me mind!
Simple! How about you think again when you're cooled off? What's the big deal with talking to them?
Why do we talk to them after all these wars?
Because whoever wins, the cold shoulder loses!
Why do yer alwus blather loike yisser Mamai?
-I blather like Dad too!
You know he loathed war.
Remember what he'd say every time he'd lose one of his brothers in arms?
'We fire, they fire...'
'We kill, they kill...'
'It's gone on for decades past...'
'And many more, it will last...'
Isn't it time someone ended this blood feud?
I'll be waiting at breakfast...
Waiting for you...
She's left for work...
Proper row over here yesterday...
Your Granny shouldn't have said any of it...
It's hurt Grandpa and Granny... And me...
I wanted to say sorry for it... That's why I was trying your number all night...
You don't need to be sorry for anything. There was nothing you could do...
You just wanted to lend a hand...
But still, your Granny shouldn't have said it...
I tried to explain it... But she's old...
Old habits die hard... Old people change slower...
Aye...
So...
You gonna stop talking to me again...?
No idea...
Maybe... Yes...
Or, maybe not... No idea...
I'm so confused...
Why don't you stop calling me?
After everything at your place? Everything your Granny said to you?
I can't.
It'd be a different story if Dad were here...
He was very liberal...
He wouldn't mind my talking to an Indian...
Same here...
Dad would have no issues either...
But... If they were both here... I guess Granny would have no issues either...
Because... We wouldn't be sworn enemies like this?
I'll be getting my result anyday. Just pray I get selected!
May God help me fulfil Dad's dream...
I'll pray to God too...
But I wonder if it'll work...
No idea...
Isn't it time you got your result too? A-Levels and all? What are your aims?
Dad always wanted me to become a soldier... Like him...
If you ever joined the Army... Consider it the end of our friendship! Like, for real!
You blackmailing me?
Whatever you call it...
I can be friends with an Indian...
Even a soldier's son...
But not an Indian soldier...
No one here's gonna let me enlist...
Granny... Mum...
They're gonna need me here...
Man of the house, remember? I'm all they've got.
How 'bout you try...
Software engineering?
Why?
My laptop likes to act up at the wrong moments! Make yourself useful!
Wow, you're selfish.
Aren't you?
I've never asked anything of you.
Don't you dare, either! I hate boys who order girls around like that!
Oooh, that sounds like my Granny!
You're gonna be like her when you're old...
You know, a brutal, cruel, dangerous matriarch!
Okay, stop that comparison...
I really like your Mum...
I wish to become like her...
Not your Granny.
-Wait until you talk to her...
I don't want to.
I pray God cools you off by the time she cools off! Madame?
Can't say...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5