♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 15 - 'Compromises'
how was the exam ??
d
di
did
did y
did yo
did you
did you p
did you pr
did you pra
did you pray
did you pray f
did you pray fo
did you pray for
did you pray for m
did you pray for me
did you pray for me ?
All day.
i
it
it w
it wa
it was
it was a
it was a d
it was a do
it was a dod
it was a dodd
it was a doddl
it was a doddle
it was a doddle m
it was a doddle ma
it was a doddle mat
it was a doddle mate
so... officially engineer Vishal now ?
n
no
not
not s
not so
not so f
not so fa
not so fas
not so fast
It'd be an honour to have the late Colonel Sherali's daughter as our daughter-in-law.
I talked to Aunt Sofia the other day.
We're here to talk to you today.
We always wanted Cüneyt to marry into the family of a war hero. We hold the Colonel in the highest regard.
Thank you so much for this proposal...
But...
I don't want to get Sarah married off just yet...
Yeah, Aunt Sofia mentioned you'd rather she graduate first...
We've got no problem with it... She can get engaged now...
Sarah doesn't even want to think about it right now...
She wants to focus on her studies.
Besides...
She's too young...
I understand that kids don't like getting engaged young... We don't, either...
But we're here to honour Cüneyt's wish...
And we'd ask you to think about it...
Just once?
Maybe, if Sarah and Cüneyt met each other...?
We'd like to talk to Sarah first.
If she's okay with seeing him...
We'll let you know...
Sarah!
Hey!
Hey...
I didn't know you come here for a walk.
Just started a few days ago...
Me too.
By the way...
You're here alone?
My place ain't that far... So... I thought I'd come here for a stroll...
I'm on my way back.
Well... Guess what? Me too.
Come with me?
As a soldier... I like to get straight to the point...
There's something I wanted to say...
I'm sure you know what it's about.
If it's about your proposal, please don't...
I heard you don't want to get married just yet?
In fact...
You rejected the proposal?
May I know...
May I know why?
I'm the eldest daughter...
I've got responsibilities...
I can't take such a huge decision right now...
I can... Wait... If that's what --
I don't want to waste your time.
Your parents said they wanted to get you married ASAP.
When I hadn't met you, aye...
But I can wait...
For you...
Can you wait five years?
If you don't want to be a Captain's wife...
Would you like to be a Major's?
I don't want to be a soldier's wife...
A soldier's daughter...
Doesn't want to be a soldier's wife?
Odd.
I'm a martyr's daughter.
Perhaps it sounds less odd this way.
Martyrdom, Sarah...
Is a medal...
A badge of honour...
Make it your crown jewel and you won't grieve. Ever.
On the frontlines, you die once...
On the home front, we die everyday...
Being alive, yet not quite, like this... Turns any honour or medal into helplessness... And grief...
Anyway...
I'm glad...
Why?
You didn't reject me for someone else...
Who knows...
You may not have to worry about this tomorrow!
Cüneyt...
Anyway, forget it...
I think...
We ought to start off as neighbours...
And good friends...
We're home.
Bye.
See you soon.
He's nice...
Pleasant... Gentlemanly...
Grandpa and Granny have been cruel to him... And his family...
Why'd you reject his proposal then?
Told you, I ain't marrying a soldier.
You promised me you ain't joining the Army either.
Aye... Just pray...
What d'you mean? I've been praying for you all day. When d'you get your result?
You'll ace it, I tell you!
Soon...
Do -- D'you see him everyday? In the park?
-Aye.
We go for a stroll everyday... But we don't really talk much...
Mostly exchange 'Hi's... That's all...
Why?
You mind it?
N -- No -- Of course not...
Why'd I mind it?
You said he's pleasant...
Nice...
Cares for you...
Why'd I mind it...
If he's so nice?
By the way, you said you were worried. What is it?
It's sorted out.
How?
Just... Sorted out.
Bless yer... Yer luk nice... Young, if Oi may say so...
'Young' is stretchin' it...
The grub dees days... It takes a toll on yer...
Aye, roi...
All our lives, we've done everythin' ter take care av Mamai, Da, brothers, an' each other...
Dad used ter walk two miles every mornin'.
All 'is life.
But me...
My joints craic an' pop an' 'urt al' de time.
Have sum marmalade. It'll ease de pain.
Really?
Always worked for us.
We make lashings av marmalade! An' 'av it loike afters!
I'll ask Vishal ter git sum...
Not sure if we can git sum good marmalade the-day though...
Did Vishal git into university?
Aye.
We're waitin' for 'is result...
But oi'm confident 'e'll ace it.
Vishal...
Is jist loike Vijay...
Vijay never failed an exam. Ever.
Just loike Sherali.
He did everythin' on 'is own...
We barely knew aboyt 'is exams an' al'...
He'd tell us... Whaen 'e'd git 'is result...
They say boys are a 'assle...
You nade ter keep an mince pie on dem...
But Vijay wus never a 'assle...
Sherali...
Always listened ter me...
Ever since 'e lef us... We've been... Uneasy... Troubled...
Aye...
Our kids are who we live for...
-Absolutely...
'E's de only wan oi 'ad...
My son-in-law is so greedy... So greedy...
God forgive 'im...
I canny even tell yer waaat a 'assle 'e's been after Vijay's death!
Gud Lord...
I can understan'...
We've done everythin' for our kids al' our lives... But we've got nathin'... Naw wan...
An' ter tink... We wouldn't be cryin' loike dis...
For our lost sons...
If our nashuns did not fight dees bleedin wars al' de bleedin time!
War killed dem... An' us...
Aye...
Why'd you have to talk about any of this?
Couldn't you talk about something good?
You're crying too...
You're making her cry too...
Mrs Malhotra...
Please...
Talk all you want about Kathiya Wala Bazaar... Or the woods of Amritsar...
Or the river Jhelum...
But...
Let's not talk...
About those we've buried...
And those...
You've cremated...
Hey.
You stopped coming here in the morning because of me!
No... I just ain't that regular... I come here when I feel like...
It's quite reassuring, you know... That it's not because of me...
Anyway...
This is for you.
What's this?
-A stethoscope keychain. Caught my eye in a shop, I thought I'd get it for you.
A stethoscope keychain. Caught my eye in a shop, I thought I'd get it for you.
Wonder what'd you like. A gun keychain?
No.
One like the Victoria Cross would do.
Ma'am...
-Hmm?
Got this letter.
-Who sent it?
No idea.
Thank you.
What's this?
You're not joining the Army!
I don't have a choice, Mum...
You lied to me?
You dare lie to me?
Mum...
You sat the exam, cleared your medical check-up, and you didn't even tell me!
Your Granny knew this...
Your Granny knew this, didn't she?
-Aye...
You're her grandson... But my son!
I've got no one else...
She's got no one else too...
What d'you want?
D'you want me to end up like her one day?
Yeah?
I can give you everything...
I can give you the security you were looking for...
I can't lose my son...
For some security...
I turned that proposal down... Because you promised me...
And -- I will keep it, Mum... I can fix everything, Mum...
In that case, don't join the Army.
I can't live without you, Vishal...
Mum...
Who says I'll end up like Dad? Millions join the Army... Not all of them get killed in action.
The only one who ever mattered was from our family...
The widow he left behind was your Mum...
The orphan... You!
Are you seriously telling me that not everyone ends up like that?
How are you so sure it won't be you?
Please, Mum... Please!
Vishal...
I did...
Just as you said...
You've got to listen to me this time!
-No...
I've always done as you said... Always will...
But... This is something...
I've chosen for myself...
If we want to live...
We must live with honour.
And honour...
In this part of the world...
Means power...
Then -- Join the bureaucracy -- The Civil Service or something...
I need the power that comes with a uniform!
A uniform that makes lions of men...
That all? Your reason?
Is that all the Army is to you? Seriously?
The only thing Vijay...
And your Grandpa cared about...
When they joined the Army...
Was the nation... They loved it with their lives...
They honoured their vows to the nation in death...
I don't have just one reason.
I've got many more.
No, Vishal! No!
Mum...
Why'd you have to betray me?
I did everything...
For the honour of the family...
How much more blood will it take to satiate this 'honour' of yours?
What d'you want?
D'you want me to go through everything you're going through?
I've lost my husband...
My world...
My life, as I knew it...
Was gone...
You want something to happen to Vishal... So I'm gone for good!
-God forbid...
Don't say it...
What's it matter?
If something happened to him... Sunanda won't be able to live without him...
Please... Stop him, Mum... I beg you...
Please...
Stop him...
He's not just my son...
He's your grandson too...
He's Vijay's son... Vijay lives on through him...
Please... Stop him... I can't live without Vishal... Please...
Please...
Stop him...
He's all we've got left... We can't lose him...
Granny!
Where's Nawab?
Getting the groceries...
He didn't leave anything for me... I'm knackered... And starving!
He made some kebabs... Let me have a look...
Jesus, it's right here, in front of you!
You don't see anything, do you?
Not when I'm hungry...
Vishal got into university...
Who told you?
Vishal's Granny. We talked yesterday.
I'll ask him...
He didn't even tell me!
Hey! Don't forget to send him some sweets!
We'll be even.
Just a sec.
Hello?
Way to go, mate.
What is it?
What d'you mean?
You got your result. Got selected. But you didn't even tell me!
Who told you?
Your Granny told my Granny, of course.
What?
Don't take me for a ride. You got into engineering college and you didn't even bother to tell me!
Just found out today...
-You're so mean...
You always come to me for prayers... I'm sure you've told Neha already though.
Jesus, however did you think of her?
-Just did...
I didn't like it...
But I'm not angry.
Congratulations.
You can hack into my computer now.
That's the most I can do...
You don't sound too happy...
Didn't you get into the university of your choice?
No...
Well... That explains the silence...
Anyway...
Big deal... Once you're done... Go for a Masters... You're so bright. What've you got to worry about?
Misfortune...
Why are you so upset? Is it that bad? The uni you got into.
Which uni did you get into, by the way?
Forget it... I've compromised...
It's always good, innit? To compromise...
You asking me or telling me?
How 'bout both?
Why are you upset if you've compromised?
It's gonna be good for you.
Good for me...
Aye...
Where's Mum?
In her room...
She hasn't had anything...
Don't worry... She will...
Hello?
Your new number, is it, Vishal?
I'm his mother...
Oh... Aunt...
Everything alright?
For now...
Can't be so sure about tomorrow...
What d'yo -- Vishal's okay, right?
I...
I need your help...
I'm all ears...
I'll do what I can...
Right now, you're the only one who can stop Vishal from joining the Army...
Please... Stop him...
What? He's joining the Army?
No -- He got into Engineering... Didn't he?
Who told you?
-He and his Granny.
They lied to you.
He's been selected in the Army.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5