The shelling's getting worse, sir!
Pakistan fans, you need 136 more runs to win...
India putting up a fantastic show...
In the air, and Sreesanth takes it!
-Yeah!
-Woo hoo!
I hate cricket!
Terrorist attack in Jammu and Kashmir...
We've reason to believe there's still one terrorist in...
India made them pay.
-India can't get away with it.
Dad was a brave man. He stopped the enemy in their tracks.
My Dad said everything we've got to say to Sarah Sherali's Dad.
The children of two martyrs face off...
We're enemies, aren't we? My Dad... Because of your bloody old man!
Our enemies would do well to remember that it won't end with one Vijay Malhotra.
Your old man's responsible for everything we're going through!
You cut the Paki down to size!
Good show, m'boy! Way to put that girl in her place!
Not fair, Papa...
Sarah?
Alright?
No...
Out of nowhere... We're neck-deep in problems...
You or me?
You're not as bad as on the telly.
You're not as bad as I thought either.
The war between our nations has claimed many lives...
But much more importantly... It's exposed cold-blooded blood ties.
You've been nattering away with our enemy and you say he's worried?
Don't they suffer all the same?
You're a good man, Vishal...
We're sworn enemies, Vishal! Never forget that!
We kill a few, they kill a few!
Don't even think about her!
It's gone on for decades past, it'll go on for decades more... Isn't it time someone ended this blood feud?
'The Wall of Sunshine'
♪ Sarah... Please don't be mad... ♪
♪ Or... India and Pakistan will be very sad... ♪
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5
♪ Sarah, Sarah, Sarah...! ♪