♪ Every promise, every vow, every oath, ♪
♪ Everything just snapped... ♪
♪ Heart and soul mine, cry both, ♪
♪ In this life, trapped... ♪
♪ I'm whiling away sleepless nights ♪
♪ And restless days, ♪
♪ Searching for you in the dark anights, ♪
♪ Hoping to see you through the haze... ♪
♪ Who's gonna stop these tears from falling? ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
♪ There's just this wall, ♪
♪ Just this wall, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, ♪
♪ That's betwixt us, standing tall... ♪
Episode 14 - 'Family Across the Frontier'
Where in Amritsar did your Dad live?
Wonder why you're suddenly thinking of Amritsar...
I talked to Vishal's Granny.
His Grandpa was from Amritsar...
Why'd you talk to her at all?
Just... Saying hello... Thanked her for the sweets...
She mentioned Amritsar somewhere in-between...
You two didn't have to start talking about Amritsar and Jhelum...
How d'you know I said anything about Jhelum?
I'm sure you've found something to rekindle old ties...
'Rekindle old ties'...
Her in-laws were from Jhelum...
All those TV dramas are damaging your brains!
Blimey, her fluent Punjabi though...
She told me a lot about Amritsar... A lot that reminded me of everything your Mum and Dad used to say...
Kathiya Wala Bazaar! That's where Mum and Dad lived, remember?
She mentioned it many times!
And Dogurji Chowk!
What's this Dogurji Chowk thing?
Dad never even mentioned it! Not once!
Anyway... I've heard of Kathiya Wala Bazaar myself...
Shoba's Dad ran a furniture shop there!
Your Dad worked with him, yes?
Aye!
He's the one who supplied the wood!
Sofia!
Leaving me in the middle of a conversation is --
Ab
Abso
Absolutely
Absolutely despicable!
She said she'll send a few pictures of Jhelum...
Including the place by the river where Vijay's grandparents lived...
She knows every place there...
Every place...
I've only heard about from his Grandpa...
Granny...
Can't believe you're so close now...
I mean, you were barely ready to talk!
♪ I'm close to them? ♪
Ah wait, Oi exchanged sweets, roi?
Vijay's Grandpa used to sit by the river...
Writing poems...
Vijay's Grandma told me...
When the land was divided...
And he had to leave the city...
He was crying all the way 'ere...
By the way...
Mr Nasir Ali's from Amritsar too...
His family...
Had to leave their home too...
Both Sherali's Grandpa...
And my Dad...
Used to work in the Bazaar...
Jesus Christ... They talked for an hour... At least!
I thought you said she doesn't say one more word than needed? But... Whoa...
I've never seen Granny talk to anyone else like she did to your Granny...
By the way, why'd your Granny have to mention the sweets?
What? She told her?
-Aye...
Your Granny must've been furious... I hope she didn't say anything...?
No... She did mention it though...
I'm sure she's gonna tell Grandpa too...
My Granny would've told Grandpa everything... If he were with us... Like she just told us at the dinner table...
That my Grandpa's Dad... Used to write... And sing...
By the banks of the Jhelum...
Guess I'm like him...
I'm attending a wedding tomorrow.
-Really?
Where?
Our neighbours'. Their daughter's getting married. We've been invited.
Nice change for your family.
Mum ain't going... But Grandpa and Granny might...
When do your classes start?
In a few days...
Okay... By the way...
Don't forget...
To send me some pictures.
What'd you do with them?
-Nothing... Just -- Have a look?
Check out how weddings are over there.
I'll play it a bit louder... How 'bout you sing this time?
♪ My love, look up at the stars, ♪
♪ -My love, look up at the stars, ♪
♪ Recounting through the memoirs ♪
♪ -Recounting through the memoirs ♪
♪ A tale so odd, so bizarre, ♪
♪ -A tale so odd, so bizarre, ♪
♪ A tale that's vaguely like ours... ♪
♪ -A tale that's vaguely like ours... ♪
♪ Bless you, yea, you ♪
♪ -Bless you, yea, you ♪
♪ You shine bright in someone's eyes... ♪
♪ -You shine bright in someone's eyes... ♪
♪ It's someone very close to you, ♪
♪ -It's someone very close to you, ♪
♪ Though none will ever realise...! ♪
♪ -Though none will ever realise...! ♪
Thank you so much for coming here... Please, take a seat inside... Thank you!
Hey!
-Hey.
I'm glad you all came here...
But -- Where's the others?
Granny will be here in a moment...
I got here with them because they were ready.
I didn't expect to see you here.
Why?
Just --
Anyway... Come in, I'll introduce you to my sister. C'mon.
Meliha! Our neighbour, Sarah.
Hey!
-Hiya!
I live nex --
-Sarah, daughter of Colonel Sherali?
Yeah, how'd you --
-Cüneyt told me everything about you.
They came over, aye.
-No, he mentioned you before.
Okay, Meliha... You wanna tell her everything right now?
She's her guest... Why don't you show her inside?
Come in.
C'mon.
The date of your Ability Test...!
Can't hide it from Mum now...
♪ Shrug... ♪
♪ Take a good long chug... ♪
♪ Oh yeah! (Everybody!) ♪
♪ Oh yeah! ♪
♪ -Yeah! (Everybody!) ♪
♪ -Yeah! ♪
♪ Oh yeah! ♪
♪ -Yeah! (Everybody!) ♪
♪ -Yeah! ♪
♪ -Yeah, cut a rug, ♪
♪ Oh yeah! ♪
♪ Yeah, cut a rug, ♪
♪ Give your worries a shrug ♪
♪ Take a good long chug, ♪
♪ And shake a leg, fellas! (Everybody!!!) ♪
♪ Everybody! ♪
♪ Shake a leg! ♪
♪ Let's go! ♪
I hope you're not getting bored here!
♪ She's got the moves, aye, ♪
Not at all! You're quite the dancer, by the way!
♪ Ain't got no time to shy, ♪
You're embarrassing me... I mean... If they didn't force me... What's a soldier got to do with... These things?
♪ Come shake a leg with me, get high... ♪
♪ I ain't got a care, ♪
C'mon! On the dance floor!
♪ I got my eyes fixed on her, there... ♪
♪ Imma get my dancing doll today! ♪
♪ (Way to go!) ♪
♪ Yeah, cut a rug, ♪
♪ Give your worries a shrug ♪
♪ Take a good long chug, ♪
♪ And shake a leg, fellas! (Everybody!!!) ♪
Blimey, she's real lovely.
Have you talked to someone already?
Not yet...
She's too young... Still studying...
I got Meliha engaged in her first year. Now that she's got a house job, we're getting her married.
I would've gotten her married earlier... If her man had not been out of the country for higher studies.
-Great. Yeah...
She can study all she wants after her marriage.
That's all ?
Isn't it enough already?
isn't it enough already
i don't see you... where are you ??
you just asked for some pictures .....
didn't say i gotta be in them
okay,
okay, i ll say it .
okay, i ll say it . Send me your best pic.
'P'
'Pl'
'Ple'
'Plea'
'Pleas'
'Please'
WOW
You look ....
your text looks incomplete .....
I beg to differ ......
I don't really have words...
To discribe how beautifull you are...
♪ Everybody! ♪
♪ Shake a leg! ♪
♪ Let's go! ♪
♪ She's got the moves, aye, ♪
♪ Ain't got no time to shy, ♪
♪ Come shake a leg with me, get high... ♪
How was it?
Lovely.
Cüneyt's father asked about you.
He wanted to come and get you... But I stopped him.
Aye...
He called me...
I'll be there at the party tomorrow...
Cüneyt's mother proposed Cüneyt's marriage to Sarah.
Sarah?
She just got into college!
Aye. That's what I told her too.
She said she got her daughter engaged when she'd started college too...
She doesn't mind waiting.
We're not marrying Sarah to a military man.
Who knows what may...
That's what I thought...
So, I didn't talk about anything else...
Cüneyt's really nice though.
I don't want my girl to live my kind of life...
I want her to study...
She won't be a liability...
If - God forbid - anything ever happened...
She won't be dependent...
You're right...
We got Ayesha and Rabia married off too early...
If we'd let them study...
They wouldn't have been suffering at the hands of their husbands and in-laws...
I don't really have words...
To describe how beautiful you are...
Aye, Vishal?
Got these at the traffic light...
You know I love their fragrance...
Oh, yes... Dad used to get you these... And put them on you himself...
That's all... Long gone...
I'll get you your flowers...
In a few years... For your wife... Sure...
Not sure if you're even gonna remember how much I like them then...
I never forget anything, Mum...
Anything you say or ask me to do...
By the way, you're back late...
Yeah... Busy day today...
Too many patients...
I went to the hospital to surprise you...
But they said you'd left...
Must've been -- When I went over to a friend's...
I saw you with someone in the cafeteria on my way out.
Who was he?
About time...
I told you...
He's an old friend... Raj...
He knew Dad too...
He's proposed to me...
I wasn't even thinking --
But -- He's not taking a 'no'.
Vishal...
My life's been very lonely...
With your Dad...
And now without...
With all my insecurity...
Having someone with me...
To be honest... It felt really...
Nice... Comforting...
But -- Before I decide anything...
I'd ask you -- Pari -- Laxmi...
-No... Mum -- No...
No.
No... Don't do this...
I...
I don't want to lose anyone after Dad... No -- Please...
What will I tell my friends?
How can I face the world?
I -- I know it's been hard on you...
But -- You've got me...
I'll do as you say -- I promise...
But please... Don't do this...
Please, Mum... No...
Okay, park it right here...
Thank you so much! For all of this...
Anytime, Uncle...
It's my duty...
Thank you.
Hey...
You didn't attend the wedding?
Just a bit busy, you know... Sorry!
I was waiting...
In fact, everyone was waiting...
I'll be there at your wedding.
No way you can miss mine...
He's an old friend... Raj...
He's proposed to me...
Hello?
Where were you? I've been calling for ages!
Sorry...
I wasn't in my room.
What happened?
You don't sound okay...
Nothing...
Just... Not really feeling myself...
Lemme guess. Something happened there. Because of me.
Not you...
There's a lot else to worry about...
You can still tell me if you like...
There's things...
I can't even tell myself...
Telling me... May help?
You don't hide anything from me...
I'll tell you...
But not today...
The pics were lovely, by the way. I was looking at them...
Even in your worry?
That's when I miss you the most...
When I'm worried...
You didn't send me the pictures of the wedding today though.
I --
I wasn't there...
Why?
Something -- Came up...
What?
He...
Sent a proposal for me...
Who?
The neighbour's son...
The Captain...
It was his sister's wedding...
A -- And?
And his Mum talked to Granny. Granny likes him, but...
We'd rather not want me married to a soldier...
Have you met him?
Aye... A couple of times...
He dropped Granny and Grandpa home today.
He asked why I wasn't there.
He's nice...
Good-looking... Pleasant...
In fact, he even knows about our row... I don't really remember, but... He said he wrote a lot of comments...
What's his name?
Cüneyt.
Is he there in the pics?
Maybe...
He was on the dance floor.
Why d'you ask?
N -- I -- No, I ain't asking --
I don't want to marry a soldier, Vishal...
I want to live a normal life...
Not die everyday like your Mum and mine...
I don't want to be uncertain every waking moment...
I want my husband to come back home from work every evening.
I don't want to send him off to conflict zones or exercises for months...
Why are you quiet?
What's your ideal man like?
I mean...
What kind of a man would you like to marry?
Someone...
Who's a good friend... Kind... Gentle...
Someone with a lot of patience! Enough to listen to everything I say...
Someone who understands me... Someone who can feel my pain...
Sounds like me.
I'm kidding...
We can have a Turkish together, can't we?
Of course...
You can't be serious... Seriously...
Aye...
Seriously...
What's your ideal girl like?
What'd you look for in a girl?
I'd like...
Someone lovely...
Doe-eyed...
With silky long tresses...
Someone who, decked up for a party...
Would take my breath - and words of praise - away...
Whose enchanting smile would make me want to make that moment stay forever...
Whose tears I'd like to line on my fingertips...
Like pearls dripping from the oceans of her eyes...
And never let go...
Someone who can share anything with me... Someone who'd like to know my deepest secrets...
Someone who'd love to have a tiff...
Who'd be cross with me...
Who I'd try make up to...
Whose words...
Are as sweet as honey...
And whose bitterness...
I'd drink like a heavenly nectar...
Well, good luck... I doubt you're ever gonna find her...
What if I said I've found her?
You didn't tell me...
Why don't you look for her yourself?
You know me inside out.
Hello?
I can't hear you, Vishal...
-Hello?
Hello?
-I'm losing the signal...
I'm losing the signal...
Hello? Sarah?
Cüneyt's a proper nice lad...
Everytime I see him...
He reminds me of Sherali...
Aye...
He's a real gentleman...
A good kid from a nice family...
His Mum talked about Sarah again.
We don't get to decide that.
It's Sarah's decision. And Amna's.
-But still...
We can tell them what we think...
-Of course.
But... I'm troubled...
Amna was right...
Sarah...
Shouldn't marry a military man...
No idea why...
But when I see Cüneyt...
It feels like Sherali's back...
I'd like someone lovely...
Doe-eyed...
With silky long tresses...
Someone who, decked up for a party, would take my breath - and words of praise - away...
Whose enchanting smile would make me want to make that moment stay forever...
Whose tears I'd like to line on my fingertips...
Like pearls dripping from the oceans of her eyes... And never let go...
Someone who'd love to have a tiff...
Who'd be cross with me...
Who I'd try make up to...
Whose words are as sweet as honey...
And whose bitterness I'd drink like a heavenly nectar...
It ain't me...
It can never be you, Sarah...
Our faiths divide us...
As does a border...
It's a wall neither can vault...
This him? Cüneyt?
How'd you know?
He's an enemy...
My enemy... How could I miss him?
Pray for me, okay?
Pray I do well on the test...
Ye tell Sunanda?
Not yet.
Anyway... I'm getting late... I'll get going...
God bless yer. Good luk.
Granny...
Hmm?
If you...
Talk to Sarah's Granny...
Don't tell her, okay?
I don't want her to know I'm joining the Army.
Why?
I've told her...
I got into engineering school...
Okay...
Helloo
Pray for me, will you..? Got an important exam today....
Always prayin'... which university, by the way...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5
You're the only one who can stop Vishal from joining the Army...
No -- He got into Engineering, didn't he?
They lied to you.
Why'd you make promises you can never keep?
Life forces you into things you never want to do...
You didn't want me to join the Army... But now, you've gotten engaged to a soldier...
You started it...
And you're gonna end it...