My eyes are filled with nectar
What will you do after your F.A.?
B.A.
And then?
A job.
That's it?
Nothing else?
Hand over my first paycheck to Mum and --
Your tea's getting cold.
I've lost myself
The shadow of love falls on the courtyard of my mind
These days and nights don't while away
For you have robbed me of all serenity
Your love changes like the seasons!
Thus I sacrifice myself before you
I have begun to despise love!
Not love; you despise me.
My mind pirouettes, my body pirouettes
In the guise of love, woe pirouettes
He who falls in love pirouettes every moment
My body pirouettes
My mind pirouettes
Behold! With what artful beauty the sorrowful secret conceals itself
The arrow has struck my heart, behind the curtain the bowman conceals himself!
These eyes speak the truth
These eyes have never seen someone like you
Days and nights I have spent wide awake
For separation from you has devours me like poison
Thus I sacrifice myself before you
I have never loved you!
But I have!
My mind pirouettes, my body pirouettes
In the guise of love, woe pirouettes
He who falls in love pirouettes every moment
I've lost myself
The shadow of love falls on the courtyard of my mind