I didn't expect this from you, Meryem.
You didn't behave well with Alam Sir.
He'd come to your place to ask forgiveness.
And when you were ready to forgive him on my insistence
Why was all of this necessary?
You're complaining to me?
What did you want?
That I treat show my hospitality and cordiality towards him?
Beat drums on the occasion of his gracing us with his presence, or
Shower flowers on him as he walked in?
No...
I don't have so kind a heart.
Whatever happened to his sister
Had nothing to do with me.
God has had him reap the reward
Of the seed of hatred he had sown.
He has gone through his share of the punishment.
You shouldn't have insulted him like this.
Insult?
Were it not for your sake,
I would never have forgiven in this life
That wretched man for ruining my life
And snatching from me my parents.
On Judgement Day, in God's own court,
I would've grabbed him by the collar,
And pleaded before God
To give him the harshest punishment.
But
You have stopped me from despising him.
Go, Jan'e Alam!
Meryem forgives you!
I forgive you!
Thank you, Meryem.
By forgiving me today,
You have spared me my life.
Come in.
Shani, come here.
Sorry, mate...
Something came up, and I had to leave.
All the burden must've fallen on you.
It's okay.
So, did everything go well?
The 'something' that came up?
Yes...
Everything's been done today, at long last...
Although I didn't expect it to be so easy...
Perhaps Mum's prayers have had their effect...
They've made this impossible task
So easy.
Yes.
It lingers on, lingers on
This dolorous, damned life
It was Mum's prayers
That
Got us where we are.
But now,
She's no longer with us.
Her prayers
It lingers on, lingers on
This dolorous, damned life
Could stop every trouble coming for us,
But now, we've got to face them all.
My Master...
No, Shani...
Mum may not be with us,
But she's not so distant either.
Her memories
Live in our hearts forever.
Forever.
My Master...
You'd gone to Murree?
Yes, I'd --
Gone there, who told you?
Khurram told me.
He saw you there.
Oh --
I'd gone to drop Malik.
He lives there.
Alright... So that was it.
When did he shift there?
It's been a few days since he shifted to Murree from Karachi.
Okay.
You could've asked me; I'd have dropped him.
Or sent the driver.
-No way, mate.
It was the least a friend could do.
Thank you.
Get some sleep; it's late.
The day must've tired you.
Fear a trothful heart
Do nothing malapert
Its beats
Never trample underfoot
You should get some rest too.
Those who shatter it
Are shivered into shards by it
For this heart is not merely a heart
It is the abode of God
Love was a debt unto you
To return that was an obligation unto you
What happened? What are you thinking?
Nothing, mate...
Did Meryem call or message you to convey her condolences?
She sent in a message.
But not her condolences.
What, then?
She doesn't want to marry me.
What?
But she'd agreed to it. What happened?
No idea, mate...
Strange. If she didn't want to marry, why did she agree to it?
You'd taken Aunt to meet her,
Perhaps that may explain why she refused?
What do you mean?
Perhaps Aunt had said something that she didn't take nicely?
No way --
Nothing like it...
She didn't say any such thing.
In fact,
Mum liked Meryem very much; she was chuffed to meet her.
I can't imagine why she'd refuse so suddenly, then.
Mum had
Taken Meryem to another room to talk about something.
What?
I don't know, I
Was sitting outside.
Perhaps it was then...
But no,
If it had been something then,
Meryem would've reacted to it
When she came back.
But she was normal.
Perhaps Meryem didn't want to show it to you,
But something might've been said then,
Which made Meryem reject your proposal.
No, I don't think so...
If Mum had wanted to say no,
She'd have said so before me.
I wouldn't have questioned her decision.
Perhaps Aunt didn't want to hurt you?
So, she said something to Meryem so that she would say no instead.
Anyway, leave it.
Don't get yourself all worried.
Ask her when you meet her.
Resolve this matter.
No, mate...
I've blandished and pleaded to her as much as I could.
I can't convince her now.
But at least talk to her once --
-No. That's enough.
I've taken my decision,
And I don't want to think about it too much now.
Thank you, Hammad,
For standing by us in these trying times.
What are you saying!
I'm not an outsider.
Right.
You're family now.
Have your dinner.
What happened, Shani? Is everything alright?
Yeah. All good.
Why are you so quiet? Have your dinner.
Yes --
I've decided
After Mum's fourth [end of mourning], I'll get you married.
What?
Shani's marriage?
But --
To whom?
There's a girl
That Monsieur here likes.
To her.
Shani?
Why didn't you tell me?
No...
It's nothing like that.
And I'm in no mood to get married right now.
What happened to him?
No idea.
You destroyed, piece by piece,
All my hopes and dreams
In but a moment
Shattered my heart into pieces
From you, I got
Nothing but such contumelies
As those that left on me
Ineradicable smirches
My love bears witness
Listen, my duplicitous dear,
Watch, now, as God makes His move
What's the matter, Shani? What happened?
Nothing.
Something's not right.
Why are you so suddenly refusing to marry
The girl you'd wanted to marry?
I'm not interested.
What do you mean, you're not interested?
There must be a reason for this.
What happened?
You cannot avoid me like this, Shani.
Tell me what has happened.
Why are you rejecting the girl
Whom you were so eager to get married to just until yesterday?
She's rejected the proposal; I have not.
What?
Yes.
She sent in a text
That she doesn't want to marry me.
But why? There must be a reason.
I don't know.
Then ask her, know the reason from her.
I would have, sure.
If, at the very least, she'd conveyed her condolences at Mum's death.
All my friends came to convey their condolences, and those who didn't called to excuse themselves.
But
She didn't think for once
That she should convey her condolences?
What kind of a life partner will be one who's not even with me in this great sorrow of my life?
She may have some problem of her own...
Yes.
She does have a problem.
Her problem's that she's raving mad.
She's insane.
What have I not done for her?
But she thinks I'm characterless.
I want to marry her; that's why I took Mum to meet her.
You had said she
Loves you?
I was mistaken!
I was wrong to have trusted her.
Shani, this is no way to start this journey.
Give each other some time,
It ain't no joke, mate.
Saying yes today and no tomorrow.
That's what I'm saying.
But who'll tell her?
Don't worry.
Take me to her tomorrow.
I'll explain to her; I'll talk to her for you.
No; there is no need. I've decided now.
Shani?
I'm your elder brother.
Had it been Mum in my place,
She'd have gone to her to talk about it for you.
Do you know... Mum liked her very much.
Who told you?
She said it herself.
I had a conversation over the phone with her the night she was coming back from your place.
She was delighted, she had
Liked the girl very much.
But that --
-Shani, I'm your elder brother.
I'll never think of something that's bad for you.
Take me to her tomorrow
And I'll talk to her for you.
Have some sleep; it's getting late.
Every bit of mine afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
My life is now ruined
O Lord
Decide my fate
Hear my prayer
Here we are! Come.
She lives here?
Yes.
She lives here.
Meryem.
My Master...
Shall we?
Hold!
What happened?
Come on.
You're so anxious as if we're bringing your proposal.
We've come for mine.
C'mon.
Watch, now, as God makes His move
Your tea.
Have your tea; I'll see.
Who is it?
This heart is its own nemesis
It ruins its life
Someone wants to meet you.
O Lord! Sap away my life
Come.
My Master...
Master...
Will you -- keep us waiting here or let us in?
Who is it, Meryem?
I'm Malik.
Malik who?
He's an old friend.
P -- please, come in.
I have heard the skies
Have rained all night
But it is that city that has remained athirst
Sit.
On you shall descend one day
The wrath of the Heavens
Obloquies yours
Shall resound in this world
Ashes yours
Shall be blown away with the winds
Dead ends shall you find
In your room in every heart
Recompense for my pain
Is my perseverance
Watch, now, as God makes the next move
Meryem, get some tea for our guests...
It lingers on, lingers on
Isn't he the same friend
Who'd come to pay a visit the other day?
He's my brother.
Released from prison just a few days ago.
Brother...
-Yes --?
You'd come here to talk about something --
I -- What?
About... My marriage?
Yes...
This heart is its own nemesis
Talk -- to whom?
What do you mean, talk to whom?
You'd come to talk to Meryem, of course.
It ruins its life
Now that Meryem's brother is with us...
Malik, I --
I wanted to ask if you'd --
If you'd --
Give my brother your sister's hand in matrimony...
How strange!
You're asking for my hand in marriage?
I've rejected the proposal.
Hasn't he told you?
He did.
He told me.
I --
I have come here to convince you myself --
To think about your decision again.
My brother is very good.
He'll keep you happy.
And what do you think?
I'd change my decision on your insistence?
Never.
I've already told you that I do not want to marry you.
Why do you not understand?
I will not marry you.
And this is my final decision.
You may please show yourselves out.
We have no interest in a girl like you for him either!
Shani, let's go!
-Erum! Sit down!
Erum! I'm asking you to sit down!
Shani, she's not a suitable girl for you.
Brother's engagement was broken because of her, and that's why he's still all alone!
Tell me
Aren't you the same Meryem?
Speak up! Aren't you the same Meryem?
Yes.
I am the same Meryem.
There! Did you hear that? I told you!
Come, Shani!
Erum!
My Master...
You may leave too!
I don't know
What to apologise to you for...
Perhaps destiny wills it
That I atone for my sins myself.
I'd ruined your life, hadn't I?
Thus it falls on me to rebuild...
Accept my brother...
As much I despised you,
So much love I have seen in Shani's eyes for you.
He's so innocent... He loves you so much.
Don't punish my brother for my sins.
Accept my brother...
My Master...
You have a problem with me, so --
After your marriage, I'll leave for somewhere far away from you.
You won't ever see my face again.
But please,
Don't rob my brother of his happiness.
On you shall descend one day
The wrath of the Heavens
Obloquies yours
Shall resound in this world
Ashes yours
Shall be blown away with the winds
Dead ends shall you find
In your room in every heart
If I matter in the very least to you, do not go forth with this marriage!
She's not suitable for you!
She'd been blackmailing Jan for so long!
Please don't marry her!
What's she saying?
Is it true?
Tell me...
She's a very good
And virtuous girl...
This dolorous, damned life
Erum, listen to me patiently.
Whatever happened in the past
Was a misunderstanding.
If Shani wants to marry her, let him.
Don't create problems.
What do you mean?
Do you mean to say that her accusations against you were true?
What accusations?
What kind of accusations? Would anyone please tell me?
So atrocious and disgraceful that they're unutterable!
Tell me! Were they true?
Tomorrow, Shani's bride will be with us.
Tell me!
And these things will get out and come to asperse you.
Why are you silent? Tell me!
And I don't want a single finger raised at my son.
Therefore,
Consider it my order
That you won't speak of this to anyone. Not even Shani.
Say something! Why are you silent?
-No!
N -- No...
They --
She was just rather gullible --
My enemies had led her astray.
That's why she'd said all of that.
As your elder brother, I'd advise you
That you should definitely marry her.
She'll keep you happy.
She --
She's whiter than white.
We'll talk when she agrees to...
She will.
I've talked to Malik; he said he'd talk to her.
Hopefully, things will turn in your favour...
Erum,
Find happiness in your brother's happiness.
Don't create problems.
Fear a trothful heart
Do nothing malapert
Its beats
Never trample underfoot
Please, Shani...
She's not worthy of you!
Please don't marry her!
Those who shatter it
Are shivered into shards by it
For this heart is not merely a heart
It is the abode of God
Love was a debt unto you
To return that was an obligation unto you
Watch, now, as God makes the next move
Why must you be so adamant, Meryem?
When your destiny knocks to rebuild your life,
Why are you kicking it out?
What are you saying?
You are asking me to
Live at my ex-husband's,
As --
His brother's bride, at that?
No...
He's said it.
He'd be out of your lives.
And when Shan finds out?
That's his concern.
Let him deal with it.
You've not concealed your past from him.
He wants to make you his, knowing every bit of it.
Whatever you say,
I'll not listen to you this time.
You may not,
But I care for your happiness.
Like any other brother, I, too, want to see my sister settle down in life.
Consider it my request or my command,
But if you have the slightest respect and sympathy for me in your heart,
If you truly consider me your brother, you will not reject him.
Because I'm telling Mr Shan
That you've agreed.
All that you have done
You know it in your heart
Watch, now, as God makes His move
This cold, callous life
Sir, this is Jan'e Alam speaking.
I would...
I would like to transfer all my property to my brother, Shan'e Alam.
Yes.
You may come to my office tomorrow with all the necessary documents.
Thank you.
You're great, mate!
You did just what you said!
What did I do?
Your friend called.
Which friend?
Malik.
He called me just now to tell me that he's convinced his sister to marry me!
He's convinced Meryem!
As always, you've fulfilled this wish of mine!
I love you so much, old chap!
How could I not?
I cannot disappoint you.
But now, you...
Need to fulfill a wish of mine.
What wish?
Just say the word!
Malik told me
How his sister
Has gone through a lot in life.
She has suffered a lot.
I want you to give her such love
Care for her so much
That she forgets all the bitter memories of her past.
Promise me.
You will give her love,
Care for her,
And give her not an ounce of sorrow.
I have heard the skies
Promise me.
Have rained all night
I promise.
But it is that city that has remained athirst
I will take good care of her,
Give her every bit of happiness,
She'll forget every sorrow of her past.
On you shall descend one day
The wrath of the Heavens
Obloquies yours
Shall resound in this world
God be praised!
My sister looks so wonderful in this gown.
May you be blessed with a lifetime of bliss!
May you be safe from every evil eye.
Why are you doing all of this?
For your happiness.
And if I said
That I'm not happy?
Then I won't believe a word of what you say.
Because I know you love Shan'e Alam.
You want to turn away from your happiness just because
He's Jan'e Alam's brother?
Punishing the innocent is a crime in itself.
If Jan'e Alam has been cruel to you,
It does not mean
That you exact your revenge on Shan'e Alam.
Alright, tell me.
Would you be happy without Shan'e Alam?
You won't be.
I knew it.
Fortunate are those
Who get the life partner of their choice.
Thus, I request,
Don't cast a hateful gaze over this moment of jollity.
Start your new life with rapture.
Now,
Would you do as your brother asked?
Smile now, quickly!
Smile!
You're ready?
I am.
My brother looks like a hero today!
Just today?
Don't I always?
You do.
But this coat's got a dazzle befitting a wedding.
Yes.
That's true.
Anyway, take this.
What's this?
These
Are all your property documents.
Yes, but why are you giving me property documents now?
Because I've transferred all our property
Over to you.
Why?
I'm worn out now, old chap.
I'm worn out managing all of this.
That is why I want you to take up this responsibility,
So that I can depart in peace.
Depart? Where are you going?
I'm leaving the country.
What are you talking about?
You'll leave me all alone like this?
I'm not leaving you all alone.
I'll get you married and then leave.
My flight leaves tomorrow morning.
You're not alone now.
This is not right.
Your life partner is with you.
You've got a beatific life ahead of you.
Alright, no need to get all emotional over it.
Look here.
My brother's getting married today.
And I want to see you delighted and nothing less.
I can't be happy without you.
Hey! Smile!
Shani, I said something.
Shani?
I said something to you.
That's more like it.
My Master...
Come quickly; I'll be waiting for you.
Meryem Bibi, daughter of Naseer Ahmed,
Do you accept your marriage to Shan'e Alam, son of Ahmed Alam,
With a dower of 2,000,000 Rupees?
I accept.
Meryem Bibi, daughter of Naseer Ahmed,
Do you accept your marriage to Shan'e Alam, son of Ahmed Alam,
With a dower of 2,000,000 Rupees?
I accept.
Meryem Bibi, daughter of Naseer Ahmed,
Do you accept your marriage to Shan'e Alam, son of Ahmed Alam,
With a dower of 2,000,000 Rupees?
I accept.
I have seen you many times before,
And each time I found you more beauteous than the last.
But I don't know why, today...
My heart is on edge...
I can't bring myself to look at your face...
Why?
Perhaps I fear
That I may be enslaved by your charm.
To enslave you is something
I can never even conceive remotely.
I do not know how to praise a lady;
I lack the words to compliment you.
But I believe
That every poet's beloved,
To whom he sang odes,
Would pale before your beauty.
A little something for you.
A little something.
I guess I now have the right to give you something now; you can accept it now.
It goes on, goes on
This cheeky, puckish life
Thank you for entering my life.
Thank you for becoming my life partner.
On you shall descend one day
The wrath of the Heavens
Obloquies yours
Shall resound in this world
Ashes yours
Shall be blown away with the winds
Dead ends shall you find
In your room in every heart
Recompense for my pain
Is my perseverance
Watch, now, as God makes the next move
Wait. Let me see...
I heard a gunshot!
From where?
Upstairs!
Erum!
Brother!
Brother -- Brother!
What happened?
-Broth --
No --
What have you done?
Those who shatter it
Are shivered into shards by it
For this heart is not merely a heart
No --
What happened --?
What have you done --?
Brother!
What have you done?
It is the abode of God
What have you just done?
Love was a debt unto you
To return that was an obligation unto you
Watch, now, as God makes the next move
What have you done -- I'd said --
I'd said my happiness means nothing without you...
Nothing!
It lingers on, lingers on
This dolorous, damned life
There is no peace left and I grow restless!
Do me a favour, Mum...
Curse me that I die!
Calm down, son...
I have heard the skies
Why did you do this?
Have rained all night
You have a problem with me, so --
After your marriage, I'll leave for somewhere far away from you.
You won't ever see my face again.
But it is that city that has remained athirst
I have suffered every punishment
God meted out to me.
Just -- forgive me, Meryem...
My dear brother Shani,
I am confident Meryem would prove to be the best for you,
Which is why I want that you never trouble her,
For I have troubled her enough already.
I have been very cruel to her.
I would have told you any of this in my lifetime,
But Mum's order
And the fear of being disgraced in the eyes of all of you
Silenced me.
I know you would despise me after reading this letter,
But try to forgive this brother of yours,
And if you can, please weep at my death,
Else, my soul would not get any peace.
And one more thing:
There's a photograph on my side table.
Many questions would come to your mind when you see it,
And the answers to all your questions
Lie with Meryem,
For she knows well how dastardly I have been.
She knows that I was a wicked man.
Keep me in your prayers.
Fear a trothful heart
Do nothing malapert
Its beats
Never trample underfoot
Those who shatter it
Are shivered into shards by it
For this heart is not merely a heart
It is the abode of God
Ashes yours
Shall be blown away with the winds
Dead ends shall you find
In your room in every heart
Recompense for my pain
Is my perseverance
Watch, now, as God makes His move
This cold, callous life
This dolorous, damned life
You knew Alam was my brother, didn't you?
Yes.
Why did you not tell me, then?
I was under your mother's oath.
She didn't want that you and Erum
Should ever come to despise your elder brother.
This cold, callous life
This dolorous, damned life