Love's testimony is not to be asked for
It pulls out tears and throws them from the eyes
Ask all you may what comes out of falling in love
The heart is its creator and it ends up being destroyed by it...
Mama... Who is she?
Who -- Who's speaking English?
Sorry Nano...
Hmph...
Hmph!
Ammi Begum, please take your medicine.
You ask her.
Have you called the lawyer?
Yes.
He'll be here by the morning.
Morning --
The bequest...
I've kept it in the casket.
If --
If the morning sun is one I get to witness, alright;
E --
Else, it is to be considered my last will and testament.
It is indeed you!
Your hair have turned all grey in a mere eight years!
Won't you pull me into an embrace?
Come.
Please, Ammi Begum
Don't speak English, you wastrel!
The rapscallion might come knocking.
Inheritance --
If he gets word that he may get a share --
Perhaps he'll pay a visit...
I used to think --
He deserves not a penny
That I should write,
'The rotter has been disinherited.'
Then I thought --
He who got his hereditament
But remained forever unloved
What has he really earned?
Ahh...
Why did you come to receive me if you despise me so much?
My Maheen is here...
A -- After eight long years, I'm hearing
The rathe shuffling of your footsteps...
Just like this, you used to come eagerly
Hying --
As if --
As if you'd trample everyone under your feet...
You're afraid, aren't you?
You'd have --
You'd have felt that --
Before your arrival --
Ahh...
Tomorrow --
Tomorrow, put up a nice game of cricket in the lawn,
And I'll show you what it means to be vivified.
Play with whom, Nano?
Love's testimony is not to be asked for
It pulls out tears and throws them from the eyes
Ask all you may what comes out of falling in love
The heart is its creator and it ends up being destroyed by it...
You smoke too?
Just casually, sometimes.
Munshi Alam,
Why have you called me?
Actually, Ammi Begum --
What happened to Dado?
She's still with us, isn't she?
She...
Won't be for much longer...
So say her doctors.
You cannot go there!
She'd die by your footfalls.
And if you do get there,
Neelam will tear your face apart,
Wali will hurl expletives at you,
And Suraiyya Bibi will smite you.
And all of this will be too much for Ammi Begum to witness.
Then why have you called me here?
For now, come inside.
I'll tell you at length.
Have some tea first; have a smoke,
Then I'll tell you why I called you. Come.
You gotten married?
You would have...
No?
How many children do you have?
Hearing about the children
Is something that will definitely make me happy.
Where did you get my address?
From Jiya.
She was the one who told me that you now live in France.
Where does Jiya live?
I asked not.
She didn't seem inclined to tell anyway.
So I just asked humbly where you live.
The will and testament shall be written down tomorrow.
Ammi Begum had, before me,
Written a lot in her bequest.
You'll be getting a lot.
I thought it'd do you good to come and collect it.
Dado...
She misses you a lot.
When at a loss for imprecations
Seeking to utterly miscall somebody
Then
Yours is the name that occurs to her.
And when your name finally escapes her mouth
She hoicks to rid herself of the gob.
Like this...
Neelam...
Come, it's too late already...
I -- I can't fall asleep...
I feel afraid.
Alright, how about some tea --
-No, no.
I just want you to be with me for a while.
Talk to me...
It would've been more proper of you to bring your wife and kids along,
Being all alone -- it frightens me too.
Anyways; come.
Photos of the kids?
I don't have kids.
No wife either.
I've not gotten married, Munshi Alam.
I couldn't bring myself to get married, Munshi Alam.
I'm not among those who can mend their broken hearts with another.
And I feel that the heart I broke with my own hands
Often becomes more alluring than ever.
And in such love I could never think of the trifles of matrimony.
And even when it did occur to me
I heard a voice asking, "To whom?"
You tell me - Who'd I have gotten married to?
To Jiya.
I would have, sure.
But there is no second option in love.
You know what I mean by 'option,' right?
There is no option of perfidy in love either.
One seeks company every moment
Not daring to contemplate separation.
You know
What Ammi Begum
Plans to write
At the very end of her will?
What?
That Waqar Ahmed
Not be permitted to either see my exanimate face or bear my pall.
She despises me so much?
So much affection she had for you.
Shall I make some tea for you?
By the way, I have also prepared your favourite dishes.
I haven't forgotten your tastes.
I'm not eating anything.
Alright.
I'll sit here for a while.
How is she, Munshi Alam?
When you were being sent off to England for the first time
I was the one to express the strongest opposition.
I had said repeatedly
That you'd get accustomed to being distant.
Tales of love, you'd believe, are a thing only in India and Pakistan.
I have seen, Waqar Ahmed
Neither does the soil in which one has not played stick to one's feet and stop him,
Nor does the one leaving notice that someone is stopping him.
The same has happened with you, Waqar Ahmed.
You have spent your days of romping among feringees
And come back here in search of love.
But
Treacheries such as theirs don't work here.
And so
You lost,
And defeated us as well.
I asked how she is.
Her gait has slowed down
She speaks little
And speaks as if
She's afeard and unnerved.
Doesn't she play cricket nowadays?
I left my job at Kaneez Mahal five years ago.
I retired when my son enlisted for the Marine Police.
I do sometimes visit them
I meet all of them
And meet all of them to know
That they're all fine.
In these five years, I've seen her twice.
Greeting me
And turning away momentarily.
Has she gotten married?
Munshi Alam, I asked if she's gotten --
N -- Nano!
You silly girl.
Your screams beckon to everyone; For once, call out my name. Please.
Have you seen your face?
You look a bit boorish and skint.
Let me get hold of you, I'll tell you everything.
I'd die rather than you catch hold of me.
You took it so seriously!
Please go.
Step aside.
Time to take your medicines.
May I come in?
Come in, Uncle.
Get up, Nano.
Rinse your mouth.
Have your breakfast.
If you and Suraiyya come into my room for the night
Fear does not let you fall asleep.
You're afraid that I may be breathing my last.
And look at her
Slept so peacefully
As if she could ensure that would not happen.
Have your breakfast.
I promise, Nano.
I won't let you breathe your last just like that.
Did you hear that, Dastoor Ahmed?
I ask Death to provide me respite to work on my last testament
And this numbskull's making promises that she won't let me breathe my last just like that.
Ask for respite from me,
For Death never grants any.
Alright, give me respite
So that I can leave him his deserved share.
He inherits half my property and the entirety of my odium.
Love's testimony is not to be asked for
It pulls out tears and throws them from the eyes
Ask all you may what comes out of falling in love
The heart is its creator and it ends up being destroyed by it...
He's here, Nano.
He's here?
Where is he, Dastoor?
Where is the varlet?
Who told you?
I don't know anything about this.
I know how to find out.
Whenever he comes here,
The cacti in Nano's lawn blossom.
Sorry to hear you left your job at Dado's place.
Sorry to hear that
You had left everyone.
It was after you left that I realized
That she could go through any mishanter
And therefore, I had no reservations about retiring.
Honestly, she didn't feel bad in the slightest either.
I said to her, "I'm leaving."
And she said, "Leave."
Today
The will is going to be drafted
I'll give you
Its signed copy.
Then, you're free to leave.
I want to meet Dado.
Rather
I want to meet them all.
I suggest
That you should not meet them.
Dastoor Uncle will slap me, right?
And Aunt will tear my face apart?
And Aunt Mehru?
What'll she do?
She'll be derisively wounding.
I'll take that slap,
Take those curses,
But I'm not leaving without meeting Dado.
Now
The doors of Kaneez Mahal are locked for outsiders.
When a stranger knocks,
The servants ask,
"Who are you?"
"Where do you come from, and"
"Whom do you want to meet?"
The servants have been shown your photograph
And instructed that this man is not to be permitted inside.
Then why are they giving me a share of the property?
This, too, is an expression of their disgust,
Or is it perhaps that you are no longer capable
Of being despised?
Therefore
Every connection of yours with Kaneez Mahal
Ends with this will.
Oh God!
Ammi Begum had said the same thing when she got to know of your departure.
"Oh God!"
And her voice reflected the same torment.
You're not crying, are you?
No.
Surely not.
You're on the rack.
Everyone was on the rack that day,
Weeping.
You don't know the circumstances that made me leave.
They don't either.
And I guess I can't even explain now.
Why are you smiling?
The story you're concealing so hard
Is etched on the walls of Kaneez Mahal.
Everyone's read it
Everyone's heard it.
What?
So everyone knows what happened that day?
Yes, everyone knows it.
So was it wrong on my part?
Should I not have left?
This question of yours
Won't be answered by anyone else.
When leave this time, you'd start asking yourself
If you should have gone there.
And if you ever return,
You'd say to yourself,
"No, I should not have left."
The will is being drafted there.
I've been called as a witness.
I'm leaving.
I'll be back before lunch.
What are you doing?
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV