What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance
This duty of showering flowers and saying prayers ends today.
I'm not coming after today, Gulrez.
The treasure you'd held in your possession for four years
Which you'd been safeguarding for four years
I'm returning it to its rightful owner.
Your debts
Are thus cleared
As is my gloom.
Neelam
Please
You have to be brave.
Sit down.
Sit.
Don't take me along, Wali.
It kills me.
You have to come.
And I'm not one who'd listen
That Neelam is not generous with happiness.
Remember
How you'd said
'He's my brother too'?
If he is not, why had you said it?
Get the car out.
She's donned the same gown
The same song is playing
The same beautician has been called
To deck her up.
Ahh!
I don't hesitate in speaking it now, Fajr.
I lack the strength to stand up against English!
Why are you quiet today?
What do you think today?
Don't you feel it's a love marriage?
You asked me to close your eyes again,
I closed my eyes and opened them.
You told me a joke again
I said
'What was that'?
I got delighted when you finished with the make-up quickly again.
I'm laughing every so often again.
But you haven't asked again,
'Is yours a love marriage'?
The second time, it's just a marriage
Not a love marriage.
It doesn't add much to my sorrow
But had you been here, it'd have felt as if
I've not lost eight years.
Do you know what it's like here?
Everyone's quiet...
As if struck by a thunderbolt, as if afraid
That the groom may run away again.
Come on, mate.
Enough of it.
They're calling.
Let's go.
What happened?
Just --
Remembered something.
Tell me
I'm really afraid.
You're not afraid, you're just embarrassed.
Come on, buddy!
Who brought this Foxy?
I did.
Your Dado said that the procession must be led by this Foxy.
Get in.
Here we go!
You departed then and are arriving today.
You wretch, you swallowed up eight years.
Neelam!
Bring the bride.
Go.
Go and sit by the priest.
What are you looking at?
Go forth with the marriage now that you've arrived.
What else will you have for memories?
She's here.
Come.
May the evil gaze not touch you.
He's left.
Thrown his sherwani here like rags.
And left you this letter addressed to you.
I'd never wished that you be defeated by my hand.
But I feel like leaving you bitterly defeated today
Having shown you that if you want to win in the name of love
You've got to accept defeat, Maheen.
Begin the marriage rituals, Reverend.
Shall I start, my child?
Please.
Maheen, daughter of Aurangzeb
Your sacred bond of matrimony with Waqar Ahmed, son of Mashood Ahmed
With five million rupees' worth of dowry
Is, in the presence of these witnesses
Hereby sealed.
Do you accept this marriage?
I accept.
Waqar Ahmed, son of Mashood Ahmed
Your sacred bond of matrimony with Maheen, daughter of Aurangzeb
With five million rupees' worth of dowry is, in the presence of these witnesses
Hereby sealed.
Do you accept this marriage?
I accept.
Thank you.
Do you know
Why I'm thanking you?
I've never seen such a beautiful bride.
You did it for me.
And also because
You didn't let me remain a loser
I needed seven runs to win on the last ball
He played a no ball,
And you hit a six on that.
I've won, Maheen.
I'm the winner.
But
I've lost so many times in life
That I know how those who lose feel.
You know what?
Winners never think
Of what those who lost go through.
He's lost.
But nobody knows
That he used to win.
But why did he lose today?
He's left.
But that does not mean
That he's perfidious.
His love for you is no less
Than your disrelish for him.
My heart says
That he'll come one day.
And
And I'll wait for him.
So, too, shall you.
Promise me
That you'll wait for him.
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
I'll sleep outside.
You're exacting your ultion.
I swear by you, no.
I'm just safeguarding.
I've kept you with me as a treasure
I'll keep you safe.
Good night.
Ask all you will what comes out of love
The heart is its creator, and ends up being destroyed by it
Quaff the blood out of me
Quaff the blood out of me and feast on my heart
And feast on my heart
Go, my boy.
Your trials end here.
Best of luck.
Why are the lights turned off?
Don't you want to see me as the groom?
Alright, let it be so with you.
Close your eyes.
But I want to see you.
I'm turning on the lights.
Maheen
Maheen!
Stop right there, Waqar Ahmed!
Right there -- Standing before me --
Like -- a criminal in a witness box...
Suits you well.
Nano says,
'Waqar Ahmed'
'Looks like a groom even in casuals'.
Scared, eh?
Yes.
I'd warned you
I'll finish you off
Where there's not the slightest relief for you.
Quaff the blood out of me
Quaff the blood out of me and feast on my heart
And feast on my heart
Ma --
Ma -- Maheen!
Dado!
Dastoor Uncle!
So flightly is your playfulness that you desert in moments of jollification
That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart
Maheen!
What happened?
Go and get a doctor!
Go!
Maheen! Open your eyes!
What have you done, Maheen!
She's gone, Dado...
They're --
They're just trying -- to no avail...
When she says,
'I'd finish you off',
She does so indeed.
And when she says,
'I'll die --'
She dies...
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
As she left --
She --
Left me this letter.
Should I read it out, Dado?
Yes...
Read it out.
Waqar Ahmed,
You're scared, aren't you?
I will keep with me the memories of our conversations and of you
Such bounties, O Love, are all one gets from you in benefaction
I will laugh wholeheartedly at this, I will embrace the heart with rapture
I will remember you then
Surprised, aren't you?
I sacrificed myself to surprise you.
Tell me -
Why did you not read the diary this time?
I'd even asked you to.
You felt embarrassed.
You felt ashamed.
Tell me -
When you ran away from the marriage
Did you not feel any step of the way that you were doing something wrong?
Didn't you feel ashamed any step of the way?
You just saw my handwriting,
But failed to see your name etched in my eyes,
Failed to see that detestation had given way to love,
Failed, also, to see
How I'd surrendered before you.
Don't leave, Waqar...
I beg you.
You went, trampling the girl
Who'd already accepted her defeat underfoot.
Turned out to be your usual Londoner tramp.
Fell in love
Without knowing how to be in love.
Now that I'm dead, don't think
That I've exacted my vengeance.
I've just shown you
That the one you love,
You should have faith in them;
Else, in ceremonies of espousal, every boy gets a girl
Who needs to love?
Do you know
I have one thing to thank you for.
When Gulrez died four years ago,
I used to think
Why I still dragged on.
But he was right.
You came back at last.
Coming to know of it,
I was enlivened again.
For before my exit, I had to be vivified for once.
Ask all you will what comes out of love
The heart is its creator, and ends up being destroyed by it
Seeing your smile on the day of the wedding
Took me back eight years to my happiness
On hearing about my marriage.
You were separated from me in the same happiness then,
And in this happiness, I am from you.
Interesting coincidence, isn't it?
You'd felt then that I don't deserve you,
I felt now that you don't deserve me.
The truth, Waqar Ahmed,
Is that those who plead for love with rue
Do not deserve it.
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
Ask all you will what comes out of love
The heart is its maker, and ends up being destroyed by it
Should, after I'm gone, the woe of separation excruciate you,
Tell people miserably,
That this eternal affliction of yours
Is a trifle before mine in that one moment
That struck me when I got the news that you'd left.
From what you did to me
I leave you absolved,
But I wonder as I depart
Who will give you shrift for your sin
Because of which
For eight years
I had grown to despise love?
I had told you, Waqar Ahmed
When it comes to ego, Maheen Aurangzeb can be far more ruthless than you.
I'll finish you off
Where there'll not be the slightest relief.
What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance
What is union and separation to one struck by love
What is this illusion you, O Love, create, and then expunge
Quaff the blood out of me
Quaff the blood out of me and feast on my heart
So flightly is your playfulness that you desert in moments of jollification
That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart
That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV