She must've given some reason.
Asking you not to come so suddenly...
No, Mum, she didn't say anything...
She just said, 'Don't come'.
My dear,
I know there is a lot you'd rather not speak out
Or share with anyone.
Look,
Please tell me if there's any problem.
I can go to any length for your happiness.
I wish I'd kept quiet about this one, too.
If I'd not told you about this wish of mine, I'd not have been embarrassed before you today.
Ashir?
No, Mum, I'm right.
I told you about my wish without thinking of Dad's dream that you worked to realise all these years,
Which you'd chosen me to do, without thinking for once
That it could affect that dream.
I didn't know that my happiness was hollow on the inside.
Why are you thinking that way?
Something could've compelled her to do this.
Alright,
I say, in a few days --
-That won't be necessary, Mum.
Please confirm my ticket.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
O Lord! You know my predicament
My life has become an affliction
Every gasp weighs at me
Why don't these doleful nights come to pass?
How do I recount what has befallen me
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
Reham,
It was possible to talk to Uncle and explain it to him.
He'd said all of it in anger.
You won't get it, Suboor.
Dad's vow was based on his trust.
His pride stands on that trust.
I can't snatch his pride from him.
And Ashir?
Can you forget him?
I'll try.
I can't promise it.
Reham...
Why are you punishing yourself and Ashir, mate?
Just try to convince Uncle for once.
I've accepted this punishment happily.
But Reham --
-Enough, Suboor!
Don't give me any new hopes.
Because it really hurts when things go south.
He was just provoking you.
You shouldn't have sworn such an oath in a fit of rage.
I've not just sworn an oath, Shakira,
I have all the courage to honour it.
That's why...
That's why... I didn't tell you anything last night,
I thought -- once your anger cooled down --
It's not about anger, Shakira,
Not one bit about anger.
If they can fall so low in accusing my daughter,
I, too, can stand so tall in her defence.
Over here, ol' chap!
Help me pack my things.
You put up quite the act.
I know you're very hurt.
You really love her.
I've never seen you this way before.
Adan, it doesn't always happen
That we get
What we wish for.
But...
I get everything that I wish for.
Because you make it possible.
I'm sorry I couldn't do anything.
Please, don't say that, mate.
It's nothing like that.
And
It's good that you've come. There's a lot for you to do.
I'll tell you.
Promise me,
You'd take good care of Mum and Appa Bi in my absence.
I've always told you that you're a kid,
But I'm saying today that you've grown up.
I'll be at ease over there
I'll be at ease over there because you're here.
Promise?
Promise me, too,
That you'd be happy.
I promise.
Take care.
Likewise.
Appa Bi, remember to take your medicines.
I will.
Take care.
You remember your promise, right?
Yes.
Whoever would he have stayed here for?
You've broken his heart.
I called him many times, but he didn't answer.
Did he talk to you?
No.
What's left to talk about?
You surrendered too quickly, Reham.
If only you wanted --
-I had no choice but to surrender, Suboor.
Besides, who were involved in this conflict?
Ashir on one side,
Ashir on one side, and Dad on the other.
No matter the victor, I'd lose.
Alright, don't be disheartened.
Things may get better with time.
I've asked Fesl to talk to Ashir.
I hope it'll resolve it.
No, Suboor,
Nobody will talk to Ashir.
Not you, not Fesl -- Nobody!
Nothing's going to change.
Nothing's going to be right now.
That's what was destined for us.
I wish I could help...
You've tried your best, haven't you?
I'm bound by family traditions, Suboor.
One prays rather than do something for my kind.
What's this, Sofia?
You saw Ashir off with such rapture,
And now, in just a few hours,
What's with all this gloom?
Here.
You're right.
I am a bit sad.
Not because he's gone,
But thinking
Of how he'd left so griefstricken.
Ashir was so delighted.
It was you who'd agreed to go to that girl's place rather unexpectedly.
But why did she do that?
To our Ashir, at that,
Who's uncompromisingly selfless in love!
Appa, do you remember
Back when I'd gotten married to Reza,
Ashir was just 14.
I was very tensed
Over whether he'd accept me as his mother.
But he accepted me wholeheartedly.
Gave me respect,
Love.
He didn't even think of me as a stepmother.
That's what Ashir's like.
It's that girl who's the unfortunate one
To have broken Ashir's heart like that.
You're right.
Alright,
Don't get all worked up.
Just have faith
That the Lord has willed it this way because it's for the better.
Alright?
Alright, Appa, I have to go to Adan's school tomorrow morning.
I'll be leaving early.
Who knows what fresh exploit I'd be hearing about tomorrow!
You won't hear about any exploit. I'll rouse you early in the morning, alright?
Thank you.
Alright.
Catch some sleep.
-Good night.
What's up, Mum? You woke me up so early...
I'd gone to bed so late...
Your Dad's not well.
Go to the shop; I've had a hard time stopping him.
I've told him, 'Rest for now, Ahmed will run the shop'.
What happened to Dad?
Whatever could happen?
Remember the scene your Uncle and Aunt created?
His blood pressure's shot up ever since!
What?
So Uncle and Aunt made a scene here, and you didn't even tell me?
If only you stayed at home, you'd know!
Why are you sitting here?
Go and get ready. I'll get you some breakfast.
Go.
Reham,
Tell him
Not t --
-He won't be coming.
He's left the country forever.
Let me see Dad.
I --
I can't believe this is his result.
I know, Sofia,
But this is Adan's result.
He's just cleared one subject. At just the passing marks.
It's not that he's not smart or inefficient, but I think he gets distracted and loses focus.
He really needs someone to make him sit down and study.
Sophia, I'd suggest you send him to a tuition academy.
Otherwise, I'm afraid his result would suffer in the final exams.
But what guarantees that he'd study at a tuition academy when he doesn't study at school?
Why don't you hire a home tutor?
Maybe, that way, he'll not get distracted.
That may not be a bad idea.
I think that might work.
Do you know anyone,
Or maybe someone from the school, or his class teacher might offer him tuition at home?
That's not possible.
Out school policy does not allow class teachers to tutor their own kids outside school premises.
Here.
This is the contact information of an academy that provides home tutors.
I'm pretty sure they'll be able to help you.
Thank you so much.
My pleasure.
I really appreciate this.
Has it come down?
It's better,
But still high.
Dad...
Please don't stress yourself.
That's what I'm telling him - it's just how Rehmat and Parveen are.
They're just looking for an excuse to create a scene.
But that does not mean
That one be hurt over their words and sicken oneself.
I don't give two hoots about what they say!
I'm not worried about anything they say.
But yes,
Whatever they said that day
Has certainly
Pained me a lot.
But right now,
I'm just worried about the shop.
What happened, Dad?
Why are you worried about it?
My dear,
The earnings have come down, and we're spending a lot.
Electricity bills,
This and that,
Plus, there's a lot of those departmental stores in the city now.
People have stopped coming to the shop.
If only His Royal Highness were capable of anything
That he'd be there to help me!
That's it?
Just that?
You've made me so capable, haven't you?
I can help you.
Besides, I've applied already.
I'd get a job offer very soon.
There, now!
There she goes again!
Adamant about getting a job, now.
Everyon --
-Should we stop breathing out of fear of what everyone would think?
What do we do?
They have to object to every single thing.
'Everyone'!
Don't worry, Dad.
I haven't applied to a company.
I've applied as a teacher.
Sure, why not?
Start working.
Teaching children is such a noble deed.
And now,
Don't ever get worried if anyone said anything.
I'd take care of that. I'm right here.
I allow you to work.
Fair enough!
Dad and Daddy's girl have united
Against this outsider.
Mum!
Leave it, my dear, let me deal with that.
Let her say what she wants to.
Alright, get some rest.
Everything's good, isn't it?
How do you like the place?
Yes, Mum.
Everything's perfect.
The house is nice, too.
Good.
Tell me,
Is everything alright?
Yes, everything's alright.
Alright,
I'd say you rest for a few days.
You don't need to go to the office right away.
Alright.
Take care.
Goodbye.
No, Mum, there's no chance. No chance I'm having a tutor!
Behave yourself, Adan.
Have you seen your results?
Would you attempt your exams this way?
Sofia,
Have your dinner, and talk to the kid calmly after that.
Everything's a joke to him, Appa.
Do you know how much I've been embarrassed because of him today?
Please, Mum,
I'd study on my own, I promise.
I don't trust you Adan.
Not this time.
I'm hiring a tutor,
And you're studying under him.
Adan!
At least have your dinne --
Goodness, Sofia.
He said he'd study on his own.
Now, he's left his dinner.
He'd come and have it when he's hungry.
We can't be emotionally blackmailed by him.
We have to be stern with him for his good.
Hello?
Yes.
Yeah, can you hold on for a minute, please?
Yes, please...
Please give me her number.
Yes?
Right.
I'll call her right away.
Alright, thank you.
Thank you very much.
5 p.m.?
Alright.
I'll take care of that.
-Sorry, Appa.
I would've come,
But I have an important meeting today.
Didn't I say I'd take care of everything? Don't worry.
Alright,
Tell Adan to behave.
If I got one complaint, he's grounded. No PlayStation, no going out, nothing.
It won't come to that.
It's not like the lad's so insolent...
Thank you.
Don't worry.
Alright, goodbye.
Goodbye.
But that's so far away!
How would you commute?
By rickshaw, Mum, of course.
And when would you be back?
It'll be around 8.
Alright,
Please ask Ahmed
To leave me at the stop.
I'd thumb a ride.
Alright.
Ahmed!
What is it, Mum?
Go with your sister and help her get a rickshaw.
Jeez...
I'm coming.
And yes,
If there's anything,
Feel free to call your Dad or your brother.
That's alright, Mum,
But if you'd worry like that,
I'd be very tensed.
I wouldn't be able to focus on my work.
Shall we?
Yes.
Let's go.
Wait.
She's not riding to battle.
I'm waiting outside. Come quickly.
Alright.
Take care. Goodbye.
-Goodbye, Mum.
I'm searching for the number but can't find it.
That's how it is with you.
Throw the cigarette away; she's coming.
Wait. I'll be back.
Where are you off to, Ahmed?
Uh...
Reham has to go to teach.
I was helping her get a ride.
She's going to teach?
As in, as a home tutor?
Isn't Uncle's income enough for you folks?
Munir,
It'd be better if you don't poke your nose in our matters.
Oh.
As if your matters aren't our matters.
Or is it that Uncle's decided to cut himself off from the family?
Ahmed...
Go and talk to the rickshaw driver.
Let me be clear,
I don't like it one bit tha --
-I don't give a hoot what you like or don't.
And yes,
We're as good as cut off from the family,
Because they've never bothered to ask about our condition,
Or the hardships we face.
So, it'd be better
That you open your eyes before opening your mouth.
Come.
Before we start, let me make it clear, sir:
If you're here, thinking that you'd scold me and be stern with me,
You can turn back and leave right now.
Adan!
Don't worry.
Neither would I scold you, nor would I punish you.
I'm --
I'm sorry, I thought --
It's okay.
Please, sit. I'll have tea sent.
Hi, I'm Adan.
Reham.
Sit down.
And there he is, right in the middle of the street, saying,
And there he is, right in the middle of the street, saying, 'Isn't Uncle's income enough for you folks that Reham's going to work'?
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Now, Rehmat would be coming in the evening to create a ruckus over it.
She's going with my permission.
I'm her father.
You'd better stay quiet.
You don't need to say anything.
One jibe of Munir's has awakened your sense of honour,
But you aren't ashamed one bit over why
Reham has had to help me when you're there!
First, make yourself so capable
That you can proudly have her live a respectable life, staying at home.
That's the bleedin' limit,
Calling me from the shop for this cod.
And listen,
Don't bother her by calling!
That's strange.
I have to hear both the jibes and the lectures!
Alright,
So, when do your exams start?
I guess
Next month?
Alright.
And
Which subject do you find the most difficult?
We'd start our revision with that.
Revision?
You're talking about revision. I haven't even covered the syllabus.
Listen,
If you don't want to ruin your teaching career,
You should leave.
It's an honest advice,
Because there's no way I'm going to pass.
And what if I said that I like challenges?
One can only taste victory
When one's afraid of defeat.
Subject?
Accountancy.
Shall we?
It's a good start.
And if
You're regular like this,
I'm sure you'd get excellent results.
Is that an order?
No.
It's a request.
I'll see you at 4 tomorrow.
Goodbye.
That lippy cow!
Well, why wouldn't she be?
Her father's always backing her!
Dad,
You've been too soft with Uncle.
You're older than him,
How dare he reject this proposal?
Should I beg before him for your sake?
I'm not going there again and again only to be insulted!
You'd better stay quiet.
I'd say you talk to him, Mum.
I might jump off the roof one of these days.
M -- Munir!
My dear!
I can't study and look at her at the same time, mate.
It doesn't feel like she's teaching.
It feels like she's reciting poetry.
Just look at her hair and smile, mate.
She's beautiful...
However did you get her number?
What do you mean, 'however'?
Maria gave me herself.
Excuse me,
'Miss Maria'.
I can call her Maria.
She's my friend.
In fact,
More than a friend.
He's lost it.
I know, you folks must find it odd,
But I'm seriously
But I'm seriously involved.
'Involved'?
Yes.
It's 4, mate. Time for my game.
It's 4 already?
I'm getting late, folks, see you!
Bye!
What's up with him?
-No idea.
Adan would bother you like this.
Adan would bother you like this. But please, don't give in and stop coming.
It's nothing like that.
Adan's a good boy.
He's just
A tad irresponsible...
But don't worry,
I won't stop coming here.
Please, sit.
I'm sorry, I'm a bit late...
Thank God you've come.
Please, start your session. She's been waiting for long.
Alright? Very good.
I was with my friends, so...
I got a bit late.
Oh?
Speaking of which, we're friends too, aren't we?
It'd be better if we spent this time together from now on.
I don't study with my 'friends'.
Right...
But some friends are a bit different, too, innit?
I find it all so boring.
Alright.
I'm going to make sure you don't find it boring at all.
Okay?
I --
I'll get my books.
Okay.
Every gasp weighs at me
Why don't these doleful nights come to pass?
How do I recount what has befallen me
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
Appa was praising you so much!
She's so good!
She deserves every bit of it!
Splendid.
It's quite the accomplishment that
Adan's accepted you.
You're going to score good grades, okay?
Don't worry.
Hopefully, if the Lord wills, he will.
Adan...
Your handwriting's so horrible.
I can't understand a word of this.
I hate Urdu.
And
Writing is so hard...
It isn't even that hard.
A bit of practice will help.
I'd say you keep a diary.
Diary...
But what'd I write?
Whatever your heart feels like.
The point here is to write as much as you can,
So that you can improve your Urdu handwriting.
I'm nearly done with my papers,
I'd leave by next month.
Are you alright?
Yes.
I'm fine.
I've started teaching,
So time flies.
Uh...
Fesl had talked to Ashir, too.
He'd said --
Suboor,
I was working on my notes.
So,
I'll call you -- in a while.
Okay, bye.
Dad...
Here's my
First packet.
It's been a month since she started teaching.
Time just went by!
It's your hard-earned money, my dear; you have the greatest right over it.
What'd I do with it?
Keep it with you.
Keep it with you. Get something for yourself.
You've worked so hard
To educate me,
And if --
If I want to help you today,
Please don't turn me down like that.
I'd feel like all my efforts have gone to waste.
But --
-Please, Dad.
You've always felt pride and happiness in every achievement of mine,
So why not this time?
Or is it that a daughter's earnings are an issue of ego
For you as well?
-Not at all, my dear!
Don't even think of that! Here.
You were my pride,
And so you shall always be.
In fact, now, you are my vainglory.
May you live long.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
These ill-timed showers!
They just bring ill health!
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
You could've taken a day off.
How could it have hurt his studies?
You're brilliant, I give you that.
This rain only brings diseases.
Translation: J. Mir