Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Come.
I've seen you.
Just ask quietly
Where I'd gone and who I've met.
Hey!
Who have you met?
As if you don't know at all!
I swear, Farah, I don't.
I'd gone to Arifa's place.
Arifa's place?
Yes.
I thought I'd sit with her for a while,
Comfort her.
So, could you comfort her?
-I tried the best I could.
The Lord will reward you for this.
You don't even think
Where you're going when going to comfort them.
But she's very hard-hearted.
She isn't particularly grieved that her brother's left them.
So she didn't give you the photograph?
Photograph?
I'd dropped that idea long ago.
So, what did you talk about?
We
Were talking about the Farah who writes him letters.
Lubna, I think
He's eloped with her.
And you said this to Arifa, too?
I'm just telling you my guess.
And such wayward lasses
Are there the moment one calls them.
He'd have said, 'Come',
'Now's the chance'.
'Let's steal away together'!
She'd be living with him, now,
Without getting married.
But know what,
A tragic end awaits her kind!
Their end may be happy, too.
Perhaps the two of them have gotten married?
You're right.
I didn't even think of that.
And he's the son of a Reverend.
He'd know every nuptial rite!
Yes!
I'm beginning to understand what Arifa said now!
What did she say?
She said, 'He's left Hyderabad for Karachi'.
'He'd be back when he's become something'.
The blighter!
He'll come back a father!
Mam!
Get up.
Wali's here.
Wali?
Where is he?
Open the door,
Or he'll create a scene before everyone.
At ease.
It's Jasmine's cousin.
He's the loafer type.
He always rings the bell like that.
Everyone in the family's got issues!
But Jasmine's nice, boyo.
What is it?
Why are you here?
Jeez, Modryb...
You'd ask your nai why he's here?
I'd said I'd be here on the 25th,
And it's the 25th today.
And I'd said back then that you don't need to come here.
What about you, Modryb, you say anything.
Step aside, will you?
A quarrel between a Modryb and her nai doesn't look very nice.
We'll talk inside.
You can't come inside.
I'll have to make my way in if you stop me.
You might even get injured, Modryb.
Muster all your courage, boyo.
And try your Modryb's, too!
Babu Hamid!
Hey!
She's crying for help!
Sit tight.
Let her cry if she does.
Such an effete man!
Babu Hamid!
Hey!
Hey -- Boyo -- Afzal!
Don't do it, Modryb,
I'm getting angry.
Babu Hamid!
Alright.
Call him one more time.
If he comes, alright.
Otherwise, open the door yourself, Modryb.
What is going on?
Just --
I'm joking around with me Modryb.
Who are you?
Afzal.
I'm her tenant.
But she was calling Babu Hamid, wasn't she?
Where's the bugger?
Look,
Don't use foul words.
It isn't proper to misbehave at your Aunt's doorstep.
You've just gotten up, haven't you?
Go back to sleep,
Or I'll put you to sleep right here.
What is your name?
Answer me, sir.
Wali --
His name's Wali.
My Dad says it's not good to pick a fight,
But my heart says it's no good to desert a fight once it's started either.
This is your Aunt's house,
But you don't even enter your Dad's house without permission.
You're new here and I think nobody's told you about me.
Well,
Never mind.
I'll get going.
But don't take this meeting as my introduction.
Next time, I'll show you who this bugger called Wali really is.
Okay, Modryb.
I'll get going.
Take care of her.
I'll be dropping by any day this time.
God be with ye.
Thank you very much, my dear.
He didn't come in?
Sent the scoundrel away.
You sent him away and he left?
Ain't buying that, Mam...
He isn't going away like that.
Afzal sent him away.
He understood it in a moment when he said it.
What do you mean?
He scared him away
Like Babu Hamid had?
Yes.
Then the poor soul's dead.
Don't you remember
What he did to Babu Hamid?
I do.
But everyone should remember
It's only a man's duty to save a girl.
Whether the man's one's own or an outsider.
Whose duty, then, is it to save him?
The blighter would have ten men with him when he'd be back.
They'd beat him black and blue.
The poor man's our tenant, Mam,
Not our guardian.
In fact, he's not even properly our tenant.
What did he say as he left?
He said,
'I'll introduce myself when I come back'.
It's the same, then, isn't it?
He said one day, 'I break legs for an introduction'!
Oh God!
I'll tell him to vanish from here.
-Hey!
Hey! Listen!
Do you see this wound?
Look at this one, too.
The bugger struck me with a 2 kilo pistol.
It still hurts here.
Come on.
Gather all your things and make yourself scarce within 15 minutes.
Go where?
And why?
Haven't I paid the rent?
You have,
But Wali is going to pay you back
What you've given him with a tenfold interest!
When?
What do you mean, 'When'?
At least tell him not to come.
I'm the son of a priest.
I don't charge interest.
Do you even know what she's talking about?
Yes --
She's talking about the interest, mate.
I've told her
I'm not taking any.
They'll be bringing some 10 ruffians for interest,
They'd clobber your face until it's beyond recognition,
And that Wali will smite your legs for the sin of grabbing his collar.
At the very least.
Does he not have legs?
What do you mean?
It's clear what that means, Babu, mate.
An eye for an eye,
And a leg for a leg.
What --
You want to be a hero?
You'd fight 10 men all by yourself?
He even carries a pistol!
That's odd, mate.
Dad wanted me to fear God,
And you want me to fear His men?
For God's sak --
-Don't swear by God.
I know, too, that he'll be coming.
We'll see when he comes
How powerful ten ruffians can be.
Look,
Your have pretty face just like me,
But he only likes women with pretty faces,
He doesn't like men with pretty faces.
He'll mangle that face of yours.
Why
Don't you wait for him quietly?
Let him come.
Let him show what he can do.
I'm waiting for him, too,
And I don't like to wait.
This lad's going to die, Babu Hamid,
And get you killed too.
I'm going to get you breakfast.
Eat whatever you have for breakfast and lunch as if it's the last thing you'll ever have
For breakfast or lunch.
What does she think Wali is?
Who knows what you think Wali is.
He's not going.
The lad's proper manly, Jasmine.
I saw his courage in the morning.
One of these days,
You'll see the 'proper manly' lad scurrying like a rat.
He won't even be able to eat if he got hurt around the mouth.
We have the things to make soup, right?
Is he asking for soup?
He isn't right now, Mum,
But he will, in a few days.
He'll only have soup for a week or two,
And if Babu Hamid is spared, he'll be having the bread.
He didn't feel the sligtest of fear?
Not at all.
And Babu Hamid?
Didn't he tell, either, what kind of a tyrant Wali is?
He did.
The poor man was even showing his wounds,
And this lad was laughing.
What's this long 'hmm' about?
Thus beat the drums of war, O daughter of Fortune!
A ferocious battle shall mark the days to come,
As the forces of the righteous and the sinful shall clash,
And the sinful shall be disgraced.
What forces will clash?
Don't think of a single man as a force.
The ten or so blokes will crush him together.
-I've seen his eyes.
They're not the kind that would accept defeat.
Peace be upon you.
Sit.
That's what I'd come to say.
Mum had advised me,
'Go and tell Arifa to recite the Ayat'e Karima [Prayer for Relief from All Difficulties]'.
Where's Lubna gone?
To Arifa's.
It just occurred to me that they should recite the Ayat'e Karima [Prayer for Relief from All Difficulties].
If they do, you should go too.
One should always do one's part in good deeds.
She could've just called...
Arifa's asked her not to call.
She says,
'When the phone rings, it feels as if Afzal's calling'.
'So, it's better that you don't call'.
'A ray of hope'
'Shines bright when the bell rings'.
Why has Afzal suddenly become so important to us?
Mum!
I'm asking you.
You've made him important.
Acted out love, and then an engagement,
And now it's time for 12 Labours of Farah to find him and bring him back!
12 Labours?
To find him and bring him back?
What are you saying?
I'm only saying what I am seeing,
And whoever's seen it
Is out of control.
You've turned everyone in the house around your finger.
Do you know what happened in the morning?
What?
Your Dad left his cellphone at home.
What's bad about that?
I've left my phone --
At home many times, too.
Listen to the whole thing, Farah.
He went and called me from the office, saying, 'Irsa, I've forgotten something important at home'.
I asked,
'What have you forgotten'?
He said,
'I'll call you when I can remember'.
So, could he not remember?
He could, the very next minute.
He called and asked, 'Any news about Afzal'?
Afzal?
He was referring to his cellphone as 'Afzal'!
Your Dad left his cellphone at home.
He went and called me from the office, saying, 'Irsa, I've forgotten something important at home'.
I asked,
'What have you forgotten'?
He said,
'I'll call you when I can remember'.
So, could he not remember?
He could, the very next minute.
He called and asked, 'Any news about Afzal'?
I swear by God I didn't say that.
Your seeing a psychiatrist doesn't mean you've gone mad.
Lubna?
-Just see one for once.
At least it'll satisfy everyone.
I'm your sister,
Which is why I double as a psychiatrist in times of need.
The truth is that your madness does not convince people!
Care to ask
What happened to Afzal's photograph,
And what Arifa said when I asked her for one?
What did she say?
She said you don't even deserve his photograph.
Tell me,
Do you?
No.
Not at all.
O Prophet, peace be upon you.
O Messenger, peace be upon you.
O Beloved, peace be upon you.
Prayers of the Lord be upon you.
O Prophet, peace be upon you.
O Messenger, peace be upon you.
O Beloved, peace be upon you.
Prayers of the Lord be upon you.
Ball -- Throw the ball.
Uncle Reverend!
Yes, Babloo?
How come you're here, Uncle Reverend?
What are you asking, my good man?
I've come to watch your match.
In all honesty, I've only realised it today
That if you just play cricket,
There can be no better sport
Than cricket.
Hey, Babloo!
Why are you crying?
I am the one who'd dropped him.
I'd had him board the train.
Don't stroke my cheek with affection.
Slap me, Reverend.
No.
The fault is not yours, Babloo, my dear.
If the one who's going is unbending in his intentions,
The fault never lies with the one who drops him off.
Go,
And play,
But
Just play cricket.
You're sitting here!
I considered waiting at his doorstep to receive you,
But changed my mind later.
Care to properly tell me the reason for going there?
I'd gone to talk about the Ayat'e Karima [Prayer for Relief from All Difficulties].
That's it?
That's all you said?
I didn't even have to say it!
They were reciting the Ayat'e Karima [Prayer for Relief from All Difficulties] when I'd gone there.
I recited too.
Splendid.
You folks think over here,
And they act on it over there.
Yes, it surprised me too.
But it felt great to see
That everyone thinks alike in times of sorrow.
What's the sorrow with you folks?
Leave it, Farah.
You feel sorrow over his departure too.
Don't you?
You think so much about his Mum and Dad,
You were even prepared to run an advertisement on TV.
It's a different matter that you changed your mind later on.
But your feelings have been made clear.
From now, you're not going to his place without asking me.
Why?
It's my friend's house!
How can you stop me from going to my friend's house?
Arifa's friends with me, too.
I go there too.
Do you know why she didn't invite me to recite the Ayat'e Karima [Prayer for Relief from All Difficulties]?
Ask why she hadn't invited me.
Why didn't she?
Because the blame for Afzal running away
Has fallen on me!
Not at all.
No one's blamed you for anything.
That's their gentility.
But I know the fault lies with me.
That's why I've decided
That I'll leave no stone unturned
To wash this blame off me.
I thought this door leads to your place, so...
I came here on the pretext of handing you the utensils.
Pretext, as in?
No, it's --
Babu Hamid thinks
I've broken your heart.
I couldn't fall asleep.
Afzal!
Afzal, get up.
Get ready; he's here.
He's riding a motorcycle?
'He' is riding motorcycles.
What do I do?
Open the door on the inside and go upstairs,
Jump across and get inside the house next to this one.
Alright?
I'm not talking about fleeing,
But about fighting.
Don't think of doing anything stupid; you have little time,
Get up.
And leave this place.
I'll flee on one condition.
Go on.
Quickly.
If I run away,
You'd fight them.
Done.
Go,
I'll fight them.
You bugger!
You're a lone wolf.
They'll kill you.
What does it matter, boyo?
If they spare me, the cops will kill me.
You'd better get out.
He hasn't knocked the door yet.
I'd have to open it if he knocks,
Or he'd break through it.
You're a Lahori, aren't you?
Talk like the Lahoris do.
Why are you besmirching the reputation?
C'mon.
Where are you going, Mam?
It's not Wali.
Just two lads showing off stunts on their bikes.
They've left.
C'mon, shake hands with me.
I used to think Babu Hamid was a coward.
I swear by you, I'm a pure coward.
And I swear you're one, too.
This courage is just a necessity...
One feels ashamed to die by the hands of one like Wali.
Who exactly
Is this Wali?
Jasmine's Mam is his Modryb.
If she's his Aunt, why doesn't she let him in?
He's got his eyes on Jasmine.
He says, 'I'll marry her'.
Doesn't she want to?
She'd rather spit in his face.
The bugger's an ace ruffian.
Hey!
She should just talk to him for a change.
If he actually loves her, he'll give up his thuggery.
What'd he do with his wife?
He's already married.
And he had a 'love marriage' back then.
In fact, I've heard it wasn't his first.
He's had one before that, too.
His 'love' lasts 6 months, and his 'marriage' 7.
He leaves the old one
A month after his 'love' ends.
Why is his name Wali [Saint] then?
His name should be 'Lovely'.
The bugger's besmirching the name of every saint out there.
You gave me a fright there!
What happened?
I can't sleep.
Me neither.
Come.
Want some juice?
Yes, give me some.
Who said the thing about the psychiatrist?
I mean,
Whose idea was it?
Mine...
So you think I should see a psychiatrist?
No.
I don't now.
I think I was wrong.
Don't say that.
I think you're right.
I should see a psychiatrist.
Why?
I mean, why do you think so?
I've started thinking about people
About whom I shouldn't really be bothered.
Who, for example?
Name a few.
For instance, I was just thinking about Mehtab.
I started thinking
That, seeing how he'd left my swing in flames,
How he must be up in flames all within himself!
Then? So what?
It's alright.
But I shouldn't really be thinking of him.
The thing is,
Deep down, you're a compassionate girl,
And, over time,
You're forgetting the sorrow of the burning swing,
And you're beginning to pity Mehtab now.
No, it's not that.
Then,
What is it?
I'm thinking that Afzal
Has eloped with the Farah who used to write him letters.
That's why I should not go to Karachi.
Where's the logic in this?
It's pure logic, Lubna.
If I chanced upon him in Karachi,
He'd think I've come to Karachi for him, wouldn't he?
Although
It really feels so cheap to even think of it.
Find out
Who the best psychiatrist in Hyderabad is.
I'll be seeing him tomorrow.
Good night.
Also,
Mum and Dad must not know about it.
Don't worry.
Promise?
Promise.
Jasmine!
Jasmine, get up!
What is it, Mam?
I'm very afraid.
You're a grown-up and yet afraid, Mam?
You've grown up.
That's why I'm afraid.
It's 2, Mam.
He won't be coming now.
It's better if he does come tonight.
At least this long night of waiting for tomorrow will end.
Shall I get you some tea?
Alright.
What happened?
He's here.
Give me the gun.
Give it to me!
You're not opening the door.
The bugger's laughing!
Putting up a show of courage?
I give you another chance to save your life:
Get me up on your shoulders and drop me before my Jasmine.
Ahh!
So that's why your Aunt doesn't let you in!
Yes
Yes or no?
Alright,
Let's rather not fight.
Your name's Wali [Saint].
At least live up to your name, mate.
Yes
Yes or no?
Had you been in Hyderabad,
Your cronies would be pleading before you with their hands folded,
'Save your life, Wali',
'Don't ruffle Afzal's feathers'!
Yes or blimmin' no?
Hey!
I'll feed you your teeth, you bugger!
My second punch will break your jaw!
As if you will deliver a single blow, M. Wali!
It's your crony who's doing the dirty work.
Wait.
He's mine!
You bleedin' --
Pakku, Nasir, Wahid --
Fill the bugger with lead!
Deal with the bugger.
I'll handle the shooters.
Nobody here takes a bullet or a beating for someone,
And only those fear the gun who don't have one themselves,
Or lack the guts to fire one.
I'm the son of Reverend Subhanallah, M. Wali,
And he used to tell me,
'Death stands guard over life',
'Do not fear it';
'Fear life'
'For it will kill you off where you'll not have the slightest relief'.
Begone, now!
I'll spare you.
That's alright,
Thank you very much.
But I won't spare you, Wali.
I was never, in Dad's eyes, a good son,
But never did he grab my collar, you bugger!
Quiet!
Don't scream!
People will remember your screams and laugh at you!
What are you looking at here and there?
Rats don't make good soldiers in the legions of wolves.
Alright.
Forgive me.
Alright, I forgive you.
May I go?
What's the hurry?
Come.
Come, let's sit here for a while.
C'mon!
Sit.
Forgive me, too.
In my childhood,
Someone insulted me.
I beat him black and blue.
He asked forgiveness.
When Dad found out, he said, you should apologise to him too.
I was just as surprised as you are.
I said, 'But Dad, he insulted me'.
Dad said,
'He's asked forgiveness for his mistake',
'And so should you for yours'.
So?
Say that you forgive me.
I forgive.
There's one thing that's wrong with you.
It pleases you to see that someone fears you.
No.
That's not right, mate.
Dad says that only the Lord has this right -
That man should fear Him,
And He be pleased with it.
It angers Him
When a man fears another.
Fear His wrath.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV