Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Hello?
You're still awake, aren't you?
Yes.
Just stay awake.
I've found out about the lass.
Who is it?
Jasmine.
Jasmine?
I've agreed, beaut.
I thought that the blighter's adamant,
And he may pick any Mary, Jane or Susie in this chaos,
So, I've decided to sacrifice my principles.
Besides, there aren't any principles in love, are there, Farah?
There's
Just love.
Farah!
Farah Ibrahim!
Why are you sleeping here?
I'm not sleeping...
I was just sitting here, waiting
For you to get up so I could tell you what's happened in Karachi last night.
Target killing?
Yes, target killing.
Have a lot of people died?
A lot of dreams have been killed.
Those of the Farah who used to write those letters,
Those of Lubna Ibrahim...
That wee lassie's clawed the eyes of both of you out.
'Wee lassie'? Who?
Hold it, Lubna Ibrahim,
If I told you in one shot,
You'll have a heart attack.
I won't.
Tell me whom you're talking about,
And while you're at it, tell me
Who the killer of my dreams is.
Jasmine Afzal.
Jasmine or Afzal?
Jasmine is going to become Jasmine Afzal.
They're getting engaged today.
Hey!
So he's actually getting engaged to Jasmine?
But you'd told me that Jasmine had refused?
I'd also said that she's proper cheeky.
She was saying proudly yesterday,
'I refused',
But she called me the next hour, saying,
'I've agreed'.
Right...
Should I give you her number?
What for?
Call her and say some of the finest four-letter words!
The blighter --
Dodgy lass -- riggish --
Hey!
However is she riggish?
She's marrying the one she loves.
And Afzal's proposed her, which means
The love isn't one-sided.
The thing is,
It's hurt me very much,
But one doesn't insult lovers.
It'd have killed you to hear...
Obviously...
But what could be done now?
The blighter...
He was never destined for me...
Make a vow.
For what?
Say that you'd offer 100 extra prayers if the engagement breaks.
One who has a heart herself
Couldn't possibly curse anyone with heartbreak.
In fact,
I'd pray now
That the two live together,
And always remain happy.
They'd not remain happy, that's for sure.
Your heart's been broken.
It'd have consequences.
You'll see.
She'd weep
Facing Hyderabad.
Now,
You shouldn't curse either.
I'm not cursing her.
I'm telling you where the 'love' of such dodgy girls leads them.
The blighter
Shifts from one girl to another when he shifts from one city to another.
He's not the type.
He'd left Hyderabad, defeated,
He'd have thought he'd return from Karachi victorious.
He'd be victorious to get engaged to Jasmine?
Whatever is this Jasmine?
A lippy BA pass.
She doesn't even have the manners of how to behave and talk!
Engagements can be broken,
But if he got married,
Not a victor,
He'd be bitterly defeated on that day.
Who'd defeat him if he came back a victor in love?
Farah Ibrahim, or the Farah who used to write him letters?
How long have you been sitting here?
Ever since she called.
Forget her.
Take a pill and sleep.
Just think you've gotten the news of a target killing from Karachi.
Such incidents happen over there every now and then.
Don't grieve over it too much.
I won't.
Just think you've caught a news story from Karachi.
No idea who's died.
You've died, Farah Ibrahim.
Don't take it - seeing that I've come
On the day of the engagement -
That I woke up, thinking
That I ought to invite you, too.
I've only invited you.
I'd told her there's no need to go.
She would've invited herself.
Yes...
She's had us promise we'd come.
The Reverend was asking before he went to bed,
'What should I wear tomorrow'?
We haven't had anything new made...
Why would we need anything new?
We'd wear the same that we'd worn to that pretence of an engagement.
It was a new one then.
Anyway... So, what time have you fixed?
I mean, when's the engagement?
After the dusk prayer.
The Lord's willed it [Great].
It's such an auspicious time.
Where's the Reverend, Madame?
She'd sent him to get some sweets in the morning.
He was just left asking what the sweets are for.
Yes, Arifa, what are the sweets for?
I'll tell you, too, when he's brought the sweets.
Everyone here has a penchant for surprises...
Like father,
Like daughter...
And like the blessed son...
That rapscallion gave me a right surprise, too...
What about the wedding? Is it this year?
It'll be this year, if the Lord wills.
If the Lord wills.
Arifa!
Arifa! I've brought sweets.
Here.
Oh! Praise the Lord... Such honoured people have come here!
Peace be upon you.
-And upon you, peace.
How are you, Reverend?
Thank the Lord [I'm fine].
Peace be upon you, Madame.
And upon you, peace.
We'd just been waiting for you.
In the Lord's name [Pray tell].
It's just
That she'd
Sent me to get sweets -
Sit -
Otherwise,
I'm usually at home.
You've come to invite us to Farah's engagement, haven't you?
Yes.
There!
So you'd have to say that, now!
Madame,
I've never felt that she's your daughter.
She has a place here.
In my heart.
I await her coming all the time...
Thinking when she'd come...
And he treats her to coconut biscuits when she comes!
She's your daughter, Reverend.
It's just that she couldn't be yours, or, I'd thought I'd meet her here.
Oh...
Forget about that...
Here, Uncle. Have some sweets.
Oh, Arifa! We forgot about the sweets entirely.
Alright.
Pray tell, now, what it's for.
Our Afzal's getting engaged today.
I mean,
It's his engageent today, too.
What've you just said?
Were you lying to chaff them or terrifying your Mum?
I'm not lying.
He's getting engaged today.
He's actually getting engaged.
It's his old landlady's daughter;
He's getting engaged to her.
Her name's Jasmine.
Swear by me.
I swear by you.
The artful blighter...
How easily he can ensnare a girl...
Well, I'd always known that he'd give a befitting reply to Farah one day.
He just did.
You'll see,
He'll get engaged after dusk.
She'd wear the ring here,
And he'd put the ring on her there.
Good morning, Dad.
Good morning.
We'd gone over to Afzal's.
We've invited them to the engagement.
Take these sweets.
Arifa's sent these.
They're celebrating Farah's engagement?
She's celebrating her brother's engagement.
Give some to her, too.
Hello?
Farah?
No, it's Lubna.
Farah's sleeping.
It's 10!
She went to bed at 8 a.m.
Ask her to call when she gets up.
Everything's alright, innit?
I
Wanted my sister-in-law's number from her.
Sister-in-law?
I'm talking about Jasmine, Lubna.
Oh...
Mum's so eager to talk to her.
Wait, I'll wake her up.
No.
There's no hurry, really.
Let her sleep.
Stay on the line.
Perhaps it is time for her to get up.
Farah!
Aye -- Has the wedding procession gotten here?
Get a grip on your senses, Farah.
No wedding procession comes on engagements.
Here's some sweets for you.
From whom?
Afzal's family.
Arifa and her Mum are celebrating the engagement.
Arifa's on the line.
She wants her sister-in-law's cell number.
Sister-in-law?
Jasmine, of course.
Here. Talk to her.
Hello, Arifa.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
Sorry for waking you up.
No...
It's okay.
Ever since
Mum's found out, she's not calmed down.
She's been saying again and again, 'Get her number'.
Ah, right...
I have her number.
Listen,
You've met her, haven't you?
Yes.
How does she look?
Also, tell me,
What does her voice sound like?
She sounds sweet, doesn't she?
Yes, she does.
She must look very comely.
She does.
I'd said the moment I'd heard it, 'She'd be very comely, Mum'!
As lively and jovial like a sparrow jigging about!
Give me her number, will you?
I'll text you.
And
Have the sweets, too.
It's been sent specially for you.
I'll have some.
I'll disconnect.
Disconnect...
She was thumbing her nose at me.
She was saying everything herself,
'She's very comely, isn't she'?
'Her voice would sound sweet, too'...
So, isn't she comely?
Doesn't she sound so sweet?
She may be.
She can talk to her and taste her sweetness for herself.
And look at that,
She's deriding me, saying,
'She'd be lively and jovial'
'Like a sparrow jigging about'!
If only the blighter knew she's a hawk!
At least text her the number.
I'm doing it.
Leave that be.
I won't have the sweets.
But I will.
I'm opening them for myself.
Hold it,
Hold it, Ruqaiyya Begum!
He's not given you any such happiness,
That you feast on sweets to death.
You've already had half a kilogramme.
I'd thought your heart would be thunderstruck today.
It's your Afzal's engagement today,
And he hasn't even invited you!
Well, I do feel sad about that,
But my happiness is far greater, Reverend.
He'd have thought at least once,
But your judgement must've scared him...
Which judgement are you talking about?
You brand him a sinner just like that.
You'd be thundering right now
Had he invited us to his engagement.
'I won't attend that sinner's engagement'!
Have some shame, Ruqaiyya Begum.
He didn't even ask you.
He picked a girl on his own,
And he's going to put the ring on her himself.
In all honesty,
This is cause enough for us to die of shame.
I'm thinking of writing a letter of disownment,
And having it published in every newspaper in Karachi before the evening.
Mum...
I've gotten her number.
Whose number have you gotten?
My sister-in-law's.
Hello?
It's Jasmine, innit?
Yes; who are you?
I'm from Hyderabad.
Venture a guess
Who it could be.
Farah!
No...
This isn't Farah's voice.
Yes,
It isn't Farah's voice.
Are you Afzal's sister,
Arifa?
Mum!
She's recognised me!
Give me the phone.
I'll talk to her.
Alright, tell me now,
Who am I?
Afzal's Mam.
There!
She's recognised me, too!
Honestly, my dear,
Do you have a special skill?
Is this knowledge because of your craft, or just guesswork?
I mean, I'd heard that ascetics can tell one's name from one's voice,
But never that lovers could be ascetics.
She's head over heels for Afzal!
Tell me, you're fair and comely, aren't you?
Come and see me.
How could I come when the rapscallion's not invited me...
It does sound like you are...
You're no less than Hyderabadis.
Let me talk to your Mum.
She's gone to the lapidary to get my jewellery polished.
She called the jeweller 'lapidary'.
She knows her English!
Who's there in your family besides your Mum?
Just my Mam and I.
Oh...
Didn't you ask him to bring his Mum and Dad along
If he's going to get engaged to you?
I did feel like saying that,
But I got scared.
Why were you scared?
I was scared that he may change his intentions.
Just let us get engaged,
I'll ask him after that.
In fact, I'll not say that;
I'd come over and bring Mam along.
You're saying that to make me happy, aren't you?
I like you this way.
Alright,
Talk to Arifa.
There's just the four of us over here,
My Mum,
Dad,
My brother, and I.
My brother's in Karachi, so take it
That there's 3 and 3 quarters of us.
3 and 3 quarters? How?
The three of us try our best to fill his absence through our memories of him.
That's why there's 3 and 3 quarters of us,
But not 4.
I've seen him somewhere.
It's
It's the same MP, innit,
Who wears kurta-pyjamas,
And rides a bike to Parliament?
What do I do with him?
You have to kill him.
He's an ace impostor.
He wears kurta-pyjamas and rides a bike to Parliament
To show the people.
I don't quite feel it's right.
Politicians today are great actors, M. Afzal.
They make one laugh
And cry as and when they want.
The people are so anguished
That sometimes, you can just see it.
The same anguish
Echoes later in the citizens' cries.
Don't fall for his tricks.
One who can make others cry can also impress.
His performance doesn't end here.
He doesn't stay at the MPs' hostel.
He's rented a small apartment.
He doesn't pay his rent for two months,
And hears the most vile insults from the landlord.
Then,
What good is killing such a man?
He barks like dogs in Parliament.
He says to honourable ministers, 'You are all looting the nation's money',
'You are all traitors'.
We have intelligence that he's working on someone's orders.
Whose orders?
Just think
That he's paid in Dollars to bark and insult.
Where does he keep the Dollars?
That's something we'd find out after he's dead.
One finds out about all the property owned by such people
When it's to be divided among their heirs.
And such people get elected to Parliament.
In this bag
Is 20 million in fresh notes.
Fresh.
All that's asked of you is that the murder should not look like one.
One can easily believe about such people
That, succumbing to mental illness, they've committed suicide.
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking why one would pay 20 million to kill a pigeon.
So we're going to kill a pigeon?
It's a man...
But the bugger's a proper pigeon...
Mr Zaki!
Yes?
You have guests.
Have them sit; I'm coming.
Alright.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
I'm sorry but I don't recognise you.
You don't seem to be from my constituency.
Do you recognise everyone from your constituency?
I don't recognise them by their names,
But I do, by their faces.
Pray tell what brings you here.
My name's Afzal.
Yes, Mr Afzal,
Pray tell
How I may be of help.
Be done with this act and tell me - who do you work for?
They don't let me work at all.
They stop me
If I say something,
And scold me
When I start working.
Speak for yourself.
Tell me where you keep the Dollars.
And who pays you Dollars to speak for him in Parliament?
I can take the Dollars, too, if I want.
But the thought of disgracing the Rupee scares me.
Who are you?
Get in the car.
Where'd you take me?
I'm sending you back.
Your time's up.
You could've come earlier.
I've been washing clothes for an hour.
Who'd wear them now?
Come. Please.
Come.
Wait.
Sit.
Aren't you afraid?
I am, yes...
If you address someone my age
With such disrespect,
I might as well die of shame!
So, it's better
That you do your job
Without all this insolence.
Tell me,
Why are they paying me 20 million to kill a twopenny man like you?
Go on.
If you address me so discourteously,
I won't answer.
Alright, I won't be discourteous.
Why do they want you dead, sir?
And why are you not afraid to die?
I'd pursued an MA in Politics.
At University,
They'd stress
Every lesson about democracy.
'Democracy is the rule of the people',
'By the people',
'For the people'.
It touched my heart,
So, I entered politics.
I was an energetic orator.
I'd give
Vision to the people,
So, they fell for my tricks
And they elected me with a lead of 54,000 votes.
I entered Parliament, burdened
With my promises and vision.
Only to find out soon enough
That the definition of democracy I'd studied
Was incorrect.
The correct one is,
'Democracy is the rule of the feudals',
'By the feudals',
'And for the feudals'.
The academic definition of Parliament is one thing --
Well, it isn't really relevant to you.
You've gotten your 20 million,
So, do your job,
And have a jolly good time.
Even if I 'earn' 20 million,
I don't 'have a 'jolly good time', Mr Zaki.
Then, distribute your 20 million
Among the people of my constituency.
By the Lord,
I'd commit suicide before you return.
It'd do your job,
And remove a thorn in their side.
And this will just be an excuse
To ease the pain of the those fools, the people of my constituency.
Otherwise, I'm usually sitting here, cowering,
Worried about how I'd face them.
Please get in the car.
I said, please get in the car.
Come.
Please, follow me.
Take a seat.
There's 20 million in fresh notes in it.
Get in my car and go to your constituency from here,
And distribute this 20 million among 'those fools'
Who'd trusted your vision.
And sleep peacefully when you return,
And roar on in Parliament tomorrow, assured
That nobody can dare touch you as long as I'm alive.
Who are you, my good sir?
I'm another one of 'those fools' who'd been waiting for 66 years for a leader who'd wash their own clothes,
And humbly listen to the landlord's insults for nor paying the rent for two months.
Don't call me 'my good sir' if we meet again.
I'd feel that you've accorded me respect if you just call me 'my good man'.
This bag's rather heavy.
You'll need help lifting it.
So, I'm sending someone along.
Timmy!
Take this bag and put it in one of our cars,
And ask the driver to stay with him.
'Democracy is the rule of the people',
'For the people',
'By the people'.
Thank you.
Is it done?
We've begun.
It'll be done in a few years.
No, M. Afzal, we just have 72 hours.
Those who've been kind to you don't even have 4 hours, sir.
Please, tell them
That if there's so much as a crease on Zaki Ahmed's pyjamas because of them,
I'll round them all up in a coffin.
I'll disconnect.
B --
-You can try me if you have any doubts.
The Lord's willed it [praise]!
May the evil gaze not touch you.
You look so sweet!
May the Lord protect you from every evil eye.
When would he be here?
After the dusk prayer.
Alright.
C'mon.
Sit.
Come, all of you.
Why don't you all take a seat?
They're here!
His Dad's dancing, too!
Do you know why he's dancing?
Because we've had dal chawal [Indian lentils and rice] made!
So we're serving dal chawal [Indian lentils and rice] today?
We aren't serving just dal chawal [Indian lentils and rice].
It's just that we're serving dal chawal [Indian lentils and rice] too!
Haven't they come?
They've all come.
And he looks very dashing.
I'm not talking about him.
I'm talking about Arifa and the others.
They've not come yet.
Perhaps they've had a change of heart at the last moment?
Hey!
Call Arifa.
Now's not the time to call.
They'd come here if they want, or stay at home.
I'll get going!
Quickly, now,
Be done with it already. The dusk prayer was quite a while ago!
Yes; just two more minutes.
Your two minutes have been going on for the last 15 minutes.
Go and see if Arifa's ready.
I'll be ready by the time she is.
Dad...
Here she is.
Here she is. You'd better come, now, too.
-Yes.
Take this, Dad.
Give this ring to her.
It's of no use to us now.
Whatever would she do with it, either?
Don't worry.
She'd only wear this one.
Let him know, too,
That the ring's gone up to her hand.
Alright, come.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV