Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
G -- Get this off me, doctor! I --
I'm going to see Mum!
Only after you've been unfettered!
For now, lie down!
There.
Dad's here.
M -- My heart is sinking.
Why is his heart sinking, Doctor?
-It's about the police! Happens with me, too!
Peace be upon you, sir.
And upon you, peace.
Is he alive?
He is.
Alright, go home,
I'll take care of him.
Alright.
Give this scarf to the driver and send him to us once his wound's been dressed.
Whose is it?
Farah's.
Here.
Could he talk?
Easily.
He asked, 'Where am I'?
Why did he ask that?
Because when he came to,
He wasn't where he was supposed to be...
He's out of harm's way, isn't he?
He is in harm's way.
If he slit his wrist properly the next time,
He won't be able to talk.
You'll just be left remembering him talking.
Your love has killed my son!
Not at all?
He's alive -- alright.
Have mercy on him!
Don't show ingratitude to God
By kicking away the lover at your doorstep!
Aunt -- The thing is --
I've made a vow...
If he got to Karachi safe and sound,
I'd offer 10 additional prayers.
Have some glucose.
It'll comfort your heart.
His heart won't get any comfort
As long as he doesn't get you.
He's here.
That's all it was!
Isn't he here?
Dad will bring him along.
He's alright, isn't he?
He's alright,
But his heart sunk at the sight of Dad!
Hey!
Doesn't it feel exhilarating
When one slits his wrist for someone?
Then change your mind.
To the Devil with your MPhil;
Think you've hit the jackpot
Getting a lover ready to lay down his life!
You're right,
But the nyaff didn't even slit his wrist properly!
Wouldn't he have died had he slit it properly?
One should have confidence in one's love, girl,
They say its mere touch vivifies.
And what about all those who died -
Heer, Laila, Majnun, Ranjha [Romeo & Juliet] -
Why weren't they vivified?
Lack of knowledge, sweetheart.
They didn't know
That if they tried a loving touch instead of struggling and dying in vain, they'd have been vivified!
Divined the 'news' somehow
And lay down their lives just like that!
Honestly,
Which film are you talking about?
I swear
I'm not talking about any film.
But my heart says
That love does have such power.
And I'm inclined to believe
What my heart says...
Did you hear, Madame,
What she just said?
She'll only find peace when he slits his wrist properly!
Don't worry, Madame,
She must be kidding.
Does she intend to kill the poor lad with such kidding?
There, now...
Hello, Afzal?
Hello?
I've left after waiting for two hours.
Your father left the office before my eyes
And never came back.
Ah, yes, I almost forgot!
We'd run into a right trouble at home.
Mehtab, you know,
Had slit his wrist.
Thankfully, we got to know on time.
He'd almost died.
For Farah?
No, for me!
He is bent upon laying down his life for Farah!
Such is his love?
Well,
He's proven it today.
I'll talk to you later.
Hey, listen!
We'll talk in a while.
Sit, Madame.
Sit.
Please listen carefully.
This is the last of his theatrics
That I've tolerated.
The entire neighbourhood would know if someone from my family had to see the doctor because he'd slit his wrist!
Let this be the closing bit of news after this one -
Mehtab's marriage to Farah is not possible.
What would he protect my daughter
Who couldn't protect his own life?
Yes, sir?
Apologies, my good man; something came up and I had to leave my office.
My PA mentioned that you'd come and left.
Yes, sir.
Please, come now.
I'll be reaching my office in about 15 minutes.
No, sir...
I'd be unable to come.
What do you mean?
I won't be coming, sir.
Here.
I'm giving him a cheque 400,000 instead of 200,000.
Shove it in his face.
Threaten him if you have to
That if he left his job without notice,
He'd have to pay a penalty amounting to three months' pay!
The blighter wouldn't even have dreamt of 400,000 Rupees!
Should I go to his place?
Obviously.
He's not answering his phone.
And should I also say that he should meet Dad?
He'd better.
And would Dad meet him after his refusal?
Or will you give him a cheque or 400,000 too
And say, 'You'd better meet him, Dad'.
Where does he live?
Just about four alleys from here.
Get the car.
Please, sit down.
You'd call upon him?
Got a problem?
His house isn't like ours
That you can pull him into a corner and talk about it!
You'd come across Arifa the moment you get there,
Then, his Mum,
And the Reverend is at home after the night prayer.
If you'd meet a man from his family before his eyes,
What would he think?
It'd be taken as your desperation.
I don't care.
You're the richest girl in the neighbourhood
But your dominion does not span it.
If the Reverend pronounced a judgement, you'd be utterly disgraced in a moment!
Judgement?
A Reverend's place is one of dignity,
And Mademoiselle would do well to honour it.
What kind of judgement?
A faithful girl strikes a deal
With a Reverend's son about 'love',
With the condition that he should two-time her.
You tell me if a harsh judgement ought to be ordained or not!
You're digging your own grave there.
And remember,
Just as the spade strikes the ground, Dad will have you sit in a palanquin for Mehtab.
Besides, you've earned a bad name in the entire neighbourhood because of Mehtab.
Sorry,
But a 'bad name' is the only way to say it in polite company.
Give me his number.
Sure.
Hello?
Hello.
This is my number
And it's me speaking.
Remember,
If you stayed quiet today,
I could become your worst nightmare!
Reply to everything properly.
You're under your Dad's oath now,
Tell me that you're listening.
I'm listening.
Splendid.
Now I know how to get you talking.
Tell me, now,
Why did you refuse to meet Dad?
What would it do if I met him?
What's that noise?
It's --
It's the lads from the neighbourhood playing cricket.
Brilliant!
And you're there, betting on it!
I'm not into betting anymore.
I've signed a cheque of 400,000 for you.
Take it from Lubna whenever you want.
But I won't meet your father.
Why not?
Am I blowing these 400,000 for nothing?
I won't collect those 400,000 either.
What's the matter with you?
Changing your colours like a chameleon!
I felt I was doing something worse than gambling,
So, I thought I would rather not.
To the --
Care to tell me
How saving a girl's life
Is something wrong?
When someone else loses his life as one tries to save a girl's life,
That makes it very wrong.
Oh!
So you've come to know about the incident with the blighter Mehtab!
Don't push love away,
And don't call one who loves you a 'blighter'.
Honestly,
Has your girlfriend come to know?
Has she asked you
Not to love Farah?
Tell that twit
It's not for real!
For the first time, someone's getting paid to 'love'!
Oh, she hasn't the foggiest.
She doesn't know anything.
Look,
I'm in a proper mess.
And you're intent on betraying me.
This sword called Mehtab is ready to strike my head off!
Dad's perplexed, too, because of your refusal.
God forbid if he voted in favour of Mehtab...
I'd --
I'd curse you!
And remember,
My curses always work!
If I vow to offer 100 additional prayers, my wish is granted after just 12 of them!
Fear me,
Or I'd say,
'May you never get the one who writes you letters'!
Wait!
Please don't curse me like this!
Scared the bejesus out of him!
Alright, then,
You're coming to office tomorrow, aren't you?
I will.
Call Dad the moment I disconnect,
Say sorry and tell him you're coming tomorrow.
So much noise!
Cookie's been caught out.
Who's Cookie?
One of the lads.
Anyway.
You'd call him, right?
I will in a moment.
Okay, bye!
I will tell you when I can understand it myself.
It felt as if he'd shoved me from behind and I'd fallen face first!
Said plainly, 'I'm not coming',
And disconnected.
Figure out what it could mean and tell me!
Pay him a visit.
But I can swear we'd find no better suitor for Farah than him!
There's no need to go there now.
He'll come to meet you tomorrow,
And apologise to you too.
Why did he refuse, then?
Because of Mehtab.
He thought
It's not good to have someone like him in the house
Who'd attempt suicides for me!
He shouldn't have taken a half-dead Mehtab to the doctor in the first place.
Please decide the time for tomorrow.
I'll call and tell him.
No --
Please don't call him.
He'd have to apologise
Before you talk to him.
Just fix an appointment.
Lubna will call and tell him the time.
The same -
9 a.m.
May I go now?
Alright, go.
Yes, come in!
How do I come in?
You've bolted the door!
What's with bolting the door?
I --
Wasn't quite paying attention --
Wasn't quite paying attention -- And -- Bolted it.
Beware, Monsieur Afzal.
You may get caught!
Why do you always suspect me?
Ask forgiveness!
I've never suspected you.
I always trust you, but you compel me to doubt!
Alright, please, go. I'm feeling sleepy.
Your phone's ringing.
So it is.
When the phone's with me,
It would ring now and then...
Answer it, then.
I will.
But never before me, eh?
Right...
Please, Arifa, leave. I'm very sleepy!
Alright,
Promise me you'd sleep without answering the phone.
It's stopped ringing.
You'll see, it'll ring again soon.
And why are you going to bed so early?
Mind if I say something to rouse you?
Go on.
Dad's found out that you don't go to your office anymore.
You blew the gaff on me after all!
-He told me himself.
Said, 'We are God's men'.
'We get the news even when we don't get it'.
You should fear, Afzal.
If he indeed gets the news,
He'd know who she is.
He may say it over lunch tomorrow,
'Listen, my good man'!
'Her father had come to pray today'.
'Sat with me for long',
And what they talked about in their meeting...
God alone knows better.
Bolt the door, now,
Answer your phone,
And forget that you'd be able to sleep.
The blighter!
There he is, the geezer!
I mean -- the good man.
Peace, Uncle.
And upon you [as well].
How are you now?
I'm great.
Alright, then, get ready.
You're leaving for Karachi in half an hour.
What?
Look, you can't make us accept you as ours,
So it's better you'd not worsen our ties.
Your suicide attempt has embarrassed me greatly.
Your mother's almost ready
And waiting for you downstairs.
That which was destined to happen has come to be,
So you should better do what's best.
May I get ten minutes?
For what?
I want to sit on this swing one last time.
Sit, then.
No.
Not before you
But alone.
You may not like to hear it, but
Consider this the last wish of one who's about to depart.
Fulfil your wish.
Lubna will come and tell you when ten minutes have passed.
Otherwise, she'll tell me.
You wouldn't have to bother.
I won't sit here for more than 10 minutes.
Okay.
Come.
Hello?
Peace be upon you.
And upon you.
Why weren't you answering the phone?
Arifa was with me.
You could've texted me that she's with you.
Next time, I will text.
Alright.
9 a.m. has been decided upon.
9 a.m.?
Yes.
You'll go to the office and meet Dad tomorrow morning.
I'll meet him.
Right,
Don't do anything stupid.
I handled it today, saying
That you got angry because of Mehtab.
I'd be out of excuses tomorrow!
I'll be very careful.
You don't worry.
Please, tell me, though,
What if he said,
'I'd like to meet your parents'?
Why, let him meet them!
That would seal everything.
Dad will be delighted to hear,
And exclaim, 'Such is my son's good fortune'!
What else am I paying 800,000 for?
What?
You forgot already!
We'd decided that you'd turn out perfidious in the end!
How could I turn out perfidious?
Dad will remain firm over his word.
We don't accept perfidy here.
Don't scare me.
I swear I'm not trying to scare you.
I'm afraid myself.
But think over it and tell me,
Must I be perfidious?
There's no other option!
We may just be parted...
What?
I'm saying it right -
It'd do your job, and
Save love from this calumny.
Are you alright?
What 'love' and 'calumny' are you talking about?
No, I was just saying --
Love
Is pious
And in perfidy is its calumny.
Yet if that's what you desire, alright,
We'd calumniate it.
Alright, wait.
Let Lubna come; we'll talk then.
Should I call later?
No.
I'll call you myself.
Alright.
I'll stay awake.
It would've been better if she'd come too.
We'd have seen her face one last time as we left.
I think she's retired.
Alright.
As it pleases her...
Come.
Sit.
Come, my dear.
God be with ye.
Bye.
Fire!
By God! Fire!
T --
-Where?
Mlle Farah's swing on the terrace!
It's all up in flames!
Come!
Quickly! Get some water!
Get some water!
Afzal!
Yes, Dad?
You're still awake?
I'm about to sleep, Dad.
Go to sleep early, my son.
You have to go to work in the morning.
Right, Dad.
Shut up, Lubna!
Sleep peacefully, already!
He would've reached Karachi by now!
Or you could call him
And mouth every four-letter word you can!
That's exactly what he wants
That I should call
And abuse him!
And he'd be delighted to hear them!
I won't insult him
For he doesn't even deserve that.
Hey!
It's 2.30 already!
So what?
Take another leave.
It's not about taking a leave, Lubna.
I'd asked Afzal to wait for my call.
When did you say that?
Before the fire started.
Right...
That was three hours ago.
What do I do now?
You'd better not call him. The poor man must be sleeping now.
But why had you told him you'd call?
I don't know what had gotten into him!
He said,
'In perfidy is love's calumny'.
'So, instead of that',
'We may just be parted'.
He gave me a right fright there.
I said it, promptly,
'I'd ask Lubna for advice'
'And then talk to you'.
God...
Think of something!
He said
That if Dad invited his parents,
His father would finalise everything that instant!
So let him!
Listen to the whole thing.
His father is the kind who'd stay true to his words.
And also
They don't accept perfidy there.
What are you looking at?
I'm not looking...
I'm thinking
How fortunate the girl he loves is!
As if I care a hoot!
Don't insult love like this.
It afflicts even the likes of you in its anger!
Let's talk business, shall we?
Text him and ask him to postpone the meeting with Dad.
How would he postpone it?
He could call and say,
Something came up and he's got to leave for Karachi,
And it'd take a few days.
What would that do?
Buy a few days' time
To think, strategise, and decide.
But this time,
You'd better both think and strategise.
I'd say
Get the poor man out of this trouble too.
Mehtab's gone,
And judging by the way he's left,
I don't think he's ever coming back.
The danger is past.
Now, it's better that you free Afzal too.
You're using up all of his girlfriend's time.
This is not fair.
Pay him for this farce
And relieve him from this responsibility.
What will I say to Dad?
Dad is Dad, after all.
What's the worst that can happen even if he found out the truth?
He'd be a bit angry,
But getting angry with you is something he's incapable of,
So, he'd just forgive you and spare himself.
So I should sign a cheque of 800,000?
Sign one.
He's hit the jackpot then!
'Your work is done... You don't need to meet Dad now... I've signed a cheque of 800,000; collect it from Lubna... Thanks'.
I've made some for you as well.
Have it.
Your suit's in the cupboard,
And Eladio polished your shoes last night.
Sit down, will you?
What's the matter?
And what's this?
You came here straight from bed?
Why, mate?
There's no water here to wash your face.
What would you do?
I'm not going anywhere.
I've come to meet you.
Hey!
Weren't you full of yourself last night saying you've got to go there early in the morning?
Yesterday's plan ended this morning.
Mind if I ask you something?
Not at all.
Is there room for being self-seeking in love?
Only in love is there room for being self-seeking, you bugger!
How much?
As much as possible.
One's got to be willing
To reduce the world to ashes to get one's beloved!
Do you know the last thing Samina had told me?
What?
'Elope with me'.
'Get legally married to me'.
I said, 'You're insane'.
She got married ten days later,
And I felt like I lost my sanity.
Remember,
Don't turn tail once you fall in love.
Or you'd end up like me, bugger!
Today, I listen to others' stories,
And she, her husband's abuses.
I've learnt this at the price of losing her -
Don't think what Dad will say when you fall in love;
See, instead, what your heart says.
Where've you kept the suit?
In the cupboard over there.
So you're going?
Yes.
Hello?
This is Ibrahim speaking.
You don't need to come to the office.
Bring your parents to our place after nightfall.
I'd like to talk to them first.
Tell them they'd be having dinner with us.
Ri -- Right, Uncle.
Alright. Take care.
Okay?
He didn't wash his face and hands,
Didn't change his clothes,
Didn't have breakfast... How did he leave for office?
It's never happened this way before!
Leave it be, Dad.
You know, too, that he doesn't go to his office now.
He does say he's leaving for office.
I have a feeling she studies at some university.
I have no problem with it,
If only the whippersnapper would tell me who she is!
Suspicion isn't justified either, Reverend.
Ask Arifa
If I've ever suspected him,
Pronounce a judgement against me.
Dad's right, Mum.
She studies at a university.
See?
You're back from the office already?
I --
I don't go to the office now, Dad.
My job ended on the second day itself.
You could've told me earlier.
I get the news
And get to know everything.
Anyway.
What have you thought about, now?
What would you do?
May I get married, Dad?
In the name of God! [auspicious beginning]
Would you tell us after you've tied the knot,
Or invite us too?
I hold you very dear, Dad.
I fear both your anger and affection,
Which is why I make mistakes.
Talk about your marriage.
You're splendid, Reverend.
How can he get married?
He's got no job and earns nothing.
And only God knows who's the one he's carrying on with!
Sh -- She's pure and fair.
But
I'm not getting married just yet.
I just want you to
Get things started.
Get things started with whom?
With Monseigneur Sheikh Ibrahim.
How does Monseigneur know her?
She's --
Monseigneur's --
Daughter.
What?
Wha --
Come again? What --?
Did you hear what he just said?
No, I'd say you tell me again --
Wh -- What do you want to say? I --
I couldn't quite get it --
Wha -- What do you want to say?
I --
I'm talking about Monseigneur.
It's fine up to that point.
But I think I heard that you...
Are talking about his daughter.
I'm --
I'm going to marry his daughter.
There he is saying it again.
I mean,
One who'd not give him a job has agreed to give him his daughter.
His pulse is alright,
Nor has he got a fever...
Still, it'd be better if you see a doctor.
Someone like me
Cannot know about the afflictions of the mind.
He's invited the two of you
To dinner
After the night prayer.
He's saying the same thing again, Ruqaiyya; tell him
That excesses of either delight or shock are bad for me
And if something happened to me,
Your Afzal would be responsible for it!
Dad, I'm telling the truth!
Keep on saying that, my good man.
I can't believe it.
I'd have gone up to the terrace for a stroll
Were it not so sunny!
Afzal's right.
My friend, Lubna -
She's the one who writes him letters!
She even calls him.
I'd answered once too!
I think she's been successful!
She would've convinced her father!
No -- It's --
Not Lubna!
Ask me first!
You just saw the name on the phone and said what you figured before everyone!
It's not Lubna.
Then?
Farah.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV