Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
My Afzal!
He's alright, isn't he?
Yes, he's --
He's alright.
Sit down.
Sit...
If...
If you are tormented like this,
It'd make things difficult for me.
This lordly wont of yours of whacking him,
Get this out of yourself!
Your son's a young man.
And he's --
Out of control, at that.
What if, one of these days,
He went astray?
So?
You've forgotten already!
He threatens us
With his departure
From here!
Should I yield to his threats?
It won't be this way, Reverend,
If he does something wrong,
I'll whack him.
Alright, then, don't budge!
But remember, also,
That it won't be like this every time.
One of these days, you'll wake up
To the news that he's boarded the 3.15 a.m. train and left!
This is why
I'm keeping good terms with the Doctor.
So that if I have to tell you something like this,
I would
Bring the Doctor along
And say to him,
'Keep every medicine for the heart ready'.
'I'm about to tell Ruqaiyya'.
Praise the Lord [Subhanallah], Reverend!
Praise the Lord [Subhanallah]!
You just told me.
The blighter's left, eh?
If he boarded the 3.15 a.m. train, he'd have arrived there by now.
You're alright, aren't you?
You wept at your Mum's death,
That's when I last saw those tears.
And then, I'm seeing them today.
Fear God, Reverend.
Don't vilify my Afzal with your tears.
Praise the Lord [Subhanallah]!
It's beating like a train.
Chuff-chuff!
You --
You're alright, aren't you?
Well, what does it look like?
So what if I'm Afzal's mother?
I'm also Reverend Subhanallah's wife.
And breakfast too.
You've come from Lahore?
You stare as if you're from Lahore.
Hey, mate,
How much will it be?
-40.
How do the Lahoris stare?
Like I used to.
When I came here from Lahore, I used to stare at people like you do.
Where are you from?
Nowhere.
You looking for a place to rent?
Nobody came to get you, you had breakfast at the bistro and are now sitting at the bus stop.
Which means you've come here like a certain Lahori.
Won't you check what kind of a man I am?
Alright, tell me what kind you are.
Not the good kind...
Then come along, will you?
I'm not the good kind either.
However fast you stravaig about,
You can't get to Karachi.
He's gone.
He's switched off his phone.
Now, you can't apologise to him even if you want to.
Why would I apologise to him?
I've begun to augur like you.
Like you knew last night that he's going.
You'd even said,
'He's out now', 'He's gotten there', 'He's left'!
Just like that, I have a feeling you're desperate to apologise to him.
Of course, I'm not!
I hear words like these as an augury.
But wait and watch what happens in the evening.
-What?
I'd find you on the terrace.
So?
So what? Let the evening come; you'll see...
Does he have another number?
I'm pitying
His Mum and Dad.
If he turned back and returned,
I wouldn't have any problem apologising.
Just for...
Humanity's sake?
Ask your Dad not to lead the prayers for a few days.
Only the Lord can take care of a prayer
That constantly reminds one of the son...
I could bathe six times with so much water.
And in five minutes, not a drop will drip from the tap.
Oh? Why is that?
She cuts off the water supply at 8.
Who?
The landlady's daughter.
So
Why don't you talk to the landlady?
Don't you pay the rent?
I did.
Except the last four months.
How much is the rent?
6,000.
6,000 a month?
Aye.
How say I pay it?
A total of 24,000?
Yes.
Be my guest.
But steel yourself for you won't be getting it back.
I won't demand it.
Oh...
You're developing a relationship, eh?
Aye.
Tell me...
Tell me something about yourself.
What do you do?
What's your name?
Tell me his name!
What's your problem?
How many times do I tell you!?
Hey!
Tell me!
That's --
There's a girl screaming!
You get to hear this on Saturday nights.
The shinach comes steamin' fou.
The shinach is her husband.
Then, he remembers his wife's old affair.
What's he full of?
You belong to this world, don't you?
Don't you know what it means to be fou?
Oh...
That stuff.
Not 'that stuff',
The sup.
The pric pwdin drinks the bevvy.
Then, he asks her the bloke's name;
He knows it very well, but still asks her.
'Where did you meet', 'Where do you talk',
'Where do you meet', 'What are youse twos up to' - Every single detail.
And she tells him everything?
She's told him everything before her marriage.
Now, she just
Takes a right walloping, and says...
Stop it, will you?
You've donged me twice already!
Everyone will hear it
If I scream.
Be done with it already!
It doesn't look proper for a man to cry.
There!
Please stay quiet!
Let me do the talking.
Step aside.
-Wait, Jasmine!
Step aside!
I'll clobber him today!
Leave it be.
He's crying in a corner now.
Who's...
Who's this girl?
She's the landlady's daughter.
She's the blighter who cuts off the water supply here.
Don't peek from the window;
If she saw you, she'd turn and barge in here. Come in.
Why would she come?
I'm not allowed to have guests stay over; come in.
Yes, Dad?
Sit.
Why are you so anxious?
No?
It's nothing like that.
You
Just called me so suddenly...
I figured it must be something important.
Now, I'm anxious...
What it may be...
Your going to London is nothing to get anxious about.
I'm going to London?
That's what I'm asking - when?
Never?
What are you saying?
I mean, what's the need to go to London?
I'm all alone.
What would I do there?
But your mother told me you'd rather not get married.
Not at all, Dad...
I didn't say I won't get married.
I said I'd rather not get married just yet. I would in a year or two...
What about your MPhil, then?
I'll go to Karachi for it.
We have a house there, too!
Lubna can come along too.
When did you think of this?
The same day I thought I'm not going to London at all.
You seem a bit disturbed.
Tell me if there's any problem.
You may take your time if the haste has gotten you perplexed.
Think carefully.
Discuss it with your Mum or Lubna.
Alright.
I'll discuss it with Lubna.
-Sit.
What is your problem?
There's no problem.
Everything's alright, Dad.
What's alright?
I'm your father, not a chickpea chapman!
I'm talking to you about your career!
So what have I done?
You're saying you'd discuss it with Lubna after telling me everything?
But it was you who'd said,
'Discuss it with Lubna'...
Alright, call Lubna here.
She's standing outside.
Come in, Lubna.
Lubna, come in.
I've told Dad that you're --
Just outside...
Yes, Dad?
What were you doing, standing outside?
Nothing, Dad.
I'd come with her.
Then, I realised that it was just supposed to be between the two of you.
So, I thought I'd stand outside.
Come and sit.
What is going on in her mind these days?
Karachi.
It's --
Right...
So the two of you have talked about the Karachi plan already.
Yes...
And what would you do there?
Me?
What would I do, Dad?
You've still got three semesters left.
Semesters?
If you've talked about it, haven't you thought about your admission?
What if you waste your first semester?
Alright, you don't have to worry about anything. Don't worry about your admission.
But has either of you thought about what'd happen to us over here?
The two of you would be left alone...
Thank goodness, Mademoiselle remembers as much.
How could I not remember?
How would you stay alone?
I'm not leaving you.
Get her out, Lubna.
She'll shred my brain into a spaghetti.
Discuss it thoroughly with her today,
And tell me what it is that she wants tomorrow.
Come.
Good night, Dad...
Why have you come to Karachi?
Looking for a job?
To become a great man.
So are you a twopenny-halfpenny man?
Nowhere will you find a great man if he's not inside you.
Why did you come to Karachi?
Don't ask me anything, boyo...
Then don't ask me anything either.
I'll see whose oul' fella's got the guts to stop me once I become a great man!
Give me the gasper.
25 runs were needed to win in the last over of a match.
Everyone thought it's impossible.
Because when you need 25 runs to win in the last over, you just can't make it.
But I made it.
Didn't he figure out why you're talking about going to Karachi?
Figure out?
I've told him clearly that I'll be pursuing my MPhil there.
He was chuffed to hear that I dropped the option of London.
For Afzal?
What?
How does that even make sense?
Am I pursuing my MPhil for him?
Are you touched in the head?
Then why Karachi?
Why not Lahore or Islamabad?
Do I look like a moran?
I know you inside out, Farah Ibrahim.
That is why Dad's asked me to find out what you're up to.
So you think I'm going after Afzal?
You loony lass,
If I had to go after him,
Why did I let him out of here in the first place?
But, because of him, I've thought
That one should not leave one's parents like this.
I keep on thinking about Aunt Ruqaiyya
And the Reverend.
They've only got one son,
One so magnificent [= Afzal] at that!
I don't believe that.
Believe what?
Your intentions and actions
Are polar opposites.
You remember him more than his Mum and Dad!
You'll get whacked by me now.
I'd take it.
But I won't go with you on this SAR mission with you!
I'm not insisting that you do.
Don't come if you don't want to.
I'd just mentioned your name to ease Dad.
How does it ease Dad?
If you're with me, I'd thought,
Mum and Dad would think I'm not alone there.
Someone's there to look after me.
A fib.
I can swear on it.
So you're not going after him?
Ask forgiveness of God!
And you don't love him either?
God forgive!
Place your hand on my head.
Swear on me.
I swear by you.
But if I chance upon him somewhere,
I'd grab his collar.
Why?
I'll say, 'Come to Hyderabad, you blighter'!
'Your Mum and Dad are looking for you'.
Who are you to say that?
I mean, if he asked,
'Who are you to ask this'?
'Who are you to me'?
'And who do you mean by Mum and Dad'?
'The same you'd invited over and humiliated'?
'And before whom'
'You'd humiliated me at my home'?
What would you say to that?
Would he say all of that?
As if he'd laud you for grabbing his collar!
Remember,
It's his turn now.
You got him out of Hyderabad, and this fact won't ever get out of his heart.
He'll get even with you one day.
Get even?
'Like a king would treat another'.
How would a king treat another?
I'll tell you tomorrow.
I don't know it well enough.
But I have a feeling it's very cruel.
Step aside.
Where's that blighter Babu Hamid?
Babu Hamid!
Now where did he go?
And who would you be?
Good Lord, it's you!
What are you doing here?
Have we met before?
Met, as in?
Do we have those meetings?
Not at all --
You just said, 'It's you'.
Pray tell, who?
I saw you on the train.
You were coming to Karachi from Lahore.
No, I was on the train from Lahore to Karachi.
You don't have the manners to sit at your place,
Spreading your legs as if they're someone else's!
Go.
'Go'?
Would you leave yourself or do I need to grab your hand and drag you out?
What?
What did you just say?
You'd drag me out
Out of here?
Out of this house?
And you'd grab my hand, too!
That's tidy; tell me,
Where are you from?
In which city of the world is it a trend that it's no problem if you grab Jasmine's hand like that?
I've come from Hyderabad.
And if you said again that I'm tailing you,
I'd thro --
-Throw?
Mam!
Your Mum's the same one, is she?
From the train?
You're going to --
Just end this quarrel and leave.
There's no Babu Hamid around here.
-How come?
I'm Babu Hamid.
I'd just gone to get some breakfast.
You've kept her standing all this time?
As if he'd have me sit, Syr Babu!
He was about to throw me out.
Who's this blighter?
Such a brash girl!
Shut up, boyo, she's my landlady.
And...
He's -- no blighter either,
He's a rather topping [Afzal] type.
You've come to collect the rent, haven't you?
You're saying as if you've got the money in your pocket!
Exactly.
I've got it in my pocket since the morning.
Hold this, will you?
Right here.
That's a total of 24,000 there.
But what's he doing here?
If he's come to meet, that's alright,
If he's here to stay, show him out right now. C'mon!
Get out!
No -- He can't leave.
How wouldn't he? Even his Tad would --
-If you mentioned my Dad, I'd break your face!
Good Lord!
He's a ruffian!
No, he's --
-Mam!
Mam!
A ruffian!
Why does she call out to her Mum every time?
She's got no one except her Mum.
-Mum, a ruffian!
Mum, a ruffian's broken in! Come here quickly!
-Why doesn't she come here, then?
She's wise.
What's that bosh?
It's just that you don't know the true story...
These 24,000 you have clenched in your hands,
He's paid it.
If you kick him out, your money's obviously out the door too.
So, either you can
Return the money,
Or just talk to your Mam for once.
Alright.
I'll be back after talking to Mam.
That's tidy.
She won't be coming back.
Why?
She's a blighter,
She won't ask; she'll be advising,
'To the devil with all sorrows if we're getting the rent on time'.
Alright, let's just have breakfast, shall we?
Come. Here.
Where are the plates -- Oh, right.
Don't let her go to Karachi.
I won't let her go anywhere until she's been married.
Then talk it out with her straight.
Everything's been talked about.
You don't talk, Madame, you chaffer.
'Talk' as in, explain it to her.
And 'explain' as in, she's got to agree.
She's not being reasonable when deciding.
She acts first and thinks later.
It was just yesterday
She was ready to wager everything to be able to go to London.
And today, she's suddenly figured that she should be going to Karachi?
Do you know why she wants to go to Karachi?
Because Afzal's left home and gone to Karachi.
Are you in your senses?
We've talked to her about Afzal already.
Has she forgotten
The day she'd insulted Afzal?
Once, before us, and then again, at his home!
You've forgotten too,
You'd said just a while ago,
'She acts first and thinks later'.
So, she's thinking right now that she had not been fair on Afzal.
Good morning.
-Good morning.
So you've decided to go to Karachi?
Yes?
I'd told you already.
Think over it again.
Why should I need to think over it again?
I've decided after a lot of thinking.
That's what you think.
Everyone else thinks that you'd ponder over it after you've left.
Why are you making an issue of it?
You should be delighted.
Because I'm not delighted.
That's why I've decided that you're not going to Karachi.
What the devil is going on?
Care to tell me?
How could I tell you?
I haven't the foggiest about what it is Dad wants to talk about.
Put a sock in it!
Dad said
That I'd think after I've left,
And that everybody thinks this way.
Everybody, as in,
Including you.
But I'd only told Mum about this,
And said that it's strictly confidential.
What?
She was working on your character sketch.
She was trying to fathom her Farah's noble qualities.
I thought
She didn't know about this one.
But don't worry.
Dad will think about who it is he's messing with.
Say your prayers.
Why?
Do you doubt my belief in the Lord?
I doubt my belief that you're alive!
Say your prayers,
Or you'd be herded along with the sinners!
What are you looking for?
I'm looking for a knife!
You'd kill me?
Let me just find a knife, I'll tell you!
Hey!
Don't talk about bloodshed.
Just go and say it plainly that you've fallen for Afzal,
And you're going after him.
Bring your head over here.
What'd you do with my head?
Place my hand on it and swear that I don't love Afzal!
Just think as if
I've not exactly despised him.
There, now.
Don't surprise me.
Why would you be surprised?
I have some experience too, Farah.
So what, if I've never fallen in love?
I have borne witness to love blossoming.
You haven't the 'e' of experience,
Not with your world going round thanks to devilry and bijoux!
Just let me get to Karachi,
I'll scupper all your experience and send it to Davy Jones' Locker!
There are only two ways out for me:
Drown in the ocean,
Or surface and get across.
Honestly,
Have you come here after you lost in love?
I've triumphed in love and come.
And one who loves like me can never lose.
Why, then, do you talk like you've lost?
Why did you say
That there's just two ways out for you?
There's but one road to love
That starts from the heart
And ends at the beloved's doorstep.
Is there someone in your way?
Yes.
Who?
A twopenny-halfpenny man who looks like me.
I'd been hiding behind him,
Which is why she could never seen me.
How many runs did you score in the final over of the match?
25.
Amazing.
Then, it'd do you good to hear and remember that love is a match that's all about the final over, Syr Afzal.
You'll only score as many runs as she'd want you to,
And if she does not,
On all six balls,
You may get beaten all ends up.
I know how to play cricket.
And I've learnt to love.
Remember that if I ever needed to score 25 runs there,
I'd do it.
Otherwise, only my corse would be returning to Hyderabad.
Should it have to come to that,
Please send my corse with your own hands.
And never say that I'm going back defeated.
Even if I'm beaten all ends up,
You'll see that I've won.
And said,
'I'd throw' --
-Throw?
And it's now that you're telling me!
He never said anything beyond that.
Wouldn't I have broken his jaw had he said anything?
-He did 'throw' you. Isn't that enough?
You and your words, Mam!
He didn't actually throw me,
Just said it as they do!
Who says such words to a girl?
I'll talk to him in the morning.
One should never tell you anything, Mam!
I told you, he just uttered it casually.
If you show him this fury or kick him out, we'll have to give him 24,000 back.
Why would we have to return it?
Because he's paid it.
And Babu Hamid?
He'll collect his 500 or 1,000 and leave.
I'll whack him on his face with a boot.
He'll take that boot but won't leave without his 500.
What are his dues, besides the rent?
14,800.
No --
He'd given 600; now, he's got 14,200 due.
Alright, note it down, will you?
It'll be 14,700 tomorrow.
What happened?
Isn't it good?
It'll take a while.
It takes time to start liking and digest Karachi's food.
Would you prefer home-cooked food?
How'd I get that?
You can.
Our landlady, you know,
She'd cook you some.
She'd charge for it each month, though.
Oh, her!
She'd serve it peppery!
-No, it's her Mam who cooks.
Back when I had some money, she was the one who'd provide me.
So when there's no money in it,
There's no food?
No, boyo.
She does blabber a bit.
But she used to cook me food.
I had some shame,
So I said I'd eaten something already whenever she asked.
You used to lie?
Yes,
Sometimes...
So what was the last thing you said?
He's been saying the same thing for 15 minutes.
That you cook the food and collect your money each month.
So,
How much would you take?
Ask him to shut his gob.
He has a bad reputation in Mam's eyes.
Go on.
What were you saying?
We'd serve you food and you'd pay us for it each month?
Exactly.
Just like old times?
Enjoyed your food for three months and gobbled up the payment for a month!
Talk to me.
I'll enjoy the food for two months and pay you for three.
Ask him what he thinks I am.
Hold it right there you lippy laddie!
I hand over 50 or a 100 to the likes of you every now and then!
Anyway,
Go on.
Go on with what?
How much would you pay?
The payment would be the same old one.
8,000 a month?
Remember how much potatoes cost back then?
And you'd get lentils for a 100 Rupees a kilogramme.
It's 120 now.
How much do spices cost?
Spices, let's see...
Why are you asking about spices?
No, it's just -- You were mentioning the rates, so I thought you could just as well tell me about spices too.
Look,
Let me get this straight,
I'll charge 10,000 per head for the food.
Let me know if it's okay; otherwise, I'm off.
It's okay.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV