Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Have some tea, my dear.
I'm sure she's talked to you about going to London for her MPhil.
Yes.
Yes, she has.
What did you say?
I said,
'Alright, thank you'.
She should've been the one to say 'Thank you'.
I thanked her because she asked me.
Oh...
Good...
Excuse me.
It's my sister.
Hello?
Yes, how's it going?
You're still awake?
I'm asking you how it's going.
Have you succeeded?
Succeeded?
The meeting's going on.
It'll be over in a while.
You're hiding something.
I'll be back -- In a while.
Sorry.
If I don't answer her call,
She gets angry over it.
So, you were saying
She'll be going to London for her MPhil?
That's done, old chap.
Tell me - if the marriage is indeed fixed,
Would you go to London?
Not at all --
-But of course!
You just said yes inside!
That you'd go along!
I would, of course,
But it doesn't seem nice
That the wife goes to London for her studies,
And the husband follows her around like a bodyguard.
My conscience doesn't quite allow me.
But I've agreed to.
That's like a man.
Alright, then. See you tomorrow morning at 9 at the office.
Hear good news as you leave that we are both very pleased to meet you.
And we
Have no objections to this marriage.
Thank you, sir.
Tell her, too.
She'll be delighted too!
Alright.
Who can it be?
Young lady,
Would you see who it is?
I'll take my leave.
Best of luck.
Thank you, sir.
I'll ask the driver to leave you --
-No, sir.
It's just about four streets away to my home.
I'll go myself.
I've told her.
She's delighted to hear.
Goodbye, my dear.
-Goodbye.
What happened?
It's him again!
Who's there again?
The same who'd come before.
Tell me his name.
I don't quite remember his name.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace...
Please have the outer gate opened; my car's outside.
Go.
Open the gate.
She dashed inside the moment she saw me.
He's --
Mehtab Bhai.
Who's this?
Afzal.
Alright, Afzal, you may leave.
Nice to meet you.
Same here.
What is it this time?
He's here.
Wh --
I think you want to say
'He's gone'?
Not at all.
I'm saying 'He's here'.
With his Mum!
Hey!
His Mum's here too!
Care to ask who I'm talking about?
Who are you talking about?
Mehtab Chawla.
His Mum's with him,
And both of them have such expressions
As the spectral undead!
In fact,
In fact, if Dad declined a second time,
Aunt Shugufta would be no more.
Why would he be any more, the spalpeen!
-Look at his face.
He doesn't need to die a second time.
It would be better if you get some rest tonight.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
All tranquility's been burnt to ashes, Monseigneur.
Would you look at him?
He's not slept for three days!
Ain't right, my dear.
It's important to get some sleep.
Why don't you
Give him that pill --
Whatsit --
Leave the name.
If he takes one now,
He'll wake up tomorrow in the afternoon, all fresh!
I have it with me; should I get it?
I've gotten him many pills,
Begged him day and night,
'Take one, my dear'.
'If you sleep for a while, you'd find peace'.
But do you know what he said?
What?
He said, 'I'll find peace when I take a bullet right here in the chest'.
Hey!
Why are you crying, Madame?
Please, be brave.
Don't ask me to be brave, Monseigneur.
Please change your decision.
I told you we'll talk about it tomorrow.
I can beg Farah if you'd rather...
I'll fall at her feet.
I'll ask forgiveness if he's unknowingly said something wrong to her.
No -- Not at all --
What are you talking about?
Monseigneur, we accept every condition of hers.
If she wants to go to London for her studies, we have no objections.
He won't even go along with her.
It's just a matter of two years.
He'll wait.
That's fine,
But there's someone else who's going with her.
Good.
Why should the girl leave the country all alone?
Someone ought to go along.
You didn't quite get it...
We've decided something else.
We've talked about it
And Farah is delighted too.
What have you decided?
We'll talk tomorrow.
He doesn't seem well.
Mehtab?
Why don't you say something, my dear?
Yes?
Mehtab,
Have you had anything to eat?
Nothing.
I think he had something the day before yesterday.
What did you have?
Right,
I'd gone to the shrine of Abdullah Shah Ghazi.
I'd received some rice as sacrament,
He'd eaten it because he wanted the blessings.
He just drinks water now.
Won't you eat something?
Get up.
Go and eat something right now.
Get up!
Irsa, take him and get him something to eat.
Come, my dear.
One doesn't stop eating over such trifles.
Come.
Monseigneur,
For the love of God, have some mercy.
Look at his condition.
I'd said we'll talk about it tomorrow.
For now, go and have something to eat, and then get some rest.
No...
I'll meet Farah first.
Please, do meet her.
But don't beg before her.
Alright.
This is utter harlequinade!
Coming here with his Mum when I've rejected the proposal!
Now he'll stay here
Waltz around before everyone,
And grab my hand the moment he gets a chance!
Splendid.
Why would he grab your hand now?
And if he does indeed by mistake,
Whack him nicely with the same hand!
That option is off the table now!
I'll clobber him on the head with something!
And create such a scene
That Dad will call the police!
Think about it.
I've thought over it!
Don't look at his face then.
-God forbid!
Why, though?
You'd have mercy on him.
It's today that I've seen, Farah,
What one who's lost in love looks like.
God forgive.
A face that's drooping,
A visage devoid of all vigour,
With exanimate eyes...
I have to see him once!
Not once, but a hundred times.
I've come here to have you see him.
Uh -- A -- Aunt --
I -- I'm sorry...
The thing is --
P -- Please, sit.
I'll sit at your feet now that I've come.
I'm not leaving with a rejection.
What can I do?
He's my only son!
I can't see him languish in love!
Call him a blighter,
Or an unsuccessful lover,
Or say that the very sight of him stings you;
Say what you will, my dear,
But nobody can stop a drowning man from flailing.
But I can assure you
He won't grab your hand.
That option is off the table, thanks to you.
I've talked to your father.
He says he'll talk tomorrow.
I'll stay awake all night, waiting for tomorrow.
Only God knows
How he would while the night away...
It's Afzal!
Hello?
It's Afzal.
I know. Go on.
I won't meet your father in the morning.
Bravo!
He's come up with something.
What will you do?
I'll resign from this job.
Which job?
The one I'm doing for 200,000 a month.
Why?
I won't two-time her.
What did he say?
He said, 'I won't two-time her'.
Hello?
What did you just tell Lubna?
You'd abandon me right in the middle of the rapids?
Right,
I get it,
You would've realised that my boat's about to run aground.
So you would've thought, 'Let's blackmail the girl'!
You could've asked for a raise, if that's what you want!
I squander a few hundred thousand just like that!
Tell me.
How much do you want?
What's your new rate?
And remember,
I won't let you waver
From the amount that we decide now.
Tell me!
Go on!
He's getting embarrassed now!
But natural
For a Reverend's son!
But no problem,
You can demand unrepentantly!
Tell me!
Hey!
He's hung up!
As if he'd quietly listen to your ignoble banter!
How much have you paid him?
Or is he begging for a penny that you're so scoffing!
You should remember, Mademoiselle Farah Ibrahim,
He's been working without pay so far.
Neither have you given him a penny, nor has he asked for one.
The cell phone, suit and boots you'd gotten him was your problem
And not his demand.
Yet, you only need to ask and he'd return all of it.
I can assure as much.
Pray tell, then,
What gives you the right to use such harsh expletives?
No such deal was struck, after all,
That he'd be kind to you,
And you'd be so lippy with him!
So lippy!
To be honest, you're abusing him!
I thought he was resigning to get a rise.
Not at all.
He's resigning to be spared all of this.
You hatch a new plot every five minutes,
And the situation changes every sixth minute.
What can the poor man do?
You work out a plan about 'love' at night,
And expect him to act out his hatred in the morning.
It had been decided that he'd love you with all his life for four months.
And you're urging him on the fourth day
To two-time you and be done with it.
That's not how it is, Farah.
Even a veteran actor can't give such a performance!
But he's still performing.
He handles the situation in a moment.
Pause and think
You brought him before someone like Dad,
And said to him, 'Prove it that you deserve Farah'.
Has he not proven
That he deserves you?
Dad's singing his praises!
And a lady like Mum who scorns more when she talks
Has forgotten everything about the poor man's status.
What else can he do?
Breathe fire like a dragon?
Honestly
I was just furious at Mehtab for dropping in.
And I vented it out on him.
Well,
That works for you.
How?
He said he won't two-time me.
He's two-timed you already.
When he said he's resigning from the job and going back to his world,
It means he's gone from yours.
He's two-timed you.
Now, plan out everything after it.
Weep and wail,
Break your bangles!
Rather,
This isn't the occasion to break bangles.
Just weeping will be enough.
Withdraw into your room
And keep on weeping and wailing!
Are you insane?
Won't Dad go to his place if I start crying?
He'd kill him!
Think about it this way -
If it happened this way,
Wouldn't it strengthen that blighter Mehtab's case?
So what should be done then?
Call him.
What will you say?
I won't say anything.
You should talk to him.
Tell him
Not to two-time me.
He should go on with his love for now.
He isn't answering.
He must've retired.
Impossible.
One can only die - not sleep - after such humiliation.
Shall we go to the terrace?
What?
I'll spend the night in vigil and penance.
I'll call him again and again.
Until he answers
And talks to me,
I'll stravaig about the terrace.
Wow...
What a way to expiate, mate...
I'm feeling very guilty, Lubna.
Until I say sorry to him,
I can't be at peace.
I appreciate that
But I'm feeling sleepy, Farah.
I have to go to University in the morning.
How can you leave me here?
Can't you stay awake with me in my sorrow?
I'm sorry, sweetheart,
But I can't be a part of a cabal
Whose chieftain would utterly disgrace someone and say,
'I'm ashamed at what I've done'.
I'll talk very sweetly to him now.
I sw --
I swear by you.
He'll answer.
Keep on trying.
I think he's taken sleeping pills.
No way.
He's just angry.
Who can sleep after such humiliation?
Call him.
Okay, wait.
Text him.
Write,
'If you don't answer',
'I'll be paying you a visit'.
And if he doesn't answer?
I'll think the rapscallion's taken sleeping pills and fallen asleep.
Rapscallion?
Hey! I'm saying it affectionately.
Done.
Look what we have here!
What are you doing here?
What could I do?
Look at your watch.
It's 2.00 a.m.
So it is by your watch.
I'm a rather harmless man, by the way.
It doesn't matter to you whether I am here or not.
Please go to your room
And sleep peacefully.
I don't think either of us can find peace.
I'm awake,
As are you.
I've been here since 11 p.m.
I'd prayed
That if my love is true,
You'd come up here within three hours.
Do you know
There were still five minutes left when you came up here.
Don't they have good trick cyclists in Karachi?
They have.
But mine is in Hyderabad.
Have your prayers been accepted?
Yes.
They've been.
So leave, would you?
The two of us have come up here for something important.
Forgive me,
But I'm not getting up from this swing.
Why not?
You've sat with me on this swing twice.
This swing is my place of worship, Mademoiselle Farah.
Then this swing is henceforth yours.
Put it in your car,
And take it along.
Hey!
That's brilliant.
What would I do with just the swing?
I've tried sitting on it alone.
It's been asking me all this time, 'Where's your partner'?
Who?
Who's been asking you?
You won't get it.
Ask one who was informed on the way
That it's the wrong way.
I'm not leaving.
It is obligatory on me to take in this waft of air
Redolent of your fragrance.
Oh God!
-O God, hear my prayers!
What are you praying for?
I won't tell you.
Don't.
But don't you dare mention me in your prayers!
He's calling.
So talk to him!
Here. Let me talk.
Before Mehtab?
Yup!
As if I'm afraid of anyone!
Hello?
It's Farah.
Are you listening?
Just say a soft 'Hmm'.
I'll take it that you're listening.
Hmm.
Be done with your anger.
All that guff --
I'd like to apologise for it.
Just keep on loving me,
So much
That beholders and earwiggers
Die of envy!
The plan about two-timing has been cancelled for now!
We'll talk about that
Once this rascal Mehtab is gone.
I hope you're listening?
Here.
Talk to him.
And ask him if he's heard everything I said.
And yes,
He didn't say 'It's okay'
In response to my apology.
Hello?
Lubna speaking.
I know.
Why didn't you say 'It's okay' in response to her apology?
It's okay.
There.
Right,
Keep on 'loving' Farah
As long as she's in the soup!
I will.
But how is she in the soup?
Mehtab and his Mum have come here again!
He met you.
You shook hands with him at the gate, remember?
So he's Mehtab?
Obviously.
Tell him
I'll give him a cheque of 200,000 tomorrow.
Listen,
She'll give you your cheque tomorrow.
For what?
She's giving you your salary in advance.
Oh...
I'm sure you're pleased.
I'm very pleased.
But may I ask something?
Sure, go on.
Does she love someone else too?
I mean,
Does she love someone?
Sorry.
Why are you saying sorry?
I figured I shouldn't have asked this.
No, you may ask.
But I don't have the answer to this.
As far as I'm aware, that wee laddie hasn't been born yet!
So may I meet your father tomorrow?
He's asking if he can meet Dad tomorrow.
He'd better.
In fact,
He should finalise everything with Dad!
I heard that.
And ask her, what if he asked me to bring my parents?
Bring them.
What's the problem with that?
Okay.
Good night.
Don't you
Have any dreams these days?
I've made arrangements so I don't.
And if, perchance, I have a silly one,
I'd pray to it, 'Go, sir',
'Show yourself somewhere else'.
'There is no hope that you will be reified here'.
How you warp those words...
And how is that?
Put it plainly
That reality scares you.
God forbid!
He has been very kind.
Everything is going on fine.
Why should I be scared?
Your son has lost his job.
I thought I'd rather ask you about your dreams
Because
You conceal the truth so well.
Was that something to conceal or speak about?
What did he -- He was just a clerk.
As good as doing nothing.
I used to think what would happen
To Hazrat Sahab's foretelling if he started off as a mere clerk.
Perhaps it'd take a hundred years to be fulfilled.
God willing, he'd do something worthwhile now.
You'll see,
I'll have hopes again.
But then, where does he leave for at 8.30 in the morning?
He won't sit at home, after all!
He tries his luck.
He'll find a post for himself on his own now.
But you don't trust him!
I trust him,
But it seems you don't trust me.
It is not necessary that I tell you every insignificant bit to prove that I trust you.
Only that it was significant,
Except when you said it.
By the way, is he looking for a post or a popsy?
It'd do you good to remember carefully.
It's possible
That you accidentally uttered 'post' instead of 'popsy'.
So you know everything.
We are God's men, Madame.
We get the news
Even when we don't get it.
The only thing I haven't been able to find out
Is who the popsy is.
Arifa knows.
She won't tell me.
How can she avoid telling when you ask?
She won't avoid
But it'd break her oath.
So, I thought
It's better that I remain in ignorance
Than commit the sin of breaking an oath.
You're cross with me.
I have lost the right to be cross.
Honestly, Reverend,
Is placating someone like this morally justified?
Politics isn't morally justified in love either,
Nor that you drag in the law at the time of need.
I consider this title of 'Reverend' an honour,
And you use it as a barb.
It'd be better
If you don't conceal anything.
It's also better because
Nothing ever remains concealed.
Do you want me to apologise?
There is no
Injunction against
A wife's apology,
But if you apologise as a mother,
You'd get me in the mire.
And if it displeases the Master,
A lifelong of dominion shall be ravaged.
Then, here's a compliment.
Go on.
I consider this title of 'Reverend' an honour.
You may have me say it under oath.
How about some breakfast?
No,
Just some tea.
Okay.
Know what,
I had a strange dream last night.
I saw you on the train headed for Karachi.
You had to see the train headed for Karachi!
Trains leave everyday, mate.
Have I ever been to Karachi?
Anyway, tell me about your dream.
I saw a girl with you.
I recognised her as soon as I saw her.
Who was it?
Not the one who writes you letters!
What do you know who writes me letters?
I do know it isn't Sheikh Ibrahim's daughter.
What are you saying?
She was with you in the dream.
She was so relaxed and convivial as if thoroughly acquainted with you!
W -- Which one?
The elder one.
I don't know her name.
Farah!
Hey!
That's not how you mention someone!
I'm getting late.
Have your tea.
M -- Mum!
Mum!
-Mum!
What happened?
-Mehtab --
Mehtab?
-Come!
It kills me to see --
Mehtab!
My dear...
My child! Careful there --
-Quickly!
Easy there.
-He's losing a lot of blood...
Quick!
Let me go!
Mehtab!
He'll be alright, Aunt --
-He's bleeding!
Madame, please calm down.
-He'll be alright.
Easy, Aunt...
-My child...
Madame --
He'll be fine, Madame.
So much --
Aunt!
-Madame!
Why are you standing here like that? Go and get some water!
Madame!
Look here, Madame!
God willing, nothing will happen to him!
Easy there, Madame. Hopefully, we'll get some good news.
Nothing will happen to him.
Madame...
My son --
He was still breathing.
I didn't let him lose a lot of blood.
I tied my scarf
Around his wrist tightly.
Get up, Madame. Come.
What do I do?
Come.
Come here.
What happened to him?
He slit his wrist.
Attempted suicide?
Yes.
It's one for the police.
It's one for the doctor.
Blood was gushing like a fountain before this scarf was tied.
That's alright, but we'd have to inform the police.
Get him back among the living and then inform the police.
His heart is beating fine.
It would.
It's a rather chary attempt at suicide.
Bring him to.
Nurse,
Get him on the drip.
How long will it take?
Just about 15 minutes.
But who is this?
Our guest from Karachi.
It seems his family's quite well off.
Very well off,
But he's very bad himself.
Why has he attempted suicide?
The police will ask about this.
Why tell the police? It's an internal matter.
He's opening his eyes!
Our eyes have been opened too.
-Where am I?
You tell me - Where are you?
If you're still alive, let me tell you
You're still in Hyderabad.
And if you're dead,
You'll get to know after all your deeds have been accounted for.
Why am I still alive?
Because you didn't slit your wrist properly.
Alright, doctor,
Call the police.
Police?
Why?
It's a legal affair.
There's only two ends you can get when you attempt suicide -
Straight to God if you're dead, and straight to the cops if you survive.
Kill me, doctor!
Don't worry.
Dad will be here soon.
Hopefully, he'll kill you!
Oh God, what will I say to Uncle?
Forget about Uncle,
Think about what you'd say to the cops!
The punishment for surviving is worse than that for dying!
-Mum!
Mum fell unconscious in a moment,
Only God knows
If she's been revived or not!
G -- Get this off me, doctor! I --
I'm going to see Mum!
Only after you've been unfettered!
For now, lie down!
There.
Dad's here.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV