Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Please, have a cup of tea one last time.
One last time?
Who knows whether you'd ever come again...
I'd happily serve you if you come again.
But today,
It'll be the last time from my side.
I'd said
That I've become the type who'd shatter glass utensils at the slightest provocation, hadn't I?
But you hadn't said that you shatter hearts.
But what good is it, now that it's been broken...
Glass utensils
If not a heart...
Are you coming or leaving?
I'd leave after having tea.
I'm sure you would have;
Aye, you'd be busy mending it afterwards.
And to be honest,
You did break his face, which made him leave,
And you're busy putting it together.
But you don't know, Mlle Farah Ibrahim,
They say a gentleman's face, when broken, can be mended,
But a mended head cannot be held high.
I know what you're thinking.
Aye, you'd know it very well.
I'm thinking about that blighter Sibtain.
No.
You're thinking why you broke Afzal's face in the first place,
And even if you had,
You shouldn't have shattered his honour.
So he tells you everything?
Who?
The blighter Sibtain, of course!
No.
These psychiatrists are very professional.
They don't share what their patients say with anyone else.
Give me his number.
Leave it be, will you, Farah.
It doesn't look proper.
What'd Dad think if you met him twice in one day?
Who told you I'm calling him to meet him?
Then?
Oh...
You feel like having a chat?
Aww...
That's so sweet.
Alright,
Here.
Use my phone.
Yes, Lubna?
Monsieur 'Lubna',
It's Farah!
Hold on -- Wait.
I'm coming!
Where are you coming?
I don't think you're well -- You just called me 'Monsieur Lubna'.
This is a case of complete memory loss.
If you set foot in this house again,
I'd break your legs!
Listen,
I have to say this is very insulting,
But --
It happens in my profession, so --
-To the dickens with your profession!
If you dropped in here again,
I'll make sure you drop dead!
Never forget,
My name's Farah Ibrahim.
I'll hurl such insults that - forget about you -
Nobody in your profession would ever have heard!
Are there six of them?
No.
There's 4 gunmen with him.
They guard him.
Call him downstairs.
Why did you have him wait upstairs?
I've seen it in the movies
That one is taken to old places he's forgotten
When his memory gets lost.
I'm trying the same.
I'm not talking about fleeing,
But about fighting.
Don't think of doing anything stupid; you have little time,
Get up.
And leave this place. Get up.
I'll flee on one condition.
Go on.
Quickly.
If I run away,
You'd fight them.
Done.
Go,
I'll fight them.
Why have you come to Karachi?
Looking for a job?
To become a great man.
So are you a twopenny-halfpenny man?
Nowhere will you find a great man if he's not inside you.
I've given your gunmen their tea.
This is for you.
Thank you.
No...
I should be thanking you.
You agreed to what I said,
And agreed to have a cup of tea.
Thank you.
Please, drink.
Look around - Does it look like you've left this room?
I clean it everyday,
And keep everything just like the two of you used to.
Surely, you must remember it sometimes?
Rem --
Remember what sometimes?
This room,
Babu Hamid,
Of course...
And you've forgotten to collect your dues of 2,100 Rupees.
You didn't eat anything in the last 7 days of the month.
Collect your dues when you leave.
No --
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about the dues.
When you've paid all of yours, why don't you let me pay mine?
You forgot your bag here.
I had a look the other day.
I found a photo of your Mam and Tad,
A picture of Arifa,
And an old mobile.
Don't worry.
I just saw the mobile.
I didn't see anything on it.
But
I saw the picture of your Mam and Tad,
And locked Arifa's face firmly in my memory.
I'd recognise her immediately if I ever meet her.
You'd recognise me too if you met me again, won't you?
I mean,
It's possible that we may never meet again...
Or that we meet after years...
Promise me, then,
If our paths crossed again, you won't say, 'I've seen you somewhere'.
Do you know
That a second heartbreak
Is just as bad as a second heart attack?
I have many precious memories with you, Jasmine;
I can never forget you.
I know that too.
Jasmine isn't the type that could be forgotten.
But why would you remember me?
And if anyone ever saw you remembering, what would you say?
Whatever was Jasmine to you?
Tell them, 'She was my landlady'.
No.
I'd say, 'I liked Jasmine'.
You'd recognise me too if you met me again, won't you?
I mean,
It's possible that we may never meet again...
Or that we meet after years...
Promise me, then,
If our paths crossed again, you won't say, 'I've seen you somewhere'.
Do you know
That a second heartbreak
Is just as bad as a second heart attack?
You'd vowed at the shrine, hadn't you,
That you'd come everyday for 7 days?
Won't you go today?
Why should I go now, when just one day has done the trick?
He said as he left,
'Jasmine, I like you'.
That's it.
My wish has been fulfilled.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
Congratulations.
What for?
Sibtain's parents
Are landing in Karachi today.
I hear they'll be here tomorrow.
Here, as in, at our place.
Have your breakfast.
His Dad's a right jolly fellow.
He'd praise the English at length,
And finish with a grand insult.
But I felt pity at one thing...
He said, 'You can get anything in Yorkshire, except even half-decent dal chawal [Indian lentils and rice]'.
You could've said,
'Our Farah cooks excellent dal chawal [Indian lentils and rice]'.
Hey --
But I don't know --
Don't worry, I'll teach you everything before your marriage.
Excuse me.
Won't you have breakfast?
I've had my breakfast.
You haven't even had tea.
I'd have tea at Afzal's place.
Afzal -- I mean --
Arifa...
She'd called.
She said her Mum's missing me a lot.
May I go?
You'd gone the day before yesterday, too,
And you'd told me after getting there that you're at Afzal's place.
Why, sure, go if she's called you.
Give her my regards.
Ask how everyone is.
May I go, too?
What'd you do there?
I mean, just to have a chat...
An outing...
Besides, if she saw both of us, she'd be much happier!
Alright, take her along.
After all, Arifa's her friend before she's yours.
Come.
She doesn't seem right.
She'll be alright once she's learnt to cook dal chawal [Indian lentils and rice].
Who
Got this picture up here?
Had it just been Dad's picture,
I'd keep it this close to my heart.
But this is a picture of Reverend Subhanallah,
The father of an Afzal earning his lawful 10,000 Rupees a month.
The sight of 98,000 won in a gamble in my pocket would torment him.
Just think what he'd do if he saw millions now.
Or, think what I'd do...
And this,
Is the commander
Of Dad's legion of virtue
Up in arms against sin.
She'd destroy
Every trace of immorality with one slap.
Take this picture off.
Otherwise, they'd have their eyes on me,
And I won't be able to look straight into the mirror.
Oh! In the Lord's name [auspicious beginning].
-Peace be upon you, Uncle Reverend.
Peace be upon you.
-And upon you, peace.
Over here, Arifa!
Both Farah and Lubna have come!
Bring them here, will you?
They've come here to take care of me.
She's not ill at all.
She's just putting up an act.
I've come, too.
Seize my hand, too; you'll gain from it.
Come.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
What'd you do here?
You'd said the other day
That you see Afzal
When you look at Farah,
So, I thought I'd look at my Afzal for a while too.
I'd just said it --
So to speak...
She may mind it
If you say it to her face.
No.
I don't mind it.
I'm not ill at all.
I'm just putting up an act.
There!
Didn't I say just that?
I'd heard it, Reverend.
Get us some tea.
Come here everyday until I get better.
Call me
If you're busy.
No.
I'll come here everyday.
You're very compassionate.
You have pity on the ill.
No, Aunt.
I love you very much.
I love you very much, too.
Did you talk to him?
We saw him on the TV the other day...
He was standing next to a minister.
He thinks it was Afzal.
-It was surely Afzal, Ruqaiyya Begum.
Granted, I'd only glimpsed him,
But I'm his father.
I can recognise him even when he's got his back towards me.
Would you look at that!
He's showed himself on TV...
But he couldn't show himself around here, at home...
He will.
He will, one day.
You've started thinking like me, now!
Where are you off to?
I
Thought I'd get some snacks to go along with the tea.
-No...
There's no need --
Let him go.
He just needed an excuse to leave.
Why an excuse?
You just said, 'He will come one day'.
It's hurt him.
Hey!
The homecoming
Of the one whose absence torments him would hurt him?
That's why I'm ill, too.
He's pronounced a judgement and declared him a pariah.
He torments for his son,
But he'd never let a sinner set foot in the house.
So, Farah's getting married?
Hey!
Who told you?
She told me herself the day before yesterday.
Would you see that!
Yes...
I'm seeing everything...
All the stories are going to end, now, one by one.
I'd write in my diary someday,
'There was one Farah',
'My best friend's sister',
'And then there was my best friend'.
'Who knows where the two of them would be now'...
On the page next to it, I'd write,
'There was one Afzal',
'My brother, dearer to me than my life';
'But his life was not dear to him'.
Nothing will happen to him.
He'll come back one day.
You'll see,
He'll be gambling on matches with the old colony lads, just like old times.
Who's she marrying?
A psychiatrist from around here.
Is he better than Afzal?
I mean,
He'd be very good...
Does she like him?
The tea's boiling...
Right...
She had to like him...
It was Dad's order
'I will not hear any excuses'!
She, too, figured
That there's no option other than accepting him.
When's the wedding?
Judging by the bustle, sometime very soon!
I'd known it already.
The day Afzal murdered Wali,
I said,
'Farah's out of the picture'.
Peace be upon you.
-And upon you, peace, Reverend.
How are you?
The Lord has been kind.
-What'd you like?
Just
Some of these biscuits,
One fruit cake, and
These cake rusks.
Aye, laddie, what are you looking at?
Give the Reverend some cold drinks.
No, I'm not having any cold drinks.
By the way, you didn't even ask
'How many biscuits', and
'How many cake rusks'?
Reverend,
I'm having a kilo of each packed.
No, my good man...
Not a kilo each...
A quarter of each.
Leave that to me, Reverend.
Why, good sir?
I'm buying,
So, it'll be as per my order.
The
Thing is,
I've also brought money for just a quarter of each.
Who's asking for any money, Reverend?
You won't ask for money, old chap?
Why?
Feel at home, Reverend.
Afzal's your son,
He's like a brother to me.
Who asks one's brother for payment?
When I was just a trifling father,
You'd take the money from me.
You never thought, then,
'Who asks one's father for payment'?
Take your biscuits and cake rusks.
You've said such
Sinful words in relation to these.
Reverend!
Hey!
Hey --
The Reverend's gait has slowed down
Ever since he's run away.
He would've reached the bakery late.
You should've stopped him.
You let him go for nothing, really...
It was necessary that he go.
He makes sure to walk 200 steps when he's angry.
Anyway,
Have your tea,
And make do with your Aunt's affection.
Would the wedding be fixed directly,
Or is an engagement planned?
There'll be an engagement before that.
Just think that the engagement's this week.
You'd invite us to the engagement, won't you?
Or would you skip us, remembering us as hopefuls the first time around?
Look,
I've forgotten it entirely.
You haven't forgotten it at all.
I haven't forgotten it either.
I remember how I gave sorrow,
And how you braved through that sorrow.
I'd remember that ring
When I'd wear any other ring
That Uncle Reverend had quietly kept in his pocket again.
You're under my oath,
Once I'm married, don't bless me;
Just remember me and say,
'To you, your way, Farah',
'We forgive you'.
I can't sit here any longer today.
Hey!
You're leaving?
You've had tea, haven't you?
Yes...
So,
What's with these tears?
Who's made her cry?
She's getting married.
She's crying out of the grief of separation.
Oh,
Right...
So she's crying just as a formality, so to speak!
Don't cry when you come here again.
I'll serve you some of the finest coconut biscuits, aye!
She may be the first girl who's wept in sorrow for you.
That's why you've started missing her.
Marry her.
You couldn't get anything in love.
Give someone something, and get even.
Are you crazy?
You want that I should give her four days of my life that I've got left, and ruin forty years of hers?
If love gets four days,
It doesn't bother about forty years.
I've seen her condition.
She sees you a hundred times in one glance.
God have mercy on my Mum;
She'd say, 'Marry the girl who loves you',
'Not the one whom only you love [but doesn't love you back]'.
She's taken great care of me for four months, mate...
She's a right spitfire.
Seeing her, it doesn't seem that she could love anyone, really.
But --
-If you commit the sin of kicking love away,
It'll kill you one day.
Anytime you laugh, it'd torment you that she weeps at the thought of you.
Here's an idea.
Never think of her again.
Don't remember, also, that she'd taken good care of you for four months,
Nor that
You have pity on her
When she weeps.
I won't think of her again.
More than a hundred Englishmen in Yorkshire
Have taken to playing gilli danda [Asian sport], I tell you!
And the credit goes to me!
I'm settling the scores with them.
I'll ruin them with this habit of gilli danda
The same way the buggers had ruined India!
But, Monseigneur,
Even a single man there
Is like a nation by himself.
Touché on that.
That's why even gilli danda can't ruin them.
Sit over here.
I know the history of this room.
You bring anyone you want to insult here.
The history of this room is about to change tonight.
I've brought you here to tell you
That I've decided to marry you.
What?
Hold your horses!
Listen to the whole thing.
I'm listening.
You don't listen to the heart, do you?
I will keep on listening to it, now...
By the way, you're not a good psychiatrist either.
Look,
You may insult me, but do not say a word against my profession.
Know what,
We'd just get married.
We'll never be able to love each other.
I don't care.
Love isn't required to get married.
Know what, there's no feeling like 'love', psychologically speaking.
It's just a knavish trick to have one's way and get to that end.
But marriage is no trick; it's a contract.
A lifelong contract between two parties.
Even if the world turns upside-down,
One's got to stand by that contract.
So you don't believe in love at all?
When did I say that?
I do, but
I don't believe in marrying out of love.
Do you know, most of my patients are that sort --
The kind who'd loved before marriage.
When I see anyone in love, I say,
'Aye, yer comin' to me, laddie'...
That's just what I deserve...
What?
I'm getting married to a lowlife like you!
This is very insulting!
I'll have this one specifically written in the contract
That you can't insult me again and again like this!
Why are you picking your nose?
Come here.
Over here.
Show me your hand.
Like this.
Hey! Don't hit him!
I'm not hitting him, Mam; I'm just scaring him.
Go back and sit.
And don't you dare pick your nose again.
Alright, where were we?
Mam, would you see who it is?
Alright...
Ifrah!
You're sleeping when I'm teaching?
Come here.
Over here.
Show me your hand.
Properly. Like this.
Hey! Don't hit her!
I'm not hitting her; I'm just scaring her!
The tea's fantastic.
Why were you surprised to see me?
Because we met again the very next day.
But why are you skirting around the point?
Get to the point, will you?
The point?
You said yesterday that you like me,
Alright, thank you very much.
Go on.
What it is is, I'm the kind of girl who'd talk in a clear-cut and to-the-point way.
I don't like it that a don type chap like you should say one half and hold the other half in.
I'd said something else to you, too.
I think I forgot...
Remind me again?
You've forgotten too, innit?
How couldn't you?
Just a thought of me is enough to cause this memory loss of yours.
Whatever would you remember if I stood firm before you?
Besides, which muppet would say in a surprise meeting,
'Listen, my dear, I don't love you'.
Be a man, Afzal Subhanallah.
I find those who talk politics before saying 'I love you' rather toxic!
I love someone else, Jasmine.
Every compeer abandoned me...
There's something new!
Now you sound like a man!
Just that, or are you going to add anything else?
I mean,
What's her name,
Where does she live...
You don't really have to reply,
But I can't help it; I'm a girl...
I'd even ask such meaningless questions.
How does she look?
Well, to the devil with her looks.
What does love care if the lass looks as lush as Jasmine or not...
Is it the same one, by any chance, who'd come from Hyderabad?
Farah!
Farah Ibrahim!
There!
My Spidey Sense had started tingling the moment I'd seen her.
I won't tell you her name.
Why?
She doesn't love me.
So everything's going on one-sided?
There!
Mam had been right all along, hadn't she?
So, there was a lass after all!
And you're such a secret squirrel
That you never let anyone know for five months!
You didn't even let me find out!
Alright, don't tell me her name.
Just tell me this -
Is she more beautiful than me?
She's very beautiful, Jasmine,
But not more than you.
Loser...
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV