Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
What's his name?
Babu Hamid.
Who shot him?
Wali and his hoodlums.
You'd come here before, right?
With another wounded
Who'd been shot in the leg?
Yes.
Who are the two of them to you?
They're our tenants.
Wali had shot him, too?
-Yes.
There!
That's what happens when you don't file a complaint.
Is there any guardian or relative with him?
There's the two of us.
You're the landlady.
What about his family?
He has no family.
There!
He's here, too.
Peace be upon you, Uncle.
And upon you, peace.
My dear,
How is he now?
No idea.
They've taken him to the operation theatre,
But they're not telling me anything.
This is Afzal's landlady,
And this is her daughter, Jasmine.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
Is his condition rather serious?
He's taken a lot of bullets.
How are you?
I'll be walking by tomorrow.
I've checked,
I have no difficulty walking.
Is any of you a relative of Babu Hamid's?
Under whose name would the complaint be filed?
We'll talk after the operation's been done.
May we talk about us for now?
Babu Hamid had come to save me.
Do you know why he was crying buckets?
For his friend.
No.
For Jasmine.
He'd be cursing his friend.
If he hadn't taken bullets at that very moment, the two of them would've met today, for sure!
Met?
Well, they couldn't really have met...
We'd dropped in, too.
Please, Farah,
His friend's stuck between life and death,
He can't move without a wheelchair,
And you think he'd think of a date at such a moment?
Then, you haven't seen how he's stuck!
Between Jasmine on one side, and you on the other.
Me?
You're here, too, aren't you?
Jasmine would've called before coming,
And you've come without.
He's just hiding his face from you.
Even Karachi's water can't have its effect...
You're here in the same condition you'd left in.
You're here now, aren't you? You should relish Karachi's water.
If the Lord wills, it'll kill you off where there'll not be a drop of relief.
Why are we standing here?
We could go where the struggle's going on.
Come.
If there's a man with you, please call him.
Yes?
Tell me.
Four bullets had struck him,
Three in the stomach,
And one right here by the heart.
The one that struck the heart was very dangerous.
He's --
Alright, isn't he?
No.
We couldn't save him.
Look what we have here!
My heart knew
There'd be such a scene going on here.
He's dead, Farah,
That's why this 'scene' is going on.
His wounds were bleeding again today.
The poor man.
He's gotten himself mired in so many troubles ever since he came here.
If he came here with his parents' curses,
This was bound to happen.
Shut up, Farah!
Parents don't curse.
Maybe not a curse,
But their wails do work.
I've seen his parents torment for him.
They even feared
That he may bolt his room from the inside in his anger.
Someone's died, Farah!
Someone's lost his life.
Don't you feel any sorrow over it?
This has all happened because of him, innit?
I heard everything at the mourning.
The poor man
Had gone
To save Afzal's beloved from the killer.
And do you know why this had come to be?
Because Afzal
Had beaten Jasmine's cousin before everyone!
Cousin, as in,
The killer.
I've heard everything about him, too.
He's the neighbourhood's ace hooligan
In fact,
He's got a handful of neighbourhoods under him.
Shut up, Farah.
I'd been quiet for three hours there, hadn't I?
I've seen every scene put up by everyone.
Remember
How that Jasmine was getting dizzy?
Would you look at that!
No bond or tie whatsoever -
Does one weep like that
For just a tenant?
I understand such weeping very well.
She was looking for Afzal's shoulder to cry on.
She'd be thinking
Of Afzal's shoulder to cry on as an excuse to wrap herself around him.
You're raving mad.
Who knows what you're talking of!
Did I say anything wrong?
If you didn't, tell me,
What's our relation with Afzal?
Why had your Dad come looking for him?
And why have we come to take him back?
You'll find out when you've seen the world
That you won't find compassion in ties of blood,
And you'll find passions driven by bloodlust.
I, too, have come with someone's sorrow as a weight on my heart,
Because I feel that when a mother torments over separation from her son,
It falls on all mothers to torment in her pain.
Tormenting in someone's pain, too, is a kind of a tie, Farah.
If I'm tormented out of this tie, that girl must be, too.
Try and get this across to her,
Or tell her to go to sleep.
What would you get it across to me?
I'm doing all of this for you!
Otherwise, she may wrap herself around Afzal
Otherwise, she may wrap herself around Afzal for all I care!
Come.
Sir, this...
This is our house in Karachi.
Now,
You're staying here until your wound's healed.
I've talked to the doctors; one of them will check you regularly here.
But, sir --
-You've done a lot as you wanted to.
Even if you've not made any mistake, it feels as if you have.
So, it's not proper that you reply to me with 'but',
Or want
That you be left to yourself in this condition.
Stay here a few days,
And you may go wherever you please once you get better.
Come with me.
Carefully now. Good.
Room #9.
Yes.
Right.
What?
When?
Alright, thanks.
Thank you.
Here.
Have something.
How could I have anything, Mam?
He's left, too.
Who?
Afzal...
But this was bound to happen.
The day she'd come here, looking for him,
Was the day my heart had told me,
'It's time for Afzal [to leave]'.
He's not at the hospital?
No.
He's left the room.
And those who'd come from Hyderabad, looking for him,
Have taken him along to Hyderabad.
Surely, he wasn't so uncultured?
He's stayed here for three months.
He'd have some shame about our dealings.
Plus, he's a Reverend's son,
Surely, he can't be so treacherous!
He'd come here someday to account for his shame.
He'd bring her along.
He'd say,
'She's my wife'.
But she said she was nobody to him?
That's how I'd reasoned it out with you.
Remember what you'd told me?
Take the dinner away.
I'll start eating tomorrow.
In sorrow, one would rather stay hungry just as a formality, if nothing else...
So he doesn't have a phone with him even now?
That's where he'd been clever!
He neither kept a phone, nor gave me a number.
The blighter would've thought from the outset,
'I'd fly away and disappear the moment I feel like'.
Just think that he was a talking parrot.
Enjoyed his treats for a few days,
Indulged us,
And, having engrossed us in his words, flew away.
Good night, Mam.
Hey!
You're here, sleeping!
Do you even know who's come here?
Who?
It'll rouse you proper if you heard it.
You'd sit before the mirror, setting your hair right.
Oh...
He's staying here tonight.
Who?
The same
Who's a watermelon and red on the inside.
Watermelon?
Yes.
Dad says,
'To find a gentleman from among men'
'Is like finding from a heap of watermelons one'
'That's bright red on the inside'.
The rapscallion!
He's cherry red, I give you that!
-Oh, shut up!
Who is it?
Not now. I'll tell you in the morning. He's fallen asleep now.
I opened the door and had a look at him.
He's sleeping peacefully.
Get
Get out!
What?
I said get lost!
I'm in no mood for a load of guff.
I couldn't sleep,
So I thought I'd come here and talk to you.
But you're not a good choice.
Now, I'll go and wake him up,
And talk about everything with him.
Halt.
Tell me,
Who is it?
Afzal.
Here?
Not here, over there.
In the guests' room below.
Who brought him here?
Dad.
Hey!
The poor man,
He was griefstricken over his friend.
Dad thought
He'd be looked after here,
And comforted, too, if necessary.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Congratulations to you, too.
He's
Just limping a little.
Pray that he gets better.
Go.
I've prayed.
Know what, Dad said he'd take him to Hyderabad when he gets better.
Just see,
I won't let him go away from there, then!
You?
Yes.
He's begun obeying everything I say.
I said,
'Take your medicines',
And he took them instantly.
I said, 'Have your soup',
And he had his soup instantly.
And when I said 'Go to sleep',
-He fell asleep instantly?
Obviously.
Wait and watch. I'll go and wake him up,
He'd get up in a moment.
Go, then,
And wake him up.
One day, he'd wake you up,
And you'd come to me, crying, saying,
'Oh, Farah',
'How long it's taken me to wake up'!
Good night, Farah.
Are you awake?
Who is it?
It's me, Lubna.
Yes...
I'm awake...
Awake, as in, I may come in, right?
Easy there, lie down.
Hey!
So you've got a cellphone, too?
No, it's
My friend's.
Oh...
The poor man.
Call Arifa when it's charged.
No.
I won't call them for a while.
I've sworn an oath.
Wouldn't you go to Hyderabad?
-I will, someday...
What 'someday'?
You're going one of these days.
We haven't come to Karachi on a tour.
We'd take you along.
I said I'm not going now.
Have you lost your heart to Jasmine?
Why do you lose your heart
To a new lass every few months?
What's your star?
Must be Leo.
Don't worry, though.
If you still feel
That you love Jasmine after going back,
Come over to Karachi with a wedding procession.
Look,
Jasmine's a very good girl, but --
-If she's so good, why this 'but'?
Shoot away all your older love stories --
Speaking of shooting,
You've taken a bullet for her, too, haven't you?
What would you hide from me, now?
I know everything.
In fact, Farah does, too.
Actually, she's the one who'd told me.
Farah had seen it when she'd wrapped herself around you, weeping.
She said the moment she saw it,
'Would you look at their love'!
I'd seen some of it for myself, too.
She felt dizzy thrice at the mourning,
And she'd looked your way before she got dizzy all three times.
Please, Lubna,
My friend's death is no joke.
You're right there...
But the love of those who live is not joke either.
Fleeing Hyderabad like cowards,
Two-timing the Farah from the letters,
Attempting an engagement with our Farah,
And this affaire de cœur with Jasmine is no joke either.
Your Mum, Dad, and Arifa at home are tormented for you,
And you're stumbling around in your love for a new comely lassie?
By the Lord, I don't love Jasmine.
Right...
Whose turn is it this time?
It's my turn.
This time, I won't play a gambit
That I'd have to lose my heart to win.
I've come from Hyderabad, having learnt
That love matters to us,
But we don't matter to love.
Have you taken your medicines?
I have.
Go to sleep, now.
And refrain from talking about love
Until the end of your course of medicines.
Good night.
Listen,
Give me the phone.
Sure.
Good night.
It's my turn.
This time, I won't play a gambit
That I'd have to lose my heart to win.
I've come from Hyderabad, having learnt
That love matters to us,
But we don't matter to love.
Done with your little chat?
Yes...
I finally asked about Jasmine today.
Doubting someone isn't good, so to speak,
But you'd gotten this doubt into my heart.
I thought I'd ask this
Now that I'm talking about so much.
And he'd have said,
'Not at all',
'It's nothing like that'.
No.
He didn't say that.
He said, 'By the Lord, I don't love Jasmine'.
That means
He doesn't love Jasmine.
Good night.
Jasmine!
Get up, Jasmine!
Your phone's ringing.
Get up and see
Who it is.
Babu Hamid?
Don't worry, it'd be him.
Afzal.
Hello?
It's Afzal here.
Hey!
I thought you'd run away.
Where would I run away to, now?
I'll be back any of these days.
You'd stay here, won't you?
I don't know where I'd stay.
But I'd stay in Karachi.
Should I get you something to eat, now?
Yes.
No, Uncle Ibrahim, they wouldn't have fallen asleep at all!
The two of them stay awake all night.
Dad!
-Yes?
Uncle Ibrahim's calling.
-Oh?
Begin in the Lord's name! [Auspicious beginning]
Peace be upon you, Monseigneur!
And upon you, peace.
I hope I've not woken you up?
No, Monseigneur,
We've been sleeping for five days, hopeful
That if the Lord wills thus, you would call,
And we'd wake up at the sound of your voice.
Please, wake us up today.
We can't
Pretend to sleep anymore.
I've found him.
Praise the Lord!
Monseigneur's found him!
M --
May the Lord give you your due reward for this noble deed, Monseigneur!
May the Lord always keep you happy, Monseigneur!
Where's the rapscallion?
-He's here, with me.
I've brought him to my place.
-Alright.
He'd be nearby, listening?
No, he doesn't even know I'm talking to you.
Oh?
Get to Karachi tomorrow,
And bring Madame along.
Just
Disconnect the call, we're leaving right now.
No, not right now.
Get here tomorrow evening.
Lubna's just told me that he's not ready to go to Hyderabad,
And I don't want that he should suspect you're coming either.
Does he not miss even his mother?
He says, 'I' --
'Won't go back to Hyderabad'.
No,
Let me talk.
-Jus -- Just a minute, Ruqaiyya.
His face --
His appearance is the same, innit?
Don't worry, he's the same.
He isn't the same at all, Monseigneur.
The blighter's heart has changed...
Is he sleeping?
Yes.
Your Afzal is sleeping.
Didn't I tell you, Ruqaiyya,
That we're not dear
To our dear son?
Thank you so much, Monseigneur.
Please give your address
To Arifa.
There's no need to give any address.
My driver would be there tomorrow evening,
Just get in the car with him and come here.
What's the need, Monseigneur?
It's absolutely needed, Reverend.
Please, don't refuse.
As you command.
God be with ye.
May God watch over you.
What does he say?
He says, 'I'll send a car; just get in and come here'.
And he says he's not coming to Hyderabad?
Let him say if he wants to!
I'd plead with him
With folded hands,
I'd take off my turban and place it in his feet,
What could he say, then?
We're
Parents, Ruqaiyya,
It's on us to keep trying everything.
And she's going along, too!
She'd even
Grab the unduteous lad
By his collar!
He'd come if you call him.
Otherwise, he'd stay in hiding.
What'd you do if he came?
What's left to be done?
I'd finish this trivial rivalry.
He'd think we want to hand him over to the police.
He won't think that.
He knows that no complaint was filed against him.
He'd think you're afraid of him.
He'd seize and take away a scared Jasmine.
That'd happen only when he'd think that I'm afraid of him.
That's what he'd say if you talk about ending this rivalry.
He'd say, 'Give me Jasmine',
'And our rivalry ends'.
I've given him Babu Hamid's corpse.
I'll say, 'That's enough'.
You don't know him, Afzal.
He doesn't know me either, Jasmine.
Just call him once,
But don't tell him that I'll be there to meet him, too.
Then I'd say whatever comes to mind.
Sure.
Say whatever comes to your mind.
Alright, I'll disconnect.
I'd await your call.
What is it, Jasmine?
Afzal's afraid of Wali, Mam.
What is this, Arifa?
It's Mum's things and clothes, Dad.
I'm locking the door.
Hold on,
Wait, Ruqaiyya.
Why are you taking such a large suitcase?
How many days would you stay there?
-As many as it takes.
Remember
What Monseigneur had said.
He's not agreeing to come back just yet.
So?
So, Reverend, as long as he stays in Karachi, so will I.
I'm going along, am I not?
Which means on this very day
I'll bring him back.
Leave it be, Reverend.
Our faith does not permit making such claims,
So, get in the car quietly,
And keep praying until we get to Karachi that he agrees to come back.
If he does, alright.
Otherwise, how far is Karachi?
You can come and meet the two of us whenever you please.
Come here,
My good man.
This --
Put this suitcase in the bag.
A son's adamance
Is heavier than any suitcase, Reverend.
Leave it be, good chap.
I'll carry it myself.
God sufficeth me. There is no God save Him. In Him have I put my trust, and He is Lord of the Tremendous Throne. [Prayer for strength in times of hardship]
God is the Greatest!
On the phone again?
Lad's the odd sort.
Hello?
It's Afzal.
Afzal, you bugger!
It's Afzal! Afzal!
Where were you, you blighter?
And why was your phone switched off?
Do you even know
That those who love you weep when the remember you, mate?
I weep when I remember them, too, mate.
But stop crying now.
Bring everyone over here to me.
Where?
Karachi.
Tell them they'd get a job,
And a salary like their stakes.
Who'd give such a job?
I would.
Right,
And what's the job?
You'd have to sacrifice your life for me.
He says, 'You'd have to sacrifice your life for me'.
-Oh?
What happened, bugger?
Scared?
No --
I was just thinking
That one'd have to get a good salary if one has to sacrifice his life.
What do you say?
Your appointment letter's ready.
-Just take it! Take it!
Alright.
When do we join?
Today.
Right now.
Just a minute.
What happened?
What is it?
Your family was going
In Monseigneur Ibrahim's car.
Monseigneur, you know?
The mill owner?
With him.
Alright, disconnect the call,
And get here before the evening.
Alright,
We'll be there.
Okay.
-'We'll be there'?
Come in, Monsieur le Docteur.
So, how are you?
Now,
I've started walking.
I'd run away by the evening.
I mean, I'd be running by the evening.
-Don't even think about it.
Running isn't good for you.
You've come to collect the rent, haven't you?
You're saying as if you've got the money in your pocket!
Exactly.
I've got it in my pocket since the morning.
Hold this, will you?
Right here.
I hope it doesn't hurt?
Not much.
Okay.
Here.
You can run after two days.
Nothing to worry.
You're taking your medicines, aren't you?
Yes.
Have your medicines on time for a few more days.
Sure.
Alright,
See you.
Alright, thank you so much.
-Thank you.
Listen...
Did you
Talk to Arifa?
No?
Not at all.
Surely,
You must be talking now and then?
Yes, I do, sometimes...
How are Mum and Dad?
Only they'd know that...
I've heard that when sons run away from their homes,
One only looks at his Mum and Dad's faces,
One doesn't ask, 'How are you'?
Anything else?
No.
Thank you.
May I ask something, now?
Yes?
Why do you have this penchant for running?
And if you ran away,
Where'd you go?
To Jasmine?
In that case, give me her number.
I'll call her here.
And if you have any shame left,
Don't run away from here.
I understand what you mean very well,
But you'd better understand this nice and clear, too,
The hearts of those who hold you dear stop beating when you run away.
Alright,
If you marry me, what'd you do to the one sitting at home?
Tell me what I should do.
It's obvious.
Two swords can't share the same sheath.
Oh, she ain't no sword!
You're the sword.
Your very gaze slits throats!
Whatever.
Say it again.
What?
The same.
'Whatever'.
You say it so well.
Don't get me busy talking.
Send her away if you want to marry me.
I can call her right now if you say.
She'd be gone before the evening.
Get here before the evening.
Talk to Mam.
If Mam asks for 500,000 in Mahr [bride price], just say, 'Alright'.
Don't get all worked up to hear about 500,000. I'm not taking any from you.
Have I turned you down, Jasmine?
Forget 500,000, I'd give 1 million.
And if you want, you can have my head along with it.
Say auspicious things.
Auspicious?
As in,
At least don't talk about having your head.
My late Mam used to say, 'When a girl thinks of someone as her husband',
'One could just as well sacrifice his life for her'.
Just tell me, is it fear or love?
I've fallen in love.
You're lying, sweet wifey.
It is fear, for now.
You'd only fall in love later.
Go and face them,
And tell them you're prepared to die.
I'm not ready to die just yet.
I'm not afraid of dying,
But I want to live on.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV