♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
♪Who were those people♪
♪Who won their love?♪
Ruqaiyya?
What happened?
Nothing.
Nothing, really.
A bite is stuck in my throat.
When one's son is nowhere to be seen,
One can't digest the sorrow or the food, Reverend.
Nor can I, like you,
Defeat grief with sheer will.
Did you offer your prayers?
Prayers?
It protects you from upheavals and wards off countless troubles, you blighter!
Get up!
Purify yourself right now,
And get yourselves on the prayer mat.
Why did you slap me?
Girls like you are only brought to their senses when slapped!
Offer your prayers, quick!
And pray for the well-being of those
Whom you meet,
Or call.
What?
While praying today,
My eyes teared up.
I didn't even realise I was weeping!
The angels would be laughing at you right now.
Bother about your own -
They listen either to the clinking of your anklets or the sweet melodies of 'I've tasted blood'!
The poor fellows would be sitting with their ears shut!
Get up!
Offer your prayers,
So that it relieves the angel on your left shoulder [scribe noting evil deeds].
I've heard that when your type finally sits on the prayer mat,
One can hope for an immediate relief!
I don't know why my heart's saying
That you're in need of urgent relief.
Are you getting up,
Or do you want another?
I am.
Wait.
Just for now,
Take off these anklets for a change.
You don't need this background music in orison!
You hag!
Both the bullets had hit him on the leg, right?
Right...
Then there's nothing to worry about.
Why aren't the doctors coming out, then?
Why don't they say that everything's fine?
They're busy with the surgery, mun.
Right...
He must be talking?
No...
How'd he talk?
They'd have given him shots to put him to sleep.
It'll be a few hours
Before he comes to, right?
-Right...
Where were you?
I mean, where were you when the blighter had come to kill him?
You're at home all day,
But you'd gone for a good night's stroll tonight?
Sit down, everyone's watching...
What? What are they watching?
Look,
Don't change the topic.
Why don't you change the topic?
If you talk and ask about him again and again, they'd ask you who you are to him.
Hey!
I'm his landlady, mun!
Hush!
Sit, now.
Enough! C'mon.
Sit down.
... Leaves an impression with his humility, my dear.
-Just mention her name and address.
I'll talk to Dad.
-Love Farah for four months --
What's this balderdash!
-Swear on my life if I'm lying.
Just keep on loving me,
-That's neat.
You're a right emotional man.
-She's just voicing unfounded suspicions!
-The move he's played
Is one I'll never forgive him for!
-What's your wife's name?
-My Afzal has become the best one [Afzal] today!
You've just gotten up, haven't you?
-But he's a first rate fraudster.
-Just a spot of lipstick's got you stunned!
Then why did you take us there?
-How say you tell me -
How does this lipstick look?
-Farah is the one who used to write you letters, right?
I'd kept you as an option.
-You'd leave Hyderabad for the one who doesn't love you,
Shoot the bugger!
-She's not the one who used to write letters to me, Mum.
The job as a security guard, you know...
-And you'd leave those who love you
In Hyderabad?
-'My Afzal'
'Has become a great man'.
-Spit in my face if I lose.
10,000 a month, and loving Farah Ibrahim!
-Just don't do that
Which you would be ashamed to do.
-Proposals will line up once Wali's out of the picture, you'll see!
He'd kill me if he got out! What are you waiting for? Shoot the bugger!
Afzal!
I've offered my prayers.
Now, beseech the Lord
That he be alright.
Who?
Do I have to tell you his name, now?
His name is etched in every breath of yours
And courses through your veins, Lubna.
What happened to him?
There!
Now you know who it is!
Don't worry.
Nothing's happened to him.
I just thought
That may nothing happen to him.
I've prayed for many people,
But when his name came up, I thought
The most effective prayers for him would come from your heart.
What did you think?
And why did you think that may nothing happen to him?
Why are you on the rack?
Beseech the Lord if you've already offered you prayers
That
May the Lord will that he be fine.
In fact, you should keep praying for him.
I said it
Because it just occurred to me,
'Alright',
'Offer your prayers',
'Beseech the Lord'.
You're hiding something from me, aren't you?
Good Lord!
It seems you'd tear up any moment!
Didn't I just say it's nothing, really?
Mum had said once,
'You offer prayers'
'And beseech the Lord'
'The moment you have the slightest of doubt'.
What is going on?
Nothing, really...
We're both scared, so, for a while,
We're avoiding each other's gaze.
Why are you scared?
The 'most excellent one' [Afzal] in the eyes of the two of you,
That rapscallion has disappeared from our sights,
And her megrims give your mother's heart a painful plight.
If milk spills from the kettle when it's being boiled,
Or an eye blinks,
Or this wastrel, this heart beats a tad hard,
She gets scared.
But you're scared too.
Out of respect, yes.
I've heard
'Ordinary people should be scared'
'When a mother gets scared'.
Alright, Ruqaiyya,
I've decided to sleep peacefully until dawn.
Stop telling your rosary,
And chant a hymn to get me sleepy.
He's alright now.
He's talking, isn't he?
He's unconscious right now, sir.
When he'd come to in the morning, he'd be talking, too.
Excuse me.
There! That's all it ever was. He's alright now.
Let's get going, then.
Going?
Call me if you need anything.
You'll get it.
C'mon, now.
Mam, how could we just leave like that? The poor man's just come to!
Just come!
Very bad, Mam! We should be staying here, how -- Mam, how could we just leave?
-Everyone's watching you!
Okay.
God be with ye.
-God be with ye.
Is Farah coming along?
No? Why would she?
But she's in the car!
♪Every compeer♪
Hey!
Hold on. She's sleeping.
♪Every compeer♪
But why didn't she tell us?
She's told us now, alright?
♪Every compeer♪
♪Every compeer abandoned me♪
I'd say
Go and see if Lubna's awake; ask her to pack a few of her dresses in a bag.
♪Every compeer abandoned me♪
♪After ephemeral moments of companionship♪
The bag's in the car already.
I'm not talking about my bag; I'm talking about Mlle Farah's.
♪After ephemeral moments of companionship♪
♪Who has the leisure to stand by♪
I'm talking about Mlle Farah's bag, too.
It'd been kept before yours.
♪Who has the leisure to stand by♪
♪One so crazed in love♪
Okay.
I'll get going, then.
♪One so crazed in love♪
Goodbye.
-Goodbye.
♪One so crazed in love♪
♪I found even my own shadow♪
♪Apathetic and blasé♪
♪When obsecrating for rosebuds♪
♪I was presented with a garland of thorns...♪
Where's Farah, Mum?
Isn't she going to University?
♪Who were those people♪
No.
Why?
♪Who were those people♪
She's planning to use everything she'd studied
♪Who won their love?♪
As an charm on Afzal today.
She's headed for Karachi?
Yes, Karachi.
Mam!
Mam! Get up, the sun's come up!
It's been four hours since the sun came up.
Aren't we going?
Where?
To the hospital.
No.
Why, Mam?
We shouldn't even have come back!
He's taken bullets because he fought for me!
He'd be thinking, now that he would've come to,
'Where's Jasmine'?
And Jasmine's enjoying herself at home here!
As in, 'The ones for whom I'd sacrificed myself/Were but left purifying themselves'.
Goodness...
Breakfast, some healthy food,
That's what the doctor would've told him.
Who'd get him that, now?
Babu Hamid?
That blighter would get him papar [snack] with bread and some rotten lentils!
You'd say it yourself, then,
'They got the bullets out, but couldn't get the lentils out'.
C'mon, now,
Have something.
How could I have something?
Who feels hungry in sorrow?
Why are you in sorrow, Jasmine?
Hey!
Fear God, Mam!
One feels sorrow even when one's enemies are at the hospital.
Then, he's Afzal.
Our own tenant.
Right, you sympathise with your tenant,
But not feel sorrow like you do!
Besides, I've told Babu Hamid
To let us know if he needs anything.
I'll send
Whatever he asks for right away.
I'd do my duty.
Send it?
As in,
You have no intentions to go to the hospital?
Won't you see,
Now that he's come to, how he is?
See if the poor lad's scared now,
And if he isn't, why isn't he?
He isn't scared, Jasmine.
I'm scared.
Right...
America's scared of a war between India and Pakistan.
But I know the American disposition very well!
They say they're afraid when they want to ruffle your feathers!
Talk about yourself, Jasmine,
Let America remain on the other side of the pond.
Whatever's up with me?
It's not as if
I'm dying to go to the hospital.
It's just --
My heart felt that God's watching...
What'd he say if he saw such aloofness?
I'd just say that Mam had stopped me from going.
May I call?
I'll just ask if he's come to.
He would've.
Of course he would've, Mam, but I think I'd just ask to show the Lord, if nothing else!
Or He'd see you!
Call him.
What are you looking for, now?
My phone.
There it is, by the pillow!
Before your eyes, but out of your sights.
Who knows where your gaze is fixed!
There's nothing to worry about.
Everything's okay.
Was I worrying?
No, sir,
You weren't worrying.
The people who'd come with you were worrying.
You're not going to eat anything solid before tomorrow evening.
Just milk
Or juice.
Alright?
Now, take care.
Thank you so much.
Why were you worried?
She was worried more than me.
She couldn't think of anything else.
If anything happened to you,
Perhaps it would've killed her to hear.
Her Mam practically dragged her away, or the people here would've started asking her who she was to you.
Jasmine?
Yes.
Jasmine.
The police came here for your statement; I've told them to come in the evening.
Good.
Go back to Hyderabad as soon as you get better.
I'm honest, Afzal,
If you stay here,
And keep this enmity with Wali going on alive,
It'd be difficult to keep yourself going on alive.
There is no place
For Reverend Subhanallah's son in this city.
I can't go back now.
Send me back in a coffin when I die,
But I will never go to Hyderabad to live.
Has he come to?
I didn't ask.
Why?
I didn't call.
You didn't call?
I thought
He'd not like it if I asked how he is over the phone.
How bad, Mam, innit,
He'd fought for me,
Taken the bullets because of me,
And if I, now, just ask him how he is over the phone
And shoo him away,
Wouldn't it grieve his heart?
So?
What should we do?
We should go there,
Stay with him until he gets better.
Don't even think of that, Jasmine.
You won't go there.
Why, Mam?
Is there anything wrong with it?
Yes.
It's wrong for the wrong type.
It's better that he come to his senses;
It'll be real bad if you came to your senses
Once you got there.
Alright,
Will you have a paratha [bread] or a toast with your tea?
It's this building here.
Are you coming along?
Shouldn't I?
It'd be better if I go, though.
He'd come along the moment you ask him.
Alright, come.
C'mon.
Dad!
There he is!
Right...
Excuse me...
Peace be upon you, sir.
What's your name?
Mehmood Ahmed, sir.
Mehmood Ahmed, is there any security guard with you around here by the name of Afzal?
There is, sir,
But he's not come today.
He's absent without leave.
Alright,
Tell me,
His address,
As in, where he lives?
Your name, sir?
Ibrahim.
Are you his family, sir?
Yes.
I'll ask and tell you, sir.
I've come to know he's come to,
And the doctor's checked and said he's alright.
Have something now, will you?
Don't be angry with me.
Just think, you, as a girl...
If you worry so much for any lad out there,
He'd think
That you've fallen for him, right?
And if you have, tell me.
No?
Surely not, Mam!
I knew it, too.
I just asked you to be on the safe side
So that I can break the face of anyone who gives me a mouthful.
Good.
That's just what I'd expected from you.
Your insistence about going to the hospital got me all worked up.
But it wasn't my fault...
Anyone seeing your condition would wonder
Why you're tormented more than the patient himself.
Should I get you something, now?
Just a cup of tea.
Tea? Alright.
One's got to start at something.
This is hardly the first time I've taken a bullet.
I'd taken one in Hyderabad, too.
It'd struck me here.
Right at my heart.
Ripped right through my heart.
That's why, to save myself, I'd come to Karachi.
How did you survive if the bullet struck your heart?
The miracles of nature, Babu Hamid...
I'd felt I'd not survive.
Put a sock in it!
I don't believe that.
Believe it, mate.
You can believe that a bullet can kill,
But can't believe that I survived?
Have your milk.
When the bullet had ripped through my heart,
Do you know how my heart felt?
Just ask who had operated on me.
Who?
I had.
I put on each of the stitches myself.
I'd fixed it and made it a heart again,
But I feel that a heart that's been fixed isn't much solid.
It can only do so much as help a man live on.
Do you have the slightest shame?
Farah, let's go --
Hey! Get off!
Let me see who's the boss!
Now that your engagement plan failed,
You stand in my way to get even?
You're playing the lover in front of everyone?
Want to besmirch my reputation?
You're Reverend Subhanallah's son,
So I thought you wouldn't step out of the house for days after all the insult that day.
You'd drown in shame,
Or leave Hyderabad to hide your disgraceful self!
The police are here to note your statement.
But you'd said they'd be coming in the evening?
It's almost evening, mun.
I'm looking for him...
I have his address.
I got it from his office.
Grab him by the ear and put him in the car if you find him.
That's what I've thought,
But I'm not sure he'd agree to get in the car.
Alright, I'll talk to you later.
If he agreed to come, I'd come back today.
-A -- Alright, talk to Lubna.
Give her the phone.
Peace be upon you, Dad.
And upon you, too!
Give him a slap if he tries to hold off.
Or have me talk to him.
What'd you do?
Dad, just let me talk to him, will you?
I'll give him such a scolding he'd calmly get in the car with you.
Alright, I'll have him talk to you if it's necessary.
Stop the car here.
Ask him.
Alright, disconnect already, now.
Please give the phone to Farah.
Here, talk to her.
Hello?
-Hello, Farah,
You're so wicked!
You didn't even tell me that you're going to Karachi!
Hello?
She's disconnected...
It got disconnected.
Just a minute, Mam.
Please, sit.
If I worry too much for him,
Who'd think I've fallen for him?
Everyone would,
Because people are rather undemocratic when it comes to love.
They'd weep for their own love,
But laugh at others when they weep.
Talk about yourself, Mam.
I don't fear people.
You've told me that there's nothing of the sort, right?
You're like other people, too, Mam,
You just referred to love as 'the sort'...
Tell me what I should say.
Say that Jasmine has fallen in love.
It's nothing 'of the sort'.
What it is, mun, is,
You're friends with Jasmine,
Which is why you're not intelligent like other Mams.
You don't even know when Jasmine's lying to you.
Step aside,
And pay attention to everything I'm saying -
Just like me, he's not intelligent either.
If I talk to him about you,
He asks, 'Are you talking about Jasmine'?
Ask what that means.
What does it mean?
It means he doesn't know, either, that Jasmine's lying.
How many of them were there?
Some
Eight or nine of them?
Eight or nine?
8-9.
What?
You were just saying 'eight or nine'.
Then, why are you asking 'eight or nine'?
You expect me to count
How many men are shooting at me?
That's not how you talk to your superiors!
Tell him this one, too,
'That's not how you talk to your superiors'.
Go on.
Who shot you?
I'd ask them.
Whom?
As in, you'd look for
And ask those who'd come to kill you
Which of them had shot you?
Yes.
I know a few of them.
I'd get hold of them and ask who'd shot me.
You'd ask them?
As if you would!
I've told you not to talk to the officer like that.
Babu Hamid, take them away.
Teach them some manners before letting them in.
Do you know who I am?
Once I'm discharged from the hospital, I'll tell you who I am.
Please, be kind enough to come later.
He's -- not well right now...
We have to get his statement now.
Once you get better,
I'll fix you up personally.
Babu Hamid, get them out of here.
Look at how you talk!
I'm Sub-Inspector Rafaqat Ali.
If you ask them about me,
You'd tremble at everything they'd tell you!
Babu Hamid, please ask this mad bloke to leave.
Please --
Please come later, alright?
He's gotten angry now.
If you want to ask him something,
Please don't address him so roughly.
Fair enough...
Who shot Your Lordship?
I won't tell you his name.
It isn't proper
That he be in the lock-up while I'm at the hospital.
How would a complaint be registered, then?
Oh, shoot! To the Devil with the complaint.
I don't have the time for the police and legal affairs.
My experience tells me
That this lad's intentions aren't right.
Your experience is absolutely right.
I, too, have a feeling that my intentions aren't right.
I've decided
To shoot
The man who'd shot me.
How intelligent are you, Jasmine?
Tell me, will you?
Or do you just trust your heart and think you're very intelligent?
Do you feel bad to hear
That I've fallen in love with him?
No, my dear.
It doesn't feel bad to know that you've fallen in love with him,
But it feels bad to know
That you don't know the slightest
About the heart of the one you love.
You asked him and satisfied yourself
That there's no one in his life.
One doesn't ask about those who come into and leave one's life;
One asks if there's anyone in one's heart.
Does Afzal live here?
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV