Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
What'll you wear, Reverend?
You think about it, Ruqaiyya Begum.
I will
Wear the same I did for Bakrid [feast of the sacrifice].
Why that one?
Why don't you talk about the other Eid [feast]?
I'm a believer, Ma'am.
I believe in being the foremost in sacrifice.
Are you attending a sacrifice ritual?
When
Suspicion mixes with happiness,
One should be prepared.
Any moment
May be the moment of the sacrifice.
What kind of suspicion?
Just...
But
I believe in God's mercy.
That's why I'm firm.
I'm just thinking why Monseigneur Ibrahim didn't call himself.
He sent his message; that's how it is.
And then,
When it's all done and over with,
There'll be no need for any calls.
Pay a visit in person.
In fact, take him along too.
That'll do good to both.
You'll get to meet [them],
And he'll get to see [her].
I'll never let that be.
We were engaged for four years,
And Dad had ordered that Subhanallah not pass through our street!
This here...
Are you getting even or
Guarding the tradition?
Whatever you think it is.
But the tradition wasn't wrong, Reverend.
Dad used to say,
'A gentleman's son should be the bee's knees',
'Not a bumbling bee'!
Have you ever asked me
How I spent those four years?
Will asking this bring them back?
It's okay.
They went by.
You remained over there,
And we over here.
Right...
You've had row with Lubna?
Why --
Why would I have a row with Lubna?
How did you suddenly feel that you love Farah?
Felt as in?
You're hiding something from me, aren't you?
Why would I?
And what would I hide?
You don't love Farah.
Alright.
So you'd tell me I don't love Farah.
Okay.
Then whom do I love?
Lubna.
Hey!
For God's sake,
I haven't even thought of her.
You're lying.
I saw that she was calling you and I answered it once too!
And I remember what I'd heard very well.
Not right!
And is it right that you're stuck on Lubna but want to marry Farah?
Hey -- Ask forgiveness of God, Arifa.
Am I that type?
That's what one cannot know - what type you are!
Alright.
Swear on my life.
Tell me
Farah is the one who used to write you letters, right?
I won't.
There.
You're lying, aren't you?
I don't need to swear on your life to tell the truth!
I'm saying it. Why not accept it as the truth?
Does the sight of cooking alert you too, now?
Poltroon!
Clean the dishes thoroughly. Make sure they're dry.
Let me see.
Peace be upon you, Mum.
And upon you, peace.
Lave your face and hands and freshen up.
Have your lunch; you won't have time later.
Are we expecting guests?
I asked something, Mum...
Just look at what you're asking!
Don't you know who's coming?
Good Lord, how do I know who's coming?
Would you look at what you're saying!
Servants are like family.
They'll think you change your mind like a chameleon does colours!
Will you keep on saying these things or tell me who's coming?
Are you out of your mind?
The same, again?
I'm just asking
Who is to be welcomed like this?
Oh God...
Anyway, freshen up; we'll talk later.
Talk about what?
I'm asking you a simple question.
Why are you so hesitant in answering it?
Do I have to tell you his name?
I'm not asking his address, after all!
-Remember this, Farah.
If you keep on saying these things, I'll grab something and smite my head with it.
Who's coming?
Someone's coming?
Go and check out in the kitchen.
All those cates --
The servants, the maid, the cook --
They're all busy with it.
Who could it be?
You tell me.
I've tired of asking Mum.
She's not ready to tell me.
A friend of Dad's, maybe?
No friend of Dad's.
Someone we know.
Someone we know will be coming,
And we haven't the foggiest.
Find out.
Go, Lubna!
Before this fear takes over me.
Don't send me.
I'm getting suspicious.
What kind of suspicion?
You're not getting good news.
To the dickens with bad news!
Oh, no way!
Can't be him!
You'd told him not to.
So,
Are you thinking the same?
I'm not thinking,
Just had a thought
That that's what's got you worried.
Let him show such audacity!
I'm going to feed him his teeth!
That's alright.
But what if the Reverend showed up?
But why would he?
He's your employee,
You pay him his salary.
And as per the contract --
-The contract...
Has been terminated.
He's been terminated, too.
I'd texted him,
'Your work is done'.
'Meet Lubna and collect your cheque'.
That rules out the Reverend paying a visit!
Yes.
I'm getting worried for nothing.
Why would he come?
Why would the Reverend come?
Why would anyone from his family come?
Who, then?
I'm going to the barber's.
Alright.
I thought
When I saw the yellow gown
That it'd suit you.
Thank you.
Your 'thank you' seems to have more of thankfulness
Than affection.
I, too, find more farewells than welcomes in the soirée invitation.
Hold that, Ruqaiyya Begum!
What's this twattle on such an auspicious day?
Seek God's counsel on it if you like.
I already have.
The signs are very favourable.
Sit for a while.
Okay.
Right here.
How could the signs be favourable?
The girl has changed here.
What?
She's not the one
Who used to write him letters.
Is it?
But how does it make any difference?
Does saying your afternoon prayers at daybreak make a difference?
Fear God, Ruqaiyya Begum!
You're mixing up everything!
It is also required of you to fear God.
Do not blaspheme against love by calling this good.
The same condition applies here:
You must honour your love
For the one you love, or you are a sinner.
Ask him
If his lover and his betrothed are not one and the same, say to him,
'Your mother ordains a judgement against you'
'That you cannot live under the same roof as the faithful'.
Good Lord!
It's not just Mum,
Even the maids won't tell!
When I asked Sakina Mai,
Do you know how she stared at me?
As if I've said something outrageous!
Something's cooking...
Call Afzal!
So simple!
Why couldn't you think of it earlier?
Give me your phone.
It's over there.
The two of you are sitting as if you really don't know a thing.
My dear,
Marriage is a serious affair.
The girl's family has to show some fine conduct.
Show whom?
You'd better not say anything.
If only I could know when you're earnestly being reasonable!
And you!
I'll have a good look at you after they've left.
After who's left?
I'll whack you so hard!
What are the two of you wearing today?
What are we-- ?
Anyway.
Wear whatever you like.
It's 6 right now.
Yes...
You ought to be ready by 8.30 sharp.
Get ready for what?
You will come down instantly.
And she'll come when she's called.
And remember:
Nobody should hear you or see your face
Before you're called.
Are we clear?
Yes.
Clear...
And lower your gaze
As you come downstairs.
If they ask you two questions,
Answer one [don't speak too much].
And your coyness should be visible when you answer.
And yes,
You wouldn't happen to remember the third pious declaration, would you?
I do, Mum.
-Recite it if they ask you to; it'll do good to your father's honour.
Recite the third pious declaration.
[Recitation]
Try again.
Keep on trying
Until that blighter answers the phone and talks,
Please, keep on trying!
Now you know who's coming.
Ask Arifa.
Call her.
She'd be praying.
Where are you going?
I'll pray too.
Not just the obligatory ones,
But 12 additional prayers as well.
Let's see what happens then.
-What'll happen?
The blighter will burst into flames!
Listen.
Yes?
Tell your mother
To wear that yellow gown.
I'll be coming right after the night time prayers.
Yes, Dad.
And yes,
Tell her also
That she need not be concerned about it anymore,
For the outcome will be positive.
Positive, as in,
She need not have any doubts.
Go.
Do you know now who's coming?
Yes.
Care to explain the reason for that act?
Act?
Come here.
Go on.
To be honest, Mum, I think she's bogey.
What bogey?
As they say in the Emerald Isle!
Why are you saying it here?
They say it in situations like these.
Say, when the girl changes her mind but you don't know why.
What's this you're saying?
You'd be furious,
But the truth is
She's thinking of someone other than Afzal.
Who?
There's no one!
But perhaps she's thinking Afzal's not the right choice either.
Which prayer is that?
The night prayer.
Did you offer those 12 additional prayers?
It's been a good while.
Alright, get ready.
They're coming.
And you may be called at any moment.
To the dickens with them!
Won't these two prayers and 12 additional ones do anything?
They would have, but think about it:
Whom are your prayers directed against?
One who offers all five of his and leads others'?
You'll get a bit of your reward and the 12 prayers will be of use later.
Didn't you tell Mum?
I did tell her,
And don't even ask how delira and excira she was about it!
What's the problem then?
Why should I get ready?
Dad's come, too.
Don't worry about Dad.
Mum will explain to him real quick.
If Dad understood it, it'll be time for a right beating!
Whom will he beat?
Don't ask whom.
Ask whom he will not beat!
It's good for your health
That you get ready in half an hour however you can!
Mum's hand is doing all the talking.
What do you mean?
Now, I've taken a few slaps before.
It's no problem with me.
But you've been deprived of this benediction thus far.
A single slap may prove to be fatal.
And, judging by her intentions,
It seems Mum will not stop at one,
She won't stop until you're battered!
Start in the Lord's name! They're here.
Peace be upon you!
-And upon you, peace, mercy, and blessings of God!
As God wills! [praise]
Peace be upon you!
-And upon you, peace, my child.
May you live long.
You have
Elevated me in stature, Monseigneur Ibrahim.
I used to think, like any mother, that my son is a prince.
You have made my dream a reality.
It is our good fortune,
That our daughter
Will be married to one from such a noble House.
We'll take a good look at ours when we go back,
And see
If it is indeed noble.
Please, come in.
Come.
-In the name of the Lord.
This is Farah's room, isn't it?
Yes.
Where is she?
She's getting ready.
Come with me.
You've come here with the proposal, right?
No.
We were passing by and thought we'd pay a visit.
No way!
I know everything.
I'm just asking if you're prepared for everything.
Of course.
We are prepared.
Dad doesn't leave anything half-done.
Why are you standing there?
Please, sit down.
But what about that girl
Who used to write letters to Afzal?
What do you mean?
You'd told me
That Afzal loves a girl
And the two of them have an exchange of letters going on.
Don't you remember?
When I'd asked
'Do people still write letters in this day'?
And you'd said --
-It isn't Farah, then...
Farah?
Farah would write a letter?
Are you off your nut?
She doesn't write, you muppet,
She types.
An SMS, at the most.
But don't worry
Everything will be alright.
What will be alright?
My parents have come to your place.
Is it April Fools' today
That you'd say to them, 'You took it seriously? We were just kidding'!
Do you know
Mum's wearing a yellow gown after ages.
Seeing it, she said,
'This colour won't suit me'!
Dad said it would.
And she wore it.
And, about Dad -
He never goes to the barber except on Fridays.
Today's Sunday,
But he went today.
Left with a smile on his face,
Came back elated.
What were you saying?
No --
It's nothing.
So Farah's not the one?
May I talk to Farah?
Sure.
They're calling you downstairs.
Tell them we're coming in a few minutes.
They want you to come right now.
We've got to go right now.
Come.
I'm going downstairs; you've still got time.
Wear something nice.
No need to hatch any plots!
The tables have turned such
That his pawn will take your king.
So please,
Accept your defeat today.
And marry him?
No; just get engaged.
An engagement can be broken.
But don't risk breaking so many hearts today.
Without telling the good lady,
I've brought this gold ring.
If you'd allow me,
May I put it on her after dinner?
As it pleases you, Reverend.
Thank you.
Do me another favour, would you?
Pray tell.
Pinch me a couple of times
Before she comes.
Irsa,
The Reverend has brought a ring for Farah.
He's asking if he can put it on her after dinner.
Of course,
His wish is our command.
Why wait until after dinner? Why not before it?
Your wish is my command.
Go, my dear.
Bring her here.
Right.
I thought we'd hidden the two of them from each other for nothing.
Once they're engaged, they'd get a reason to have dinner together.
You've come to call me?
Yes.
Come.
-You're coming like this?
Should I sit in a palanquin?
For God's sake, Farah.
At least wear something suited to the occasion.
What I'm wearing right now
Is far better than their better dresses!
Come.
I've been waiting for this for four hours.
There aren't many legal limitations to love.
Peace be upon you.
This is our Farah?
Yes.
Praise the Lord!
God ward the evil eye off her!
Monseigneur, I'd asked you
To pinch me.
But you forgot to!
The Reverend is just...
Sit down, my dear.
How can she sit down just like that?
Won't you embrace me?
Look closely, Reverend.
My Afzal has become the best one [Afzal] today!
Don't tarry now, Ruqaiyya!
Before I wake up from my sleep,
Put this ring on my daughter.
Come.
Sit down.
We can't wait any longer.
Please, sit.
Praise the Lord [Subhanallah], Reverend!
You've picked quite the ring.
Ask her if she likes it.
Do you like it?
She's just being demure...
No.
I'm not being demure.
It is with regret that I have to say this,
But no such engagement is happening here
As what you're so euphoric about.
It's all because of him!
The truth is
I was about to be married off to one Mehtab.
And I didn't like Mehtab one bit.
I thought I'd talk to Dad about it,
But couldn't steel myself.
Dad liked him so much then.
That's why I feigned love for someone else.
In my haste, I found him,
And struck a deal
Of 800,000 with him.
The deal's no more now.
I'd even told him
Not to bring his parents here.
But I don't know why
He brought you here
Without telling me or asking me about it!
I know
A moment's daftness brought me here.
But I'd never thought I'd call you here and decline.
Tell me,
What could I do?
And I swear by God, I don't even know your Afzal well enough!
Forgive me,
But he's a first rate fraudster.
The move he's played
Even after everything was decided
Is one I'll never forgive him for!
Forget getting engaged to him,
I don't even want to see his face!
I have but
One complaint from you, my dear...
I didn't ask you to pinch me...
Come, Ruqaiyya.
Tell Madame that under these circumstances,
I won't be able to have dinner...
Let's go.
-Come.
Do not bother, my dear...
I would much rather prefer the darkness...
Do not
Look at each other tonight.
There are questions in everyone's eyes,
But answers in no one's.
You didn't even ask him
Where he was off to!
Where could the poor lad go?
He's got the answers to your questions;
He's just hiding from you.
He must be thinking he'd come back
When Mum and Dad are asleep.
As if we could we fall asleep tonight!
I've
Seen to it.
First bought a ring for his bride,
And then, sleeping pills for myself.
You'd known it all along?
I'd known nothing!
But I'd known so much
That the thrill of gladness wouldn't let us sleep!
Here.
Take one
And give me one.
I would never take one!
I'll sit and writhe in pain all night.
Oh?
Alright.
Then,
Wake me up at daybreak.
If you run away from woe, Reverend,
You'll find him at your doorstep in the morning!
We shall see in the morning.
If he shows up uninvited,
He can't meet us when he pleases!
I'll meet him at my leisure. Right.
Your honour is a bit weak.
No.
My heart is a bit weak.
At least tell me something
That makes me feel that you consider me a friend.
I won't tell you anything,
But I'll torch all her letters today.
She left you?
Here, mate.
Take a puff of this,
Forget all your sorrows and leave her.
No. Don't smoke.
He who smokes away his life for one so unfaithful is more animal than man!
Mum and Dad have been humiliated so much!
What do I do about that?
Did they go along too?
Apologise to your parents --
Again?
I ask forgiveness of Dad every other day, and that's enough!
There's nothing wrong about it, mate.
It's your duty to ask forgiveness
And theirs to forgive.
To be truthful, parents
Do God's work in their old age.
That's what He does, too.
His creation errs,
And He forgives.
Mum thinks I'm 'Afzal' [the most excellent].
But I've realised today I'm the most depraved.
She'd not have slept!
She will, once you set foot in the house.
Won't she be furious?
Won't she ask, 'Why did you take your father there'?
Why did you take him?
Didn't you know she'd decline?
What could I do, Sajid?
One has to be untrue if one's heart is untrue.
There wouldn't have been any mention of it had my parents not gone there,
And had there been no mention of it, how would I have known that all her letters were but lies?
Who declined the proposal?
Was it her or her parents?
She did.
So did she write all those letters to get her nib working?
Just say it openly that she's turned out to be unfaithful.
She can't be.
She used to write him letters twice every week.
How can she be unfaithful?
I get it.
Her parents must not have agreed to it.
And convinced her, too, for the sake of her parents,
With a fair bit of begging and praying.
There's not a bit of perfidy in this.
When a girl listens to her parents, she just declines.
It's nothing new.
More than 50% love stories end when the parents beg before their children.
But I'm glad to hear this.
Let me say this straight, Afzal,
What could a girl respect you,
If she does not respect her parents' honour?
Shut up, mate!
If she had the slightest concern for her parents' honour,
She could've just asked her Mum before falling in love,
'Should I'?
Why must it always strike people later on?
You should forget her too.
Burn the pyre of your love,
And scatter the ashes in the Ganges,
And look towards the Yamuna.
Who's Yamuna?
You bugger!
The Yamuna is next to the Ganges!
And there must be someone beyond the Yamuna.
Can't anyone else in Hyderabad write letters?
You, too, should get out of these exchanges of letters,
And try texting!
The world's speeding up.
Speed up your love, too!
Talk to someone else!
There.
The bugger's crying now!
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV