Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
He's here, Jasmine.
He looks so handsome!
I swear!
Won't you wish me peace today?
I won't today.
How do I look?
The sweetest;
The best. ['Afzal']
Come.
It's time for the engagement.
Come on, my dear, it's getting late.
Greetings.
Peace be upon you, Monseigneur Ibrahim!
-And upon you, peace.
Congratulations!
To you as well.
Come.
I've
Brought the old ring.
Farah had said
That she'd only wear this one today.
Alright, Reverend. Come.
Here, Jasmine. Place the ring on him.
Congratulations!
Afzal, place the ring on her now.
Sir!
Here.
Your turn now, Monsieur.
No, Monseigneur.
It is my request
That Reverend Subhanallah should be the one
To place the ring on my daughter on my behalf.
Me --?
No -- I -- I'm nobody.
Come on, Reverend.
When you call her your daughter, it makes you her father.
Come.
Every compeer
Every compeer abandoned me
After ephemeral moments of companionship
Who has the leisure to stand by
One so crazed in love
I found even my own shadow
Apathetic and blasé
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Reverend!
He's had a heart attack.
A very severe one.
Come here.
Sit by me.
Don't worry.
A son's attack strikes worse than a heart attack.
Nothing happened then, and I'm sure nothing will happen to him now.
Hey! Stop crying.
Else I'd think the Reverend's words and deeds are contradictory.
It's just a heart attack, isn't it?
Everything else is alright...?
Yes, everything else is alright.
Alright.
You heard that?
I know the Reverend well enough.
It's been 28 years
He's never been into knavery with me.
Don't think
He tripped because of the heart attack.
No, no, it was something else...
You raised your hand to wear the ring
He must've thought you're pointing your finger at him.
He must've remembered his coconut biscuits...
The poor lass gets so worried.
She lacks that belief
Despite the fact that the Reverend had said to her,
'Arifa',
'If you pray and yet worry',
'It means you don't have faith in He who shall accept it'.
'Accursed be such a prayer'.
Come here, Madame.
Please, sit.
As he was getting ready for the engagement,
I thought for a while I'd stop him.
That I say, 'Reverend, it's not propitious for you to attend engagements'.
But then
Thinking of his friendship with Farah, I stayed quiet.
Thought he'd feel about it if he did not go.
Once he gets well,
Please don't invite him to the next engagement.
What are you saying?
Only what's right.
The thing is, it hurt a little to know about Afzal's engagement.
That he did not invite us.
But I was relieved,
Because if he'd gone there,
That engagement would never have happened, if the Lord thus willed.
Why don't you ask, Monseigneur?
He must've come to by now.
How's he, Doctor?
Blessed be you; he's regained consciousness.
Thank God!
There!
He's come to.
I'd known it.
He'd come to right away.
You'll see,
He'll ask the moment he gets up
If she's been engaged.
He'll be happy that the engagement's been postponed.
I saw you here for the first time.
My heart...
Felt something when I saw you.
I hope you understand what 'something' means to a girl?
She feels it'll kill her to control her heart.
You did the right thing in getting engaged to me.
I was lost, Afzal.
As you turn away your gaze, it seems you're rueful about yourself.
I know why.
You didn't invite your parents.
That explains it, doesn't it?
Yes.
-Then why didn't you invite them?
They'd never have come.
Especially Dad.
Mum and Arifa would have, then.
You don't know Mum.
When she talks,
She's Afzal's mother.
When she pronounces a judgement,
She's Reverend Subhanallah's wife.
They must've come to know.
No.
They don't know.
They do.
They called me.
She was on the rack because of you.
This is an old habit of yours, Afzal.
You torment the one
Who feels torment for you.
Who gave them your number?
I don't know.
They must've found out somehow.
Those who want to look do eventually find out, Afzal.
I'm wicked, Jasmine...
That's the second time I've struck them.
Mum must've teared up and Dad must've put his hand over his heart.
But he won't weep before anyone.
Give me your address.
I'd promised them to come right after the engagement.
If you don't, I'll call and ask them.
And this - I've just asked permission to go.
May I?
No.
Not now.
Keep up with these orders after the marriage.
For now, behave like a fiancé.
Yes, Timmy?
A -- Eladio called from Hyderabad.
Bad news, Afzal.
Go on.
It's --
T --
The Reverend's had a heart attack.
The doctors have sent me outside.
'Not now', they said.
Just see him for now, and leave.
I've seen him.
He, too, got a bit embarrassed when he saw me.
Turned his gaze away momentarily.
Why was he embarrassed?
He used to think I'd be the one to have a heart attack.
I used to place my hand over my heart in agony,
And he'd call the doctor that instant.
And now...
His heart couldn't take it...
He doesn't let it show up on his face.
Why should it, really...
He doesn't let what's in his heart come on his face.
-Mum...
Right here.
His sweet little one's feeling bad about me remembering all of this.
But I will say everything.
Your Dad's been hollow-hearted.
How?
Once, he said to me,
'We've given our hearts to each other'.
'So, what does that mean'?
I asked what it meant,
And he said,
'If an affliction strikes my heart',
'I'll take it to mean that you didn't keep it safe from harm'.
And this --
This heart attack he's had
It's not that he's had this attack
My heart's the one afflicted.
You will see
Once he gets back home,
It'll be said plainly.
I'll say,
I'll say, 'Take your heart, and give me mine back'.
Who are you?
Hello?
Right...
Here. Talk to him.
Hello?
Who's it?
Inspector Shamsi Rehman.
Let them go.
Who are you, sir?
Disconnect; I'll call your number.
You may proceed.
-Alright.
Yes sir?
Of course I'd recognised your voice, sir.
You'd said it, sir.
Check all who pass.
Alright sir. Okay.
There you are! Good.
It's getting late, please have something.
No, thank you.
I've vowed to have breakfast with him.
I've vowed too -
I'd give something to eat to the others only after you've had something.
It's up to you.
They'll all be hungry because of you.
No -- I'll have something.
Dad called.
He gave a suggestion.
What?
He said
The Reverend will be fine by daybreak.
So?
So --
Why not go forth with the engagement here?
I mean -- I've been carrying the ring with me, so --
I'd told Dad you'd not agree to it.
Enjoy the meal.
A --
Afzal?
Come here, my dear...
I've been missing you...
Come here, my child...
Afzal...
Child...
My son... Come here.
Come here, my dearest...
Is there a Mr Afzal here?
He's calling Afzal?
He's calling him.
Go.
He's called you.
Not her; he's called Afzal.
-She's Afzal.
She's Afzal in his absence.
She's my daughter.
Enough...
My hand is drenched with your tears...
What happened?
Nothing.
Just --
You scared us all.
Scared her too?
No.
Not her.
Kept saying,
'The Reverend's not hollow-hearted'.
She has her own way to reason...
Says anything...
And God smiles on hearing it...
Who's the one he was calling out to in his sleep?
In my sleep?
Who was I calling out to?
Afzal. You mentioned a certain Afzal.
Asleep or unconscious?
I cannot make such a mistake in my sleep...
But then there's no power but God's...
Where's --?
He's not come, Dad.
He doesn't even know.
I'm not talking about him --
I was asking about your mother.
Please, let her come too...
And don't tell her
I called out to 'Afzal' in my sleep...
Her heart's a bit frail...
Sure, call her, but only for a short while.
Afzal is my son.
Rather unduteous...
Which is why I'm cross with him...
Yes sir
He's entered Hyderabad.
No sir,
Three cars.
The third one has his guards.
Don't worry, sir!
Reverend...
Guess who's here.
Miss Coconut Biscuits is at your feet.
Gotten engaged?
Did you hear that?
The first question.
Satisfy him.
Tell him she's not gotten engaged.
The engagement can wait.
Get well soon and come home. Then, we'll fix the date.
There now.
Look at his happiness.
He's saying he's not happy.
Would've been better if she'd gotten engaged.
Look -
The groom's here too.
He's been here all the time.
Ready as if
He'd go forth with the wedding on this very day.
What do you know, son,
He's one who'd not let his son get engaged.
Who are you?
He's the one who'll put the ring on me.
I'm adamant over this.
You're clashing with God's man.
You'll pay for it later.
What are you saying, Ruqaiyya?
Look at the gloom on her face...
We know whom we're clashing with.
We'll pay for it if we have to, but make no complaints.
Excuse me for a while; I'll drop them home.
No -- no,
There's no need to come...
I'm fine now...
I'll come for my rightful reward.
At this age, one has to struggle to win it.
Come, my dear.
I'll bring you breakfast tomorrow.
Good be with ye.
I'm leaving Sibtain here.
Why are you troubling me, my good man?
Sorry, son...
You're trapped here for nothing.
Not at all, Uncle Reverend,
No one's trapped me.
I told Dad I'd stay here.
Alright, goodbye.
Goodbye.
Did you see, Ruqaiyya?
The world owes a lot to people like them.
Else the horn [of Doomsday] would long have been blown...
Peace be upon you.
Is Dad alright?
Yes, he's alright.
Got engaged?
Next time, we won't invite Uncle Reverend to my engagement.
Jasmine?
She's so sweet!
Where's Dad?
Upstairs in a room.
Wait, Afzal.
He's just regained consciousness.
He called out to you as he was unconscious.
As he came to,
He got angry at the mention of your name.
Take it slowly.
Meet Mum first,
And ask her to let you meet Dad.
He'd left at odds with Dad's orders.
It's as if he'd broken him...
Now --
Making amends will take ten or so minutes...
But don't worry.
He'll meet you the moment he comes to know.
I'll call Mum.
Afzal's here?
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV