Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Peace be upon you, Mum.
What happened to her?
Why was she so furious?
She's coming after insulting him!
Who?
The same Afzal.
Came across him a few times,
And it got into her head.
She's said such things
As only God can forgive her for!
Hey...
I did the right thing, right?
In a way, you did.
But you did it too early.
If I didn't do it early,
The blighter would've besmirched my name in the entire neighbourhood!
Those who can listen to abuses quietly
Never besmirch others' names.
You've besmirched his name,
And along with him, you've besmirched your own name.
It occurred to me last night that I should call Arifa and ask her to tell him
Not to show himself before Farah.
But you...
Well,
What's done is done.
You bugger!
That'd be your fourth cigarette!
You've been telling me for two years
And now you'd die out of grief over a girl?
I'm in dire straits, Sajid.
I was in dire straits too.
Back then, you used to pull my leg.
Hyderabad can no longer nurture my life
But my Mum won't let me leave.
Where would you go?
Karachi.
To whom?
To Karachiites.
And what's your reason for going?
My conscience asks me to go.
Then why are you asking your Mum?
Go.
I will, Sajid.
If only someone told me
Which of my mother and my conscience is the greater.
Why don't you tell him?
The mother is always the greater one!
He'd only take his mother's word on that.
If she's the one who wrote those letters, who was the one who meted out such humiliation that night?
That's what I can't quite understand.
I'm thinking of meeting her one of these days
And asking her the true story.
Perhaps the two of them have had some differences.
Or perhaps it's that she does not love him anymore?
Why, then, was she talking about 800,000 and some deal?
She said she'd hired him for 200,000 a month
To 'love' her for four months.
That part about four months is a white lie.
She's been writing him letters for years!
Since the days she must be doing her GCSEs!
Ah, the pastimes of opulent demoiselles!
A letter to one,
A call to another...
She's not the type!
She's an honest type of girl!
A bit apprehensive and skittish,
One who saves herself from the evil gaze.
She's neither snappish, nor conceited.
If you sit with her, it feels like you're with an old friend.
She'd seize your hand and stop you as you're leaving.
I'd only seen her love,
This is the first time I've seen her despise someone.
Lubna's calling.
Hello?
It's Lubna.
I know.
What were you doing?
I was sitting with Mum.
She's stitching me a shirt.
Where are you now?
In my room.
And where's your brother?
He's not at home.
Have you ever asked him where he goes?
No.
Nobody asks him such questions.
Oh...
So you've given him free rein.
Lubna,
I know my brother just as well as you know your sister.
I've never called to say to you,
'So you've given Farah free rein'.
Arifa,
You're getting angry because you don't know the truth.
And you're saying all of this because you don't know the truth either.
I called to tell you something, mate.
It seems you were just itching to pick a quarrel!
Go on.
He stands in our way as we go to University in the morning
As he does
When we're coming back.
So what?
What 'so'?
This isn't something good.
Many more boys can be found standing on roads and in alleyways.
I suppose you call to tell their sisters too?
Please, Arifa,
Farah is mad with rage over it.
Tell her to buy the entire neighbourhood if she can!
Watch how you're talking!
I will talk like this, Lubna, if you talk about my brother this way.
Do you know what happened today?
Something's happened?
He was standing in our way,
And Farah saw him.
Stopped the car, got out, and humiliated him before everyone!
Are you listening?
I've just called to tell you
To stop him.
Next time, she'd slap him on his face!
Then tell Farah to be afraid!
I'm going to break her face!
Are you listening?
You might as well hear this:
If my brother's quietly taken all that insult,
Tell Farah she'll get a befitting reply to it.
I will talk to her
On that very street and alleyway!
Are you mad?
Are you touched in the head?
Give the phone to her!
I want to talk to the blighter!
Let me see her snobbery over her father's riches!
Give the phone to her, will you?
Tell the peeress to try something like this again if she's got the courage!
Leave a slap,
I dare her to talk to Afzal with so much as her voice raised!
I swear by my father, I'd rip her apart!
He'll be standing right there in the morning,
Tell her to stop the car,
And come out!
I swear by God,
I'm not Reverend Subhanallah's daughter if I did not cut her down to her puny size!
Peace be upon you.
And upon you.
She was alright just now...
Her friend called her, and
She dashed upstairs.
'Her friend called her'!
Put it plainly that Lubna called her.
She will only give such expressions when she'd call her.
Mum!
I'm going to Lubna's!
She's taken after you.
One can't tell whether you're just letting me know or asking for permission when you leave for somewhere!
Don't ask for your 98,000 now.
I've quit gambling.
I'm a bit skint these days.
Talk to the old colony lads.
We're playing a match tonight.
You must be itching to play some cricket...
You must be itching to play some cricket... Innit?
No.
I've got an itch to gamble.
Put a sock in it!
You don't believe me, do you?
You think like my Dad that I've corrected my ways?
I haven't corrected my ways, mate.
Not one bit! I'm my same old self.
A gambler.
I swore an oath,
Made promises,
But kept on playing.
The thing is, I've badly lost a big gamble.
I have not a penny
In my heart, mind, or pocket.
I've lost everything, mate.
Just talk to the old colony lads.
Tell them we're playing for 100,000.
We're playing the match today, Babloo.
I don't have any money.
And what if you lost?
Put a sock in it!
I lost to someone else.
I never played to win there in the first place.
Alright, talk to them and call me.
I'll give the buggers a proper beating!
Call her!
Get me through to her!
Let me see, too, how she talks!
Splendid,
Instead of being ashamed of what her brother did
And asking forgiveness of me,
She's showing me such arrogance!
I'm saying call her!
To the dickens with her!
To the dickens with you, too!
If you know how to create a scene on the road,
I know how to barge in and take on the likes of you!
What's this, Arifa?
Sit down and talk calmly.
Sit down my foot!
I consider it my insult to set foot in the house of the haughty!
It was her depravity that compelled me to come here to give a befitting reply,
Else, I would not even spit at your doorstep!
Look, you're being insolent there!
If I uttered something, it'd inflame you!
Shut up, Farah.
She's come to our home.
Is there anything left for you to inflame?
Or do you think that you can don this knavish veil and be hailed as virtuous?
You're not virtuous.
Behind your innocent face, you conceal the disgustful truth of your character!
Your family may be nescient but I'm not.
I know everything,
As does he
The one you've humiliated in broad daylight.
He listened to every bit of your bosh quietly because he's Reverend Subhanallah's son.
Don't take this for his poltroonery;
Such is his upbringing,
Farah Ibrahim.
Whether a woman is one like yourself or like one
Miss Rosy from your office,
He's been taught to respect her at any cost.
Look, Arifa,
This is not proper.
If she's made a mistake,
Talk to her calmly.
Too much has been said already for me to talk calmly now.
The only thing left, now, is a confrontation.
I'll meet you in the same alleyway tomorrow morning.
My brother will be with me.
Get out of your car and walk up to him if you dare,
And if I fail to make your disgustful reality show up on your face,
I'd change my name!
That's enough, Arifa.
If you cannot talk calmly, you may show yourself out.
I'm leaving, my dear.
But let me just
Hold a mirror up to her as I leave...
Here
Are four letters for you to read.
There are over a hundred in my brother's cupboard.
Reading these would
Tear the curtain of her virtuousness that's been pulled over your eyes.
She is the one
Who used to write letters to my brother.
Sorry, Aunt,
But I had no other option.
Do you have these memorised by heart or do I need to read them out?
Farah!
May the Lord reward you [for this favour].
Peace be upon you.
Hey!
You're back already?
Didn't she serve you tea or something?
I needed just so much time to do what I had to.
And you know just as well
That theirs is not a place where we can have tea.
I'm going to offer my afternoon prayers.
What did you have to do?
There is still time for the afternoon prayer.
Would you say something only when your Dad asks or would you give me the honour?
Farah had misbehaved with him.
I'd gone to give her a befitting reply.
Why did she misbehave?
She thought Afzal stands in her way as she goes to and comes back from the University.
Is there any bit of truth in this?
Well, he's surely been going somewhere for the last two days...
There are bits of truth in a lot more, Mum.
She'd concealed some, and we'd concealed others.
Everything's come out in the open today.
-What have you done?
Shoved her letters in her face
And said that I'd have her answer for this latest insult.
What a silly girl!
She lives in a glass house and throws stones at lovers.
Get it straight, Mademoiselle,
Even if Afzal loves you,
We are not bound by his love.
Our intentions may change any minute.
Look, Afzal,
I've talked about the match,
But I've only got 1,500 Rupees.
That's enough.
Keep it safe in your pocket.
What about the remaining 98,500?
What for?
You bugger!
We'd have to give 100,000 in cash if we lost the match!
Spit in my face if I lose.
I've told you,
There's no chance of losing, Babloo.
Hey!
Watch those big words.
Remember,
It only takes one ball to get bowled.
Be positive, mate.
Think how long it takes to not get bowled.
Tell me the time.
8 p.m. sharp.
Get ready.
I'll be there at 8.
That was all it was.
Lie down, dear.
Come with me.
Where's she going?
She's fine, doctor.
She had to go somewhere.
She's late.
As you wish, but she's not completely fine right now.
She will be in a while.
Come, doctor.
Where to?
Tell him.
Where?
Why, Arifa's!
Turn right.
Where's she gone?
To Afzal's.
Why?
She came across him on her way and insulted him.
Arifa came here and put her right in her senses when she found out.
She must've gone to apologise.
Who's Arifa?
Afzal's sister.
She'll have to admit it one day, Irsa,
That he's very virtuous.
My impression can never be off.
God is the Greatest...
Rush to your success...
For there is none but Him.
Sit.
Don't worry.
There's nobody here except the two of us.
Would you like some tea or coffee?
We also have coffee at our place.
No, thank you.
Do you want to check the cups and dishes?
They're clean.
They've been washed.
Please, Arifa, sit.
I want to talk to you.
You will not say one word against my brother.
I will neither listen nor let you speak.
I will forget that you've come to our house.
I promise
I won't say a word against your brother.
I've just come to explain my side of the story
And I hope you'd believe everything I have to say.
I can't guarantee that.
Alright.
I have a way out.
Get the Qur'an and keep it here.
I'm ritually pure
And have come to swear on oath.
If you don't believe my purity,
I can purify myself before you.
Alright.
Go on.
No.
Bring the Qur'an.
I will say everything as an oath on the Qur'an.
No, my dear.
Go on.
I trust everything you have to say.
I solemnly swear with the Lord as my witness
That I've never written any letter to Afzal.
All these letters are false.
Or the Farah in these letters
Is someone else...
I've only seen Afzal passing by
About three or four times in my lifetime.
Or heard from the maid or Lubna
That Afzal is Arifa's brother.
I met him for the first time in my life
In her presence at the restaurant,
Where we decided he'd --
Feign love for me for four months,
For which I'd pay him 800,000 Rupees.
I mean
200,000 a month.
This, too, happened because of her
Because she'd wanted to help him
As he had been ousted an innocent and was out of work.
She thought it'd earn him some.
And
If he's ever met me during this period,
Or paid a visit to meet Mum and Dad, it was all a part of his job.
I was able to get rid of the one
I was getting married off to,
But if Mum and Dad
Found Afzal suitable in these meetings,
What's my fault?
What do I have to do with their choice?
This is why we'd planned it with Afzal
That under any such circumstance,
He'd leave Hyderabad for a month or two.
But -- I don't know what suddenly got into him,
He brought you and Uncle Reverend over to my place to get engaged to me.
I believe your purity.
Place your hand over the Honourable Qur'an and swear that everything you've said is true.
Hold it, Farah.
Wait.
Ask me instead.
I can place my hand over the Qur'an and swear
That everything she's said is true.
Peace be upon you, Monsieur.
And upon you, peace.
Who's come?
Mesdemoiselles Farah and Lubna.
Right...
Everything alright?
Everything's fine.
Alright, my dear.
There, now!
Speak of the Devil!
God has willed for him such a long life!
Come here, my son.
We were missing and waiting for none but you.
Come here, my dear, why are you embarrassed?
Who's the outsider here, whose presence has you petrified?
There's good old Lubna,
And with her,
Sweet Farah.
She's come here to listen to all her letters!
You read them out with such evident pleasure!
And the poor lass cannot even remember what she's been writing to you all along!
She's not the one who used to write letters to me, Mum.
Why didn't you take us to her place then?
I will, one day.
I live in wait of that day.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
You've come
To pinch us again, haven't you?
And
What's with this walloping before the guests?
The blighter's knavery has been caught again!
He's been up to knavery before?
He used to rob me of my serenity,
But now, it's as if he's killed me!
We'll take our leave...
No, my dear, how can that be?
You've come here for the first time,
And seeing this empty table, it seems
Like you've had nothing at all!
Sit. Please, sit.
Go, my dear, get some tea or coffee. Go.
And, Ruqaiyya Begum,
Robbing parents of their serenity and life is no robbery,
For both are a treasure in the possession of children,
That they can dig up and collect when they desire.
My good man,
Rob us of all our serenity if you want,
But please don't suck the life out of her just yet.
Your mother is very helpful to me.
Right,
Ruqaiyya Begum,
She's come to our house for the first time.
Do not let her leave empty-handed.
How's Dad, my dear?
He's fine.
And what are you doing, standing here like this?
Go and purify yourself.
Offer your night prayers
And beg forgiveness for all the sins
That only God and perhaps the four of these know about!
Go!
I have
A fair idea about what you want to say, but pray tell,
What's the news?
He's said it today
That she's not the Farah who used to write him letters.
Who is she, then?
Well, I'm sure you'd tell me about that later.
Pray tell, my dear,
Do I beg forgiveness
On his behalf,
Or ask his mother to?
You're embarrassing us, Uncle...
My dear, if it's embarrassing to you,
Alright,
I'll humour both of us to guard our esteem.
The truth, my dear,
Is that I am firm with regard to my honour,
And I'm fully aware
That a child is a benefaction from God.
But, my dear,
I lack the courage
To return such a benefaction to God in my lifetime.
He's my only son, so naturally, I'm afraid
Swept away by emotion,
He may take a wrong step,
Or perhaps leave me.
That is why
I usually talk in such a manner
Before him
As I used to before my Dad.
So,
All I have said to him before you
Has been, by this standard, rather too harsh.
Yes -- I know...
Now that the truth has come out, it pains me so much to think
Of all the cates we couldn't relish that day.
All of you
Must've prepared
Some real delicacies!
I'll invite you again sometime.
We'll prepare the same delicacies again.
No, my dear,
When a man fears embarrassment,
He no longer feels hunger.
Now, how would I be...
I'll go and see; he may have bolted the door from inside.
There!
He's bolted the door from inside.
Check --
-What --
Afzal!
Yes, Dad?
You're offering your prayers, aren't you?
I will in a moment, Dad!
He'll offer his prayers.
You'll see,
God will forgive him the moment he prays.
Please, my dear, forgive him.
Listen!
What did you do there?
She's proven that she's not the Farah who writes letters to Afzal.
So that's some other Farah?
So it seems.
Why was he head over heels for our Farah, then?
There.
That's one mystery left unsolved.
Nor could one understand
Why the sight of Farah brought him to tears.
Nonetheless,
The truth has been made crystal clear.
What's this in your hands?
I don't know.
Perhaps a shawl, a suit,
Or cloth for a suit.
The Reverend said that Farah had come to his house for the first time,
So she must not leave empty-handed.
The unfortunate Reverend.
He's unfortunate too,
But one can only feel his helplessness,
And not understand it.
I hope she didn't show her fury there.
Not at all, Mum!
She was shaking like a leaf.
And, given the kind of family his is,
Nobody would dare show a hint of fury before them!
They only know love,
And it is with their affection that they can kill.
May I go now?
I need to ask her, too,
Why she teared up when leaving.
At least I know
That Afzal is the only spoilt one in the family.
I told you,
There's one mystery left to be solved...
One's mind says he's not noble,
But one's heart cannot agree to it.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV