Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Whatever happens to you every time?
Blowing hot and cold like that!
Mind your temperature, would you?
I can't look Dad in the eyes...
I feel as if I've committed a grave mistake.
Instead of making a right bags of it, I should've taken Mum into confidence and told her I'm not marrying Mehtab.
I'm not marrying anyone!
I'm going to London for my MPhil.
What could be done now?
Why not?
Dad could be saved from this sorrow called Afzal by telling the truth!
Dad won't trust you for the rest of your life!
He'll think you lie openly, and I back you up with false statements!
What's my fault?
Why are you besmirching my image?
-You're worried about your image?
And it's killing me to see Dad's woe!
Woe will engulf him anyhow
Whether you decline Mehtab,
Or stay adamant about Afzal.
I hear Dad had made yours and Mehtab's match in your childhood.
Thank God his Dad's no more,
Or he'd be at our doorstep, creating a ruckus,
Telling everyone
'Ibrahim is not true to his words'!
Idea!
Ever tripped in a swamp?
Yes, once...
Don't you remember --
-I do. Don't remind me.
Just remember that those who trip don't get ideas.
Then
Should I remain firm?
You'll have to.
Don't try to disgrace me in Dad's eyes!
Call Afzal.
What do I tell him?
Why,
Fix a meeting for tomorrow!
Why don't you call him?
Ask him to meet come before the news bulletin.
If you'll meet him before the news bulletin, when will he meet Dad?
Why would I meet him?
You'll have to.
Sit with him and tell him what to wear tomorrow
How to comport himself, behave, and talk,
And how to look back
When Dad stares at him!
How?
As if --
He's cadging!
Cadging?
Cadging, as in...
Begging, pleading.
Right, so...
How about you meet him?
Tell him everything one by one!
For God's sake, Farah,
Talk to him for once.
He, too, should see that the one he 'loves' is easily accessible.
Accessible?
Or else he'll start stammering before Dad at the mention of your name!
Alright.
I'll tell you everything now.
He loves someone else.
She, too, writes to him twice a week.
It's an old love story.
So?
Try to understand, Farah.
To get such a connatural lover to feign love for another girl is not easy.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
It's no big deal.
Besides, for the amount you're offering,
Any indigent artist would agree to give his best performance!
He's my friend's brother,
And hasn't got a job these days,
I thought he'd earn something this way.
Where do I meet him?
At the same restaurant.
You'll see.
He'll die of greed.
If his girlfriend found out
You'll see what she does to him!
Call him.
Wait.
I'll get my phone.
He's meeting me tomorrow.
I'll say it flatly,
'Take your one million',
'And spare our lives'!
Don't say such a thing.
Why?
As if I have anything to fear from him!
I fear him.
He's not that type.
I don't know what you've seen in him.
It was just yesterday when he used to gamble on matches!
He'd win some and lose some.
But he's certain to win here.
Say yes,
Take his one million,
And make himself scarce.
Alright, satisfy yourself.
But please,
Stay quiet if he says anything back.
Don't let him go.
Should I have him stay if he turns rude?
He won't turn rude.
Just ask him not to leave before meeting me.
Hello?
It's Farah.
You listening?
He's not even listening!
I'm listening.
Well, then, I want to hear it!
Yes?
We're meeting at the same restaurant
At 1 p.m. tomorrow.
You'll be meeting Dad tomorrow
No --
You'll meet Mum first.
We'll go to the boutique from there, and get you a fine suit.
And listen to this carefully,
Mum is more inflamed at the sound of your name than Dad!
Come with your parts thoroughly rehearsed.
You'll be heading for our place from there.
Okay?
At least say okay!
He's not saying it...
Are you there?
Lubna speaking.
I recognised your voice.
Do you understand it?
Understand what?
Farah just told you about the meeting tomorrow.
I heard it.
So, when are you coming?
Where?
To the restaurant, of course!
Tell me, when should I come?
At one.
1 p.m.
Obviously...
It's not like she'd meet me at 1 a.m.
Don't worry.
I'll be there.
Do you remember that you're meeting Mum tomorrow?
I'll meet anyone after that.
No problem.
Alright then.
Listen.
Pray tell!
The thing is --
Farah had called me before you did.
Said 'Hello', told me her name, and disconnected the call.
Oh God...
Why are you saying 'Oh God'?
Just...
'By the way'.
Will she be coming tomorrow too?
She'll be coming; I'll just accompany her.
I'll pay for dinner then.
Why?
Just 'by the way'.
What happened?
Mum will devour him like a bonne bouche!
Oh God...
Yes...
Yeah!
I'd told you earlier!
Dad...
May you live long.
Why hasn't he
Taken his lunch box today?
He has a working lunch today at his office.
Oh.
You still suspect him?
A father's questions are not a mark of suspicion, my dear.
They are a mark of care and prudence.
Who brought this English newspaper?
Who else could it be?
He's been reading it for two days!
Oh...
Somebody must've thrown him a jibe over his English...
Listen,
Ruqaiyya!
I'll be attending a congregation,
And heading to the Mosque on the way back.
Alright.
Alright, my dear. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
-Goodbye.
It was the Reverend,
He's attending a congregation.
No, he has not the slightest interest in politics.
His 'congregations' are not congregations, really.
It's a congregation for him wherever
A handful of pious people gather to listen to his sermons.
Sir,
Would you like to have some tea?
Yes, please.
Okay, sir.
Listen!
-Yes, sir?
I hope you remember.
What, sir?
Come here.
I'll pay the bill.
Of course, I remember, sir.
Alright.
Okay, sir.
Why are you laughing?
I thought I'd put on this cream because I don't have any aftershave.
And
It isn't yours.
Where'd you get this cream?
I bought it.
When? You didn't step out of the house.
I bought it on my way back from the office yesterday.
You wouldn't have seen it.
You're brilliant.
When you could go and buy that,
Why didn't you get some aftershave?
It costs 450!
And this one costs 120.
Satisfied?
Where is he?
Right over there.
Hi!
Please, sit.
Yes.
How long have you been here?
Since 9.30.
9.30?
But we asked you to come at 1.00?
I -- I leave for -- my office at 9.
I haven't told my family that I've left the job.
What would you like to have?
-You're feeling hungry?
No.
That's great.
My very life is at risk here, and you're asking me what I'll have?
I haven't even had a cup of tea since the morning!
Now, I'll only have something
When you've won this round.
Round?
This thing about the round is a new one.
You didn't mention this.
You're meeting Mum at 5.
I remember that.
That's a round of the fights, so to speak.
Oh...
She'll be talking rough and coarse.
But you'll reply to her jovially and listen quietly.
You understand 'jovially', don't you?
I do.
But
It'd be better if you explained.
Even if she uses an expletive, keep smiling.
She'd use expletives?
No. She won't.
But she'll definitely say something
That'll be as acerbic.
Don't worry.
I'll listen to it jovially!
What would you like to have, sir?
What would I have --?
I mean, what would you like to eat?
You --
You're bothered about food, old chap?
Okay, sir...
What else do I tell him?
Right.
Don't stand before Mum
Like a servant.
Here.
Like this.
Stand with both your hands at the back.
Sure, I'll do exactly like that.
And be sure to get your hands out of the way when you sit.
-But of course... I'd have to.
Get to the point quick when you talk,
Even if you utter a lie,
Stick to it.
You can think I've stuck to it.
And if something enrages you, make sure it can be seen on your face.
I will.
Exempli gratia,
If she talks about your status,
If she asks you,
'Look at your status'!
'How dare you love Farah'?
Then?
How'd you react?
Don't worry.
Give me reason to.
Act it out.
I'll tell you.
Put the tea cup back on the table,
And sit irefully.
I was thinking of the same.
But --
Under these conditions -- Would she offer me tea?
We even offer tea to our enemies!
Leave the rest to me.
I would've have had my breakfast if I could leave the rest to you!
Please, have some tea.
God willing, I'll win this round.
Waiter!
I'd like half a set of tea --
I mean --
Three separate teas.
Yes, I need Ibrahim Cottons' contact number.
Alright, thank you.
Hello?
Peace be upon you. Am I through to Ibrahim Cottons?
Get me through to Accounts.
And yes,
One more thing.
If she asks,
'Has Farah been writing you letters'?
Say it strongly,
'Yes, she has been'.
She may even say,
'Alright',
'Show me her letters'.
I will show her.
I will show her all of them.
-All of them?
I mean, I'll show her as many as she wants to see.
Gor blimey, mate!
You never show your sweetheart's letters to her parents!
Oh...
I'm sorry.
So, what would you say then?
I'll say, 'These heartfelt words are treasures in the possession of largehearted lovers;'
'It is not comme il faut to reave this treasure'.
Wow...
Now you're suckin' diesel!
Was it good?
What are you talking about?
This answer will gag Mum.
She'll never even mention the letters again!
Which cell phone do you have?
No --
I keep it in my pocket.
Are you nuts?
You'd wear a suit,
And keep your cell phone in your trouser pocket?
It's --
Not the type to show around.
It's dirt cheap.
It's ringing.
Excuse me.
It's Arifa...
She -- Calls me around break time to ask if I've had lunch.
Yes, Arifa?
Where are you?
At my office. Where else would I be?
-You're lying, aren't you?
Lying?
No -- You must --
Have a feeling I'm not at the office today.
I'd told you I have a working lunch at the office today.
So --
I'm at this restaurant right now.
With my colleagues.
Alright.
When will you be back?
The usual.
No --
I'll be late.
I have a meeting with the boss.
A rather long one at that!
Alright,
Bye.
I'm a bit busy.
Thank you.
I don't know what's the matter...
I'm never afraid lying to Dad,
But it scares me to lie to Arifa.
If you think
I'm lying under my oath by you,
Then I'm not wicked,
I'm the most vile and dastardly.
I said call him here.
He's coming in a few minutes. He's afraid.
Strange.
He's fearing me
And I him...
It'll be raining soon...
It will, sure.
Mehtab's wails rumble the skies,
And his late father's curses thunder down...
Shut up!
Knock the door to the trial room.
It's been 20 minutes.
He must've started admiring his self in a suit!
So be it!
I wonder how he'd look after 5.
That'll do.
Keep it on.
I'm paying the bill and leaving.
Come at 5 o'clock sharp!
Come.
Give it to me.
When is he coming?
Five o'clock.
Five, as in...?
Five o'clock sharp!
Did you tell him who he'll be meeting first?
Yes, I did.
Alright, go.
And yes,
Remember - I don't want either of you downstairs until the meeting's over.
Hajira!
Yes, Madame?
Get some snacks to serve with the tea.
Alright.
Peace be upon you, Dad.
-And upon you, peace.
By the Lord!
We used to crave for rains,
And now it rains twice a week!
God is the Greatest indeed!
God forgive...
Where's your mother?
She's
Getting the clothes from the terrace.
Oh.
Here.
This is completely drenched.
Get me some tea
And I'll forgive every one of Ruqaiyya's inanities!
Sure.
Dad...
Does Lubna's father come for his morning prayers?
Not at all!
Monseigneur hasn't set foot in the Mosque
Ever since Afzal's started working.
But why are you asking this?
Did you talk to Lubna?
He's alright, isn't he?
That's why I was asking you.
I'll ask Lubna how he is when I call her.
Alright.
Come downstairs; I'm back!
I hope the silly lady doesn't get all drenched!
Yes, sir?
Tell me
I wouldn't get wet in the rickshaw, would I?
Not if you sit in the middle, sir.
Come!
Where to, sir?
Mohalla Naqshbandi.
Alright.
You're worried, aren't you?
I'm waiting for five o'clock.
I'm very worried, Farah.
Don't worry.
He'll stand firm in this round.
You've begun to trust him already?
Only after meeting him today.
He was bungling every now and then,
But one line struck me.
When he said,
'These heartfelt words are treasures in the possession of largehearted lovers'.
I was awed to hear that.
That a tongue-tied imbecile would say such big words...
I could never imagine!
Alright, stop here.
What's the fare?
300 Rupees, sir.
300 Rupees?
Isn't it a bit too much?
-Sir,
It doesn't suit someone wearing such a suit
To say something like this.
Alright.
Here.
Go now.
He's here!
Wait.
Where are you going?
Someone's outside.
Mademoiselle Lubna had told me
That someone was expected at five.
Alright, then,
Just ask his name; don't let him inside at first.
Alright.
-Go.
It's-a-me, Afzal.
Wait.
It's Afzal, Madame.
The Reverend's son, you know.
Alright.
I hope he isn't wet?
He's half-drenched already!
Look at the ferocity of this downpour...
God forgive...
Where's the driver?
In his quarters.
Shall I get him?
No.
Then?
What are you looking at? Go.
Get him inside and have him sit in the drawing room.
Go.
What is it?
The Reverend's son has come.
Why are you dying of a shocker if he's here?
I've just come to tell you that he's not in a good condition.
I know.
But don't worry about others
For you're not in a particularly good condition either.
You're not quite getting it...
Explain quickly, then.
Look at the downpour outside!
Oh, I hadn't the foggiest!
He's all drenched!
And if I'd opened the door on time,
He wouldn't be all soaked in water like this.
Why didn't you open the door on time?
Your mother had stopped me.
What?
Stopped me in my tracks
Started talking about the rains and the thunder...
Then?
The rain went on pouring,
And he kept on getting drenched in it.
And when she ordered me to call him inside,
He was drenched from head to toe.
His boots would splash water around as he walked.
Please, sit.
Do you need a towel?
No.
Do you feel cold?
I do.
But I won't have tea.
I'd come to meet Farah's mother.
She'd wanted to meet at 5, but it's half past 5 already.
She's coming.
Thank you.
Please, come inside.
Mum!
I'd told you that neither of you will be coming downstairs before the meeting's over.
But why isn't the meeting starting, Mum?
It's almost 6!
He's come all drenched in the rain,
I thought he'd settle down a bit
Have some tea and all.
He's settled down.
Please, go on with the meeting.
Go upstairs. Both of you!
Go!
Who are you serving this?
You.
Please don't.
I don't want to have tea.
Sit.
You may leave.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
I figure it took a while for the gate to be opened
And you got drenched.
Yes.
It's quite the downpour, really...
And would you look at the lightning!
And would you look at the lightning! All of Thor's fury...
Yes.
Our elders used to say,
'When there's lightning',
'You don't go out in a black suit'.
I stood at the gate for ten minutes in this lightning.
Nothing happened to me.
You don't fear anything
Because nothing's ever happened to you.
Yes?
You haven't had your tea.
No...
I no longer need tea.
Have a cup; you're shivering.
No, thank you.
I'm shivering because
I'm a bit afraid.
You're afraid of me?
I fear those I immensely respect.
I fear my Dad, too.
Where did you work?
I was a clerk at your factory.
I left the job after two days.
I know.
I also know why.
What are you doing these days?
I've started on a new project
That earns me 200,000.
I'll work for four months on it.
Why only four months?
Besides, who's foolish enough to offer a third division BA like you
200,000 a month?
Dad says,
'Always seek association with the enlightened'.
'And if you have to look for them',
'It means the ignorant are far more plentiful in the world'.
As for the magic number,
Unfortunately, the project will be done in four months. It ends in December.
How much do you love her?
That's a good question.
If it is, please humour me with an answer.
How much do you love her?
I'm her mother.
Who doesn't know the love of a mother?
Who does know my love!
What do you think?
Someone like you would fall for Farah,
And we'd give away our Farah
To him like a benefaction!
Not at all.
What did you think, coming here?
Nothing, really.
Farah told me you'd called me,
So, I came.
But now that I'm here,
I'll only leave after I've talked about everything.
'Everything'?
I'm sorry.
Right,
So what's 'everything'?
I wanted to say that
It is not meet, considering my status, that I love Farah,
But I have a right to love Farah.
Oh?
Who bestowed this right upon you?
No...
Nobody bestows this right,
Nor does anyone ask for it.
Or else, one would have to take permission before falling in love.
This would make a complete haymes of it all.
A complete haymes, as in?
As in, asking permission
Of the one you love first.
Mention your status,
And ask,
'May I love you'?
What would you take to just love her?
Another good question.
I've asked you something.
How much money would you take to spare her life?
The thing is, I've promised on oath to Dad I'd never gamble again.
I'm not talking about gambling.
Only that you are talking about gambling.
But it seems you do not understand gambling.
My friend, Babloo,
He says, 'Win the match, and the money's all yours'.
And you're saying, 'Lose the match, and the money's all yours'.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV