Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Sit down.
Tell me, now,
Who are you obdurate against?
Won't you share what lies in your heart with the one you'd get engaged to?
She's getting engaged tomorrow.
You're exacting your revenge?
She doesn't love you, does she?
You don't love me, either.
How would I get even with you?
By getting engaged to you?
You thought you'd toy with her with this game of engagements,
And please Jasmine, too!
You could've just said, 'I need a favour, Jasmine'.
You shouldn't have said, 'Will you get engaged to me'?
Girls are very sensitive, Afzal,
They'd lose their heart in games such as yours.
Thank goodness I didn't think you'd fallen in love with me.
I'm serious, Jasmine.
I've come here with a proposal.
I'm serious, too, Afzal.
I reject your proposal.
Come.
Mam would've dreamt about a lot, seeing this meeting...
Let's shatter everything in a moment.
Wait, Jasmine.
I give you my word,
I'll marry you and only you if I get engaged to you.
You could --
You could think I've fallen in love with you.
You lie so artfully, boyo!
It almost sounds like you're honest.
Alright, if you're honest,
Prove it to me.
Change the date of the engagement.
I won't change it to any day after tomorrow.
Then, how about a day earlier?
If you've bought the ring,
Put it on me today.
But you can have one thing in writing -
If she's getting engaged tomorrow,
I'm not getting engaged to you tomorrow.
Come downstairs if you're in the mood to get engaged.
Or I'll look down from the window and see that you're leaving.
Why are you panting?
Just a minute.
Where's Afzal?
We'll know in a moment.
Jasmine!
He's left, Mam.
He'd come over with a plan to come,
And he took the option to leave.
You refused?
You know
That I couldn't have refused!
Why did he leave, then?
We had a row over the date of the engagement.
I wanted the date of the new moon,
And he wanted the date of the lunar eclipse.
I said it too,
Whether or not we get engaged, I'm not agreeing to the date of the eclipse.
He won't come again.
I, too, pray that he never come now.
Promise me, then,
That you will never weep for him again.
You're not intelligent at all, Mam!
I don't weep for him.
I weep at the love that I have for that eejit.
If I've shed a few tears to get over this sorrow, don't think that I'm weeping.
What is that?
Shoes...
I've brought --
Shoes for you.
But why?
Know what,
I've got five pairs here,
And two lying in the car.
I've settled for these after a lot of searching... All different types!
Each better than the other!
Take the ones you like. Hi, Lubna!
Hi!
Why have you brought these?
Silly question!
Who asks one's fiancé why he's brought gifts?
Who's bought them?
I have, of course! It took me two hours to get them!
So I'd wear shoes of your choice?
No, you'd wear shoes of your choice.
I've got so many.
Keep the ones you like, and return the others.
How do you know my shoe size?
C'mon, Farah,
When you said 'My foot' the other day, my eyes darted to your feet.
It's 7, innit?
7 is Lubna's size.
My shoe size is 6.
Oh...
What's going on?
Peace be upon you, Aunt.
And upon you, peace.
Sibtain's brought shoes for Farah.
How cute!
It's not cute, Mum.
Who buys shoes for his girl?
The things men do in love...
Don't look at the shoes;
Look at his love.
You can look at size 7 shoes
If not wear them.
I can wear them.
What other hand-me-downs do you want?
Anyway,
Take these shoes away,
And get me size 6 ones.
How different is it, really?
And, frankly speaking,
Everyone will be looking at the girl's face.
Only the husband looks at her feet.
I should go after her, shouldn't I?
-Double time!
May I come in?
What is it now?
Nothing, really.
I'd just come to say
That you should've taken a look at the shoes...
I will.
It would've delighted my heart if you'd only tried them on for once...
Just decide in one shot
What I have to do to delight you.
Nothing much.
I'd even be delighted to see you happy.
And the truth is I'd come to make you happy, and not to be delighted myself.
And I'm chuffed to see 7 pairs of size 7 shoes!
Look,
We're getting engaged tomorrow.
I mean,
Our sorrows and happiness will be united.
Likewise, if our love is united,
Our feelings, and our thoughts are united,
People would hail us as the ideal couple.
Get to the point.
What could be a more important point than love?
If only you paid attention to the 'points'...
If you don't let your heart connect with your mind, how will a link form,
And, in the absence of such a link, you are always unsettled, restless, and troubled.
Is that you telling me about my illness?
Don't you dare, you bloody psychiatrist!
I'm not trying to prove myself to be a bloody psychiatrist at all.
I was actually
Telling you a lover's point of view.
Lover?
M --
-Please don't say anything starting with 'My foot'!
A psychiatrist can take his insult,
But love never takes any insult.
The thing is, you need someone who loves you intensely for such turbulence,
Provided, of course, that you love him intensely, too.
Fortunately,
Such a lover is available to you,
But unfortunately,
You aren't available to him.
Got your ring?
Which ring?
The engagement ring.
I'd returned it to you, hadn't I?
I'm not asking about that ring.
Tell me about the one you'd returned
Tell me about the one you'd returned with the fiancé.
I've decided
That I can't turn down such a trifling wish of my fiancée's.
You'd wear the same engagement ring tomorrow.
What's his Paw's name?
Whose Dad?
The bloke you folks call 'Afzal'.
Afzal's his name.
I'm asking his Paw's name.
Subhanallah [Praise the Lord].
Keep praising the Lord later; first, tell me his Paw's name.
Subhanallah is his name.
Subhanallah [Praise the Lord]!
Then, Mr Subhanallah will put the ring on you tomorrow.
Paw's said this will heal his heart's wound.
There's nothing like a wound on a heart, really, though.
But Paw said it so convincingly that I thought
That it's something beyond science.
Well,
I'd only come to say that.
Hey!
I'll wear those size 7 shoes.
Arifa!
Coming, Dad.
Yes, Dad?
Let me come in first.
Sure,
Come.
Do you remember the last time you'd come inside my room?
I don't, either!
I just remember
That I'd fallen down while playing on the stairs.
My nose got hurt, I fell unconscious.
That's when you'd come running from the Mosque.
I've heard you'd spent the entire night sitting by me?
Chanting prayers,
Saying to God,
'Make her come to, O Lord',
'Or I may miss the morning prayers'!
Please, sit.
The thing is,
The rooms
Of the mother and the daughter are places where one should show the utmost respect.
One doesn't just go there the way
I'd barge into Afzal's room.
Why don't you sit, too?
You've come inside my room after so many years,
So, tell me,
What'd you like to have?
You've half taken after your mother.
You keep your heart's secrets locked deep inside.
Alright,
I'd come inside your room
Every once in a while.
In the Lord's name [auspicious beginning].
Alright,
Tell me,
Where's the ring?
Ring?
You'd better not ask 'Which ring'.
You know it very well.
I'd thrown it away because
Ruqaiyya had thought of getting something else made from it,
Or selling it
To get some money.
Why had you kept it with you?
Just kept it...
As a reminder.
A reminder of what?
What good is it to us?
I didn't think of what good it is.
I just thought that we'd had it made for my brother's fiancée,
So, it's for the memory.
A memory of what, my dear?
Would you show us such things
To torment us further?
Go and see.
We've even taken his picture off from the room.
No, Dad...
You haven't taken it off from the room.
Mum's just changed where it's kept.
It's underneath her pillow now.
There...
Whoever would tell her
That one's only got a confrontation destined with sin;
One doesn't have any ties.
So, do you have no ties with him, now?
Have you forgotten that he's your son?
I've heard that you'd sat next to Farah to glimpse Afzal?
That was just -- that day...
I'd just mentioned his name for your mother's happiness...
She's
Got a frail heart, right?
So have I got a very strong heart, Dad?
I'm his sister.
If I'm tormented for him, I'm tormented again to see Mum.
I mean,
I'm tormented more than Mum.
The two of you will bring me to tears one day!
And remember,
A judgement will be pronounced against me
The day I wept!
No judgement will be pronounced, Dad.
Who says that if He can understand a mother's heart, He cannot understand a father's heart?
Perhaps a judgement may be pronounced over a father who did not weep even after his son left?
Just try to weep on this pretext for once, Dad.
Who knows, He may just be waiting for you to weep?
By the Lord, Dad,
Don't cry.
You just asked me to weep...
I'd asked you to weep, Dad.
I didn't ask you to show me that you're weeping.
Alright,
Give me the ring.
What'd you do with it?
She'd come utterly dispirited and penitent;
Seeing her, it occurred to me
That sometimes, the most brutal punishment you can mete out
To someone who had no mercy on you
Is to be merciful.
So, give it, my dear.
It'll be our tribute of
19,700 from us to her.
One gives something on the occasion of an engagement, right?
One doesn't give with a generous heart to someone who's broken one's heart, Dad,
Which is why I won't give her the ring.
I'd have earrings made from it,
Or sell it to get some money.
She'd have only blessings for us
If it satisfies her.
Take the blessings, my dear.
The ring won't be of any use.
The blessings would be of great use.
If someone else put my brother's ring on her,
I may utter a curse!
Just pray that she be saved from my curse.
Leave it be, Reverend.
Don't attack frail hearts, emboldened by your own strong heart.
If she were so penitent,
She could've asked for the one that ring was from.
By the Lord, I'd have gotten her what she wanted.
Did you see that?
She's thrown a jibe of 'strong-hearted' too!
Tell her, sometime,
That this strong-hearted man
Had wept at one command of yours.
Good night.
She won't give me the ring.
She gets an itch to exact her revenge every so often.
Although her Mum and Dad
Have forgotten the incident at the engagement,
She doesn't seem to forget.
I can even read her expressions.
If she smiles while looking at me, it feels
As if she's cursing me.
And when her Mum smiles?
How do you feel then?
Normal.
Completely normal.
Then, you just note Arifa's expressions.
You haven't the foggiest about her.
Not at all.
She says
That she sees Afzal in me.
They're God's dearest, Mademoiselle.
They are courteous to guests.
What do you mean?
I've seen their smile.
You'll see,
She'd kill you with the same smile one day.
It isn't really a smile...
It's perplexity
That's set in on her lips.
Perplexity about what?
How you're still able to get up and walk!
First, she'd have thought
That one smile would kill you,
Or that her second will cause the ground to be cleft asunder, and you, with all your cardinal sins, shall be plunged into the abyss.
But that didn't happen.
So, pray that she doesn't attend your engagement tomorrow.
What could happen if she attended my engagement?
Seeing you as a bride would torment her.
An ember would emanate from her eye, which would turn you to ash.
Then, she'd better come.
Let me see, too, how the ember emanates from her eye,
And how it turns me to ash.
Your face looks very spooky.
Leave my face be;
Think of how you'd look when you'd have turned to ash.
Put a sock in it.
I chant my own funeral prayers thrice every day.
It's for the better.
One should keep on doing that.
Someone else may be praying in your place tomorrow.
So, all those conversations,
All that affection, all those blandishments -
Is all of it a lie?
She'd call me up to her
And ward troubles off me.
She keeps her enemy alive.
She's decided to kill you with her own two hands.
And Uncle Reverend?
He'd brought coconut biscuits for me.
He always says,
'Let Farah not leave empty-handed'.
That's just a matter of getting even.
Remember
How you'd not let him leave empty-handed either?
You'd packed for him a lifetime's worth of sorrow, saying,
'Go'.
'Forget your son and live with this sorrow'.
Now, he lives with the sorrow you've given them,
And gives you coconut biscuits in thanksgiving.
You're envious, aren't you?
Envious?
It pains you to see, doesn't it,
How Afzal's family loves me so much?
What does this chuckle mean?
Nothing, really.
I chuckle when I hear you say 'Afzal' and 'love' in the same line.
Forget about everything.
Just concentrate on your engagement.
Tell Sibtain that I can't get that ring.
I don't want to pick a fight with Arifa.
You've already picked a fight with her.
Did you have to ask for the ring?
Here, their wounds start healing,
And there you are to rub salt in them.
Granted that you regret what you've done,
But who'd like the idea of wearing an old ring at a new engagement?
Sibtain could even die for you,
Which is why he's at your service with the shoes and his head.
Otherwise, if you'd wear a ring sent by his corrival,
It'll be the last nail in the coffin of the lover's honour.
Who's this corrival?
I'm talking about poor old Afzal.
He'd have gotten the news.
Ah, yes.
Eladio's come over from there.
He's told him about your engagement.
He'd have gotten the news.
Just watch what happens next...
What?
He won't remain at peace.
Would he come?
So, do you mean
That he'd try to stop the engagement?
He isn't the type.
What'd he do, then?
He'd give a befitting reply.
Well,
Whatever can he do now?
Get engaged.
Get engaged, as in?
You're getting engaged tomorrow,
And you'll see, he'd get engaged tomorrow, too.
To whom?
He's got an affair going on with you,
Whom would he get engaged to?
Jasmine.
So wasn't he serious with you?
He was very serious,
But she'll be the only one available to him at a moment's notice.
Plus, she'd agree, too.
The blighter...
You thought you'd toy with her with this game of engagements,
And please Jasmine, too!
You could've just said, 'I need a favour, Jasmine'.
You shouldn't have said, 'Will you get engaged to me'?
Girls are very sensitive, Afzal,
They'd lose their heart in games such as yours.
Thank goodness I didn't think you'd fallen in love with me.
This number is on another call. Please wait.
Who is it?
It's Farah.
Farah who?
Don't you recognise me?
It's Farah...
I'd come from Hyderabad
With my Dad
Looking for Afzal?
Oh, yes...
I remember you well.
Haven't you saved my number?
I'd deliberately not saved it.
Why?
I feared you might call.
How are you?
You're calling at 1 a.m.; haven't you found him yet?
Who's talking about him?
Just...
I was missing you
And thought I'd talk to you.
I'm sorry
But I think you were sleeping...
No, not at all.
I was awake.
In fact, I stay awake.
So,
What's up these days?
I've started teaching the kids.
Splendid.
That's very good.
That's just what's good now.
Has he left?
Are you talking about Afzal?
Yes.
He left a long while ago,
But he does pay a visit sometimes.
He's become a don now, hasn't he?
He'd said as he left,
'I'd come back a great man'.
I've heard he's earned a lot, too.
Don't you have his number?
What'd I do with his number?
Then, what'd you do to know about him?
That was just --
His name came up --
And I thought I'd ask about him.
So, tell me,
When are you getting married?
Why are you asking about my marriage?
Just asking.
That's what girls ask each other, innit?
Tell me, then,
When are you getting married?
Just about anytime now.
I'm getting engaged tomorrow.
What happened?
Why this silence?
I'm a bit surprised.
What a coincidence,
Someone else is getting engaged tomorrow, too.
Afzal?
The one whom Afzal loves.
She's somewhere in Hyderabad.
Did he tell you that?
When a lover flees from a city,
One could think his lover lives there, innit?
Tell me her name.
Don't you know?
Her name's Farah.
I only know her name.
She's been writing him letters for years.
I've read a handful of them, too.
She opens with 'Dear Afzal',
And who knows what else she writes...
So that's some other Farah?
Obviously.
As if I write him letters!
She's getting engaged today, too?
Splendid...
That is grand.
It'll be grand now, Farah.
All three will get engaged on the same day.
Who's the third one?
Afzal.
Afzal?
So he's getting engaged tomorrow, too?
To whom?
To me.
I mean, he was asking me,
But I didn't agree to it.
Why?
I felt like he was calling out,
'Is there anyone who'd get engaged to me'?
Now, if one'd ask Jasmine like this,
Would Jasmine ever say 'Yes'?
I refused point blank.
Good.
But it won't do any good.
What do you mean?
He'll get engaged tomorrow, Farah.
At all costs.
Is there anyone else, too?
I mean, to whom if not you?
Could be anyone.
If he didn't get that muppet Farah, it doesn't mean he won't get anyone.
He'd find someone better.
He's a handsome lad, beaut.
Talks little,
But hears a lot;
Who knows how many would die for him!
Did he flatly say,
'Get engaged to me'?
Obviously.
And you refused.
Point blank.
I thought the two of you had something going on.
We could've had...
But I don't compromise on my principles. No.
What do I do, and what could love do, if he'd come from Hyderabad robbed?
Love has emphathy for robbed travellers, not affection.
I'll talk to you later...
Should I give you his number?
No; what'd I do with his number?
Ask about the time of the engagement and the girl's name,
Or you'll be left asking me.
No way.
I just asked because his mention came up.
Alright, listen,
You'd keep your phone on, wouldn't you?
Why are you asking that?
I'd tell you if I found out the girl's name and the time of the engagement.
There's no need.
But my phone will be on.
Good night.
Why are you laughing?
I'm laughing at the amount of flannel in love.
If only someone starts playing with it,
It plays with one like a child plays with his toys -
Playing in the morning,
And breaking it by the evening.
Get up, Lubna.
Get up.
Tell me,
What happens next?
Next, as in?
What's up with you?
Easy there, sit down and talk.
Your predictions have been true.
More than half of them, actually.
He's getting engaged tomorrow,
And he'd proposed Jasmine first.
He's getting engaged to Jasmine?
No. Jasmine's said she won't get engaged to him.
And now, he's looking for someone else.
But who?
He'll find someone.
'He's a handsome lad',
'Plus, he talks little',
'But hears a lot'.
What are you saying?
I'm not saying this,
Jasmine is.
Did you just talk to Jasmine?
Yes.
I couldn't sleep, so
I thought I'd talk to her.
She let the cat out of the bag the moment I started talking.
That's good.
What's good?
The blighter's counter-attacking me!
What do you call a counter-attack?
He's getting engaged on the day of my engagement.
What does that mean?
Why didn't he fix any other date?
So much right is the least he's got.
After all, he's a Reverend's son,
So, he's only being as cruel as his own fate had been to him.
What do you mean?
Honestly?
He should've gotten married by now.
In fact, he should've had one or two kids by the time you got married.
Don't you have the slightest sorrow?
Just tell me what your sorrow is.
Not sorrow,
But I feel pity.
He should be ashamed.
Nobody in his family knows that he's getting engaged.
Like we care, even if they don't know!
Call Arifa.
Why?
Let her know, too,
What the brother whose name fuels her pride
Has been up to!
You'd give her new grief?
I'd just inform her.
How many days have we wasted, looking for him!
Now that we've gotten wind of his exploits,
We're duty-bound to inform her instantly.
Call her.
You might even die of sorrow...
That which you'd tasted
Was not blood,
But the soot of disgrace, Lubna Ibrahim.
Yes, Lubna?
Not Lubna, it's Farah.
Everything alright?
Tell me after you've heard the news
If everything about it is alright.
What's the news?
He's fixed his engagement on the day of my engagement.
Who?
Your brother, obviously.
And would you look at that!
He's neither told you, nor invited you to the engagement.
He's getting engaged today?
Splendid.
Mum would dance a jig to hear it!
Dance a jig?
Wouldn't she feel sad at all that he's not invited you?
Not at all.
She'd say,
'The son's become an outsider, Arifa',
'But the daughter-in-law's our own'.
Who's the daughter-in-law -- I mean,
Whom is he getting engaged to?
He'd offered Jasmine first,
But she didn't agree.
But he agreed didn't he?
So, he'll get engaged.
Have you seen Jasmine?
Why are you asking that?
Just asking.
I thought I should know how she looks.
She looks good,
But she's very lippy.
If she looks good, a tad lippy will do.
Alright, I'll go tell Mum.
-Wait!
Yes?
What'd you do with that ring now?
Have earrings made from it.
Our Afzal --
Is getting engaged today, Mum...
Did you say anything?
No? Why, what is it?
I felt as if you'd said, 'Our Afzal's getting engaged today'.
No way...
It's
Farah's engagement today.
That's sunken into your heart.
Go to sleep.
Hello?
Jasmine here.
Yes?
Didn't my refusal shock you?
I knew you'd refuse.
So, who'd you get engaged to?
You won't find anyone in this chaos.
I won't, if not with you.
I've fallen asleep, thinking that.
So, how would you exact your revenge?
What you consider my revenge is my wish.
It's beyond my control, but I wish
That my wedding procession come the same day her wedding procession comes to her.
You'd stay true to your word, won't you?
I can't guarantee that...
Alright, I'll guarantee it.
Find out the time of her engagement,
And come here.
I'll get engaged to you.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV