Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Who was it?
Afzal's family.
I mean,
It seemed they were his family by the way they asked.
They must've come asking about him.
No, Mam.
They don't know anything.
They just came looking.
They're asking where he is.
Didn't you tell them?
That's what I've come to ask - should I tell them?
How many people have come?
Two.
Father and daughter.
They didn't even mention who they are to Afzal!
Alright,
Get them inside, I'll get some tea.
I'll get them inside,
And prepare some tea.
You'd much rather sit with them.
Sit.
Come in --
-No.
I'm fine.
I don't need to sit.
I'll get you some tea.
I'd like a cup of strong tea.
I like strong tea too!
I'll get some.
You've come from Hyderabad, haven't you?
Yes.
I didn't really need to ask that.
If you're a relative of Afzal's, you would obviously be from Hyderabad.
How long has he been here?
Not here.
Upstairs.
But he's staying here, isn't he?
It's been three months.
Doesn't he come downstairs?
No.
He just came to give us some sweets once.
When he enlisted as a security guard.
What do you do?
Nothing.
Earned my BA a year ago,
And I've been at home ever since.
Why?
Because of Wali.
Wali is my Aunt's son.
He's got his eyes on me.
Eyes, as in?
Don't you know what that means?
What do you do?
I'm pursuing an MBA.
It's my last semester.
Right. So he's 'got his eyes on me' as in
He looks at me the wrong way.
Oh...
As in,
You don't like him.
Ask forgiveness of God!
He's been married twice!
The cad's an ace ruffian.
He's a strongman around here.
All his strength ebbed away that day, though!
Afzal gave the sleeveen a proper pasting one day!
Pasting?
As in beat him black and blue!
Why?
Because of me.
Wali wanted to force me into marrying him.
It enraged Afzal,
And he gave him --
-A proper pasting?
Yes.
If he comes back in a while, that's alright,
Or we're headed to Clifton.
We live there.
I'll
Meet him tomorrow morning.
Monseigneur,
When I'd said that Afzal's gone somewhere,
That was a lie.
I was afraid about who you may be,
And who you are to Afzal.
You may be shocked if you came to know the truth.
Shocked?
The truth is
Afzal is in the hospital.
My nephew had shot him last night.
No --
It's nothing to worry.
He's fine.
The bullet just struck his leg.
The doctor's done with the operation too,
And he's said today
'You can take him home in a few days'.
Hey --
Wait.
Dad won't have tea.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
You kept me so busy talking I forgot.
Put the tray down.
May we sit somewhere and talk?
Sure,
C'mon.
Start again from there.
Where?
Well, beaut, you just said,
'Afzal gave your cousin a proper pasting'.
I like it very much.
What?
You've begun to address me as 'beaut'.
Anyway, tell me,
Who are you to him?
I'm just his landlady.
Not gonna lie to you, actually, I'm his landlady's daughter.
A lie.
One doesn't risk his life for his landlady's daughter.
Touché.
Then,
What's the story?
You think the same too?
What?
What it is is I can't conceal my feelings.
What are your feelings?
This is the first time we're meeting,
And you're getting at such deep secrets in the first meeting?
Sorry...
There's no need to tell if you found it awkward...
There's nothing to tell, really.
Just --
Our squabbles ended when he clobbered Wali.
You had squabbles before?
Oh, those!
I used to think he's a hooligan!
He said one day, 'I'll chuck you out'!
Then?
What then?
I only found out later he's very good at heart.
Very good.
Good...
It must've taken --
At least a month to get to the heart?
A month, or maybe...
Two days?
H -- Haven't you asked him
If there's another girl in his life?
Nobody.
There's no girl in his life.
I asked him the very day Mam had the impression that he's good-looking
So he must've had at least one girl head over heels after him!
So
He said there's no one?
Wouldn't she have come after him?
For his part, he'd said, too,
'There's no one'.
You tell me,
Who are you to him?
I --
I'm nobody to him.
Your --
Father's calling you.
Okay.
She didn't even have her tea.
You haven't told her, have you,
That Afzal's been shot?
I haven't.
Good.
Her father, too, asked me not to tell her.
What could have happened if I'd told?
Who's she to him?
Didn't you ask her?
I did.
She said she's nobody to him.
She must be angry with him
That's why she said this.
Angry, as in?
Is she someone to him?
She's come after him because she is someone to him!
You silly girl!
She's the daughter of an affluent mill owner.
Think about it,
Why would she come looking for a pleb like Afzal?
God is the Greatest.
Greetings, sir.
Greetings. How are you, Mehboob Ali?
I'm good.
You've come here after long.
Yes, we'd
Stay here a few days.
Greetings, Mademoiselle.
Get the luggage out from the boot.
-Greetings.
I think you didn't recognise me...
I did alright.
Are we not going back?
Why would we?
We'd take him along now that we've come here.
He's not going back.
Who told you?
Just what I thought.
He's settled here.
He's gotten a job as a security guard.
Like the dickens is he settled!
Leave it be.
You won't get it.
So why don't you explain it?
It isn't exactly picnic, whiling away my time here in Karachi!
Along with a job as a security guard,
He's also gotten the landlord's daughter.
That's the scene that's going on these days.
Come on, Farah.
Don't use your brain too much.
Dad!
Don't you believe me?
Then stay in Karachi.
In a few days,
You might even hit the enlightenment.
He's a connatural blighter,
Leching after a girl where he sees o--
Sorry --
I --
Just uttered it spontaneously.
Sorry...
Are you talking about Jasmine?
Yes, Dad.
Alright.
Freshen up,
We'll talk after dinner.
I won't have dinner.
I don't feel hungry at all.
Listen!
You're accosting my experience more so than his disposition.
Someone my age, even if blind,
Can judge a man's character by his mere words.
Then you don't know, Dad,
What he's up to!
He casts such a spell
That blinds every onlooker.
Hello?
What's the matter with you?
Why are you laughing like that?
What
Was it that you used to sing?
'I've tasted blood'?
Innit?
Listen, then -
Well, this blighter's certainly tasted blood!
He's been caught here, too.
Caught?
Well,
What's it to you?
Whether he gets caught,
Or writes letter to another Farah,
Or has a pash
On his landlady's daughter?
He's still 'Afzal' [excellent] in your eyes!
Hey!
He's not like that.
Why don't you come to Karachi?
I'll introduce you to his new girlfriend!
Are you telling the truth?
I've just met her.
The poor lass,
She'd die for him.
I don't believe this...
It's broken your heart, hasn't it?
It's my fault.
I told you so quickly.
Honestly, though, she is quite sweet.
You're lying, aren't you?
I'd die where I stand if I lie!
I've talked to her for an hour.
She's very innocent,
Trapped in that arrant knave's ploy!
Which arrant knave?
Your Afzal.
Who else could it be?
I swear,
If you'd hear her out,
You'd say,
'Alright'.
'Afzal's all yours'.
I would never!
Afzal will only be hers whose he should rightfully be!
Alright.
I'll meet her again tomorrow.
Why?
I'll ask her
If she can sing
'I've tasted blood'!
She must be able to!
So?
So what?
The two of you will duel it out.
And the winner
Gets Afzal!
I don't think you're in your senses.
There!
Your envy has burnt you to ashes,
And you're saying I'm not in my senses!
Aren't you coming to Karachi?
Get a move on!
Why should I come?
Hey!
Will you come here after that rapscallion
Has robbed you of your love?
Take a sleeping pill and go to bed.
Why should I take a pill?
You take one.
There are four pills
In the drawer of my writing table.
You may take all four if you want.
Where's Dad?
He's traumatised.
Go
And sit with Dad.
You may end up doing something!
I was thinking of the same.
Let him come before my eyes!
I'll tear his face for you!
I'll jab these long nails
Into his eyes!
Why
Have you brought us to this room from the ward?
We don't have the money to pay the bill.
We've just been ordered
To shift the patient to the room.
As far as the money is concerned,
One gets a room in this hospital only after making a payment.
What?
You can ask the doctor about everything else.
He'll be here shortly.
I know who would have paid the bills.
Who?
Jasmine.
The man who'd come along,
He's a mill owner?
Yes.
Not being funny, she's the mill owner's daughter for real!
But why did she say she's nobody to him?
If someone asked you who you are to Afzal,
What would you say?
You can call Afzal and ask him the true story.
It'll save you the fatal trouble of thinking.
I would, Mam,
But I'm afraid.
When she said she's nobody to him,
Her eyes made it clear that she's lying.
Her lie has frightened me, Mam,
And my heart says that Afzal will frighten me with his truth if I called him.
We'll go to meet him tomorrow.
I say you ask him about the true story casually.
There's no need to ask now.
He'll be taken to Hyderabad tomorrow morning.
Hey!
How would they take him?
I mean,
How can he go in this condition?
And won't he meet us before leaving?
Won't he settle his dues?
He'll have to pay every penny that he owes us before he leaves!
I'll seize all his goods in the morning.
I've given Kaneez Fatima the allowance;
She'll take care of your provisions.
Listen carefully, now,
Leave no stone unturned in cleaning this house; I'll check every corner when I'm back.
And what are you looking at?
Come on,
Put your bag in the car and come along.
Where are we going?
Why are you asking this again and again?
We'd stay there for four days?
Perhaps four, perhaps five.
Perhaps we may be back tomorrow.
Quickly, now, come.
I'm sorry Dad...
I figure you've
Not slept properly last night.
No --
I've had a good night's sleep.
I can see that.
No,
I was just thinking what we're doing here.
We should've gone back last night.
I'd promised the Reverend
That I'd only come back with Afzal by my side.
It seems you've reneged on your promise.
Afzal won't be leaving this place.
He will.
I know he can't turn me down.
Lubna and your Mum
Will be here in a while too.
Splendid!
Such sedulous preparations to bring him back!
Just the four of us,
Or is someone else invited too?
I've invited them because
We're not going anywhere for four days.
Sorry Dad,
But I'm not staying here four days.
Why don't you have Lubna stay?
Mum and I will go back today.
You don't know why we're staying here,
And you wouldn't want to budge from here if you found out.
Pray tell.
Promise me, first,
That you'll not call Arifa and her family to tell them.
Has he gotten married?
Are you in your senses?
Who'd he get married to?
Jasmine, of course!
Her expressions were just like a wife's!
Talking to her, it felt
As if she's missing him.
He's in a hospital right now.
A lad by the name of Wali had shot him.
He's taken two bullets.
And if word got to the Reverend,
Or
If his Mum found out,
I fear one of them will die on hearing the news.
So, I've called Irsa here
To ask her
What I should do in this situation.
He's alive, isn't he?
Yes, he is.
He's had an operation.
Hopefully, he'll be able to walk in a few days.
This Wali is the same one, Dad.
Jasmine's cousin.
Yes, that's the name she'd mentioned!
Yes, it's the same, alright.
Afzal had beaten him black and blue over a row earlier.
Not just any row.
A row over Jasmine.
He'd fought for her,
And it's for her he's taken the bullets!
Lassie's the real deal!
The blighter put his life on the line for her!
That's brilliant.
Lubna will be thunderstruck
To hear this.
You're absolutely right, Dad.
I'm not budging from here.
In fact, I'll go and meet him.
I'll even click a photograph of him.
The thing is,
One only finds such lovers
In books these days.
Don't call to inform Hyderabad.
No way, Dad.
Am I not the full shilling?
Babu Hamid!
-Yes?
What happened?
What is it?
You're alright, aren't you?
I am, mate.
Do you want me to take a stroll to prove it?
Leave it be, boyo.
This...
How much does this room cost?
Must be around
8 to 10 thousand?
We're dead, then, mate.
Jasmine will incarcerate me
And say, 'You'll only leave after paying me all the money'.
Where'd you leave for?
I'd go to Wali once I'm out.
Are you crazy?
Let bygones be bygones.
Forget Wali.
I'd miss him more if it pained a bit more.
How can I forget him?
Remember, Babu Hamid,
It's a real bad habit to pick up a gun and fire it.
It should be nipped in the bud.
That blighter will kill somebody else tomorrow.
Who knows,
The poor man at the other end of his barrel might just die this time!
But don't worry, mate.
I'll only exact as much revenge as he deserves for his tyranny.
Find out after lunch tomorrow where he'll be for the next few days.
He'd be in hiding, Afzal.
Where will you find him?
He won't hide.
Not when a complaint hasn't been filed.
He'd think Afzal's afraid of him.
And Dad says,
'The terrorised is worse than the one who terrorises'.
Once, in fact, he'd even said,
'The oppressor doesn't make the oppressed',
'It's the oppressed who makes the oppressor'.
Find him within four days.
I don't want that blighter to become an oppressor because of me.
C'mon, Mam, the rickshaw's waiting down there!
H -- Here. Take this lunch box.
And listen,
Don't start your inquest about that girl the moment you get there!
Not at all.
I'll ask him in private.
First, I'll see if she's there or if she's left after asking how he's doing!
Alright, get downstairs,
I'll be coming after locking the door.
Wali!
So you remember my name!
Who is it, Jasmine?
It's me, Modryb.
Wali.
You filthy dog!
Get lost!
Your anger's not waned one bit, Modryb...
The same old style...
Hurled an abuse,
Slapped me...
Think about it, Modryb.
I'm not the old Wali.
Oh, please!
Step aside!
I'm one step closer to my aim, and here you are asking me to step aside!
By the way,
Where are you off to?
You're going to the hospital.
What's in the box?
Nothing's changed here.
The Modryb's the same way,
And the Modryb's daughter is the same old...
But I've changed, Jasmine.
I don't threaten anymore.
And if I ever do,
I don't give the luxury of counting to ten.
Move inside, now, will you?
There's nothing to fear.
I'll just sit inside for a while,
Have some of your tea,
Talk about some things and leave.
I swear by you!
Alright, if you want to go to the hospital after that, you may.
I won't stop you.
I promise.
C'mon!
Come, Jasmine.
Give the rickshaw driver a hundred and send him away.
See those two roughies over there?
Yes?
They're both Wali's men.
What are they doing here?
Ask what Wali is doing here!
Where's Wali?
Upstairs.
Hey!
Where?
Your oul' fella's in grave danger.
I'm going to make it clear to him,
'Now's the chance to run'.
'Otherwise, he's coming'.
Jasmine,
Give it to me.
Over here.
No, Modryb.
Don't do this.
I'll have her tea only when she serves me.
Only then will I talk.
Look, Wali,
Only show as much audacity as I can tolerate.
There, now!
You've changed, too, Modryb.
You've begun to tolerate her preparing and serving me tea.
Just one more step.
I'll have her tea only if she serves me.
You'll see, then,
I'll become an honourable man right here.
You're just like your father, young man!
In his family, they'd poison a virtuous child
When one is born!
I just asked for one more step, Modryb.
You took more than that.
Don't get to me Tad.
He'd be sitting up there in Paradise.
God only knows what kind of 'Paradise' your Tad is in!
-Enough, Modryb!
That's too much.
Give me the cup, Mam.
I'll serve him tea.
That's like a sweet girl.
Not just sweet.
But very sweet.
This warm tea,
The warmth of your hands...
Did you see that?
You've coloured me
With the hues of your tea!
Sit, now,
Let us negotiate now.
Go on.
Jasmine!
Stay quiet, Mam.
Let me talk today.
C'mon, now!
Begin the negotiations!
I just have a one-point agenda, cousin.
Tell me,
Won't you marry me?
No.
I agree.
How say you agree to one point of mine?
Will you live with me without marrying me?
Wali!
It appears this option didn't exactly appeal to Modryb...
How about you?
I will rip you apart, you blighter!
Enough, Modryb!
It'd be better if the two of you decided who'd be negotiating.
And if we're negotiating, you'd better tell Modryb,
We'll only let our mouths do the talking.
If that's not acceptable,
Let's talk about the second option.
Honestly,
Don't you fear Afzal?
I am very afraid of him.
But who knows when - if at all - the poor bloke will be able to stand on his feet.
Wait a few days,
The day he sets foot on the earth
Is the day you will no longer be found on it.
The next time he sets foot in this neighbourhood,
I'll send him straight to the grave.
C'mon, Wali!
To your grave.
Everyone else, after you.
Afzal?
Afzal!
It's you!
Lie down!
You don't need to get up.
You --
When did you come here?
How did you find out?
You think you've ventured into the great unknown?
Karachi is just
About 170 kilometres away!
Dad can find you in a moment if he wanted to!
That's what I feared.
If word got to Hyderabad,
It'll be trouble.
Oh?
So you think my arrival brings you trouble?
Not at all!
I'm just worried that Mum and Dad may have found out...
They can't bear such news.
Hold your horses, Monsieur Afzal!
They haven't the foggiest
That you've taken two bullets and are in a hospital.
Thank you.
Thank you for what?
I -- I'm saying it because
You've not told Mum and Dad.
Well,
How are you now?
I'm alright now.
I'll be able to walk in a few days.
What will you do when you get up?
What should I do?
Get out of here and get straight to Hyderabad.
What happened?
I've grown weary of Hyderabad now...
I won't go there now.
Do you even know what condition your Mum and Dad are in?
They weep in your remembrance!
And you!
Why have you switched off your cell phone?
You're angry with me, right?
Why are you punishing Mum and Dad for it?
I'm punishing myself...
I'll go to Hyderabad once I've become something.
What will you become?
No idea.
You're not going to become anything.
In three months, you've just gotten a job as a security guard!
Have some shame!
At the very least, you wore a shirt and tie
Back when you worked at our office.
You --
Please sit, will you?
Oh, shoot!
I'll stand here, talk, and leave.
Speaking of shooting,
Where have you been hit?
It's nothing --
Just two bullets over here,
But don't worry. They've operated them out.
But,
May I tell you something?
A wound more excruciating than that of the bullets
Was inflicted by the barbs I heard back in Hyderabad.
That may never heal.
That's why I've decided
To never return to Hyderabad.
You're very much alive.
But you're an ace runaway.
Alright.
I'm going; bye!
Listen!
Pray tell.
I mean, go on.
Won't you ask me
Why I'd brought Mum and Dad along for the engagement?
You're in a hospital after taking two bullets!
Worry about your wounds.
It's better if you just forgot about your engagement and marriage.
Good day.
Hey!
It's you, Jasmine!
He's shot Babu Hamid!
That --
That was her!
The one who'd bumped into you in the other corridor.
I know her.
Who is she?
You'll find out.
You'll get to know, too,
When she bumps into you.
You can't just go like that!
The stitches will tear off and you wounds will start bleeding.
-I'm leaving because I want to!
Let me go!
Sit down!
You can't just --
-What is going on?
What's going on?
Where would you go in this condition?
My friend -- Babu Hamid...
He's been shot!
I don't know where he's been hit, but I'm going to him!
Alright,
Please.
You're not going anywhere. Sit here.
Just a second.
Sit down!
D -- Dad!
Over there!
Hey!
He's bleeding!
Wait, I'll call the doctor.
Your wound's bleeding!
Please, sit down!
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital