Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
My good man,
Rob us of all our serenity if you want,
But please don't suck the life out of her just yet.
Your mother is very helpful to me.
Come here, my dear, why are you embarrassed?
Who's the outsider here, whose presence has you petrified?
There's good old Lubna,
And with her,
Sweet Farah.
She's come here to listen to all her letters!
You read them out with such evident pleasure!
And the poor lass cannot even remember what she's been writing to you all along!
Shut the door.
Dad will hear it if I said something.
Who writes you letters?
You are aware, Afzal, that I know how to get you talking.
It won't work today.
I will neither place my hand on your head, nor swear.
Can you fathom Dad's sorrow?
Mum slaps you and vents it out,
But he no longer slaps.
He's afraid of me.
I've weakened his faith in me.
I've dragged an honest Reverend down from his tribune onto the floor.
So you know all of this?
I also know that Mum curses her hands after slapping me.
Then why don't you correct yourself?
I can't be corrected.
What do you mean?
You'd pity me if I corrected myself.
I'd have to pass through the same alley her car drives through everyday.
Dad would prolong his prayers when I'd go to the Mosque to pray,
Afraid, thinking,
'He gets involved in a malefaction whenever he prays'.
What would you call a malefaction?
My love, too, is like a malefaction.
I feel as if I've committed a cardinal sin.
I'm embarrassed before you too.
I feel I would die of shame
If she came before my eyes.
Then why don't you tell us who writes you letters?
If you love this Farah, why have you kept that Farah's letters?
-I'll tell you one day.
You'd be the first one I'd tell...
This last bit gets me suspicious,
And I'm also afraid to say that she's told a lie.
I swear by you she's told the truth.
She hasn't written these letters.
Pray tell, my dear,
Do I beg forgiveness
On his behalf,
Or ask his mother to?
Farah...
You're feeling sorrow now, aren't you?
Yes...
Perhaps it's sorrow...
Why were you weeping on the way back?
I wasn't weeping.
I just got a bit teary-eyed.
You're pitying him, innit?
I'm pitying the Reverend.
He loves him so much.
Hey!
It's still here.
Haven't you sent it for repairing?
Talk about him.
I don't even think of him.
But, seeing his family, it seems
He's not that bad.
Did you see the tears in his eyes?
I did.
But why did he tear up?
Does one cry when one's ashamed of what he's done?
He wasn't ashamed.
Not at all.
That's what I felt, too.
He stood there firmly
As if he's been wronged!
What nerve
For a trickster
And a con man!
Alright, now, forget about him.
Who's crazy enough to remember him?
The Reverend is coming to my mind every now and then.
He can't live without him.
Why would he?
He'd forget, as would he, all that happened in a few days.
He [Afzal] won't forget.
He'd remember every single thing.
He'd be afraid
That he may have to face me.
So?
What difference does that make?
It doesn't to me.
But it does to the Reverend.
He'd [Afzal] leave Hyderabad.
Who told you?
My heart says it.
Shut up, Farah!
You've suffered the consequences of your heart's augury many times before
And you are suffering to this day.
I'm honest, Lubna,
He won't say in Hyderabad.
He'd leave everyone.
And what if he didn't?
You may proclaim it
That the greatest of all fabulists is Farah's heart.
An ace fabulist.
When does it depart?
3.15.
Get to the Mosque with a bike by 2.30.
Think over it, Afzal,
Think over it once more.
There's no further scope for thinking.
I don't know where you've picked this 'scope' from!
Now there's 'no scope' for anything to you!
Hey, I can't have a long conversation.
It'd be trouble if Arifa overheard it.
Alright.
I'll be there on time.
And keep the money in your pocket.
Give it to me at the station.
I've kept it.
I'm wandering about with the money in my pocket.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
You're awake?
Yes.
Why?
He hasn't offered his prayers.
He'd said he had,
So he must have.
Arifa told me
That he was lying.
God forgive!
I'll scold him in the morning.
At the very least, he should not lie about his prayers!
There are some sleeping pills in the drawer.
I'd brought an extra 5mg.
Take one.
It'll ease your woes.
I've taken one already.
Neither has it eased my woes, nor put me to sleep.
You couldn't sleep either?
How strange, isn't it, Ruqaiyya, that I've
Never stayed awake like this even for your sorrow.
When have I given you any sorrow?
What was it, if not sorrow,
Four years until the engagement, and four years and three months of separation,
Then, your Dad's order,
'Subhanallah, if you'
'So much as pass through this alley, consider the engagement broken'!
I'd bought one of those
Little tape recorders back then.
In the quiet of the night,
I'd secretly listen to one song.
Which one?
Where art thou; call out to me,
Blossometh my youthful, merry world...
Call out to me, O where art thou;
I lie here, wasted,
Where dost thou thrive?
Blossometh my youthful, merry world...
Alright, now, that's enough.
I'm feeling sleepy.
You'd better get some rest too.
Thank you.
She'll be completing her Master's in a month,
Send her to pursue her MPhil now.
Has she said this?
I've thought of this.
That's brilliant.
Who knows how many years she'll take to earn her MPhil?
Won't she get married?
Who will she marry?
We'll look for a suitable boy.
Let me be very clear, Irsa Begum, that I'm not sending the lass to London all alone.
The pursuit of knowledge is dear to me, too,
But honour is dearer to me.
She won't agree to any one, Monseigneur.
Why won't she?
Are there no good lads left in the world?
She'll definitely like someone.
She won't like anyone. Not now.
She'll take a few years to conclude
That nobody can possibly be better than Afzal.
Let her go.
She's no longer alone.
When a girl starts thinking about someone,
So what says your augurer of a heart?
When will he leave?
Tonight.
Who knows when he'll return to Hyderabad...
If what you say turns out to be true,
I swear I'll have you perform exorcism
And make me amulets all my life.
Call Arifa in a while and ask her
Where her brother is.
She'll say that he's in his room, sleeping.
Say, then,
'Go and check'.
She'd find out, as would you,
When she'd check.
What's the time?
2.20.
He'd be about to leave.
Call and ask at a quarter to three.
She'll check and tell you that he's left.
Get going.
Didn't I tell you to get a move on?
There's no scope for stopping to look back.
C'mon.
What's the time?
It's almost 3.
Call Arifa.
Call her, will you?
Ask her where her brother is.
Call her; I'm being honest!
He's left.
Hello?
Lubna here.
Everything's alright, isn't it?
It is over here,
Check and tell me if everything's alright there.
Yes, everything's alright.
Where's Afzal?
In his room?
Go and check,
See if he's actually in his room, sleeping.
What do you mean?
I'll tell you what I mean later.
For now, stay on the line, go to his room, and tell me if he's there.
Afzal!
Afzal?
He --
He's not in his room, Lubna.
He's gone, Arifa.
He's left Hyderabad.
Who told you?
Farah.
Has he told Farah?
Farah's heart has told her.
Thank you, mate.
My train's here.
You may go now.
Afzal,
If you can somehow see some scope for it on the way, turn back, will you?
Please.
If you're vexed with someone, leave it be.
If you're obdurate, don't be.
I'm vexed with myself,
Obdurate against fate.
I'll die
Of disgrace here;
If forced to return,
I'd rather drown in the ocean.
As they say,
The waters of shame are deeper than the oceans.
You are awake
And having tea.
What is going on?
Why don't you have some, too?
Sit.
Take two or three sips first.
As you command.
God is the Greatest.
May you live long.
That's three sips there.
Tell me, now.
Mum's asleep, right?
Fast asleep.
The biddy's taken a stronger dose than 5mg.
She'll wake up just in time to make up for missed prayers!
That's very good.
Why is it good?
Here.
Afzal's written it?
Yes.
He's left?
Just one blighter
Among one's sons
Can kill; that scallywag!
You --
He had some money with him, didn't he?
Well, no worries about that.
As per his last known whereabouts,
He was playing a cricket match at night.
Let's just say
That, as he left,
He's gambled there, too.
She's sleeping without a worry.
The pill's got the power!
The wretch can even make a mother doze off like that!
But you'd better stay awake.
I'll lead the prayers
And think about a solution for when she's awake.
Keep a close watch.
If she wakes up,
Don't tell her what roused you.
Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Love Farah for four months --
-What's this balderdash!
I -- I mean, act as if you love her.
If necessary, you'd stand firm before Dad in saying,
'I love Farah so much that I'd die without her'!
Every compeer I found
Doubled my heart's grief
Just keep on loving me,
So much
When obsecrating for rosebuds
That beholders and earwiggers
Die of envy!
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Must I be perfidious?
There's no other option!
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
We may just be parted...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Hey!
Oi!
Get your leg out of the way!
Ych a fi!
Would you look at that, Mam!
How he's staring back!
Push him aside!
Get aside!
Look at him staring wide-eyed!
It's you, Reverend!
And upon you, peace.
You'll have to come.
Right now?
Yes.
What happened?
Come along, will you?
I'll be coming in a minute.
Listen, Doctor...
Bring all the heart medicines you have.
Has someone had a heart attack?
God forbid, no!
Just do as I say.
Alright, I'm coming.
O Lord, grant me peace...
Arifa!
Yes, Mum?
You darted here so quickly!
Have I never called out to you before?
Anyway,
Where's your Dad?
He'll be coming shortly.
He would be, but where's he gone?
His prayers would've ended at 5.15.
Anyway,
What about your brother?
Has he asked for some tea or breakfast?
Or does he lay shamefaced, sleeping?
Who can fall asleep shamefaced?
The poor soul must be awake.
May my hands break.
I'd hit him so hard.
His jaw must be paining.
Ask him how he is.
Give the poor lad something to eat and tell him to get some sleep.
What would you like to have?
Tea or coffee?
Don't ask about tea or coffee in an emergency,
Just bring the patient, Reverend.
Dad...
She's up.
She's only asking about him ever since she got up.
Sit firm here, Doctor.
Keep the medicines ready.
Medicines for what -- I should know first...
Have some tea.
I'll get you some in a minute.
Who's the honourable visitor?
He's
The good old Doctor.
The Doctor?
You're mentioning him as if
Mentioning him forebodes no danger.
Now that he's here, serve him some tea before he leaves.
Else, the folks in the neighbourhood will keep on asking until the night,
'Is everything alright'?
'What happened'?
'Who's so sick that you had to call the Doctor home'?
-Would you please shut up, Ruqaiyya Begum?
Going on and on for no reason!
The door's shut, isn't it?
Not a sound goes out of this room when this door is shut.
Don't you remember when I'd gone to watch a film with Nüzhet?
We had a row in this very room.
How ferociously you roared!
But not a mouse stirred outside!
May I sit?
There, now.
You'd ask permission of me to sit now?
And why would you sit?
Have forgotten the good Doctor sitting out there?
My Afzal!
He's alright, isn't he?
Yes, he's --
He's alright.
Sit down.
Sit...
If...
If you are tormented like this,
It'd make things difficult for me.
This lordly wont of yours of whacking him,
Get this out of yourself!
Your son's a young man.
And he's --
Out of control, at that.
What if, one of these days,
He went astray?
So?
You've forgotten already!
He threatens us
With his departure
From here!
Should I yield to his threats?
It won't be this way, Reverend,
If he does something wrong,
I'll whack him.
Alright, then, don't budge!
But remember, also,
That it won't be like this every time.
One of these days, you'll wake up
To the news that he's boarded the 3.15 a.m. train and left!
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV