Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Who are you?
What are you looking at?
Tell me.
Who are you?
Whom do you want to meet?
Where do you come from?
Your face looks just like my Afzal's.
But you're not Afzal ['The Great One'].
The blighter's on the run, hiding his face from us.
Go away.
Go away -- away!
Get up.
I've recognised you.
I'm talking to you, remembering only those ties that you left unsevered.
You came here to hear about Dad,
And you'd left without listening to Dad?
He tripped and fell yesterday
Face-first.
Everyone else saw it yesterday,
But I had on that day itself
When you'd dropped him face-first.
His back's hunched now, you twit;
His gait's slowed down.
You left Hyderabad,
He left his priesthood.
You started walking down the path of God,
And he came back from the path of God.
Is this the path of God, Afzal?
Does God have one commit murders?
Hearing your news,
He evades God and starts talking about worldly affairs.
Don't say a word about meeting him.
Hear it from me,
And ask the doctors to satisfy yourself.
He's come to now.
He's talking,
Smiling,
And eating, now, too.
I'm not leaving without meeting him.
And you'd leave once you've met?
Come again the next time
You get the news.
Who's that?
Is she with you?
There, now!
She's Jasmine, isn't she?
Come here, will you?
Alright now,
That's enough.
However did he chance upon you?
He's an ace hoodlum.
He may even murder you one day.
The blighter had gone to become a great man,
But has come back so low
That I have to search for my son in him.
Get aside, will you?
Move aside.
I have to ask your Dad for his judgement on meeting you.
May I come along?
Come.
But don't be too quick to tell
That you're someone to him.
Would you look at
Who's come!
Try to recognise who she is.
She's Jasmine, isn't she?
So you've come to steal all the coconut biscuits!
Now,
Will you sit,
Or meet me standing here and leave?
Not at all.
Why would I leave?
I've come here to meet and stay with you.
Did you hear that, Ruqaiyya?
She's
Come to stay with us.
Then,
Just stay here with us, will you?
He's sitting outside too.
What are your orders for him?
Tell him
I'm fine now.
He may prepare for his next attack.
He's crying buckets.
He says, 'I'm not leaving without meeting him'.
Ties of blood may be stinging him...
Our beloved son, Ruqaiyya Begum, is a benefaction bestowed upon us after many ardent prayers.
Whatever he may be like,
He must be in pain.
Tell him
That he's weeping seven months too late;
We've been weeping for seven months.
Kiss his forehead,
Shower your love on him,
Bless him and bid him goodbye.
If the rapscallion came before my eyes,
I'll start missing him again.
No, Ruqaiyya Begum,
Please don't take such a risk.
And what if he came and fell at your feet?
What would you do?
She's --
She's sitting before me.
I can't give him the reply he deserves.
Just tell him
That he can't meet me...
I'm actually a doctor,
But trust me, I'm
In a condition worse than any patient's right now.
You must be wondering who I am.
Good question.
Please tell him, would you?
He's Farah's fiancé.
It's -- Alright if you don't think of me as her fiancé.
The engagement didn't fully happen.
It just happened one way.
He didn't put the ring on her...
So,
You're from Karachi?
Yes.
What do you do?
I mean --
Business, for example.
One can start any kind of business in Karachi.
What happened to her?
Who?
The one who used to write you letters.
Well, you'd obviously be writing her back, too,
But I've heard more about the one who used to write to you.
Still talking, aren't you?
Still talking, isn't he?
Wh --
The Reverend?
Oh yes,
He's awrite.
Everyone's talking to him.
Tell me, will you?
What happened to her?
Why are you asking?
Whenever I sit with Farah,
We just talk about the two of you.
But I realised, seeing your fiancée today,
That you couldn't, so far,
Get the one who used to write you letters.
Someone else got her.
That's what happens the first time you love.
Sometimes, you don't get the letter,
And sometimes, you don't get the one who writes them.
Did you see that?
How he had her hand in his as he ran up the stairs?
Without the slightest shame, seeing that right I'm before him,
Nor the slightest sorrow that his Dad's had a heart attack!
She's his fiancée!
The fibster!
The crook!
The ignoble!
Why are you saying such foul words, Farah?
She met you so warmly.
And she's the one who had called to tell you.
However is she a crook and a fibster?
You're envying her, aren't you?
Why would I envy that chit?
Did you see her face?
My shoe looks prettier!
Control, Farah, control.
Whatever has happened to you?
Where's Sibtain?
We'd left Sibtain there.
He'll be with Uncle Reverend until the morning.
Why would he stay, now?
Now that that blighter's here!
And he's brought her along too!
Good Lord!
Look at her prance around him
After the engagement!
And she'd even held his hand to show everyone!
Call him!
What do I say?
Tell him to go home.
Let only the one who ought to be there stay.
We'll talk about everything else tomorrow.
What else is there to talk about?
I'll see
Who's got the nerve!
What are you talking about?
I'll call Sibtain and ask him to come here this instant.
You're not well.
Wait.
I'm good,
But my intentions aren't.
Please, Farah, relax.
It isn't the end of the world if he's gotten engaged.
What's an engagement, let him get married.
Whatever is it to you?
That's what I'm saying.
Now that he's gotten engaged,
He'd better get married, too!
Let him fix the same date.
The same date?
As my wedding.
Ask him to get married on the same day, will you?
When are you getting married?
Even your engagement's been stalled.
Just think there will be no engagement now.
What do you mean?
Why not?
Just try to understand, Lubna.
I'm getting married this Sunday.
Which Sunday?
Next Sunday.
And tell him if you chance upon him tomorrow,
I dare him to this one if he's got the guts!
Let him fix the date for the next Sunday.
Let me see him get married, too!
He beats you everyday?
No.
Sometimes everyday,
And sometimes every second or third day.
And you think this induces your nightmares.
The faces
Of the ghosts that haunt you resemble your husband's.
Yes.
Arranged marriage?
No.
It was a love marriage.
Oh...
How many years has it been since your marriage?
One and a half.
And
How long have you been having nightmares?
It's been four months.
Another lass?
I mean --
I figure someone's come between the two of you.
There!
That's what you think, too?
So is that it?
That's it, Herr Doktor.
I used to say to him,
But he never agreed.
He'd fight with me,
Say foul words,
And claw away the strands of hair --
But your hair look fine.
They don't seem clawed.
No...
I'm talking about his hair.
That's his style.
He'd scream first,
Then hurl abuses,
And then start clawing at his hair.
And then?
And then he beats me.
Look at this...
Here...
No --
Please don't show me.
Just tell me.
I already have.
Who's the lass?
That's what I can't find out.
Whenever I name someone,
He says, 'She's my sister'.
He may be telling the truth.
How can that be?
He had only one sister when we got married.
Very sad.
He'd be enjoying himself at home, watching TV, while you're suffering.
Not at all.
I've left him at the other doctor.
The other doctor?
You mean another psychiatrist?
No.
The usual doctor.
One who treats injuries and all.
That one.
Injuries and all?
I've hit him on his face with a plate...
There's a little wound here.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Farah speaking.
My eyes brighten the moment I hear you call out to me;
In my mind is associated with your pleasant voice your unforgettable image.
Where are you?
At my clinic.
Where's Paw?
My Paw?
Of course.
He's at home.
Tell him to get out of the house,
Come to our place and meet Dad this instance.
Is there any problem?
We're getting married on Sunday.
Non, Mademoiselle, we're getting engaged on Sunday.
Forget the engagement.
Engagements are for the cheap!
How can that be?
What did you say?
I mean --
Why
Are you saying,
'We're getting married on Sunday'?
It struck right at my heart.
This is Farah Ibrahim speaking,
Sibtain Akhtar Ali!
Yes -- I know --
I know this --
Very well...
Know, then, that we're getting married on Sunday.
I do exactly as I say.
That's alright, but --
How can we get married so quickly?
One's got to prepare, and
It's Sibtain Akhtar Ali's wedding,
Not a pleb's that it --
It'd just happen.
Know what, Paw had gone to the zoo yesterday.
Why the zoo?
To ask about an elephant.
Elephant, as in?
Elephant, as in, the large animal with a trunk and two large tusks --
Jumbo, you know --
It's called an elephant.
So what?
What'd you do with one?
Paw's thinking
I'd ride one
When bringing the procession.
If the wedding procession doesn't get here on Sunday,
You'd better stay at home.
Or in your rotting clinic.
And if I see you somewhere after that,
I'd whack you with my boot!
This blighter's yet another watermelon
That isn't red on the inside!
Here's your phone.
Easy there.
Right here.
Now, he's
Come to an awareness about the difference between righteousness and sin, Ruqaiyya Begum.
He's standing like a stranger
Outside his own home.
The blighter!
That's alright.
Alright.
Just call him in and ask for once.
Hear from his own mouth whether he's among the righteous or the sinful.
Surely, your judgement cannot be mistaken, but
It may be mistaken, too.
There's no need, now,
To inquire further
Or hear any further explanations.
If he went back now, he may not be coming back.
As if he's come back now!
He's sent a murderer in his place.
My son has stayed back in Karachi, Monseigneur...
Ask her.
Tell me,
What was he like when he'd come to Karachi?
He'd not kill a cockroach in his room.
He'd just pick it up and leave it outside.
And now, when he started killing,
He killed people...
Have him stand in the witnss box and ask him this.
He must have an answer.
You may not like his answer,
But please, for once, listen to it.
Monseigneur's right,
But --
It's up to you...
I've gone through a full heart attack
Before coming here, Ruqaiyya Begum.
I've got the courage!
Let him stand with his arms crossed!
Let him accost
The father inside me!
But I'm not going to change.
You don't yield.
You just shatter.
What do you mean?
Don't forget, Reverend,
The Reverend has been bitterly defeated in this battle between a Reverend and a father.
I have seen the Reverend succumb and fall at the father's feet with my own eyes.
Now,
If you'd grab the father by the throat the moment you've come to,
The life will ebb out of a helpless mother.
Now, she's being sentimental to blackmail me.
But --
-But nothing, Reverend.
Be blackmailed.
Let him meet his sister and mother,
And when it's your turn,
You may look the other way.
Monseigneur, his honour has been tainted forever!
He'd regain his lost honour if he set foot inside his home.
What are you talking about, Monseigneur?
Honour is not a trifle that's lost and won like that.
It is gained on the condition of maintaining integrity
And holding firm to all the pieces.
Alright.
If that's what pleases you, I'll send him back.
Now, Monseigneur, it isn't exactly something that you should be vexed with me over.
Wait.
Alright.
Have it your way.
But think carefully,
For you shall be held responsible for it,
And any associated sin or reward.
There's no question about any sin or reward, Reverend.
If it pleases the mother and daughter, I will be past the bridge to Paradise like the ignis fatuus.
Shut the door to my room.
And tell your mother
To not let him come here.
Enter your home in the Lord's name.
Be wary of your father.
Wary as in,
Just visible from afar.
Say the Lord's name.
I did.
Come in, then.
If any of you has the time to, please give me a cup of tea.
Don't look there.
He'd gulp
Two cups in his fury.
I'll get you in a minute, Dad.
Surely, you can prepare tea?
Of course.
I make a real tidy brew.
Then, prepare one and take it to Dad.
It'll wash away all his fury.
Show me the kitchen.
Come.
You're saying Sunday?
Yes.
You've thought over it carefully?
Yes, I have.
What date is it on Sunday?
The 27th.
That's what you know, innit?
That Sunday is the 27th?
You're talking about the Sunday on the 27th, right?
Yes.
Alright.
Brace yourself.
You're getting married on Sunday.
There!
Your Dad's here too.
Sit down, Madame la mariée.
Where are you off to?
Sit here and try out this bolt of yours,
Your Dad tests his heart's mettle.
Why are you folks remembering me and my heart?
Please, Monseigneur, sit.
Congratulations.
Congratulations?
I mean,
What for?
Farah's getting married on Sunday.
It's her engagement on Sunday.
We'd planned her engagement,
But Mademoiselle's planned her marriage.
Are you in your senses?
Sunday's just around the corner!
You should worry about the corner she's got herself in!
Wait!
Sit here by my side.
Right, now, what's the problem?
N --
N -- n --
N -- n -- Nothing?
Tell me,
Who mentioned the marriage?
She did, Dad.
She got touched in the head back at the hospital,
And decided when we got here that she'd get married this Sunday.
This marriage is not possible, Dad.
I mean -- Not on this Sunday.
And who are you to say that?
No, I didn't say that.
Sibtain did.
He called and said, 'I'm very upset'.
Why is he upset?
He should be delighted.
Perhaps he's -- not ready for so much delight?
There's something else going on, Irsa.
Let it go on if it is!
I say, the date's fixed.
You'd better say, too,
'She'd be getting married this Sunday'.
'She'd be getting married this Sunday'. La fin!
Irsa!
Oh God, what is going on?
No idea.
But I can tell you, Dad,
Sibtain won't marry her.
Anybody except Afzal may come in.
It's you!
You've brought tea?
Splendid.
Working on your first day here?
Here.
I really wanted to have a nice brew.
You don't seem the type.
What type?
I mean,
You're so affectionate.
But it's rather well-known that you can get furious.
Ruqaiyya really says anything!
She didn't say a thing.
I've seen for myself.
You didn't let him in for an hour and a half,
And now, when he's come in, you're meeting everyone except him?
Won't it shatter his heart?
Do you know how many hearts he left shattered here?
Three of them were ours.
Leave Arifa and me,
Tell me, if a mother's heart shatters,
Whatever would be left there?
He's sitting with his head in her lap,
And she's running her fingers through his hair continuously.
She fears him now.
Earlier, she'd whack him at the slightest!
Oh!
The blighter's affrighted her, too.
You'll see
How she dotes on him now!
She would
Be vexed with me for him!
She's right like a cauldron.
She'd tilt over to his side
The moment one gets into a row with her sweet child!
In all honesty,
I've grown weary of the politics of love.
Do you know, this heart attack I had,
This wretched heart
Has belittled me before Ruqaiyya.
You understand what I mean by 'belittled', don't you?
Yes.
The same way you've belittled me.
Wait!
Stop!
You're vexed with me over the first cup of tea on your first day here!
Call his mother's 'Excellent One' [Afzal] here.
But tell him
He has two minutes.
Hey -- Farah!
Where are you off to?
W --
Where would I go?
It just occurred to me
That I'd never congratulated Jasmine over her engagement because of the Reverend.
If nothing else,
I have a sort of a friendship with her.
Right...
You're chums with her.
And
I'd give her Uncle Reverend's ring too.
I'll say, 'This one was made for you',
'But ended up with me'.
That's it?
That's it, as in?
Won't you congratulate Afzal?
Yes,
If he -- came across, I'd -- congratulate him, too.
Splendid!
You have such a big heart!
Are you coming along?
No way!
I can't witness such spectacles!
Wait -- Listen!
Don't mention that --
You're getting married on Sunday.
Why?
Mum will, of course.
Leave such chores to her.
May I come in, Dad?
You have two minutes; that's all you have.
And, for these two minutes,
Stay at an arm's length from me.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV