Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Doctor,
Her heart's fine, right?
What happened to her heart?
It's all about the heart, Doctor; who knows what you're checking...
I can check her pulse, too;
A high or low blood pressure is evident from the way she talks,
But
I cannot know about her heart.
She's come back
From Karachi, wounded.
Please check thoroughly, there must be something wrong.
No, Reverend, her heart's fine.
Strange...
So, that means that when one is tormented,
The other person should not think that one's heart is tormented.
Won't you prescribe any medicines?
If not for the heart,
Please give her one for the torment.
There's no need.
Give her a sleeping pill if she cannot sleep.
2 mg.
Come, Doctor.
Wait, Reverend,
Let me write down the name of the pill.
No need for that.
I keep a packet of sleeping pills in my pocket all the time.
Speaking of which,
She won't even doze off for a minute with your 2 mg.
Alright, then.
That's it.
-Come.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, sir.
Come.
What do you feel?
I feel that he's not at home.
When the lass came yesterday,
It occurred to me that I should stop her,
Say that she should stay here,
And not go back.
She's nobody to me, so to speak,
But I feel that my Afzal's here when she comes.
Farah?
When you say Farah like that,
It sounds as if she used to write him letters.
Even if she did not,
For the love of the Lord, she could've written one to save the life of a mother.
Or, just ask her not to come here.
Tell her
To let the dead remain interred in their graves,
And not come again and again to offer her prayers.
She'd come to tell that she's getting married.
There, now.
Hearing that, it felt
As if she's doing something wrong.
As if she's turning back after giving us her word.
She's doing what's best.
She's doing what's best...
She's not doing what's best.
She was talking about him all the time.
She's in the same condition as you.
Her heart beats alright,
But grows restless.
No...
There's nothing to worry about, really.
Call whenever you want.
Whenever, as in,
Anytime.
No need to get so romantic.
I know very well
That no one truly loves these days,
And even when one does, one does not understand it.
Anyway, tell me, do you watch films?
Oh, no, I watch a lot!
Have you watched Chennai Express?
You shameless --
Yes...
I'd watched that scene, too,
But only secretly.
Farah was right by me, you know...
Whom are you chatting with?
Hey!
Is that even a question?
The same blighter?
Obviously.
Every girl's got just one blighter in her life.
I'll call you later --
We'll talk at night.
Not at all --
She didn't call you a blighter.
Okay,
Bye.
He heard it!
Have some shame, Lubna.
You're head over heels for a killer?
You'll see, if he gets caught,
The police will be here too!
Why would they be here?
They'd be pleased to interrogate his beloved for a few days, too!
Don't tell me!
Anyway, though,
What does love care about problems?
Have you seen Dad?
He's not mentioned him once since we came back from Karachi.
Right...
I've noticed it too.
Why are you calling him, then?
By the Lord, I'm not!
He calls me again and again.
Change your number
Just like he had.
But --
But what?
Would you settle only when Dad's been disgraced?
Just think you made a mistake.
Ask forgiveness of God,
And get married and go to your home
As soon as your next semester's finished.
Who'd I marry?
Oh, please!
As if all the other psychiatrists in Hyderabad have died!
So I should marry a psychiatrist, too?
Put a sock in it!
As if I'm mad!
So all of you think I'm mad?
Honestly, Lubna,
Why did Dad decide to get me married to that psychiatrist?
He's taken a liking to you.
He's lost his heart to you.
He pleaded before Dad,
And Dad thought he's a fine man,
And the most famous doctor in all of Hyderabad.
Don't call him a doctor!
The blighter's a psychiatrist.
Don't call him a blighter either,
It'd sink into his heart.
So what if it does?
Good Lord,
One doesn't insult one's would-be husband before marriage.
Otherwise, they exact their revenge.
I can't marry him.
What?
What now?
But --
You just said 'yes' the other day!
For God's sake, Farah,
Dad's blood pressure would shoot up!
Lubna, look,
Please don't mind what I'm saying,
But the thing is
I can't marry anyone now.
I feel as if
My heart would fail
The moment the wedding procession would come for me.
Then discuss it with him.
-Who?
Your psychiatrist, of course!
He'd have a hundred cures.
Besides, he knows very well who he's marrying.
He'd have gone through all his books again.
Nobody can cure me.
I know I'm not alright,
But the bigger thing is
That I don't want to be cured in the first place.
Do you have his number?
Yes...
Call and ask him
To stay away from me,
Or I will murder him!
I don't love him,
But it feels like I'm in love.
Well, it isn't anything spectacular...
There's a great difference between feeling and being in love.
What's the difference?
I feel so today,
But you'll see,
I may not tomorrow.
My heart will change one day
Just like he's changed his phone number.
You would've seen it in Karachi -
The clouds engulf the skies,
But it doesn't rain.
The same has happened with me -
Clouds enveloped the skies,
But brought no rain.
Every compeer abandoned me...
You could get his number.
Sajid would have it.
Who's Sajid?
His friend.
An old one.
And how would we get Sajid's number?
I have it with me.
Just ask him
To let you talk to Afzal,
Or give his number.
Why would he let me talk to him?
He'd ask, 'Who are you'? 'What do you want with him'?
Just say you're a friend of Samina's.
He won't ask anything then.
I'll take my leave.
Give me his number.
Right...
Look it up.
If you look up 'Hyderabad',
You'd see his number.
Hello?
It's Sajid, innit?
Yes; who are you?
Samina.
S --
I think it's a girl.
Didn't his 'S --' tell you?
It's Samina.
No.
Samina would never call him.
Come again, who are you?
Oh --
It's Samina.
Didn't you recognise me?
In the last two years,
I've recognised Samina's voice better than her.
So, who are you?
I'm her friend, Jasmine.
And I've gotten this number because I need something.
What do you need?
Give me Afzal's number.
I'd have to ask Afzal about that.
Do you ask for Afzal's permission to eat?
What?
You love Samina, don't you?
The two of you couldn't get married, innit?
Yes...
It's good that you weren't!
If the lad's not manly, he should remain single like you!
Note down his number.
Go on.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Please, come in.
Take these flowers.
Give the flowers to her.
You've got two hours.
Once Mum and Dad get back, you won't be able to talk.
Where is she?
She's mostly in her room.
She comes out once in a while if she's delighted.
Is she ever delighted?
What are you talking about?
She was a right lively lass - rollicking about everywhere!
Patients like her are right lively in the beginning - 'Rollicking about everywhere'.
They then turn all quiet, then.
What kind of patients?
You won't get it.
Those who fall in love become patients requiring constant and thorough attention.
Are you out of your mind?
You're calling those who love 'patients'?
I said you won't get it.
But I'm honest.
It's the world's one truly immedicable affliction...
-Love?
Yes.
And what a pleasant stroke of serendipity
Is it
That people are overjoyed to fall in love.
Just think about one's mental condition!
As if one's afflicted with cancer,
And he's calling his friends, telling them,
'Buddy, you know',
'I'm in cancer'.
Shut up, Mr Sibtain!
Don't say such things before her!
Please, call her.
I don't usually see patients on Sundays.
Get yourself treated,
Or a certain party might beat you with shoes.
Party?
Yes.
Those who love are a certain kind of party,
And the party of the heartbroken is the most dangerous.
If you said such things before them,
They'd beat you black and blue until your brain's french-fried!
So, when your sister's cured,
You'll realise that I fix the brains of those in love.
Hey!
When you said that you've fallen in love,
Were you lying then?
How did you figure I'm lying?
How could you be in love,
When you're saying so much against it?
Ever heard of the bird flu?
Or the Congo Virus?
That wretched Congo Virus killed many doctors who went to treat it!
Can't you talk in simpler terms?
The simple point is simply
That if the doctor can catch the Congo Virus,
Then, the doctor who goes in to cure it
Can catch love from the patient, too.
Doctors have feelings too.
A doctor's not made of stone.
He has feelings and emotions, too.
And then, everyone 'round here's eager to die.
I can't handle it.
Okay...
I'll call her here.
I'm coming...
Peace be upon you!
And upon you, peace.
-Come, please come, Mr Paracha...
-Please, come in.
Peace be upon you.
-How are you, sir?
I'd known it, Mr Paracha,
That you'd remember me again in just a few days,
But I have humbly pleaded with you,
And begged forgiveness, too,
That I like the courage now
To stand
At the Prophet's tribune.
No, Reverend --
It's not about the Mosque or the tribune,
But I've come to you
With a problem.
Yes?
Problem?
Just give me your orders,
And it would be my fortune if I could be of any help.
Right...
Thank you very much...
Firstly, congratulations to you.
In fact, congratulations from all of us.
Sir?
What for?
-Oh, Reverend!
Afzal has, with the Lord's grace, conquered Karachi in a blink, so to speak.
His name resounds throughout.
And he's put the mightiest hoodlums in their place!
Mr Paracha,
Talk about your problem.
Reverend...
It's nothing much, really,
But the thing is --
Your nephews Haroon and Mamoon
Had started selling books about saving lives.
Yes...
And
Some blackguard sent them a slip demanding 200,000 Rupees.
I've got the slip...
Right here.
I --
What'd I do with it?
Reverend,
Please give this slip to Afzal,
And tell him to give that blackguard a scolding.
That's all it'd take, Reverend!
Keep this slip in your pocket, Mr Paracha.
You say his mere scolding is enough,
And I say
That even dying of disgrace won't be enough for me.
Sir?
I regret to say that you're the first person in the entire neighbourhood
Whom I'm telling with utmost sorrow
That I've decided
To disown Afzal.
I am henceforth not responsible for any word or deed of his.
If the Lord so wills,
One of these days, this news will be printed in the newspapers, too,
Which will serve as a testimonial for all of you.
Why are you standing here?
Please, come in; have some tea, perhaps?
No, Reverend.
Thank you very much.
I'll take my leave.
Alright.
In the Lord's protection.
Here.
Listen to another one, Ruqaiyya Begum!
Our
Lives are ebbing away out of grief,
And people are coming here to congratulate us.
It was Mr Paracha.
He was talking to me
With such visible fear as if
He's talking to the Law Minister's Dad.
He handed me a slip for a tithe, saying,
'Give this to Afzal Bhai'.
Someone's demanded 200,000 from his wastrels of sons.
Now your habile lad's PA
Is going to
Call the cove,
And he'll be saying back, 'I'm sorry',
'Afzal Bhai, but I didn't know'
'That Haroon and Mamoon were your servitors'.
Haroon and Mamoon are Mr Paracha's wastrels of sons.
May I ask something, Reverend?
Why,
Sure!
Ask me ten if you want.
Don't you feel afraid?
If you run a bulletin of exaggerated news stories like a TV channel,
Won't it strike fear in my heart?
And when one's heart is fearstricken, Reverend,
Doctors' visits and medicines don't help.
You always look for negative meanings to positive things.
Our son
Has sprouted wings and touched the fastigium of prosperity!
And you're sitting here like a cowardly mother, wailing,
'Watch out', 'Beware',
'He may slip and fall'.
Someone's congratulated us!
Say it jovially,
'Blessed be he'.
Did you say it?
'Blessed be he'?
Say it, will you, Reverend!
Our son's sprouted wings and touched the fastigium of prosperity,
And you're watching from the bottom like the austere yet inspiriting father,
That his ladder's standing on thin air.
I've always held fast to the ladder.
I can't even say,
'Watch out', 'Be careful'...
The abyss lies ahead and it's a long way down behind.
Alas...
A mother's no soldier, Dad,
Whose resolve would strengthen with every blow.
One of them may prove fatal, too.
Then tell her not to live half-dead.
Show me her strength,
Or I will keep at it!
She's --
Lying on the bed all the time.
It kills me to see that...
I don't stop her from weeping and tormenting,
But is this even a way?
Tell her to get up and move about here.
If nothing else, she could at least pick a fight with me!
Arifa!
Yes, Mum?
Why does the sound of my voice frighten you like that?
Call her.
Who?
The one who comes here when she's tormented, but never bothers
When I'm tormented.
Farah?
Farah's the one...
The one who wrote the letters,
And the one who does not.
Call her here.
Tell her there's neither the tiger in the fields, nor the hunter on the tree stand;
She can come now.
So pleasantly will time pass when two so crazed shall meet...
No...
What's there to 'no' about?
It benefits both of us when she comes.
I'd bless her,
And she'd heal me.
Just the sound of her voice
Eases my heart.
Why do you think that a psychiatrist can't fall in love?
Remember, Mlle Farah Ibrahim,
Every lover is a psychiatrist.
He plays both the patient and the healer.
Remember, also, that no one can understand your state of mind better than me.
Why have you come here without Mum and Dad's permission?
I'll answer that at the end of our little conversation.
For now,
Just look deeply into my eyes.
What do I look for in there?
Hey!
Do you think I'm so shameless?
Strange...
You're terming treatment as shamelessness!
Treatment?
So you've come here to treat me?
Lubna!
Why are you calling Lubna?
It was a slip of the tongue!
And --
I'm always talking about treatment -- So I called this meeting a treatment...
By the way, you could've thought that I'm giving a signal of sorts.
What kind of signal?
Say, we call a meeting 'treatment'.
Let's have codes for going for a ride and going to the pictures, too, shall we?
Exempli gratia, the signal for going to the pictures could be 'operation'...
So, say
You get a text at 6 p.m.
'Operation'.
Take it that I've got two film tickets in my pocket.
You're a proper blighter, I give you that!
No problem.
What 'no problem'?
As I'd told you the other day, it happens in my profession.
People even insult my mother and sister. I don't mind it.
I'd better leave!
-Don't you dare!
What'd you just say?
I said 'Don't you dare'! Sit.
Sit!
Sit tight here and listen to me.
Don't get up.
I'd like to
Talk to you about Afzal.
What about him?
He's no longer the kind of malady a psychiatrist can treat.
He's become an ace 'Bhai' [hoodlum, lit. brother].
-So what?
I've treated many such 'Bhais' who've now become oul fellas.
Ever heard of 'The Ghost' Jessie?
He was an infamous racketeer of Hyderabad.
Came to me for his treatment.
I jesse'd him on the first day.
I thought I'd start with fixing the nyaff's gender.
Know what, he got married right after getting cured. By the Lord's grace, he's got two young'uns now.
He sells leatherware near the police station.
I saw him the other day,
And he said, 'I can get you a jess or a Jessy Made made-to-order, Doc'!
But why are we talking about 'The Ghost' Jessie?
Because you wanted to talk about Afzal.
The poor soul...
I've heard he was a nice and upright lad.
He'd even quit gambling and started praying.
But who knows
Why he left Hyderabad for Karachi...
Because of me.
I think
He left because of me.
I'd told you this one, too!
What does it matter if you'd told?
You tell me anything and everything that you can utter.
But you keep your heart's secrets locked deep in your heart.
He'd have fallen in love...
I'd told you about that, too.
Another girl named Farah used to write him letters.
He loved just her.
Who knows how many he loves now...
That's the problem with you.
What's my problem?
What's the problem with me?
No, not yours -- it's his problem...
The thing is, if he'd just mustered the courage to say it once,
'To the dickens with the Farah who writes letters',
'I love you',
He wouldn't have had to see this time in Karachi today.
What?
As if the blighter had so much courage as to come to me and say, 'I love you'?
Wouldn't I have broken his face?
I'm sure you would have;
Aye, you'd be busy mending it afterwards.
And to be honest,
You did break his face, which made him leave,
And you're busy putting it together.
But you don't know, Mlle Farah Ibrahim,
They say a gentleman's face, when broken, can be mended,
But a mended head cannot be held high.
See you.
Yes, Arifa,
Tell me,
Is everything alright?
We need your help.
Please, tell me.
What do you need?
We need you, Farah...
Mum's found a cure for her condition,
And she's come up with your name as a home remedy.
I don't get it...
How do I explain it to you...
Mum needs Afzal to live.
But he can't come now.
When you come, Mum feels
As if Afzal's here.
Hey!
Shouldn't you be in Clifton?
I should be at home.
The new chef asked for my help to cook.
New chef?
What happened to the old one?
He'd just serve the plates.
What's this guff, mate?
How could you hire any Tom, Dick, or Harry as a new chef without asking me?
This isn't Hyderabad, Sajid,
It's Karachi.
Sit.
Sit down here.
Here.
Look at these.
Don't look at me; look at these photographs.
Go through each of these and ask me who they are.
Who are they?
I've murdered them one by one.
This game of murdering and killing is so fierce that it doesn't end until the killer is dead!
There's opulence to be seen,
I live in this mansion like an Emperor,
And the police salute me like my humble subjects when I go out,
I've got millions of Rupees,
But not a moment's assurance that I can live in peace.
You're a very sweet and delicate girl,
And your dreams are even more delicate than you.
But I'm the kind who'd shatter glass utensils at the slightest provocation,
Whatever could I do with your dreams?
What's the real story?
I just told you.
No.
The real story is that you don't like me.
From our starting quarrels,
You thought that Jasmine's very insolent.
Although I'm not insolent at all.
Do you love me?
When did I say that?
I thought that you love me but are just a bit afraid to tell me.
Don't be afraid.
There's quite a bit of frankness between the two of us, now.
Just say it.
Why are you so afraid, boyo?
What's the worst that can happen?
I'd scold you.
It's late in the evening.
This is the perfect time for these things.
Such things sound bland in broad daylight.
Get in the car.
Taking me for a ride, eh?
I'm dropping you home.
Why?
Do you have a problem?
What'd your Mum be thinking?
She trusts you completely.
I wasn't even coming here,
But she insisted that I go and see what you've been up to.
So, have you found out what I've been up to?
-Don't change the topic.
When the thing about love does come up, you say just half of it, and hold the rest of it back.
Finish the line, and you can drop me home after that if you like.
You don't know, Jasmine, you're a very good girl, but --
-Now, you'd better not say that you like me!
Your grammar fails at the most crucial moment.
Are you feeling shy now?
Alright, I'll look the other way.
There.
Now, say the full thing, and don't fumble with your grammar.
I don't love you, Jasmine...
And I'm not worthy of being loved, now, either.
Drop me at my place.
Translation: Aditya Misra © Prime TV