Just two more minutes.
Still two minutes?
You're very hungry?
Very.
Just...
It'll be ready in a while.
And Maman's here!
What's going on?
I'm making an omelette for Rumi.
Didn't he eat anything?
How could he? Nothing had been cooked.
Hey!
Didn't she cook food?
The maid left at 12.
She called,
Telling that her Mum's been rushed to the hospital.
She said she had to go.
And you said, 'Go'?
What could I do?
Her Mum was at the hospital.
Would I have stopped her here to have her cook?
Come here,
My sweet.
My son will sit here and have his omelette.
Maman's going to change and come, okay?
When did you come here?
I came back early.
So what are you doing now?
Preparing tea
For you.
Don't talk about him.
What do you want?
In fact, what does your heart want?
He won't find out.
We'd board a flight at 8 a.m.,
And come back by the 6 p.m. flight.
Just say that
You'll be late on Monday.
Has Rumi been enrolled?
-Why didn't you inform Asim.. ? He got the booking done.. Why?
Yes, Mehwish?
When does the flight leave?
9 a.m.
And when's the return?
6 p.m.
I mean, when would we land in Karachi?
Around 8 p.m.
Okay, thank you.
You're welcome.
Bye.
Finished?
Well done.
You didn't even ask about Rumi's admission.
Ah, yes, I was about to ask that.
Hasn't he been admitted?
He has been.
Alright, Rumi, show Maman your books.
Go... Very good.
I hope there was no problem.
There was,
But I didn't need to call anyone.
The principal was asking about you.
I said you couldn't get a leave.
Thank you.
Do you have a lot of work at the office?
I mean, you should've at least called to ask...
The principal
Was saying,
'Mothers are very emotional at such moments'.
I was checking my phone again and again
To tell the principal if you called,
'Here'.
'Look at how emotional she is'!
But I think you were busy...
Do you know
I've been made a secretary to the board of directors?
Wow...
You're progressing so rapidly!
So, will you be paid more, too?
I'll have more responsibilities.
Obviously...
I'll take charge from the old secretary tomorrow.
I may be late tomorrow.
How late?
I'll be back around 9 or 10.
It's okay... Let it be 9 or 10.
The tea's nice, isn't it?
Yes, very nice.
Maman, books.
Yes, just a minute.
It may even be 10 or 11, Danish.
So what?
Let 9 be 10,
Let 10 be 11.
I trust you, Mehwish.
Show your books to Maman.
Look into my eyes when you talk, Danish.
What is it?
You don't want to say what you're saying, innit?
Surely, I'm saying what you want to hear?
Know what, Mehwish,
I'm scared of you,
Or is it that you've frightened me?
I feel that stopping you is no good.
You won't stop now.
So, I allow you, thinking
That you're doing everything as I please.
It's okay.
I have no problem.
Just try to come back quickly.
Rumi and I will be waiting for you.
C'mon,
Have a look at Rumi's books.
I'll get
Some bread for breakfast.
Do you want anything else?
Get some butter and eggs.
We have enough.
He and I had finished all the bread.
Okay then,
Just get some bread.
And chocolates for me.
You just had one in the afternoon.
Please, Papa...
I'll get you a small one.
It'll do.
Come here.
Show me.
Wow...
My son will read so many books?
Yes.
Promise me that you will score very good marks.
I promise.
Good boy.
This one's very interesting...
Would you happen to have a matchstick, old chap?
Uh, yes, right here.
I haven't seen you smoking before.
I smoke one or two now and then, secretly.
Thanks.
Hello?
Sorry.
I was busy with my family.
I can understand.
Are you upset with me?
Not at all?
Why should I be upset?
I know
You've got a family,
A husband,
And a thousand issues with your husband.
It's okay. Fine.
I know you're not okay.
But I have a solution.
Solution?
I --
I'll be coming with you.
Are you sure?
I said it.
But please make sure that we
Land in Karachi by 9.
Of course, we'd land in Karachi by 9.
So --
Don't send a car in the morning; I'll book a cab.
I don't want that the driver should know that I went to the airport from home.
Oh, yes, but
-Don't worry, I'll be there.
Okay.
As you say.
When do I get there?
7.30 max.
Why 7.30?
You've never travelled by air, have you?
No.
You have to be there an hour before the flight leaves.
It'll be very difficult then...
Danish leaves at 8.
Just a minute...
He'll leave at 7.15 tomorrow.
Rumi's school starts at 8.
That's alright --
I'll be there at 7.30.
Thank God.
I'll disconnect.
Listen...
Yes?
You made my day.
Thank you.
Okay, bye...
Bye.
Looking beautiful.
You rapscallion!
Hello?
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Wake up call, sir.
What time is it?
It's 6.25, sir.
I'm getting up...
Danish!
Is Rumi ready yet?
Quickly, Danish, it's almost 7.
Leave 7 be.
Look at your son.
See how much this school uniform suits him!
My son is so sweet!
You're so sweet, too.
He's taken after you, hasn't he?
Alright,
Quickly, now...
Good boy.
Bag...
Listen.
May I call you if I miss you?
Why are you asking?
Call me.
And if I miss you a lot?
Call me again, then.
Get going already.
Just a moment...
Let's click a selfie.
-Selfie...
It's his first day of school.
We'll cherish the memory with this selfie. Come.
Move in.
There...
Hey!
Alright.
Bye, Rumi!
How does it feel?
Splendid!
It's my son's first day of school.
I'll give you a surprise gift.
Sure?
Yes.
But you'll have to promise me that you'll study hard. Ace everything.
I promise.
I can't believe it either.
I don't know
How I handled it...
Do you know how I feel?
What?
I'd see others in my teen years.
I never went on a date myself,
So, I never knew how delightful such dates could be.
Why one feels fear,
Why one is ecstatic...
How an eagerness to leave
Feels in an eagerness to meet...
Say something, will you?
I'm very worried.
Don't worry.
I'm right here by you.
We'd be back by 8, wouldn't we?
Of course we would be...
I take care of you more than you do yourself.
Isn't it so?
I know.
So, don't say now that you're worried.
I won't.
Promise?
I promise.
Tea or coffee, sir?
I'll have some coffee.
In a moment.
Tea or coffee?
Tea.
Coming right up.
What is it, M. Danish?
Nothing.
I just felt a tad suffocated...
I think the AC's not working.
The AC's working alright.
So, how did you figure out I'm a tad suffocated?
Was it something on my face?
No.
It's --
Just that you stopped for a while while working.
Does something worry you?
No.
Not at all.
Yes...
It's my son's first day of school.
He's a bit naughty.
That's why I was worried...
All the kids are naughty, M. Danish.
Have your coffee, it's getting cold.
Ah, right...
It's gotten cold.
When kids go to school,
One says, 'May the Lord be with them'.
I said that.
I'd even recited a few hymns.
Was he crying?
No.
He was very happy.
Then, how say you be happy too?
Yes...
Hey!
Yes?
Please warm this coffee.
Alright.
And
Would you happen to have a pill for headache?
Do you have a headache?
Not at the moment.
But I feel I may have one soon.
Take the pill from me.
But you won't take it before you have a headache.
Of course.
Who takes one before one has a headache?
I'll take charge from the old secretary tomorrow.
I may be late tomorrow.
How late?
I'll be back around 9 or 10.
It's okay... Let it be 9 or 10.
Look into my eyes when you talk, Danish.
What is it?
You don't want to say what you're saying, innit?
Surely, I'm saying what you want to hear?
Know what, Mehwish,
I'm scared of you,
Or is it that you've frightened me?
I feel that stopping you is no good.
You won't stop now.
Come.
Have your lunch.
No, please,
Have yours,
I've ordered something.
I know, we're
Not exactly friends...
But it doesn't take long to become friends.
I've known you for four years, but never known that you have a friend.
Let's be friends.
A friend
Is more like a father in times of sorrow.
Besides,
I'm much older than you are anyhow.
30 years ago, when I got married, I'd tell my wife that she was like a blessing.
She'd agree to everything I'd say.
In the beginning, I'd only tell the truth,
And
Later on, I started lying.
There's a very definite time
In a man's life when he starts lying.
This is the time when
Another woman starts giving him time.
Then, he begins to think that the one from 30 years ago
Was no blessing.
He'd just gotten her on the pretext of a marriage, as everyone gets one.
He fights with the first one for no reason, and is upset with her,
He's angry without cause,
And says with a melancholy voice before the second, 'I couldn't have an understanding with her'.
This performance of lying
Is so realistic that the man himself begins to believe he's telling the truth,
And the day he believes he's telling the truth is the day
His household is ruined.
I've made this mistake.
I've destroyed my household with my own hands.
That's why I've come to you.
I haven't heard about your sorrow,
But I've seen your performance,
And you're putting up a performance far better than I ever could.
I request you, mate,
Do not let your household fall to ruin,
For the stones of a ruined household rain down on the head of the one who's ruined it.
Have a nice day.
Listen, M. Matin,
There's no other woman in my life,
Nor am I putting up a performance of my sorrow.
I love my wife very much.
So much that I never felt the need for any friend.
I swear
I'm not like you.
C'mon.
Hey! Papa's come back before me!
Papa!
I'm hungry.
Hungry?
Come.
I'll cook you something.
C'mon, sweet little one.
Very good. Right here.
How could it have been cancelled?
Are you alright?
Okay, let's see.
Alright.
We're headed for the airport.
Okay.
Bye.
What is it?
We have to go.
What happened?
God...
What is it?
Could anyone have thought it'd suddenly rain, and like this!
Whether it rains like this or that, just tell me what's happened.
The flight's been cancelled.
What?
But we're going to the airport; we'd board any flight that's available.
Don't worry.
Just let this rain stop; we'll be in Karachi by 8.
Why are you afraid?
He'd kill me!
Who'd kill you?
I'm right here.
I won't let anyone touch you.
I'd break his hands.
Alright, now,
Get ready.
We're off to the airport.
This number is switched off. Please try again later.
Hello?
Hello.
Is this M. Shehwar's residence?
Yes.
May I talk to him? I'm a friend.
Uh, Monsieur's gone to Islamabad.
When?
He took the 9 a.m. flight.
When would he be back?
-Sir,
He'd be back tonight.
He'd be on his way right now.
His flight's been delayed because of the rain,
So it'll land at 10.30 now.
Who are you?
I'm a friend.
Alright.
Stop the bike.
Shall we talk here?
About what?
Would you beat me when we get back?
Why?
I went to Islamabad...
You'd gone there on a business trip, hadn't you?
Yes.
What's the problem then?
I hadn't told you.
My fault.
My words had scared you.
I'm a tad possessive, innit?
So, I say some things that I shouldn't really say.
Obviously, you'd be afraid...
One lies when one's afraid.
A wife does, 100%.
I'll apologise to you when we get back.
And please, have no fear.
Just let me know if you're going to Islamabad.
No problem.
Shall we get going?
Go.
I had thought that with you by my side,
What else could I ever wish for
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
What does it matter, if I don't have
Anything in this world;
I was under the misbelief
That I had you;
But, from you, I have learnt
That, even in love,
One could rather betray,
One could rather repulse.
Go; I'll follow with Rumi.
Rumi!
-I won't talk to you, you left me.
I'd gone to pick Maman up; I'm so sorry.
Do you know I was crying?
My dear son...
-Hearing him crying, I brought little Rumi down here.
Thank you so much.
No, sir,
There's no need to thank me.
Park my bike and keep the keys with you; I'll take them in the morning.
Thank you, Guard Uncle.
-God bless you.
Did you eat anything?
Didn't the maid cook anything?
She would've; I didn't take a look.
Alright, I'll get you some bread; you should have something.
No.
You're angry?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
It's okay, Mehwish.
A --
Foreign delegation had come.
When Shehwar asked me to come,
I thought it'd be a good experience for me.
Shall we sleep?
First, fix your mood.
What should I do? Laugh?
No...
Just smile in a way that feels like you're actually smiling.
Did you eat anything?
Yes,
On the flight.
You must've travelled business class.
Yes.
Mind if I ask something?
Not at all.
Didn't you think of how much I love you?
Oh, please leave that be.
When I said 'sorry', it means I made a mistake.
Tomorrow onwards, you're not going to the office.
I'll manage everything.
How?
I'll take bribes.
I'll get you hundreds of thousands of Rupees a month if you want,
But you won't go to the office.
Good morning, sir!
-'Morning.
Greetings, sir.
Greetings.
Tea or coffee?
Tea.
Alright.
Good morning, sir.
'Morning.
Listen!
Hasn't M. Danish come yet?
He called just now.
He's not coming today.
Why?
He's not well.
Mlle Uzma's not come either.
Did I ask you about Mlle Uzma?
Greetings.
-Greetings.
Over there.
Yes, sir?
Ask Mlle Mehwish to come to my room right now.
Mlle Mehwish hasn't come today, sir.
Why?
Did she ask for a leave?
No, sir, she didn't call with any such request.
Call and ask her.
Ask her, it's urgent.
Okay, sir.
Yes?
Sir, her phone's switched off.
Okay...
English translation: J. Mir