What are you looking at?
I wanted to tell you something.
Go on.
The parking fellow Khanam Khan,
Yes?
His son's been enrolled in a school too.
So?
Do you want me to get you enrolled where he is?
Have you seen his school?
It's a decrepit wreck.
So would I be attending a majestic school?
But of course.
My son will be attending such a majestic school that all my friends would look in awe.
When?
Let me see who it is.
Good morning.
Remember me?
I don't exactly recognise you,
But I've seen you somewhere in this building.
Monty.
Oh, Monty...
Danish was talking about you yesterday.
What did he say?
The car that you have.
He was talking about it.
He said that we might be buying it.
Right...
Did he also mention
What I'd said about you?
No,
He didn't mention anything else.
What did you say?
May I say it before you?
Yes, go on.
First, take these sweets from the oblation.
My Mum's specifically asked me
To give this to the family
Of the most comely lady downstairs.
But I disagree with her.
My eye
Will never find any more comely than you
In this building.
Interesting...
Please, pay a visit sometime.
Perhaps on the pretext of purchasing the car?
Sure.
Thank you for the oblation.
Welcome.
What is it?
There. Just have a little bit of it.
Alright?
Hello?
I'm coming over.
Sure, come.
I'm not coming over as in to sit with you.
We're going shopping.
Now?
When, if not now?
No, I meant --
Danish is not at home.
If we took Rumi along, he'd be pestering us all the way.
Don't worry, mate, we'll get him an ice cream and have him stay with the driver.
Get ready, now, I'm coming.
Hey!
It's the same one I'd mentioned, innit?
It's the same, sir.
You may check again.
Yes, it's the same.
Pack this one, then.
-Okay, sir.
Pack this one here.
Here.
Here's a bundle of 100,000 Rupees.
-Alright.
You now owe me 2,000 now.
-I'll give you in a moment.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Behave like a good boy --
-Bonjour, Madame!
Bonjour.
How are you, Rumi?
Come.
You'll be a good boy, won't you?
Bye, Rumi!
Say bye to him.
Hello!
How are you?
Hi!
Hi! How are you?
I'm fine!
Shall we?
Don't you have the keys to the door?
It's you, M. Monty!
I have the keys,
But...
How are you?
Madame's not at home.
She left with a friend of hers just a while ago.
In her car.
Anoushay.
It must be Anoushay, a friend of hers from college.
What it is is
I'm not usually back at this hour.
She must've left.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Here it is!
Won't you purchase the car?
Which one?
Yours?
No, it's old.
I'll buy a new one. 0 meter [unused].
The thing is,
I don't like something
That's been touched by someone else.
Good day.
Hello Papa!
Hello, Rumi.
Where's Maman?
Maman's gone shopping with Aunt Anoushay.
And where are you?
I'm in the play area, having an ice cream.
Right, who's with you?
Uncle Driver; do you want to talk to him?
-No.
Enjoy your ice cream,
And tell Maman when she's back to call me.
I'm home.
Alright.
-Love you.
Love you too.
How's this?
It's very good.
How much for this?
70,000.
Okay.
And this one?
How much for this?
This is expensive. 300,000.
So what if it's 300,000?
Pack that one.
It's so beautiful, right?
Pack this one.
-Okay.
Anoushay!
Just a minute.
Mind if I say something?
Could you lend me 80,000 Rupees?
I'll return it in 8 months.
I mean, 10,000 a month.
No problem,
But
The money I have is all Aamir's.
Alright, hold on, I'll ask him.
Please show me that necklace.
-Sure.
Hello?
Yes,
I've bought the gown.
The jewellery too. I'm with Mehwish, of course.
-It's a magnificent design, and a new one at that.
Alright,
I'm lending 80,000 to Mehwish.
A necklace caught her eye.
She says
She'll pay us back in 8 months.
Okay, thank you.
No, I have the money with me.
I'll buy my shoes and all.
Okay, bye.
He's agreed.
Thank you!
How's this?
Very lovely.
Please,
Take this off.
-Okay.
Three club sandwiches and three cups of tea.
Maman!
Here.
Take all of these.
And
Help yourself to something.
This --
Don't give him the ones with the jewellery.
Why?
Please give me this one --
Mine's the small, white one.
Right.
I've --
I've longed for months.
I want to keep it by my side every moment now that I've bought it at last.
Papa called to tell that he's home.
Oh...
It's 6 already,
And I haven't cooked anything.
Well,
He'll have an omelette.
Give me the phone.
That was all fine, but
As it happens...
Oh, hi!
Just a minute, I'll be back.
Oh my God, what a pleasant surprise!
I was just passing by; thought of having coffee.
How are you?
I'm fine.
This is my friend,
Mehwish.
Aamir's boss.
Hi.
And who's this cute little boy?
This is Mehwish's son, Rumi.
Mon Dieu! You're so beautiful, just like your Mum!
I can't believe it
That your friend is married.
Why do all the beauteous and comely girls get married so early?
Désolé, Madame, I hope you don't mind?
Why would she mind?
What kind of girl would mind being told she's very beautiful and comely?
And you've even said she doesn't look like she's married.
Alright, so
You'll be there at the wedding, won't you?
How could I not?
Aamir's not just my colleague; he's a friend too.
I'll attend the Mehendi and I'll be dancing too!
Dance?
I don't believe it.
Why? Why can't you believe it?
Not until I see it!
Once I start dancing,
I can best the best out there.
-Oh, right!
We'll see about that.
Alright.
I'll take my leave.
Bye.
Do you know he's a billionaire?
But he's not arrogant at all.
He's more like a family member to us.
He's seen
That sorrow doesn't even spare the rich.
What's his sorrow?
His wife.
They don't get together at all.
They used to have rows for the first 8 or 9 years of their marriage.
Then, his wife went to her parents in America.
Now, she stays in America for 10 months a year!
Sad...
She's a right insolent lass.
Good Lord, so suspicious!
If she were sitting here,
She'd have grabbed him by the collar.
Is she mad?
Of course she's mad.
If she saw Maria with him,
She'd have started screaming before everyone,
'Look at yourself, gadding about with your secretary'!
Hey!
She even slapped his previous secretary
Before everyone in the office.
Why?
What do I tell you?
Shehwar went to Hong Kong
And took her along.
She created such a ruckus the moment she found out.
Why did she go along in the first place?
They do go.
Secretaries to these toffs
Generally go along on foreign trips.
It's not a big deal.
She must've thought there's something going on between the two.
That's the problem.
But why is this a problem?
She should be happy
That her husband is so handsome,
Wealthy,
And
Still loyal to her.
He's loyal to her, isn't he?
How could he be loyal?
Which husband would chant utterances of loyalty if the wife spends 10 months in America?
Well,
He's managing his part.
How long will he?
She owns shares in all three companies of Shehwar's.
I think that's why he tolerates her.
Alright,
The sandwiches are here.
Keep the phone here.
Come on.
Won't you come upstairs?
No, mate, it's getting late.
Besides,
Danish would've grown old waiting for you.
Go.
Alright, God be with ye.
-Bye!
Come.
Here.
Sorry.
Go,
Go and change, quickly.
Why was your phone switched off?
The battery had died. C'mon now.
There was nothing to eat; I had an omelette.
Yes, I knew that.
You make such a fine omelette.
C'mon, mate.
Is an omelette anything like a lunch?
Get something to eat, will you? I'm tired, Danish.
Celebrating a wedding that isn't even yours.
What do you mean?
I'm being honest.
Look at who's getting married,
And you're shopping yourself to death.
Anoushay's my friend.
Dearer to me than my life.
Splendid.
Have you forgotten? Just yesterday, I was dearer to you than your life.
Yes.
I remember that too.
You'd do well to remember, too,
How you'd usurped upon my life.
All the grandiose dreams you had me imagine,
And then you immured me in this tiny flat after our marriage.
Don't worry, my love.
Our times will change.
Your promises won't change times, Danish.
Day after day will just go by.
What's up with you?
In the mood for a domestic?
Not at all.
Then why are you acting so rough?
It's --
I've borrowed 80,000 from Anoushay.
Why?
Wait and listen.
There's no hurry to pay her back.
We only owe her 10,000 a month.
We have 8 months.
But why?
You're feeling bad about it?
I --
This --
I've bought this necklace.
I thought
You'd not be able to arrange 80,000 so promptly.
My wish will remain unfulfilled.
So,
I mustered the courage to ask Anoushay...
I know what you're thinking.
It's struck you, hasn't it,
How you'd arrange 10,000 a month?
Don't worry.
For eight months, we'd even take Sundays as Mondays.
We'd not go anywhere.
Not even to a restaurant.
That saves 10,000, now, doesn't it?
You can't believe it, can you?
Still, believe it.
I'd -- Manage -- somehow.
And save the money too.
Why are you smiling at every line?
I'm smiling because of something else.
I'm laughing at the fact that you know about everything,
But there is one thing that you haven't the foggiest about,
Nor can you understand it.
What?
I love you very much, Mehwish.
There, now.
I wondered what it was that you'd say.
What more could I possibly say?
And what more could you possibly want to hear?
Just tell me,
Surely, you don't mind 10,000 a month, do you?
And if you say that you don't mind,
And that you're delighted to see the necklace,
I'd take it that you love me very much.
Only that I do mind, Mehwish.
I do not want that for eight months, my wife should sit before her friend with her head bowed.
Don't be crazy.
Why would I bow my head before my friend?
Not before your friend,
But before the lender.
And it's quite natural, Mehwish,
One's head bows and gaze lowers before the one whom one owes something.
Alright, I'll return the necklace.
When did I say that?
Keep the necklace,
And give her what you owe her.
How?
That's a total of 140,000.
Give Anoushay what you owe her,
And keep the rest with yourself.
Where did you get so much money?
It's a reward for besmearing Dad's grave.
That's all it ever was.
If you besmear a deceased Dad's memory for once,
He dies forever.
I tell you,
He'd haunt me neither in memories, nor dreams.
Please, turn of the light; I'm sleepy.
Where's Rumi?
He's sleeping. He said he won't have breakfast when I roused him.
Right...
You're vexed with me, aren't you?
No?
Why should I be vexed with you?
The same.
I purchased the necklace without asking you,
Borrowing money from Anoushay.
That's done and over already, mate.
Once you've returned the money, I wouldn't even remember
That you'd ever done something so witless.
Why are you calling it 'witless'?
I'd apologise for saying it's 'witless'.
There's no need for that.
I admit that I made a mistake,
But I'd never admit that to wish is witless.
Even if they remain unfulfilled,
Everyone has dreams,
Wishes; everyone tries to fulfil them, too.
That'd make all of them witless.
From this day on, hold firm to all your dreams,
Wish for everything you couldn't get,
For I'm right here.
I'll try everything I can.
The Mehendi's in the evening.
We're going at 7, remember?
Yes, I remember.
Just come back quickly.
I'll be back by 5.
Take the money.
Get something for yourself on the way back, too.
The money's for you, Mehwish.
Just get something you like.
I'll be chuffed to see you happy.
I love you.
I love you too.
Monsieur's waiting for you.
Come.
May I come in, sir?
Come in, M. Danish.
We've been waiting for you for 15 minutes.
15 minutes, sir?
I -- I'm just 5 minutes late.
Who said anything about you being late?
I'm talking about waiting for you.
Yes, sir.
Meet Messrs Fawad and Jawad here.
The names sound familiar, sir.
You've heard and seen the names.
There's a file titled Fawad & Jawad in your possession.
Yes, sir, there is one.
Should I get it, sir?
-It's here.
Look at this, it's right here.
But sir --
This file was in my cupboard.
And my cupboard --
Is locked --
-Oh?
So you've started differentiating your cupboard and keys from ours?
Please, take this file,
And sign wherever it's marked
With a red pencil circle.
Sir, may I get 10 minutes?
What for?
I'll study the file.
Monsieur,
Gone are your days of fussing over studying the file.
Open your eyes and sign the file,
Take your 100,000 Rupees from M. Fawad Ahmed, and close your eyes.
And yes,
The 200,000 Rupees that had been given to you yesterday were for the same.
Oh -- Alright...
Open an account under Madame's name,
And deposit all this money to that account,
Or spend it as soon as you go.
Why -- Is there any danger, sir?
There's always a danger,
But this money is exactly what's useful when you're in danger.
Listen!
Get me some tea, will you?
I will, sure, but before I go,
Do give me a sweetener.
Sweetener?
2%.
Adding the previous 200,000, that'd be 6,000.
Oh...
You take it from the boss too?
I take it on the orders of the boss.
Okay.
You'll get it.
I'll get you your tea.
Alright,
Danish is calling.
I'll disconnect.
Yes, I'll be there on time.
Oui, Monsieur!
I figure you've begun missing me the moment you got there.
What are you doing?
I was talking to Anoushay.
Did you tell her that you'd give her 80,000 today?
I did.
It must've baffled her.
She couldn't believe it.
When you return the money,
Say 'Thank you', and add,
That she may feel free to ask for 1 or 2 hundred thousand if she ever needs it.
Ask whom?
You, of course.
You're just saying that, right?
Why would I just say that?
I'm telling the truth.
Alright,
You know the bank nearby?
Yes.
Go there
And open your account there.
What for?
You're alright, aren't you?
I'm perfectly alright, Mehwish.
Just do
As I'm saying.
Okay.
-Okay, listen.
I love you.
Me too.
Papa said 'I love you', didn't he?
Let me tell you, you rapscallion! Overhearing everything! How would you like a good tickle?
Get aside.
It's my turn.
Right, how much will it be?
Alright.
How are you, M. Shehwar?
-How are you? I'm fine. Congratulations.
Thank you!
-All good?
Hello!
You're looking beautiful!
Thank you so much; you look very handsome yourself!
There, now, if it isn't your comely friend.
Hi!
Hello!
Congratulations!
-Thank you so much.
Hello, Mehwish!
Hi.
I'm sure he's your husband?
Yes.
Shehwar Ahmed.
Danish.
Hello! How are you? Everything alright?
Shall we?
C'mon.
Over here.
Quite the arrangement, I must say! Of course.
-We've tried the best we could.
But it's their marriage and our headache.
Right, yes...
Who's this man?
Aamir's boss.
We'd gone to a restaurant the other day after shopping.
We'd met back then.
Just 'by the way'.
But he still remembers your name.
Some people have a strong memory.
Every man has a strong memory when it comes to les belle femmes!
What does he do?
'Do', as in?
I mean, where does he work?
Looking at him, do you honestly think he'd work?
I just told you, he's Aamir's boss.
He owns three companies.
Anoushay told me he's a billionaire.
Splendid!
C'mon, now, it's your turn. You have to show us your dance.
Me?
You'd promised.
Alright, but...
Get me something to drink.
Oh --
Get up, then, we'd have to go over to that corner.
Let's go.
Come.
Do you know where he's going?
Where?
To have a bevvy.
Let him.
Would you look at who's going along as his bartender?
Don't look that way, Danish.
It's acceptable among these toffs.
It's acceptable with them,
But at least your friend should be ashamed.
Shut up, please.
You've brought 80,000, haven't you?
Yes.
When she's back after indulging him,
Give it to her.
I will.
What are you doing? Come on, already.
Wait.
What happened? Are you alright?
The thing is...
Then?
Tell me, first, who would dance with me?
I would, obviously.
You know, I'm really good.
Oui,
That's true...
He's looking your way.
Your friend...
Can I dance with her?
No, she's with her husband...
And he's really conservative.
Very bad...
Why do all these jolies filles have to get married?
I don't know.
Anyway,
Good luck to her.
Finish the drink already; how much more would you have?
Whatever's up!
Where's Anoushay's husband?
He's not come.
What do you mean?
He wouldn't attend his brother-in-law's Mehendi?
Yes, he wouldn't.
Why?
Because he's no longer her husband.
What?
They've been divorced?
Hush, Danish!
That's why she's gadding about with other men.
And Aamir!
He's such a dishonourable bloke,
Having his sister dance with his boss!
Quiet, please.
What if someone heard it?
Okay, okay...
Maman, PP.
Danish,
Rumi needs to go to the washroom.
Where's the washroom?
Ask around; how would I know?
Alright, I'll see.
Come on. Come.
Hello!
Hi.
May I have this dance?
I know your husband doesn't like it,
But I want to.
I'm sorry,
But I can't.
Trust me,
My intentions aren't bad.
It --
It wouldn't exactly please my husband.
Okay.
Listen.
Please
Don't mind it.
Don't say that.
One who goes through
Such a heartbreak would mind it.
English translation: J. Mir