May I have this dance?
I know your husband doesn't like it,
But I want to.
I'm sorry,
But I can't.
Trust me,
My intentions aren't bad.
It --
It wouldn't exactly please my husband.
Okay.
Listen.
Please
Don't mind it.
Don't say that.
One who goes through
Such a heartbreak would mind it.
What was he saying?
Nothing?
He asked, 'Where's your husband gone'?
And?
And what?
He just said, 'Why aren't you and your husband dancing'?
I said -- that you can't dance.
I can't dance?
Of course you can.
I just said it to get rid of him.
Get up.
Come.
Where?
It's time to dance.
No, Danish!
Everybody's dancing; let's join in! Come.
And you sit here.
Don't budge. Okay?
Rumi?
Don't worry.
Your husband's busy now.
When did you get married?
It's been 7 years.
What does your husband do?
He's --
He works at an office of the Government.
Was it a 'love marriage'?
Yes.
Why aren't you particularly happy, then?
It happens...
I used to feel the same way in the beginning too,
That I have everything now that I've got her.
But it only took me a year to realise
That I'd actually lost everything.
But I'm okay.
Perfectly fine.
That's just what I say
If someone asks me.
After all, one's got to maintain one's esteem.
They say
That matches are made in Heaven.
I don't believe it.
People do something stupid themselves,
And throw the blame on the Lord.
Excuse me.
Come.
Danish?
Let's go home, shall we?
Pick up your bag.
Come, Rumi.
Care to tell me what happened?
Don't ask anything until we're home.
Please.
Danish!
Mehwish!
Where are you off to?
The thing is, I'm not feeling well.
We'll be there at the wedding tomorrow.
Let's get going.
Ah, right.
Take out the money.
Here's your 80,000.
I got late and she had to borrow it from you
To buy the necklace.
But thank you so much.
C'mon.
See you at the wedding tomorrow.
Bye.
Come.
Just there.
Alright, go to bed.
I'm hungry, Maman.
Ask your Papa to cook an omelette.
Wait, Mehwish.
You're being furious at me
Over what you should be ashamed at?
What have I done that's shameless?
Stop it, Mehwish.
You know what you've done.
You were doing the same.
Weren't you dancing with your arms around Anoushay's waist?
Anoushay is like a sister to me.
As if he's my boyfriend!
-Stop it, Mehwish!
Shut up!
I know you must've done it to show your jovialty.
But --
It was a mistake, wasn't it?
Would it not infuriate me?
It's very natural.
Would the agony of it not kill me
If someone put his arms around my wife's waist?
These --
These hands,
These arms --
This waist -- all of it is mine.
I know I'm possessive.
Very possessive.
But does this love mean anything without possessiveness?
-Whatever!
You shouldn't have come back.
That's what I thought best at the moment.
I felt as it --
I'd brought you --
To a lair of wolves!
I'm sorry, Mehwish.
I wasn't exactly fair on Anoushay,
But the truth is that it hasn't been fair on me either.
I'd -- gone there to enjoy, but have come back afraid.
I'm the one who's afraid, Danish.
And it pains me that I'm afraid of you!
This is so unfair.
Instead of being ashamed at your mistake, you're saying --
That you're afraid of me?
-Danish, please leave me alone.
Let me take a moment to understand what has just happened!
I feel like I've had a nightmare.
I've had a nightmare, too.
I'm scared too, Mehwish.
For the first time, I felt that you
Aren't so strong.
Amidst jovialty, you forget a woman's dignity.
Pause and think for once.
Whoever, in love, thinks about what others would say?
You should just think about
What I'd say.
I'm going to the market.
I'll get something to eat.
And I'm sorry for shouting at you angrily.
Was it a 'love marriage'?
Why aren't you particularly happy, then?
It happens...
I used to feel the same way in the beginning too,
That I have everything now that I've got her.
But it only took me a year to realise
That I'd actually lost everything.
They say
That matches are made in Heaven.
I don't believe it.
People do something stupid themselves,
And throw the blame on the Lord.
I'm sorry -- I --
It's you!
I was just thinking of you!
I mean, yes.
I just met you a short while ago.
Why did you leave?
I'm not feeling well...
I can see that.
Come, I'll get you --
-No. Thank you.
Thank you.
Please, don't trouble yourself. I don't think you're alright.
What makes you think that?
What's wrong with me?
I'm alright.
Perfectly alright.
Please, get going.
What are you looking at like that?
Please, go.
Okay.
I'll get going.
Alright.
Now, finish this milk too.
What happened to you?
I'm not --
Feeling well.
Get me in bed, please, I'm very sleepy.
Finish all of this, alright?
What happened?
People have a lot in this world.
Mansions,
Luxury cars...
They'd hire whoever they want to,
And buy whatever they want to.
But I don't care about any of it.
Bless them all with whatever they have,
But I know I have the most precious thing in the world.
The most beautiful,
The most invaluable...
Ask what I have.
What do you have?
I have you, Mehwish.
I have you.
What happened to you last night?
Last night?
What had happened?
Ah,
The thing about the dance.
Leave it be.
Forget it.
You'd forget it too, right?
I've already forgotten.
Do you think I'd remember?
Do you remember where you'd gone after we returned from the Mehendi?
The three of us?
Not the three of us.
Just you.
Nowhere?
I retired right after coming back, Mehwish.
Don't you remember how sleepy I was?
You're testing me!
We used to play such tricks in our younger days.
This isn't a trick, Danish.
You'd gone to the market to get something to eat last night,
Because we'd come back from the Mehendi without eating anything.
So I'd actually gone to the market.
I thought we'd had nothing last night.
Tell me, what did I get from the market?
Nothing.
You came back empty-handed.
In fact, you came back panting
As if the sight of someone had frightened you.
Oh...
So it wasn't a dream after all!
Dream?
No, I remember now.
I'd gone to get something to eat...
What happend next?
Right...
I was just about to get there when a car bumped into me.
No, it didn't bump into me.
I felt it'd bumped into me, and I'd fallen down.
That's why --
I was frightened.
And you know what,
I ran away sharpish as if he'd eat me alive!
Who?
The driver.
He came over
To pick a fight with me.
But I didn't pick a fight with him.
So it wasn't a dream after all...
Rumi --
Must've fallen asleep hungry.
No,
I gave him some milk.
Good.
So I'd actually gone to the market...
So it wasn't a dream after all...
What are you cooking today?
Whatever you say.
Biryani, qorma and all?
No?
Alright, cook whatever you want to.
When would Rumi get up?
We'd better rouse him.
At least he should have breakfast.
Rumi!
What's up?
Looking at you.
Now you'd look at me in photographs?
You're never angry in photographs,
Nor vexed,
Nor talking roughly.
You're always smiling.
Honestly,
Why are you so insecure?
What's this you're saying?
Why do you think that if someone grabbed my hand, he'd take me along?
No way, God forgive!
How could I think of that?
Then why are you so piqued?
If you think I made a mistake last night,
Alright, I'd say sorry.
You should forget about it too.
It's okay.
Going to the office?
Yes.
Come back early.
Why?
Why should I come early?
We have to leave at 8.
Do you know how long it takes to get ready?
Where are we going?
To the wedding, of course!
Ah, right...
I'd forgotten it entirely.
You're splendid.
Alright, tell me,
Should I wear the black sari tonight?
No.
Don't wear a sari with a half blouse.
It doesn't look nice.
Wait, Danish.
You'd bought that sari for me.
But you'd had the blouse made, hadn't you?
It exposes 8 inches of your waist.
Look at what you're saying!
I'm right in saying so, Mehwish.
It doesn't look nice that the men should cover themselves and the women bare half their waists.
It'd embarrass me if people would turn to stare at you.
And, on top of that,
He'd be there too.
He'd think you're wearing it for him.
What's this nonsense, Danish?
You know t --
-Please.
Don't be angry over it, Mehwish.
Women who bare their waists, or roam around wearing sleeveless clothes
Are like a bait thrown to ravenous men.
I'm not insecure,
But I don't want that my wife should appear before a billionaire like a bait.
You're mad.
Raving mad.
How are you, Danish?
Honestly, mate,
This banger of a bike
Doesn't quite suit the sweet Madame.
Why are you talking about 'Madame'?
Does she drive it?
You don't quite get it.
I mean --
She must ride it sometimes.
A bike like this
Doesn't suit her.
A car like yours doesn't suit her either.
Even if I had the money,
I'd not buy your car.
You may sell it to someone else.
Goodbye.
Yes.
He's been 'round the twist since last night.
He went to get something to eat,
But came back without getting anything.
He was panting when he came.
And in the morning, he didn't even remember that he'd gone to get something to eat last night.
What happened to him?
It's just
That your Monsieur Shehwar
Has gotten into his heart like a dagger.
You're laughing?
He's gotten on my wick here!
Know what,
He's stopped me from wearing the black sari.
Why?
He says, 'If you wore a sari with a half blouse, people would see your bare waist'.
Hey!
What do I do now?
One can't even get a full blouse stitched so quickly.
Do you remember when I'd first met him?
I'd told you back then,
'Your husband is very conservative, mate'.
But he doesn't agree that he's conservative.
Or perhaps he just loves me so much...
So, he's a tad possessive.
That's it with these men.
They become 'possessive' to enslave girls.
Alright, whatever.
Do you know how much your thing upset M. Shehwar?
Why?
He was cursing himself.
He said,
'All of this happened because of me'.
He said to me,
'I just wanted to dance with a beautiful lady',
'Nothing more than that'.
'But'
'Apparently, it offended her husband'.
What did you say?
What could I say?
Just comforted him with lies.
'It's nothing like that'.
Will he be there at the wedding?
Of course, mate.
Mind if I request something, then?
Not at all.
Ask him to stay at an arm's length from me.
Why are you saying that?
Do you know what he'd think?
You don't know what he'd think!
In fact, in his madness, he may even ruffle his feathers!
Hey!
Alright, I'll disconnect.
I'll ask the tailor if I could get a new blouse before the evening.
Bye.
Okay, bye.
May I come in, sir?
Please, come in.
May take a seat, sir?
Please.
Monsieur, it's better if you don't ask about such trifles.
Thank you, sir.
Pray tell.
S -- Sir, I wanted to talk to you about something personal.
Please, go on.
What is it?
I'd want to...
Buy a car.
One of those -- luxury cars.
I mean, it's just something I'd wished for for long...
And I'd promised my wife when I got married
That I would
Get her a luxury car one day.
Is it not possible, sir?
Monsieur,
What isn't possible
In what you've ventured into now?
Just tell Madame
To wait two months.
Two months?
Alright, make that one month.
But you won't get a luxury car in one month.
Anyhow,
You shouldn't be owning a luxury car before you're promoted.
Why, sir?
Someone may file a complaint,
And it may start an inquiry.
One's always got
So many enemies right under one's nose!
Th -- That's right, sir.
If you buy a small car for now,
Madame would begin to trust you.
She'd get confident that her husband's got the touch.
He'd buy a luxury car one day, too.
Of course, sir.
But never fear.
Why would I fear?
There's also raids in this trade.
Sometimes, you slip by,
And sometimes, you get caught.
But as I told you, you need not fear.
You just
Have to be a bit practical.
Pra -- ctical -- how?
Put aside 20% of whatever you earn.
Think as if you never earned it in the first place.
Why, sir?
To get acquitted honourably.
Before I came to the office,
I'd been to the court for my hearing.
Ah, right, sir...
What happened to your case?
I've been acquitted honourably.
Congratulations, sir!
Thank you.
This TV...
Hello?
I'm not wearing the black sari.
Alright.
Aren't you happy?
I am.
Should I wear the suit I wore to Meryem's wedding?
An old one?
It isn't too old.
More importantly, Anoushay's never seen it.
I'll tell her it's a new one.
No.
No, as in?
Why would you wear an old suit?
Go to the market and buy a new one.
I don't have so much money.
I'd deposited some money when I opened an account yesterday.
They can't be withdrawn.
The money's no problem.
The inner pocket
Of my blue coat has the key to my cupboard.
There's some 3,500 in it.
Take all of it.
And forgive me if my words have ever hurt you.
Forgive me, too.
Silly lass!
Yes, did you find it?
Talk about what I've found besides the money.
What?
My necklace.
Why did you take it out of my cupboard and keep it in yours?
Where'd you get the key?
This isn't the necklace you'd bought.
Then?
It's the necklace I'd bought.
When did you buy it?
And why didn't you tell me?
How could I tell you?
I thought I'd surprise you.
I'd even come home early.
But you were away all day.
And when you did come back,
You shoved your surprise in my face.
Oh God...
I'm so sorry, Danish.
It's okay.
Tell me, you have the money, don't you?
Yes.
Go to the market, now.
I'll be back by 5.
Okay, bye.
Okay,
Bye.
Listen.
I love you.
C'mon!
Greetings, Madame!
Greetings. How are you?
Never been better!
Are you going somewhere?
Yes, to the market.
I don't think I saw a rickshaw in the parking.
I'll hire one outside.
Very bad.
Madame would hire a rickshaw when her brother-in-law has a car?
You're embarrassing me.
No, it's nothing like that.
If it's not, get in my car,
And command me, 'Monty',
'Drop me at the market'.
Oh -- No, it --
-No excuses, please.
Your brother-in-law insists.
Alright,
C'mon, my brother.
Now you're suckin' diesel.
C'mon, Rumi!
Come.
Don't you have a younger sister?
I do.
She must be just like you.
Not at all.
She's far prettier than I am.
I can't believe that.
She may be just like you,
But not prettier than you.
But why are you asking about my sister?
Mum
Thinks I should get married.
I've said it plainly
That I would only if I found someone like you.
Hey!
I know
Yours and Danish's was a 'love marriage', wasn't it?
He didn't tell me.
I just guessed.
How?
You may feel bad about it if I told you.
No way.
I wouldn't.
Please, go on.
The thing is,
I can tell from my experience.
A beautiful girl
Errs
Either in the name of 'love marriage',
Or is forced by circumstances.
What do you mean?
I think -- It's a bit of a mismatch --
I mean,
Look at yourself,
And look at Danish.
Did it hurt you?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
No, it's okay...
You didn't even tell where you'd like to go.
Right --
I thought I'd told you...
I'd like to go to the Forum.
By the way, you're just bothering yourself for no reason...
It's nothing, really.
Honestly, it bothers me when you ride a rickshaw.
The thing is,
A rickshaw isn't your type of ride.
You should ride a Mercedes.
I'm selling this car, too.
I'm thinking I'd buy a Mercedes.
What do you do?
Whoever asks about work these days?
They ask, 'How much do you earn'?
Alright,
I'll ask that.
How much do you earn?
Just around
8 to 9 hundred thousand.
8 to 9 hundred thousand a month?
Yes.
Wow...
I'd even told Danish
To buy this car from me.
It's only been owned once.
Then?
He said, 'I don't have the money'.
I'd even said, 'If you don't have it right now, you can pay me in parts',
And then?
He said, 'No'.
'I can't afford a car'.
Please don't mind it,
But we're friends and he even talks about such personal matters.
What other personal matters
Does he talk about?
Just --
The usual...
About Rumi,
And you,
Or if the two of you ever have a row...
Although -- He generally conceals the thing about the rows.
Surely, I'm not saying too much?
No.
Not at all.
Promise me, then, that you won't tell Danish.
I won't tell.
Is it him?
Don't tell him that you're in the car with me.
Hello?
Hired a rickshaw?
No.
I'm in the car.
Anoushay's there?
Not Anoushay.
Monty.
He was insisting,
'I'm your brother-in-law; I'd drop you off'.
Who told you that sly devil's my f -- friend?
The blighter's an ace rogue!
And you got in the car with him without even thinking?
Get off the car! Get off!
I'll have him drop me at the Forum.
We'll talk about it when you're home.
Listen to what I'm saying, Mehwish.
Ask the bugger to stop the car!
Hello?
Tell the boss it's an emergency; I have to go.
-Alright.
How are you, Danish, mate?
How are you, eh, bugger?
How are you?
-Danish!
Danish! What's the matter?
-How are you, eh?
How dare you take my wife along for a ride?
-Da -- Danish! Mate --
As if I shoved her in! She came to me!
Danish, wait. I'll tell you!
Stay back! I'll tell you --
You can't control your bonny wife!
I didn't force her! Ask her when she gets back why she got in with me!
And I didn't take her along with any bad intentions! I see her as my sister-in-law!
Stop, Danish!
The poor man's right.
Maybe it's true that your wife asked him to drop her.
One doesn't take someone along by force like that.
There's nothing to worry about.
She willingly got in with him.
It happens among neighbours, M. Danish,
One sometimes thumbs a lift; one sometimes gives a lift...
It's just the usual.
English translation: J. Mir