M. Munir's given me.
Who's M. Munir?
He's a known contractor.
He said he's hiring me
For a new job.
This is the signing amount.
A million...
So we'd be riding our car tomorrow.
-He was lying, Mehwish.
This is a bribe.
In return for this, I have to write 'Okay' and sign every right and wrong he does.
Just do it! What's it to your father?
It's everything to my father, Mehwish.
Dad would think I've smirched his grave.
Dad's dead, Danish; he won't feel a thing if you smirch or bomb his grave.
-Watch what you're saying!
Alright, why have you brought the money, then?
Do you want to show it off or tempt me?
I'd brought this to check my integrity.
M. Munir thinks
My intentions would change
If only I kept this money with me for two days.
But I'm afraid, Mehwish,
If I kept so much money at home,
How would I sleep?
-Alright, then.
Stay awake.
Listen, will you? Why --
Why are you so furious?
You're not returning this money, Danish.
Thank the Lord if He's been merciful on us.
Keep this in the cupboard and go to sleep.
And take a bribe?
-It's not a bribe, Danish!
It's a reward for your hard work and integrity.
How hard you work,
Running around on that old bike of yours,
Only to hear a load of guff from one like Monty!
Do you remember that your bike didn't even start the other day?
Rumi's four now and he hasn't started school yet.
If we save something for his admission,
It gets spent quickly for one reason or another.
You have just 3 or 4 pairs of trousers,
And some 4 or 6 shirts.
I'm thinking of what you'd wear when we'd go to dinner tomorrow.
Show it to me for once.
What?
The one million.
Here.
I can't believe it, Danish...
I can't believe it either, Mehwish.
My head's spinning around...
Why don't you take a nap?
Relax, Danish.
No, I'm --
I'm not sleepy.
You're still struggling over Dad, aren't you?
-No.
I'm trying to forget Dad.
Dad's dead.
So,
It's over now, innit?
May he be happy wherever he is.
One can't run a household on this trifle of a salary.
I'll wash my face and hands.
Dad hasn't the foggiest that petrol now costs 110 Rupees a litre;
Rumi's fees add up to 10,000;
And
A picnic on Sunday drains out every penny one's saved.
When buying a burger, I ask,
'Which one's the cheapest'?
If he showed up in my dream, I'd say to him,
'If one can't even fulfil such piffling dreams, it feels as if one's been kicked from behind',
'Which is why I'm sorry, Dad'...
Rumi's sleeping now.
Do you feel like sleeping?
Not at all.
Are you thinking about something?
Yes...
Don't think anything about the money.
No, I'm
Just thinking about this cupboard.
Look at this.
It isn't really strong.
It'd break the moment one would hit it.
Who'd hit it?
A thief.
Right...
So you're worrying about a thief now.
One does worry.
Did you check the door?
Which door?
The door to our house, of course!
I've checked it carefully and locked it.
Good.
What'd you wear tomorrow?
Why have you gotten up?
Let's sit and talk.
I'm not sleepy.
Won't you go to the office?
Why not?
And how would you get up on time if you stay awake?
I won't stay awake that late.
I've been trying to get to believe ever since
That the million is mine.
I can't believe it,
Which is why I can't sleep either.
Believe it, Danish.
This million's all yours.
It's the signing amount for your job,
And nobody can take this money away from you.
So, what would you be wearing tomorrow?
Dark blue pants with a light blue shirt.
But you wore the same
To Anoushay's brother's wedding.
Yes, and I wore a coat over it then.
I won't, this time.
-No way.
You'd go and buy clothes for yourself tomorrow.
What's the problem now, Danish?
It won't make any difference even if you spend 30 to 40 thousand.
Alright...
There, now! The delight of getting the money had me forget my blouse entirely!
Get it on your way back from the office tomorrow.
I will.
Are you feeling sleepy?
It seems so.
Won't you buy a car?
That's what I'm thinking.
Why don't you talk to Monty?
Why Monty?
He can give you on credit if you don't have the money.
Didn't he say so?
I'd rather not see his face again.
Don't you remember how we had a fist fight?
That was your mistake.
You created such a scene over a trifle.
You didn't even think that my name would come up in such a quarrel!
Yes, I didn't think of that...
He said I'm like his sister-in-law...
So, I got in the car with him.
He was behaving so decently it didn't even feel like he was an outsider.
He wouldn't have retired yet.
Go and meet him,
Talk to him.
See if he was telling the truth,
Or just making things up.
Right now?
Yes.
Look at the time.
It's 12.
So what if it's 12?
Go and check,
He'd be awake.
Come with me.
What would I do there?
Who's asking you to go there?
Just come up to the door,
And when I've gone out, close the door properly.
Sure.
Don't go to sleep.
What are you saying, Danish; would I feel like sleeping like this?
Also,
If I knock,
Ask who it is.
I will. Now, go quickly and tell me he's agreed to it.
Lock the door from inside.
Where to?
How's your car?
Get to the point.
I am at the point.
Get this key out of your finger and put it in mine.
Why?
Does your Dad own it?
I mean
Sell your car.
And who'd buy it?
I would.
You would?
You can't believe it, can you?
Tell me how much for the car.
1.2 million.
Take 9 in cash,
And the remaining 300,000 a month later.
9, as in,
900,000 Rupees?
I'm talking about 900,000 too.
That's great...
You've run into 900,000 in one shot.
Where from, Monsieur?
What's it to you?
Look, Danish,
Don't surprise me like that.
Be honest and say you're kidding.
Or tell me if Madame's started working.
Don't even mention her name, you blighter!
-When did I name her?
I was just mentioning her.
Move away, now.
Away, as in?
I'm not buying the car from you.
-I'm not selling it to you.
But if Madame's sent you,
Please, buy it.
Even if for 3 now,
And 9 a month later.
If you so much as mentioned her name,
I'd bury you alive right here!
-Get off!
Who is it?
-It's me.
Didn't he agree?
I didn't agree. The bugger was up to a load of guff.
He said, 'Wherever did you get so much money'?
'Has Madame started working'?
He must be angry at getting beaten.
You'd given him a right beating too.
I gave him a beating?
Would you look at what you're saying!
The bruise on my cheek.
Do you know,
The bugger had punched me right here.
There, now!
You've forgotten to lock the door.
What is it?
-You...
Were a tad angry last night,
So, what it is --
-What is it?
Hey! Won't you be buying the car?
Begone!
Get lost!
'Begone'?
I told you, I'm not buying it from you.
Madame, are you listening?
I told you not to mention her!
I'll complain about you when I meet her.
I'll tell her this deal didn't go forward because of you.
-Get going.
Who was it?
It was an alarm, not a call.
So you'd set an alarm for 8.30?
Yes.
You normally set one for 7.
And see, now,
I'm late for the office.
It was necessary that you be late today.
It's not like the world has ended.
But why was it necessary that I be late?
Banks open at 9 a.m., right?
So they do. So?
What's with the bank?
-Hey!
Would you leave the money at home?
Deposit it in your account.
Ah, right...
Yes, sir?
Where are you, Monsieur?
It's 9.15 already,
And you're not at the office yet.
Sorry, sir,
But I made a mistake when setting the alarm today,
So I've gotten up a bit late.
I'll be there in half an hour, sir.
Take an hour
If you will,
But sign M. Munir's file the moment you get here.
Which file, sir?
Just sign whichever file
The peon gives you.
Full stop.
Sorry sir, but what is that file about?
You know the Ghalib Circle Road, my good man?
It's a completion certificate for it.
But I'm standing on the same road, sir.
Should I have the file sent there?
-No, sir.
I'm saying that the road hasn't been built at all.
There's a pit right here by my feet.
The work hasn't even started.
What are you saying, M. Danish?
What would've happened had the road been built?
What would have happened?
-It would've gotten damaged again, M. Danish!
M. Munir's said he'd actually have the road built
If he got the contract the next time.
Sir?
You'd be here by 10, wouldn't you?
Yes, sir.
-Alright.
I'm in my office until 10.
I have to attend a meeting after that.
Right, sir.
Okay.
The thing is,
Rumi starts playing games on the phone once he's up.
He might've disconnected...
When did you call?
I think at 8.30.
M. Danish leaves by 7.45, doesn't he?
Yes, but he left at 9 today.
He -- got up a bit late today.
Oh!
So what do you do at home?
I mean,
I wonder what you must do!
Nothing really... Attending to Rumi, household chores...
So haven't you hired a maid for Rumi?
And you do the chores yourself?
I won't now; I'm thinking of hiring a maid.
M. Danish must've been angry to hear about it.
About what?
That I call and talk to you.
But I request you
To not ask me to not call you
Even if he gets angry over it.
I swear, my intentions aren't bad.
Your voice is sweet,
And face lovely...
So I delight myself for a few moments
By hearing your voice,
Or seeing your face...
Just think as if I forget for a few moments everything that had happened to me...
What'd happened to you?
There!
It fell from your mouth, didn't it?
But I'm sorry, I don't like sympathies.
Please, tell me what had happened.
We'll be meeting at 9 p.m. tonight.
I won't sign
This completion certificate, sir.
And
I'll manage with this job, too.
Come here.
Keep this money in the cupboard.
May I leave now, sir?
Okay.
And
I'm really proud of you.
Thank you, sir.
Come here, Rumi!
Come here, now!
Watch your cartoons!
C'mon, put on this shirt.
Pay attention here!
Alright, sit here.
Hello?
I often wish that I hear your 'hello',
And disconnect the call.
Why?
That's enough for me,
Or perhaps I don't deserve any more.
May I ask you something?
Yes?
Does he know, too, that you're so lovely,
Or does he just think of you as a wife he's got?
No, he knows, too.
He says I'm -- very lovely.
Alright,
You were telling me something and stopped...
And disconnected the call, too.
Please, go on,
What had happened to you?
I'll tell you at dinner.
No, tell me over the phone.
Danish would be there at dinner, too.
Who knows how he may feel about it?
He won't be anywhere nearby then.
You'd be wrong to think that.
He won't leave me alone with you.
Leave that to me.
I think he's here.
Please,
Don't hire a taxi,
I'll send a car over at 8.30.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Hey!
You're back so early!
It's nothing, really.
I felt as if everyone in the office was staring at me.
Here's your blouse.
Won't you give Papa a hug?
Papa, I'm busy at the moment, I'll give you a hug later.
How would we get there?
We'll hire a cab, of course.
But what would I wear?
Didn't you get anything for yourself?
You're splendid, Danish.
I'd told you to spend some 30 - 40 thousand on yourself as you left.
I'd have spent some 30 - 40 thousand if I had so much money.
What do you mean?
I returned the 1 million, Mehwish.
What?
L -- Listen to me.
In exchange for it, he asked for the completion certificate of a road that's not been built so far!
If I worked for him,
Who knows how many such certificates I'd have had to sign!
Look,
I won't do that, Mehwish.
I can't do that.
I'll eat little,
Starve myself,
But never live off the flesh of others.
Whatever is it that I lack?
I get a salary to make do with,
I have a nice little flat,
I have such a sweet son,
My world is as I wished it to be; You're there.
And it's enough for me that you're there.
I've ironed your black trousers and shirt.
It's very old...
No,
It's fine --
It isn't that old...
He's taken a proper beating!
-I've not taken a beating, mate.
She's just a tad angry with me.
I'm not talking about you. My horse has taken a proper beating.
Oh...
Where's flat number 308, my dear fellow?
M. Danish's?
-Yes.
Climb up the stairs here.
M. Danish lives on the third floor.
Thank you.
So, how do I look?
It's 8.30 and the cab's not here yet...
There he is!
Your car's here, sir.
Right...
We'll be there in two minutes.
-Okay, sir.
You look right bonny, mate.
Not bonny; batty -- Maman looks right batty!
Hey!
Who taught you that one?
Hold on, mate, I taught him this one.
Seeing you at the wedding the other day, it slipped from my mouth.
Is the car here?
Yes. C'mon.
C'mon, Rumi. Here.
-Come.
Are you angry with me?
I'm not angry.
Turn off the lights.
Come, Rumi.
I knew it wasn't a cab the moment I saw
Such a big car.
Danish,
Quiet.
Hey!
What about the cab driver?
He'd keep looking for us.
Danish, please...
Oh...
I forgot my purse in the pocket of the trousers I wore to the office.
-So?
Won't there be any problem?
We could've brought flowers for him.
What'd he do with our flowers?
I think it's okay.
There!
What does one do with flowers?
One just brings along some as a formality.
You have some money with you, right?
Yes?
Then, what's the problem?
Please, stop over at a bouquet shop around here.
I mean, a flower shop.
Yes, I understand.
Wow...
It seems you've earned a BA too.
-I have.
Hello, M. Danish!
You've honoured me with your presence.
Hi, Mme Danish,
You're looking gorgeous.
Flowers for you.
-Oh!
Thank you!
And M. Rumi,
You look the sweetest of them all!
How are you?
I'm fine.
Come. Please, come.
Please, sit.
I hope the driver got there on time?
Yes, he did.
So,
What'd you like to have?
Whiskey, or something else?
No,
I -- I don't drink.
I knew it.
Some people's days of drinking begin a bit late.
Where's your wife?
It's not necessary that every man be with his wife.
I have everything, so to speak,
But I don't have my wife with me.
So you've not gotten married yet?
When did I say that?
I did get married.
Oh -- so, you had a break-up?
I'm sorry, but
What would you call a 'break-up'?
I think I asked the wrong question, I'm sor --
-No.
You didn't ask the wrong question.
You asked just what was right.
You just don't know what a 'break-up' is.
To not get bound in ties,
Or for ties to sever is no break-up.
The break-up of hearts that never get to meet
Is actually the real 'break-up'.
People drag on together,
But they're never together.
Let's talk about something else, shall we?
Really, I --
I'm such a fool.
I was about to drown
This beautiful night in my sorrow.
But do you know, I believe
That if someone leaves you after two steps together,
You should thank that person.
That poor soul actually saves you from a long and arduous journey.
So, whenever I talk to my wife,
I say 'thank you' to her.
'Thank you, Maham',
'Thank you so much'.
I love to have pet dogs,
But I despise their barking.
Was yours a love marriage?
Yes.
Hey, M. Rumi!
Surely, you aren't bored?
M. Diwan!
Take M. Rumi along; have him ride the swing in the lawn,
And show him his favourite movie in the theatre room.
There's a theatre here, too?
Yes.
You'd feel as if you're sitting in a cinema!
Papa, may I go?
Sure, go.
Get going, mate!
So, where did you first meet?
At the wedding?
No...
Where did the two of you first meet?
-Oh!
We studied together at the university.
Oh.
Who said 'I love you' first?
-I did.
As usual...
And
When did you get the reply from her?
15 minutes later?
15 minutes later!
It's a tad long, innit?
When did you get married?
A year later.
Wow.
That's rather quick.
I must say you're both very lucky.
I'm the luckier one, M. Shehwar,
She's completed me.
I thought, 'I don't need anything else'
'When I've got her'.
Please don't mind it,
For I'll only speak the truth -
Whoever would've gotten her
Would've said the same.
'I don't need anything else'.
May I see your theatre room too?
Yeah, sure.
Why not? Come, I'll show you.
Come, Mme Danish.
Goodness, mate!
M. Danish,
Please allow me to
To drop her outside my theatre room.
-Yes, sure.
Of course...
Come.
Just a minute.
Right,
So what did I say?
Yes...
I'd said,
'Please don't mind, M. Danish',
'But honestly, whoever would've gotten her'
'Would've said the same -'
'"I don't need anything else".'
Tell me,
Did I lie?
I don't know.
Well, then,
Alright.
Fine.
Call your husband,
And ask him to take everything that I have,
And give me his Mehwish.
Dad used to say,
'You serve one good food'
'To win one's heart'.
So, tell me, M. Danish,
Have I been able to win your heart?
Do you usually talk so little,
Or am I speaking too much?
I'm listening.
I'm looking at the confidence in a man's tone
When he's successful.
You've been successful, Monsieur.
That's what I think.
To get whatever you want
Is not to be successful.
To get the one you like
Is success like no other.
Hey!
Serve some soup to the good man.
Try some of this soup.
Hey!
-Papa!
What's this?
Couldn't you pour it carefully?
M. Diwan!
Danish,
You're alright, aren't you?
Please, take him to my room,
And give him a shirt from my wardrobe.
And stay with him.
He might need something.
Please, don't come downstairs.
You --
Just got worried so suddenly.
He'll be fine.
It'll take just about 15 minutes for him to be back.
Please, sit.
Sit.
He'd ask me why I didn't go with him.
Just tell him, then,
'I would rather not go into another man's bedroom'.
Everything happens as you wish.
I wish that he not come down all night,
But this won't happen.
How many years has it been since your marriage?
8 years.
-Oh.
That's enough.
What do you mean, 'enough'?
It's enough
For a comely girl like you to give a pleb
8 long years of her life.
You're feeling bad about it?
Yes.
What do you like?
To live in pieces?
To live, entrapped by a man
Who's caught you like a hunter?
He loves me so much.
-Tell me, also, if he deserves your love.
Or if he deserves you.
Look, M. Shehwar,
I like to talk to you,
But I'm sorry, I don't want to talk about these things.
Okay, sorry.
I'll not say it again.
Where's your wife?
Who knows where she'd be!
Perhaps in New York, perhaps in Toronto...
She'd be somewhere.
She tells me when she calls.
What do you talk about?
About the business, about the profit...
Or, she gets angry
If any company's facing a loss.
Doesn't she ask about you?
Yes.
Sometimes, she does ask about me, too.
She even says, chuckling,
'Why don't get married a second time'?
Have there been any issues between the two of you?
Yes.
What?
That we don't have any issues of love between us.
I'm sorry,
But sometimes,
I laugh at the wrong things.
Excuse me.
-Alright.
How was it?
Very good.
This flute is my friend.
And this tune
Is the tale of my heart.
When I'm alone,
I hum this.
When I'm tormented,
I play it.
Why don't you say anything, M. Danish?
You've been so quiet.
By the way,
This shirt suits you.
Perhaps it wouldn't even suit me so well.
It's 1 now, M. Shehwar.
We should leave now.
You're a strange kind of friend.
Even in friendship, you'd remember the time when coming and leaving?
I have to go to the office in the morning. I'd been late today, too.
Yes, I can understand.
C'mon, then.
Come.
Did you have fun?
You enjoyed your movie?
How was the movie?
Innit?
Oh, great!
M. Danish,
Here's a watch for you.
Hey -- Why?
Please, keep it.
It's a friend's first gift to his friend.
Also, it's a tradition in my family
To give a gift to our guests
On their first visit here
To cherish the memories.
Please, take it, or it'd hurt me very much.
Thank you.
Here.
And
This is for you, M. Rumi; there's a lot of chocolates in this.
And here's a little piano,
It also has the tune I'd just played.
-Thank you.
You're welcome.
And
This is for you.
All of this is very expensive, M. Shehwar...
Your lady is priceless, too.
Lovers are priceless.
Such things are an offering unto them.
In fact, why don't you have her
Put this on right now?
Please, put this on her.
I'd be chuffed if you put this on her.
Should I take this one off?
English translation: J. Mir