Papa...
Please meet Maman for once.
She won't cut her vein again.
And I want to see my Mum alive.
Please, have your breakfast.
I just said it casually.
Please don't be angry.
No, I --
I've had my breakfast.
I could've gotten you half or even a million off if you hadn't been in such a hurry.
But if you would've delayed,
I could've paid a million or even a million and a half more.
Thank you.
'(The Late) Akhtar Ahmed'
Is the plaque up?
Yes.
Here's your money.
Thank you.
Should I open the door, Ma'am?
No.
Has everything been cleaned?
-Yes.
Alright, you may go.
We'll get him enrolled in the school.
The rapscallion spends his entire day watching cartoons.
Bad word, Papa.
Look at him speak English now.
'Very good, Papa',
'Have a nice day, Papa'.
Hello, Mehwish!
I hear you've bought this flat.
Yes.
And
Who's this Akhtar Ahmed?
Danish's Dad.
Please, come.
Have some tea.
Not in that way.
I've gotten married.
I'm not alone now.
I'll have your tea
When I come to live here.
Won't Danish be coming?
How could he...
He lives in that grand mansion now...
Have you two sorted things out?
One sorts things after a quarrel, Monty,
But we never had a quarrel to begin with.
Hello.
Hi.
Ever imagined we could have a row?
Why are you laughing? Tell me.
I won't tell you anything if you ask such questions.
Where's he?
In his room.
I asked him to come with me, but he's afraid of you.
Splendid.
As if he could be afraid of me.
I'm afraid of you, too, now.
I'm afraid of your silence.
It feels like you'd burst into a cloud of smoke out of anger one day.
Shut up.
What are you saying!
Alright, promise me,
You'd keep smiling like this when I say something.
I'll keep smiling.
I've brought Mehwish over to my place from the hostel.
Take good care of her.
Where are you off to?
Outside.
I'm afraid the two of you may begin to justify disloyalty.
And remember, Ayesha,
Even animals would laugh
If one ever found a defence for disloyalty.
They'd write 'love' on someone's footprint
And display it at a museum,
And tell the visitors,
'There was a time when people used to be so stupid'.
You turned out to be so disloyal.
You don't miss me
Or talk to me...
I do miss you, but don't talk to you.
Why?
Nothing, really.
What good would be missing you if you got married to someone else?
Splendid.
Who'd you get me married off to this time?
I'd wanted to get you married to Papa, but that ain't possible now.
Now, I want that you stay away from him.
I'm so mean...
I'm so mean... Innit?
Yeah.
But I'm angry at my meanness.
Don't be angry.
I'd stay away from him.
Please, have some.
Teacher!
What did he say?
He said, 'Take good care of her', got up, and left.
Where'd he go?
Outside.
He said, 'I'm afraid of you two'.
Afraid, as in?
Anyway, just relax.
He'll be fine.
Please, tell me, Ayesha.
Why was he scared?
He felt we were justifying disloyalty.
He's right there.
He doesn't want to see my face
Or meet me.
Know what, I thought if I'd slit my wrist,
It'd torment him somewhere.
I felt it'd tormented him when he'd come to the hospital,
But realised when he'd left
That he'd come to torment me.
Just don't die with this hope.
I doubt he'd even come to see you.
Just sit and wait.
My heart says that he'd meet you one day.
Then, he won't be able to leave you.
Stay here if you want to talk about all of this.
It'd keep me busy.
Know what, I want to fight him too on this.
I want to convince him
That disloyalty may be a sin,
But there's something called penance, too.
I've bought that flat today.
Which flat?
The one we used to live in together.
With the money Shehwar gave you?
I thought I'd buy it.
He can give the money to have it transferred over to him.
Didn't you think why he didn't buy the flat himself?
Why?
He said, 'I don't even come close to that building'.
'I'd die if I went inside the flat'.
'Shehwar Ahmed's footprints lie within',
'And the stench of days spent with a two-timer fills the air'.
Why don't you play with me?
What kind of question is that?
You've changed since you've gotten rich, Papa.
Oh, please...
You do meet my teacher, don't you?
Don't hide. We're friends.
No, my friend.
I don't meet her,
Nor have I got anything going on.
You know, I'm proud of you, Papa.
You're lying.
Please don't.
Do you know why?
Why?
There's something going on in her heart.
Do you remember how old you are?
Yeah.
Have some shame.
These aren't things you should be talking about.
Wait, Papa.
Yes?
I can't give my Papa to anyone.
Don't worry.
Your Papa is only yours.
You do play quite well.
You've beaten me just now, haven't you?
Do you know why?
Why?
You don't want to beat me.
See you at dinner.
He says, 'See you at dinner'.
Know what...
What?
He's lying to you.
Actually, he's told you that there's something going on in your heart.
C'mon, mate...
Keep it simple, will you?
Go to Hania and say, 'Will you marry me'?
Shut up!
Or, come to my place.
Just think she'd gotten off her train at the wrong place.
The train left,
And she realised it wasn't her destination.
She's standing there, waiting.
Forgive her mistake and bring her back.
Hung up?
Yes.
And he said,
'I wanted you to',
'But now I want you to stay away from Papa'.
Blimey...
He said, 'I'm so mean, ain't I'?
Blimey, such a wee kid,
Saying such things. He even sai --
-Stop it, Hania.
You're laughing too much.
I get a feeling it's a new way of crying buckets.
Dinner's ready. Come.
Although one doesn't really feel hungry in such a situation.
Wait.
If I was laughing, it doesn't mean I was actually crying.
But I can cry for him, too.
And, because I don't love him,
It's true that I don't.
But I could as well be in love with him.
What I don't get is whether it's proper for someone who's loved so intensely the first time to love a second time,
And if it is proper, whatever is he left with to give this second time?
Come, let's have dinner. I'm starving.
What's a divorce, Maman?
Maman and Papa no longer remain friends?
And Maman leaves?
What happens then?
Don't ask that, Rumi.
You won't get it.
I'm the only one who's understood it, Maman.
Everyone gets separated from everyone when Maman's left.
Please don't say such big words, Rumi.
Papa says the same - that I say big words now.
The two of you have made me grow far beyond my years.
Please, Maman,
I don't want to grow up just yet.
Get me through to your Papa.
He won't talk now.
Just ask him.
Just for once?
Won't you have dinner?
I'm talking to Maman.
Wait, Papa...
Maman wants to talk to you.
She's requesting.
He left with an angry look.
Alright, I'll go have my dinner.
Call your Maman.
Listen...
If you didn't get him,
Remember,
You'd miss him a lot.
And it's very improper of a woman
To marry one
And miss another.
You might as well die for him.
No.
I love to see how you might even die for him.
Mum used to say, 'When a woman repeatedly says that she dislikes someone',
'She's actually begun to like him'.
And when someone like you says, 'Whatever is left',
She actually wants to know
If there's anything left at all.
Embarrassed already?
Come.
Please, come in.
Call out to him.
Whom?
M. Diwan.
You used to call out to him the moment you entered.
M. Diwan!
He didn't come.
He's not coming.
His wife has a fever. He said he'd be with her tonight.
But
Now that you've come back,
I thought I'd give you your pride back.
Whether or not someone comes,
Just keep calling out, okay?
Honestly,
Have you grown fond of me, or are you having mercy on me?
Come. I'll tell you.
Here.
Sit here.
Please, sit down.
I've begun to believe you're a man.
Mum used to say, 'He's made men and women in pairs'.
'You find another when you've separated from one'.
I figured
That if I have to find another man after separating from you,
Are you so bad yourself?
Play it, will you?
I've heard
That you
Played the piano for Mehwish one night.
You danced with her late into the night.
Play the same tune today, will you?
Just forget Mehwish, will you?
Have you?
I have.
A lie.
Remember her so you can forget her.
You've got to remember someone to forget them.
Play the same tune.
Let us remember her together to forget her.
How do you like it?
Very good.
What?
Dancing with you.
Not dancing.
Getting out of your cage at the lockup.
Finding what was lost again.
Honestly, Maham?
I can't believe it.
I can't believe it either.
You'd gone to Europe with her, too?
For two and a half months,
You've danced about in someone else's arms,
Intoxicated with another woman?
I'll apologise after the dance.
No.
Not just yet.
Apologise after a few years.
Right now,
You're on probation for this new relationship.
Someday,
I'll call out to you as I leave,
Saying, 'I forgive you, Shehwar'.
'You've become the chairman of the Shehwar group of companies again'.
Until your period of probation is over,
You're not our chairman.
From now on, you'd sit in the same chair, in the same room
Where I'd seen you work with all your heart,
Seeing which, I'd lost my heart to you.
I've begun to fear him, Mehwish.
He's trying to break me.
Thinking that divorce is some trifling crossness between two people,
He says, 'Why don't the two of you sort things out'?
Yes, why don't we sort things out?
Why don't you just agree to what he says?
Alright.
Just act out a reconciliation.
Give me a place to stay in a corner of the house.
We'd have dinner together to show him,
Play with him,
And show him that we've not separated.
Soon,
He'd have grown up enough to understand the meaning of divorce.
He may even say himself,
'Why do the two of you live together'?
You're there, aren't you?
Even if he understood, he'd never say,
'Why are you living together'?
Alright, even if he doesn't say it, I'd leave myself.
You're laughing?
Because you're talking about leaving.
Of course, you know about leaving only too well...
I wish you talk about it all over again,
And I die when I hear it.
You've brought tears to my eyes,
And I wouldn't like to cry over you.
Of vexed hearts,
The path is straight
Never is it
That they look back.
The strands of love,
The bond of loyalty
Once broken, can never be mended...
Thank you, Papa!
Thank you for what?
You've come to drop me at school. After a month!
Mind yourself, laddie. I'd be coming everyday now.
Then, just say that you've minded yourself!
Go.
Bye, Papa.
Bye.
Close the door.
Hi, teacher!
Let's get going.
Papa would come everyday now.
Earlier, Papa would just send me with the driver.
Your classroom.
Are you angry with me?
Of course not.
Why did you leave my hand, then?
This is not my classroom.
Oh...
I'm sorry.
See you.
Yes, Watira?
Did you see him?
Whom?
Danish, of course.
Don't be cheap.
Cheap?
He knows you, you know him.
But you know neither me, nor him.
But I'd said 'Hi',
And waved, too.
Thank God...
Thank God?
What?
Polar bear...
Polar bear is the most endangered animal.
Do you know
Which one is the second most endangered animal?
Rumi?
Are you here?
No, I'm not.
I'm sorry.
Is there any problem?
Yes.
But I'm thinking about the solution.
You?
Yeah.
Think after the class.
Okay, fine, teacher.
Right, where was I?
You were saying that the polar bear is the most endangered animal.
Correct.
So...
Know what,
I can't look him in the eye now.
I feel like I'm looking at my Dad.
Seriously, mate.
I used to fear Dad a lot.
He'd get angry
At the slightest mistake.
He'd say, 'I'm going easy on you for now'.
After saying something sharp, he'd say, 'Where's your sense of humour now'?
So, what's new about that?
After so many months,
I'd gone to drop him at the school today.
He said as he got off,
'Thank you, Papa'.
So, what's the big deal?
That's what you don't know.
It was the same with Dad.
His 'Thank you' sounded like an insult.
-Thank you.
When he got off the car,
Hania showed up.
Hania said, 'Hi',
And - blimey - how the little bugger was looking at her!
And - blimey - how the little bugger was looking at her! Then at me, then her again.
-How?
-How was he looking at her?
Just try to understand it.
As if Dad's looking at her.
As if --
I'm hitting on her.
Alright, leave Dad be.
If he was looking at her like that, it means he knows everything.
What does he know?
He must've seen something.
Seen -- where?
In Hania's heart.
In her words.
He's at school for 6 hours.
She's got 4 classes with her.
They must have talked sometime.
She'd have said everything, thinking of him as just a kid.
-What 'everything', mate?
What's there between the two of us?
Who's talking about the two of you?
Only the open book gets read.
You've sealed yourself shut.
He's her student.
He might've read her.
Latif! Get me a cup of tea.
Hi, Papa! Good evening.
Good evening.
Going somewhere?
Yeah.
I'm going to meet Hania.
Why?
Nothing, really. I thought I'd meet her.
Where'd you meet her?
At her place.
At her place. Of course.
You didn't even ask me.
Oh -- My mistake...
Alright, may I go?
May I come along?
C'mon, Papa. It'd be suspicious if you came along.
Who'd grow suspicious?
What's it with suspicion, Papa?
I may grow suspicious, too.
May I?
See you at dinner.
Bye!
Bye.
Hello?
Hello.
It's Danish.
Yes?
Did you call Rumi?
No?
He called. Said, 'I'm coming'. I said, 'Alright'.
Didn't you ask him why he's coming?
Why?
Why would I ask that?
You'd come, too.
Did I ask you why you were coming?
No, it's nothing like that.
I was just worried about him.
He's up to some fresh tricks.
Anyway...
Listen...
Yes?
What fresh tricks?
I mean --
Exactly --
Can't tell exactly...
Don't worry.
I'm his teacher, not his student.
I'm his teacher, not his student. I'll take care.
Okay.
Send him back.
Sure.
Bye.
It's Danish.
Yes?
What's going on, Salman?
What's going on?
Rumi, mate...
He's gone to meet Hania so royally decked up as if --
He didn't even ask me.
You're suspecting him?
Oh, please, mate...
He's gone on a date, boyo. Simple.
I'm serious, Salman.
Let me have dinner.
I mean, I'll think seriously after dinner.
I'll tell you why he's gone there.
Go to hell...
Guess
What's bothering him.
Rumi's gone to meet Hania decked up and all -- And he didn't even ask him.
Excuse me.
We'd decided we're friends, right?
Yes, we are friends.
So I can talk to you about anything?
Don't you remember you talk to me about everything?
I was just checking your memory.
But what I'm about to say is the most important of it all, teacher.
Very serious.
May I?
Yes, go on.
May I hold your hand?
Yeah, sure...
Please, get up from the chair, will you?
Will you marry my father?
Come here right away if you haven't had dinner.
I've been waiting.
I haven't had dinner.
I'd promised I'd have dinner with you.
Good boy.
Actually, you weren't waiting to have dinner.
You couldn't bring yourself to eat.
Why?
All the suspense...
What suspense?
I'd gone to Miss Hania's.
You must be thinking why I'd gone there.
Shall we have dinner?
So, no suspense?
No suspense.
Why'd you gone there?
I'd gone to convince her.
I said, 'Get married'.
I proposed to her.
What?
You proposed to her?
What did she say?
Look at your age!
Why are you so rude?
No, Papa, I was just saying it lightly.
You'd hug me if you heard what I've done.
What've you done?
I've talked about the marriage, ol' chap.
I seized her hand,
And said,
'Will you marry my father'?
At least have your dinner, Papa!
Why are you shying away?
Papa...
You're laughing?
I thought you'd be angry with me.
No way.
I'm delighted.
I feel so good.
You're taking so much interest in my life.
Are you joking?
No way, mate.
I'm complimenting you.
Go and call your Maman.
Say, 'I've found a match for Papa, and I will not rest until I've gotten them married'.
She'd be chuffed to hear that.
She'd give you a kiss.
No, she won't be happy to hear that.
She'd cry, but say, 'Splendid. Well done, Rumi'!
Then, go and tell her. Hear her compliments, too.
I already did.
I've already told her.
I'd called her on the way.
She said, 'Go and ask Papa'.
Alright, I'll ask tomorrow. Have your dinner.
I'm starving.
You're starving?
C'mon.
Let's have dinner.
English translation: J. Mir