Good evening.
I'm Ifrah.
Monty's wife.
Oh.
May you be happy.
Likewise.
Come.
Why are you washing your face again and again?
I haven't seen you like this before.
It's because he's gone to meet Mehwish, innit?
What are you looking at there?
I've begun to fear this door.
He'd walked in through it.
You'd walked out through it.
Please, Danish...
Have your tea, will you?
Thank you.
So you still put out your cigarette when you see me?
It felt as if you're scared of me even today.
Rumi said you looked dashing.
I don't like to look dashing.
Do you know the date?
17th November?
What'd happened today?
What?
We'd met for the first time today.
Oh, right...
Don't you remember?
No. I chose to forget it.
I just remember the day you left.
I can't seem to forget it.
Of vexed hearts,
The path is straight
Never is it
That they look back.
Of vexed hearts,
The path is straight
Never is it
That they look back.
The strands of love,
The bond of loyalty
Once broken, can never be mended
You're leaving?
No...
I was opening the door.
My heart grows restless...
Know what, everyone thought that if I met you,
I won't be able to leave you.
I never felt so.
But I feel so today...
This wind...
This cool breeze...
I want to live...
I was right there the other day, wasn't I, Mehwish?
Well, you didn't even look back at me.
I was right there, mate...
And I'd stopped
The man who thought himself to be a great businessman, saying,
'You're offering me 50 million for this worthless, unworthy woman'?
Know what, Mehwish,
Many people had said to me,
'Wives often forgive'
'When their husbands commit such sins.'
'Why don't you forgive her, too?'
I always said,
'I've already forgiven her'.
'If only she forgave me'...
'And spared my life'!
But you didn't spare my life.
Do you know, I believe
That once you've two-timed,
Just move on, mate.
If you've been two-timed yourself,
Don't look back at your old, loyal partner.
What could he do now?
But know what, I couldn't figure out to this day
Which of murder
And infidelity is the greater crime.
A murder just...
Takes a life.
But infidelity is a brutal murder
That spares the life.
No...
Please, Mehwish -- Please --
Don't come close to me. Don't touch me.
Please...
I realise today
That to touch
Is a gifted right.
One gets it only when one deserves it.
Just think about it -
Do you deserve it?
You don't, do you?
Listen, Mehwish --
Please don't visit my grave if I die.
Alright, don't come too close.
I'm keeping my distance
From the disloyal.
I'll do to you what you did to love.
You'll lose me, never to find me again.
Forget finding me...
I wouldn't even pay you a visit in your dreams.
It's been two hours since I'd come, innit?
Rumi was supposed to come --
Rumi was supposed to come -- After two hours, Mehwish...
Please -- If he comes --
Comfort him -- Take care of him...
He's gone through a lot more than me.
Please -- Don't touch me...
Please, Mehwish -- Don't touch me --
Please -- Don't touch --
Ifrah!
Monty!
How would I
Heal the beats of this heart,
For like it,
I, too, am broken...
How would I
Heal the beats of this heart,
For like it,
I, too, am broken...
He's had a severe cardiac arrest.
Give him entropy.
And start dopamine infusion at 10 ml.
And keep the AED ready, okay?
Okay, sir.
R --
Rumi...
My mistake, Maman.
Papa thought that if he met you,
He wouldn't be able to come back.
Rumi...
Who's Rumi?
Me.
Come. He's calling you.
Not you.
Just Rumi.
The patient has asked me to call just Rumi.
Please wait here.
Rumi...
Yes, Papa?
Are you crying?
No.
Remember...
Your Papa is your strength...
Yes, I remember.
I --
I've had a heart attack...
I know...
Don't laugh, Papa.
I will laugh, Rumi.
Your Maman's made me laugh...
His SPO2's dropping...
Please don't take it off. You need oxygen.
Please, doctor...
I'm fine.
Alert everyone.
Monitor SPO2 and heart rate.
When I met your Maman today...
I saw --
She's not the same anymore --
Know what, she was trying to make it up to me...
Saying sorry...
Remember...
How I always used to make it up to her?
Saying sorry without reason?
Know what --
Sh --
She --
She's my weakness.
I never thought in 8 years --
That --
I'd ever have to live without her...
And --
I couldn't -- Could I?
That's why I'm laughing...
She used to scold me --
Put me to sleep --
Like she used to scold you to sleep --
Back then -- It felt --
She's not just your Mum --
A bit --
Mine too --
And when your Mum leaves you --
How would the kid live?
You're not crying, are you?
No, Papa...
G --
Good...
She --
She's back now --
She'd left us --
To do something --
It's done and over now --
She knows now --
By leaving Paradise in your search for Paradise --
You can never find it...
We'll talk over breakfast.
Get some rest, Papa.
No, Rumi --
Keep me awake...
Don't ask me to sleep --
I'll sleep --
Alright, sorry, Papa. Stay awake.
Eyes open.
Want to know a secret?
Yes, Papa?
I didn't usually remember my Dad...
Know why?
Why, Papa?
He'd pay me a visit in my dreams every day.
Wake me and have me sit for a chat --
He'd ask --
'What'd you do today?'
'You go to the office on time, don't you?'
'You don't take bribes, do you?'
'What about Rumi's admission?'
After your admission -- He'd ask --
'He's studying hard, isn't he?'
'Do you check his homework?'
He'd say --
Tell Rumi
To become a great man --
I will become a great man, Papa.
But remember --
He'd say --
'A great man'
'Has his earnings in his pocket,'
'Not his price.'
Look --
That line --
-Prepare the AED.
Quickly!
Yes, Papa.
Okay, sir.
It's --
The line of the heart.
Level --
Now --
Straight.
-Check his heart rate. Vitals?
We're losing him, sir.
The heart's stopped --
But --
But -- I'm alive --
My son --
In your heart --
Your --
I live in your heart...
Say 'Yes', will you...
Y -- Yes, Papa...
R -- Rumi!
We'll meet in your dreams...
I'll be th -- there -- everyday...
Check vitals.
-Rumi...
Papa...
Take the kid outside.
Clear the bed.
-Rumi...
Rumi...
We'll meet in your dreams...
Delivering the shock...
Rumi...
-3...
We'll meet in your dreams...
-2...
-1...
3... 2... 1...
Rumi...
We'll meet in your dreams...
Papa's alright, isn't he?
Sorry, Ma'am...
He's no more.
Papa says he'll pay a visit in dreams.
He promised...
How would I
Heal the beats of this heart,
For like it,
I, too, am broken...
How would I
Heal the beats of this heart,
For like it,
I, too, am broken...
Granted, that I am
A bit angry with you,
It is also with this life
That I am cross.
I have learnt
From the sin of disloyalty
That to part
Is to die...
Teach me your ingenious skill
Of forgetting as you leave;
Efface every trace of your memory
From my life, now that you're leaving.
As nothing more than a formality, if nothing else,
Turn back and glance at me for a moment;
Fulfil the vows of our bond for once
As you break it.
English translation: J. Mir
Sometimes, it's nagging me,
And sometimes, making me weep.
Forsake your place in my heart,
Gently and stilly;
Bless you with this parting,
Fare thee well.