Alright, Anoushay, they're waiting. C'mon.
-C'mon.
Right...
I'm Maham.
Shehwar
Shehwar Ahmed's
Shehwar Ahmed's wife.
What's up?
I'm beholding my affluence.
There, now.
I'm honest.
If I ever feel that I don't have much money in my pockets,
I pull out the wallet and look at your picture;
In but a moment, a gust of opulence overwhelms me.
There's nothing like that, my dear.
I'm happy with how you keep me.
I love you.
Honestly, Danish?
We can't live together anymore.
Crazy lass, I can't live without you.
But I can.
And I want to.
Why do you trouble yourself for a woman
Who isn't even ready to be loyal to you?
Hello?
Hania here.
Yes, Hania? What is it?
Do you even bother about Rumi?
Why? What happened?
Did you ever feel that I didn't care about him?
Yes.
Where are you?
I'm outside.
And where is he?
He's at home.
So that's how you're caring for him.
A child of the age of 6 is alone at home, waiting for you, and this is how you think you're caring for him?
I'll be home in 10 minutes.
10 minutes from now, yes,
What'd you do tomorrow?
Or the day after?
Obviously, you'd be out of the house if you run a business.
You'd have to leave for work often.
Sometimes, you'd even like to hang out with the lads.
So, please look for a permanent solution, would you?
How?
Who's with the kid when he's at home?
His Mum.
Granted that his Mum's left and is never coming back
It's not as if the world has ended!
No, sir, the world is as it was!
The same old!
Get married ASAP!
You don't have to worry either,
He's found someone for you, too.
He's friends with her, too.
There won't be any issues with a stepmom.
Do you know her?
No.
But he does.
Trust me, he's a rapscallion, but his choice ain't bad.
As in, you haven't the foggiest about who she is.
I just told you.
I've asked him to introduce me to her a few times, but he says, 'It's confidential. I won't introduce you to her'.
I've seen her.
Splendid.
I've met her, too.
Right...
How do you like her?
She's very cute.
Here's an idea - introduce me to her,
I'll talk to her.
You won't be able to talk if you heard her name.
You're underestimating me.
Should I tell you her name?
Yes?
He's talking about you.
Who are you?
What are you doing at my house?
I think you don't know who I am.
Mr Shehwar, I've got an arrest warrant for you.
What warrant?
What have I done?
Fraud and forgery,
Illegal transfer of funds,
And...
-And?
And transferring 1 billion US Dollars through an IOU.
Lies!
Baseless!
Prove that in court.
C'mon.
Where?
We're throwing a grand pre-wedding party for you at the lockup. Come,
Or these nice folks here would have to shove you into the car.
Who's the complainant?
Your wife,
Maham Syed.
Maham?
Have a good day, dear husband.
Enjoy the party.
Shall we?
I want to talk to my lawyer.
Sure.
I'll get you through as soon as we get there.
What are you looking at?
Tell them to stand down.
It's so insulting!
Oh, this is just the beginning...
Just wait and watch what I'll do to you in court!
Now, get lost!
Should I drop you?
No. I've come on my bike.
Then, please get going.
The groom's left already.
Alright.
What are you?
In fact, ask yourself -
Whatever is left of you now?
Do you know why I didn't send you with your boyfriend today?
Because he's been caught today.
He'll be presented before court tomorrow and the trial will begin.
But it'd be months before he gets punished.
But you've been tried.
Sentenced, too.
Pack your things and get out of here.
A long term of imprisonment awaits you outside.
But where would I go?
And -- How would I, I don't even --
Diwan!
Give her some money.
Give her far more than she's expecting.
I'd better not see your face
When I come upstairs again,
Because you're so beautiful
That I envy you,
Yet, so ugly
That I feel like spitting in your face.
Alright, Ma'am, you may get off here.
I'd been told to drop you here.
N -- No...
Please, not here.
Drop me over there --
At the building that used to be my home.
Alright, I'll take you there.
But you know that they've left.
Either way, please drop me there.
Alright, Ma'am. I'll take you there.
I've seen that man very closely, Mme. Maham,
His face would be drained of all its colour when he'd come here.
He'd be restless,
Laughing even at things
One would cry to see.
It was etched clearly on his face that his wife
Was cheating on him,
And, even then,
He wanted to stop her.
Perhaps for his son,
Or his love...
Did he beat her?
No.
Looking at him, one wouldn't even think he'd ever raise his voice at her.
I wouldn't believe it even if someone told me so.
A man, yet so merciful?
You must be mistaken, Diwan.
If a woman gets such love,
She ignores everything she lacks.
The bloke must have been beating her,
Demeaning her...
That's why it happened -
The woman asked someone else her worth.
And how did he keep her?
Very happy.
Then, everything was fine, Diwan.
Why did you call me, then?
My heart felt
That it's all temporary,
That she's come here because she wants more than her husband can earn,
And he's brought her because he has a lot of money to give.
The poor woman.
Don't pity her, Mme. Maham!
A woman who separates from her own
To seek a union with another man
Is never worth pity.
Then, why did I feel such pity for her when I sent her?
She'd fallen face-first when you'd seen her.
That's why you felt pity.
But when I'd seen her,
She used to soar high,
Without even bothering
To look at those on the ground.
Where'd she go?
I mean,
Where'd she go at this hour of the night?
I don't know, but
Just for once,
She'd go
Where she'd come from.
Why?
After all, she'd divorced her husband.
What'd she get there?
Or is it
That he's the kind who'd take her back?
In either case,
She would go there once.
Why?
That's how it is, Mme. Maham.
If a murderer gets acquitted before completing his prison term,
He visits the place where he'd committed the murder once.
Shall I serve dinner?
No.
I'm so satisfied today
That it feels
That I'm full.
Good evening.
-Good evening.
Where's he gone after selling the flat?
Didn't I tell you the other day that I don't know?
Please, find out.
I want to meet my son.
I can give you some money -- Here --
I have 10,000 here -- Please take all of it --
-No, Ma'am, I don't want any money.
Not a penny.
Just call him.
Ask him to tell you.
Even if I found out,
I won't tell you.
You may go, now, Ma'am.
Most people in the building don't know about it.
All they know
Is that you've gone to another city
And he's gone to live with you.
So, it's better if you leave, Ma'am.
It's better if such things don't come out.
May the Lord help you.
I had been so blear-eyed
And a sinner all along
Yet, all along
I've captivated your heart
Forgive my sins, thinking, if nothing else,
That you've missed me so much...
What are you doing?
Taking the SIM out.
What happened?
Nothing, really.
I thought...
I have to talk to Dad's friends every now and then. I have to tell them that he's no more...
It hurts me so much.
Here.
Keep it.
What happened?
What do you mean?
It's Danish who's been calling you on Dad's phone for the last few days,
Or Rumi, who called that one time.
Who's calling you every now and then that's hurting you so much?
I'm sleepy...
I can't think of a single night in the past year when you've gone to bed at 10.30.
Yes,
There was that one time...
You had a fever.
The doctor had given you sleeping pills.
I've taken sleeping pills.
Why?
Because -- I felt I'd have a fever.
You're hiding something, aren't you?
As if a fever's something one would hide...
Please, go now, I'm actually sleepy.
Should I give you Dad's diary?
Why?
Read it again before you go to bed.
Go through what Dad's written on its last few pages.
Good night.
I accept this proposal.
From now on, we're partners. 50-50.
Perfect.
Here, ol' chap.
Rumi!
Maman?
Why don't you meet me?
Papa's told you not to?
No. I'd told Papa not to.
Look over there. Papa's car.
You may go. She's my Maman.
How are you, Maman?
I'm fine.
May I go? I'm getting late.
May I come sometimes?
Here?
No. My friends would ask me who you are.
Just tell them
'It's my Maman'!
I won't.
They'd ask me why you meet me at the school gates.
Give me your phone number.
I'll talk to you over the phone.
Don't you miss me?
I do, Maman.
Don't you feel like meeting me?
Then, why did you say,
'I'd talk to you over the phone'?
I'm getting late, Maman...
What've you become, Rumi...
May I come to meet you once a week?
-Once a week?
A week goes by so quickly.
Once a month. Okay?
Bye!
A woman showed up at the school gates, sir.
She pulled li'l Rumi into an embrace the moment she saw him.
She started kissing his face and forehead. She was crying, too.
And Rumi said, 'You may go',
'She's my Maman'.
Oh?
Is she actually his Mum, sir?
Yes.
Congratulations!
Thank you!
Come. Let me show you your office.
This is your office.
Good?
Very good.
Look at this painting here.
Guess who's made it.
You?
Yes.
In two days.
I've made it for you.
That's what you're like.
From the outside, and deep inside.
Surely, I'm not so colourful.
You are.
She's just drained you of all your colour.
So what?
Get your colour back.
Become colourful again.
Alright.
Come here. Sit.
Here.
I'll take a picture of you.
Come and sit.
Ready?
Just a second.
At least smile!
Yes,
You'd manage the portfolio.
He'd just tell you which shares to buy and sell.
But what'd I do, Salman?
I mean --
I'd only be a portfolio manager in name.
Yes.
Just like I'm the CEO only in name.
Sit.
Please, boyo, sit.
Look,
One's got to understand a few things, learn some.
Do you play cricket?
Yes.
Haven't you seen
That the one-down batsman is not quite in form,
But number 9 does steals the show.
He may be batsman #10 of the stock market,
But he's in form,
And my intuition says he's on his way to score a century.
Just close your eyes.
If he says, 'Buy this share', buy it,
And if he says, 'Sell this share', sell it.
Let's see how your portfolio's been doing after 15 days.
I've not seen a man so superstititious as you at the Stock Exchange, Salman.
Just wait and watch,
If it turned out as I'm thinking, I'd tell you that I wasn't superstitious at all.
Sure?
Sure.
Rumi!
Yes, teacher?
What are you doing here?
I was reading... Fell asleep...
Do you know you've missed a class?
I'm sorry...
Sit.
Are you upset?
Worried?
Yes.
You've even met your Maman in the morning,
And you're still upset?
What happened?
Any problem?
She says she loves me so much.
What's wrong about that?
Maman always loves so much...
Not always, teacher.
She takes a 4-month leave. More than my summer holidays.
The thing is, there'd been some problems then...
When there's problems between Maman and Papa, there are 'holidays' like that...
The problem's still there.
Maman's just met me. She hasn't met Papa yet.
Right...
The problem's still there...
Do you know that she was crying so much? She hadn't even come by her car.
Are you sure?
Yes, teacher. She'd left on a rickshaw.
How could that be...
Papa says they've got a lot of money.
She always used to come by car.
A big one.
That's why Papa's bought a big car.
It's time for my class, okay?
I'll get going.
Over here, Ma'am.
Shehwar...
You?
Here?
Why have you come?
Enough of -- Just go!
Go back to your husband.
If my wife found out you came here to meet me, she'd have me hung!
Just go, will you?
I can't even get a bail.
You didn't tell anyone around here your name, did you?
I've written my name - Mehwish.
Go back.
Get your name out of there.
Just say that your name's not Mehwish!
An --
Anoushay. That's right.
Just go, will you?
We have seen good moments together, mate...
Please do me this favour.
Who are you, Shehwar Ahmed?
Who?
Eh?
Who do you think I am?
Do I look like Danish?
Hey!
Who is she?
Please, take her away. I don't even know her.
Why have you come to meet me?
Please, go!
Your wife was right.
She said to me, 'What are you'?
'In fact, how say you tell me',
'Whatever is left of you now'?
Sometimes, it's nagging me,
And sometimes, making me weep.
Maman, she's crying like you, too.
Come here.
Sit.
Hello?
Hello...
Is this Salman Ibrahim?
Yes, who are you?
It's Mehwish, Salman.
Your class-fellow.
Hey! Where'd you drop in from?
How are you?
I'm fine.
And you?
Fine...
And how's he...
Danish?
Don't ask about him.
Why?
He's alive, isn't he?
No -- We --
I'm in a problem, Salman.
Can you please help me?
Go on.
I need a job.
Where are you?
Nowhere...
Alright,
I'll text you my address.
Meet me in the evening.
We'll talk.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Papa!
Rumi!
What's up? You're extra loving today!
I've been missing you.
You liar!
Tell me,
What is it?
I'm honest, Papa, I was missing you.
Do you know what I used to think of you before sending you to school?
What?
A duffer.
But you're an absolute rapscallion.
You were just waiting for me to send you to school so you can give yourself airs.
Papa!
When I went to school today, Maman was standing there.
She hugged me and started crying.
She was crying so much, Papa.
I know.
Papa, I was thinking that if she hugged you and cried like that,
You would've just said 'It's okay' and brought her home.
Done your homework?
A long while ago.
Alright, I'll go and change.
We'll have dinner.
She didn't have her car, Papa. She'd come on a rickshaw.
She went back on a rickshaw, too.
It seemed like she'd come to say sorry.
Go and tell the cook to serve dinner.
I'm coming.
Okay?
She didn't have her car, Papa. She'd come on a rickshaw.
She went back on a rickshaw, too.
It seemed like she'd come to say sorry.
Hello?
Watching TV?
No. I've just gotten home.
So, you haven't heard the news, have you?
What news?
The FIA [Federal Investigation Agency] have arrested Shehwar Ahmed.
His wife's snatched everything from him.
No comments?
No comments.
Alright.
I'll disconnect.
Bye.
English translation: J. Mir