Good morning, Ma'am.
Good morning. Please, come in. Come and sit down.
Miss Mehwish...
Please, sit.
This is Miss Hania,
In-charge of Rumi's class.
Hi.
I suppose we've met before?
No.
We've talked over the phone before.
So, you've come to meet Rumi?
No, I've come to take him along.
I'd take him along when school's over at 1.30.
I'd leave him here before the evening.
-Of course.
Would you like some tea?
No, thank you.
Okay.
Have you got a permission letter
From his father?
Permission letter?
I'm his mother, Ma'am.
Of course, you may be,
But how'd I know that?
I'm meeting you for the first time.
Please call Rumi; he'd tell you.
If Rumi said you're his mother, I could allow you to meet him,
But I can't send him with you.
If he told you I'm his mother,
Why can't he come with me?
Look...
If you don't have a permission letter,
I can't send Rumi with you.
I'm sorry, but these are the rules. We have to follow them.
I'm surprised.
I'm sorry.
Call his father.
Ask him.
We can't depend on phone calls.
You know very well
That anyone can say anything over the phone.
Besides, just a few days ago, his phone had accidentally ended up with
Besides, just a few days ago, his phone had accidentally ended up with Miss Hania.
I need a letter.
I need a permission letter,
Or...
Or?
Or an order from the court.
Alright.
Call Rumi.
I'll just meet him today.
Of course.
That's not a problem.
I'll call him here.
I'd say you wait in the room next to this one.
You can meet him there.
Thank you.
Right, so why should I marry a lad who's wearing a long face all the time?
Be a man.
I am a man.
Alright, then, c'mon.
Your Maman's come to meet you.
No.
What?
I said 'No'.
I'm not meeting her.
One doesn't say 'no' to Maman.
You'd have to meet her.
I'd never meet her.
She'd cry a lot if she heard that,
And think your Papa's told you not to meet her.
No.
My Papa never told me not to meet her.
But she will think so.
Why would she?
Why would she think so if he's never stopped me?
Don't you miss your Mum?
Yes, I do miss her...
Ask her to never come to my school.
I will never meet her.
Never!
Please, sign here.
We need your thumb impression over here.
Next.
That's it.
Here.
Give him the money.
Here's one million.
You can count if you like.
I don't count anymore.
I weigh it.
Thank you.
What?
Are you crazy?
My son would say that she doesn't want to meet his Maman?
Impossible!
Take me to him right now!
-Excuse me.
One, you're not talking to me so rudely,
And two, I've told you what your son has said,
And, being his teacher,
I cannot force him, right?
Who the hell are you?
A responsible teacher.
A responsible teacher. Thank you.
Oh!
So all of you are in on it with Danish Akhtar!
Fine.
I'll take care of all of you.
-Listen!
With this attitude, you won't even be able to see me.
The guard won't let you inside the school the next time. Do you get it?
Goodbye.
Why are you worried?
Don't you pity such a woman,
Who'd be crying out to her son, 'I'm your mother'?
Take it that the punishment for ruining a household begins here.
Have you done what I'd asked you to do?
Good afternoon, sir.
Good afternoon.
Tea or coffee?
Nothing.
Sir?
You've been coming here late for a few days, M. Danish.
Yes.
Why?
Because I won't be coming now.
Aye, mate...
The crazy git!
When I asked why he's late,
He said, 'I won't be coming now'.
He means he won't be coming late now.
No, mate.
You don't get it.
His promotion's gotten to his head.
Someone should tell him that M. Matin's no more.
He'd better not show such pride!
Bye, everyone.
Goodbye.
Do you folks even know
That M. Danish has resigned?
M. Danish has resigned?
How could that be?
I'm sorry, Dad.
I've sold the flat.
Forgive me.
Hello?
Hello.
This is Hania speaking, M. Danish.
Yes, Miss Hania?
It's been --
Bothering me since the afternoon; I was thinking whether I should tell you this...
Please, tell me if there's any problem.
There's a problem, M. Danish.
Your ex-wife is a problem.
What happened?
She'd come to the school to meet Rumi,
And wanted to take him along when school's over.
She was rather angry when the Headmistress declined.
Then, she agreed to see Rumi for a while, but...
Rumi didn't agree to see her.
Didn't agree?
He didn't meet her?
Right.
That's not good.
Mehwish is his mother, he should've met her.
That's what I've called to ask you -
Whether Rumi would decide if he wants to meet his mother, or his mother's husband?
What do you mean?
It's clear, M. Danish.
He may not be forced if he doesn't want to meet her.
I talked to the Hostel Warden a short while ago.
He's been sleeping since 5 p.m.
Do you know why kids like him go to sleep so early?
Why do they?
Because they're afraid.
They want to forget that anything of the sort ever happened.
Whatever he may do, Miss Hania,
He'd have to meet his mother.
Alright.
I'll not be responsible for his next progress report.
Your child will remain timid,
And timid children never perform well.
Take care. Bye.
Hello?
Blimey, mate.
What's it with your theatrics?
Why are you creating troubles for yourself?
Who is it?
Oh?
So you don't even know who I am?
M. Shehwar?
What do you want?
What would I want?
Be done with this drama.
How much should I pay you
To make you end this balderdash?
What have I done?
Why don't you let Mehwish meet her son?
No, M. Shehwar -- By the Lord, I haven't stopped him.
I've just gotten to know that he refused to meet her when she'd gone there.
I've even told the folks at the school that it wasn't proper.
Look,
I give you two days.
The two of them should meet on the third day,
Or my lawyers will have your hide.
I've sold the flat.
I've resigned, too.
I'll start my own business,
And this business is a full-time job.
One has to work very hard in the beginning.
If you remain adamant on not meeting your Maman,
The two of them will think I've taught you this,
That I've forbidden you from meeting her.
Two -- who?
Your Maman and her husband.
Look at me.
I know you don't like that man.
You don't want to meet him.
But you have to do this for your Maman, Rumi.
I don't want to meet my Maman.
You're just being stubborn, Rumi.
They're affluent people.
They've got a lot of money.
What if they went to court?
What happens in the court, Papa?
Nothing...
I met my lawyer yesterday.
I talked to him.
He said
That I won't be able to fight them,
That I'd lose.
So you're afraid of them?
I don't.
If he came before me, I'd say, 'You're a dirty man'.
Don't be stubborn.
Please, Rumi.
You don't understand how powerful he is.
He's given me two days.
If she comes,
Meet her.
Go along if she takes you.
Besides, it's not as if she's coming everyday.
Why are you laughing?
You're not my strength, Papa, you're my weakness.
It's time for my class; give me a hug.
I love you Papa.
I'd do as you say.
I love you too.
Get me some tea and bread, ol' chap.
-Right away, sir.
Why are you laughing?
You're not my strength, Papa, you're my weakness.
I give you two days.
The two of them should meet on the third day,
Or my lawyers will have your hide.
Surely, sir, you're alright?
Yes, I'm alright.
I'll get you some bread.
Alright.
I'll not be responsible for his next progress report.
Your child will remain timid,
And timid children never perform well.
Surely, sir, you're alright?
Yes, I'm alright.
4 parathas.
-In a moment!
The protest will go on, M. Mehdi.
Whatever does the bugger think he is?
The share will drop to its face value
If the unit remains shut for a few days.
He's an absolute scoundrel.
He buys people over from our side,
And pays them, but does not give us a raise.
Whoever gets sold this time won't be seen around again.
What's up, man?
-In a moment.
Do you know what's going on in the office?
He's after yet another woman these days.
She's the one he's been spending his riches on.
I've heard she was someone's wife.
He's gotten him to divorce her.
It's her, innit, Monsieur le Chairman,
It's her, innit, Monsieur le Chairman, the new board secretary?
Hey!
Yes?
Would you happen to have a matchstick?
No, sir. Shall I get you one?
Leave it be if you don't have one.
Also...
Yes?
My 'wife'
Had come yesterday, right?
Last night?
-Yes.
She's no longer my wife.
We're separated now.
She's divorced me.
Rumi's not gone with her, either.
I've got him in a boarding school.
Boarding, as in...
He stays at the school hostel.
Right, sir.
I just wanted to tell you this.
Hello?
Hello...
Am I speaking to Madame Atiya Munir?
Yes?
It's Danish here.
Rumi's father.
Danish Akhtar.
Pray tell?
Could you get me through to Rumi?
In about 15 minutes.
He's just gotten up and gone to freshen up.
Okay, fine.
I'll call after 15 minutes.
It's your father-in-law.
Yes, Mr Danish?
I hope I'm not disturbing you?
No.
Pray tell. What is it?
Yesterday,
You'd said rather angrily that you won't be responsible for Rumi.
It upset me very much.
But
Know what,
I've decided to be a brave man.
What'd you do as a brave man?
I'd ask Rumi not to meet his mother just because I'm forcing him.
It's up to him
If he wants to meet her or not.
When would you tell him?
What?
When would you say this to Rumi?
I'd called Rumi just now.
His warden said he'd just gotten up.
Gone to freshen up.
I'll call him again right after talking to you.
Okay, I'll disconnect.
-No, wait a minute.
Yes?
Now that I've agreed to what the two of you had said,
Please leave the anger behind.
As in?
Please say that you'll be responsible for Rumi's performance.
You will be, right?
Of course I will.
Thank you so much.
It's okay.
Please, disconnect now.
Bye.
Why does he call you so much?
Because he's Dad's friend.
I found out from Dad's diary.
Dad used to love him so much.
And just a few days ago, he's discovered that I'm his son's teacher.
Fair enough.
But I think there's something else going on.
It's nothing like that.
I've checked.
How?
He
Doesn't even look at me when he can very safely do so.
And when he does look at me, his eyes are just empty...
He puts up the show of a smile, deeply shocked inside...
Dad had even written, 'I've not him smile from within for the last few months',
But he's always the first one to smile.
Ask me why.
Why?
His wife's extinguished his smile.
Dad had even written somewhere, 'Pity the smile of a man who's begun to suspect his wife'.
Strange, innit?
Sometimes, I feel that a man
Who looks fine and strong from the outside
Is but like a bubble of water from within.
A single misstep of a woman can burst him.
Dad used to say,
'It makes me laugh when a woman doubts a man',
'But it makes me cry when a man doubts a woman'.
How does she look?
-Botheringly beautiful.
I'm saying it, she is beautiful.
Otherwise, a woman with no sense of shame is not beautiful.
Then, put it plainly, will you?
She's not beautiful.
She's a bother.
He'd agree by the day after tomorrow, right?
Who?
Please, Mehwish...
Or, you can tell me where I should take you
To make you forget this headache.
Didn't I say it before you?
'They should meet by the day after tomorrow',
'Or my lawyers will tear you apart'.
Still, you can't believe it...
You've not threatened him.
I have.
And when I say something, I mean it.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I know him, though,
He's a proper coward.
He can't sleep all night if someone threatens him.
He'd get up to drink water every now and then.
Sorry...
Hello, Papa.
Hey, Rumi!
You'd gone to bed so early!
You're fine, right?
Yes, Papa.
Are you angry with me?
Why? Why would I be angry with you?
Oh?
Why had you said, then,
'Papa, you're not my strength'.
You'd said it too, Papa,
'Rumi, you're not my strength; you're my weakness'.
Why are you laughing?
You wouldn't believe it.
You'd think Papa's lying to you.
No. My Papa never lies.
Then, listen to this -
I'm your strength.
I'm not your weakness.
You don't believe it, do you?
You're joking, Papa.
Just ask me why I'm saying it.
Why?
Because I've decided
That it's up to you whether you want to meet your Maman
Or not.
I won't decide that.
What'd it do to them, Papa?
They're very rich. They'd bother you.
Just let them.
You'll see how I'll bother them.
You're underestimating your Papa.
Really?
Just wait and watch.
I'd break the bugger's face.
Why are you laughing now?
Because you're my strength, Papa.
You are my strength.
Good morning.
I was just waiting for your call.
So, what have you decided?
I'm coming there.
Why?
I thought we'd sit and talk to decide everything,
So that there's no problem later.
Why, sure, then, come.
I'll be there in half an hour.
Good morning, M. Danish!
Good morning!
You look so dashing!
It's been a long while since I saw you like this.
You could just as well buy a car now.
This suit and glasses...
And a car would suit you very well.
Thank you.
Yes, he's coming.
He said, 'Let's resolve this issue'.
Alright, don't call me. I'll be in a meeting.
Alright, listen.
Yes?
I forgot to say something.
I love you.
Me too.
Right, what was I saying?
2.65 Rupees two days ago,
4.40 Rupees yesterday,
And then, the share's dropped by 2 Rupees when the market opened today?
-Yes, sir.
That's it?
Just a 'Yes, sir' would do the job?
What are you here for
If I'd fuss over everything from the share price to the production at the plant?
Just getting paid for doing nothing, are you?
Excuse me, sir, but I'd told you that the union had called a strike yesterday.
They'd been staging a symbolic protest for 2 hours every day for the last 15 days.
If there's no work going on for 2 hours, the plant works at 75% efficiency.
Word gets out to the market and it's discussed among the stakeholders.
Shut up...
With due respect, sir, a 'Shut up' won't do.
If we didn't revise their salaries this time,
We'd have to face the music.
The people are so furious this time
That you won't be able to buy them over.
Please, leave.
Please, show yourselves out.
Wait.
Tell me how raising the salaries would impact us.
I'll calculate it for you, sir.
Hi.
Hi, sir.
Danish.
I've got a meeting with your boss.
Just a minute, sir.
What is it?
Sir, M. Danish is here.
So what?
Have the bugger sit.
Have him wait no less than one hour.
Okay, sir.
Please, sit.
The boss is busy in a meeting.
Don't lie to me.
He's said, 'Have the bugger sit for one hour'.
Sir!
Wait, sir!
So, I say --
What is going on?
What the devil are you doing in my room?
How dare --
Keep sitting.
Sit down!
If anyone so much as moved a muscle,
If anyone so much as moved a muscle, he'd die by my hand!
Right, Shehwar Ahmed,
Chairman of Shehwar Chemicals,
We were to talk about something.
You don't know who you're messing with.
I'll make an example of you for every pleb like you to watch.
That's my line.
I'll say it today.
What are you looking at?
Call the police!
That's the bleedin' limit -- What are you doing!?
The police come in after the incident.
Let me create the incident.
But first, tell me,
Tell me!
Say whatever you want to!
Tell them all
What you'd said over the phone!
Spill the beans!
Easy there, M. Danish, let go of my collar.
-Tell them all!
Why don't you say anything?
What'd your lawyers do to me if they didn't meet within two days, eh?
They'd have my hide?
Look.
I'm wearing a suit.
I figured I'd wear something nice before they have my hide.
Don't disturb me!
I'm in a meeting!
Come here.
What are you doing?
Danish -- Wh -- What is this?
-Here! Sit down!
Just pause and think for two minutes.
If you want to have my hide, you'd need your lawyers,
If you want to have my hide, you'd need your lawyers, or your hoodlums.
You'd call them. It'd take time.
But I need only two minutes to expose you.
Look,
My ex-wife, who's with you today,
She's been sold.
You've bought her.
I said, 'Fine',
'What's sold belongs to the buyer'.
But now, you're talking about my son,
And my son is all that remains of my pride.
You said that your lawyers would blow me to bits.
You made a mistake there.
You reminded me that I am my son's strength, not his weakness.
So, remember, Shehwar Ahmed,
If you dared threaten me again,
Or tried to strike a deal with me about my son,
I'd drag you by this tie of yours,
And expose you before everyone for real.
This incident would benefit all of you, too.
He can't fire you now.
If he dares to shout at you,
Go and tell everyone
About what happened here today.
Understood?
Have a nice day,
Shehwar Ahmed.
Leave me alone.
English translation: J. Mir