So, I say --
What is going on?
What the devil are you doing in my room?
How dare --
Keep sitting.
Sit down!
If anyone so much as moved a muscle,
If anyone so much as moved a muscle, he'd die by my hand!
Right, Shehwar Ahmed,
Chairman of Shehwar Chemicals,
We were to talk about something.
You don't know who you're messing with.
I'll make an example of you for every pleb like you to watch.
That's my line.
I'll say it today.
What are you looking at?
Call the police!
That's the bleedin' limit -- What are you doing!?
The police come in after the incident.
Let me create the incident.
But first, tell me,
Tell me!
Say whatever you want to!
Tell them all
What you'd said over the phone!
Spill the beans!
Easy there, M. Danish, let go of my collar.
-Tell them all!
Why don't you say anything?
What'd your lawyers do to me if they didn't meet within two days, eh?
They'd have my hide?
Look.
I'm wearing a suit.
I figured I'd wear something nice before they have my hide.
Don't disturb me!
I'm in a meeting!
Come here.
What are you doing?
Danish -- Wh -- What is this?
-Here! Sit down!
Just pause and think for two minutes.
If you want to have my hide, you'd need your lawyers,
If you want to have my hide, you'd need your lawyers, or your hoodlums.
You'd call them. It'd take time.
But I need only two minutes to expose you.
Look,
My ex-wife, who's with you today,
She's been sold.
You've bought her.
I said, 'Fine',
'What's sold belongs to the buyer'.
But now, you're talking about my son,
And my son is all that remains of my pride.
You said that your lawyers would blow me to bits.
You made a mistake there.
You reminded me that I am my son's strength, not his weakness.
So, remember, Shehwar Ahmed,
If you dared threaten me again,
Or tried to strike a deal with me about my son,
I'd drag you by this tie of yours,
And expose you before everyone for real.
This incident would benefit all of you, too.
He can't fire you now.
If he dares to shout at you,
Go and tell everyone
About what happened here today.
Understood?
Have a nice day,
Shehwar Ahmed.
Leave me alone.
And here...
Here he falls.
Didn't fall.
He didn't fall! He's walking alright, mate!
And there...
Papa, ice cream.
C'mon.
Here.
That's it.
Run, quick.
Here.
Honestly?
I'm proud of you.
You're the bravest Papa in the world.
Innit?
You kicked and flipped his chair.
Yeah.
He fell face-first on the floor. His legs were trembling.
Just keep on laughing like that.
I'll take care of everyone.
Take care of everyone, I'll keep on laughing like this.
You're proper clever, aren't you?
You even said 'Will you marry me' to the teacher, didn't you?
You rapscallion.
Should I get things started with her?
And if she agreed?
Rumi!
You're a proper rapscallion, aren't you!
Get things started with her, will you?
She's very sweet.
Or should I get things started?
What'd you say to her?
I'd say, 'Marry my Papa. My father is the best father'.
Alright, get off now.
What is it?
I'm looking at you.
You look good.
Dashing.
Take care.
You too.
Bye.
Take care.
-Just a minute.
To be honest, if I were just a tad older, I would've married her.
Shut up, Rumi.
You're cross?
Yes.
Alright, sorry.
Okay.
Bye.
What happened?
Nothing.
Something's happened. One doesn't get injured just like that.
Tell me, Shehwar!
It seems you've fallen face-first!
-C'mon, mate.
Please, tell me, Shehwar, the worry kills me!
-First, decide who else you worry for so much that it kills you!
Shehwar!
By the Lord, what happened?
I've fallen face-first while striking a deal between you and your son.
Had a row?
A row?
Who'd dare have a row with me?
The bugger attacked me suddenly.
I wasn't expecting this.
Well, it isn't anything serious.
Just a few drops of blood.
Get me some water.
What about Rumi?
Honestly? I feel pity for myself.
The woman who was dying for me until yesterday
Is in pain to remember her son today.
May I know where I stand?
He won't meet you.
I talked to the lawyer.
The two of you can't meet as long as Rumi doesn't want to.
And please,
Control your motherly affection.
I can't meet that pleb again and again because of you.
I mean,
If he grabbed me by the collar,
What'd be left of my dignity?
So, that's the reply he's given after two days.
What?
He scared you and left.
He beat the chairman of Shehwar Chemicals
And left.
What should I do?
Go over to him with the police?
The chairman of Shehwar Chemicals has come to fight a pleb.
I could have him disappear
Without a trace.
But I've held back because of you.
When did I ask you to hold back?
If anything happened to the bugger,
You'd be the prime suspect.
The police will say plainly,
'This woman connived with her partner to kill him'.
And
The media!
If the media got wind of such a news,
They will spread it so much that even Trump would hear about it!
Your son is in his trap.
He teaches him not to meet his Maman.
He'd be a bit angry, too.
He'd say, too, 'I won't meet her'.
What are you looking at?
Try to understand.
Sometimes, it happens this way.
You'd said that it's your threat,
And your threat means something.
You'd have the bugger murdered by my hand.
Okay, I'll do something.
He'd bring his son to you.
I can't even meet someone in this condition.
What'd I say?
'My lover's ex-husband has beaten me'?
Sounds so cheap!
Why are you sitting here all alone? Why aren't you playing?
I'm resting...
When are you meeting your Mum?
I know...
You don't feel like meeting her now, but you have to sometime.
After all, she's your mother, innit?
She loves you so much.
I've seen it in her eyes.
I love her so much, too.
Didn't you see that?
My Papa loves her so much. You didn't see that either.
You've seen nothing.
Alright...
Let's talk about something else.
What?
Do you know
Your Papa called.
He said, 'He's very brave'.
He surprised me yesterday.
How?
The evil uncle, you know - my Maman's husband?
He beat him badly.
He used to threaten Papa a lot.
Don't you feel good?
I feel very good.
I know.
The three of us used to share a home.
Now, there's three different houses...
It's all because of that evil uncle.
It's all because of your Maman.
I'm sorry...
I didn't mean it.
I know you're right.
No --
I'd just --
Anyway, let's talk about something else.
What?
Get your Dad married.
I talked yesterday, and he said 'Shut up'!
He says that once a year, when he's very angry.
However did it occur to you?
It just did.
I've found a girl who looks very good with him.
He's seen her face too,
But he didn't agree. Scolded me.
Who is it?
Someone I know.
Someone you know?
Yes.
Is she sweet?
Very.
Why didn't he agree?
His heart's broken, teacher.
He won't get married now.
How say I talk to him?
Why are you laughing?
Nothing really. He'd scold you.
C'mon...
You'll see, he won't scold me.
I'll talk to him.
Laughing again?
I'm going to play.
Be done with it already.
A pleb's raised his hand on me because of you.
I took no action against him because of your son.
Now, if you're cross me like that,
Where'd I go?
And if you, being Shehwar Ahmed, are so helpless,
Tell me,
Where'd I go?
Helpless, as in?
I thought he'd be scared by your threat,
And out of fear, come running to me with Rumi,
And humbly say, 'Here'.
'Keep him with you'.
But you've come back with a broken nose.
You'd have him killed by my hand.
I want to meet Rumi.
Do whatever you must.
If you dared threaten me again,
Or tried to strike a deal with me about my son,
I'd drag you by this tie of yours,
And expose you for real.
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking of a solution.
Talk to him.
Explain to him
That he's being spared because of you and because of your son,
Otherwise, one can get a man killed for 30,000 in Karachi.
Say that you're his mother,
You have a right to meet him.
Tell him to be done with this lowly attitude,
Tell him to be done with this lowly attitude, or he'd be found in a sack somewhere.
What are you saying?
Just request him if you want to meet your son.
Even I'd go down on my knees for your sake.
I should go to meet him?
Yes.
Go.
I'd be done with the issues at the office by then.
Just see what I'll do.
What are you looking at?
So what, if it seems a bit cowardly
So what, if it seems a bit cowardly to request like this?
No problem.
Fine by me, for your sake.
I just want to see you happy.
But one thing's for sure, Mehwish,
I won't spare him.
We'd decided on 4,000. Alright?
He's leaving because of his wife.
Naturally.
A man's head sinks in shame.
It becomes difficult
To look those close to oneself in the eye.
But I didn't quite get it, Mr Sheikh.
All of it happened so suddenly.
Got wind one day that his wife's leaving,
And now that Mr Danish's following suit.
Why did she leave him?
She didn't leave him, Monsieur, she's eloped.
She had an affair
With her boss.
Oh...
Would you look at that!
Money can be so magnetic!
M. Danish is coming.
By the Lord, M. Danish, I'm very sad that you're leaving.
It feels like someone very dear to me is leaving.
Please forgive me if I've ever done something wrong.
Not at all, sir.
You were so saintly.
Please, forgive us if we've ever done something wrong.
-No. Nothing of the sort...
There's nothing like that.
You didn't mention where you're going.
I haven't really thought about it.
I'd keep my things at my friend's.
I might even leave the country.
But I'd come to meet you.
Sure, M. Danish.
We'll meet again.
If the Lord wills so.
I started a row with you,
Broke our friendship...
Please forgive me.
No, mate -- Danish --
We had a row because of me.
The fault was mine.
I don't even know what I've uttered just now --
Please forgive me.
If the Lord wills, we'll meet again.
Thank you so much for caring.
Take care.
Let me know if you need anything.
Alright?
Goodbye, M. Danish.
Goodbye.
Show them this clause.
Sure.
And discuss it with the lawyers.
I will, and I'll submit my report.
Sir,
Please call the Stock Exchange.
What happened?
The share's fallen by 25 Rupees.
25 Rupees?
As in --
As in -- The market's crashing?
No, sir.
The market's rising by 14 points.
Hello?
I'm going.
Where?
To meet Danish.
Go, then. Why are you calling me?
What's going on?
And what about the strike?
The strike's been going on for two days.
So, there's been no work?
Obviously, sir.
How would there be any work when no one's working?
Why?
I'd revised their salaries.
I'd said, 'Give them a raise'.
No, sir, you'd strongly refused to give even a penny's worth of raise.
What's gotten into you, man!
I'm saying it now, 'Give them a raise'!
And call before revising the salaries.
Yes, sir.
Leave.
Madame!
If you're here to meet M. Danish, he's not here.
What do you mean, 'He's not here'?
He's sold the flat and left.
What?
Where'd he go?
He didn't tell anything. Not even to me.
Does nobody know?
Nobody.
Is it over?
What's over?
I'm talking about the strike.
Are you alright?
Who is it?
What?
I'm asking who is it?
It's Mehwish, Shehwar.
Oh!
Why didn't you tell me?
What is it?
Danish has sold the flat and left.
He's left?
The gutless bugger's fled!
The GM called today.
Said, 'They're giving a raise to everyone'.
'Call the strike off'.
I said, 'Oh please',
'Send it in writing'.
Revise the salary
Of every single employee,
Show me the difference from the old salary,
And then, we'd call off the strike if we approve.
The shares have fallen by 2,500 Rupees today.
Monsieur le Chairman, I say, invest everything in your account.
I have, too.
Purchased shares worth 450,000 Rupees.
So have I.
Invested every penny lying in my account,
And whatever I got after selling my wife's jewellery.
Monsieur le Chairman, I say, invest everything in your account.
I have, too.
Purchased shares worth 450,000 Rupees.
So have I.
Invested every penny lying in my account,
And whatever I got after selling my wife's jewellery.
Enough with it already.
You've been drinking since 8 p.m.
Do you know,
I've lost in this business for the first time.
The wretched unionists won.
Cost me 132 million.
And I'd be robbed of it every year.
Once the salaries have been raised,
They don't come down.
You've just raised their salaries.
It's not a loss, Shehwar.
Technically,
It's a loss, sweetheart.
The more the salaries,
The less the profit.
Plus, live in constant fear of the buggers' strike.
Always thinking
When the next strike could be.
Alright, relax.
Go to sleep.
How can I sleep?
I'm so worried...
You're so worried...
How could I sleep?
And that bugger, your ex-husband,
Has fled.
You couldn't meet him,
Nor talk to him.
How would you meet your son now?
I can understand...
I know a mother's sorrow...
I know what you must be going through.
You don't need to worry about me.
I've left it to God --
-No.
Don't leave it to God.
He's not happy with women who go for a divorce.
Do whatever you do
Hiding from Him.
You're drunk, Shehwar.
No, I'm not drunk.
I'm absolutely fine.
And
I'm planning
To go on a trip.
How say we go to London for a few days,
And forget everything that's happened to us?
Let's get married one of these days.
Then, we can go to London.
What is it?
I think...
I'm drunk...
I --
I should --
Catch some sleep...
Hello?
Salman Ibrahim?
Yes, who is it?
It's Danish, mate.
Danish Akhtar.
However did you remember me today, boyo?
I needed your help.
But first, how are you? And how's Mehwish?
And I heard you have a son?
How old is he?
6 years.
Must be cute.
Yes.
And what about her?
Your English rose?
We'll meet
And talk.
Tell me,
You work at the stock exchange, right?
Work?
You're underestimating me, boyo.
I'm a member.
Ayesha and I have bought a membership.
It's still going on with the two of you, eh?
I'd heard you'd gotten married.
Yes, I've gotten married,
But I've got love going on too.
Very bad, mate.
No idea what you folks mean by marriage and love...
Listen to the whole thing, mun, I've married her. Ayesha.
Then, just say that.
I do have the licence to love now, don't I?
Openly.
Alright, what is it that you need?
I'll be coming to you tomorrow.
We'll talk then.
Come at 10 a.m.
Okay.
Done.
Bye.
And give love to Ayesha.
I've given her so much love... I swear by you!
I'd like some tea.
Just one cup.
Thank you.
Teacher!
Hi, Rumi.
What is it?
Did you talk to Papa?
About what?
You'd said you'd tell Papa to get married.
I will, sure, but first, introduce me to the girl.
Teacher, trust me, she's super cute.
You're still a kid and you don't know.
Looks aren't everything.
It's time for Miss Zara's class. Double time!
If you want to see people running after money,
Come to the Stock Exchange.
I've seen it outside, too.
All people do is chase money.
Earning your riches, eh?
I've left my job.
Why?
I've come to earn my riches.
You're alright, aren't you, boyo?
Yes, I'm fine.
Nope.
There's something that I can see more visibly on your face than before.
What is it?
Tell me.
Specks of dust from my last journey.
I'll wash it off in a moment.
You've come here on a bike?
Anyway...
How are Mehwish and Rumi?
All good and merry?
I've never asked Rumi,
But Mehwish sure is merry.
Anyway,
Have something.
You've just had one sip of tea.
I'll have the tea.
Alright.
So, what brings you here?
I've come here to invest.
Right. How much money do you have?
7.8 million.
Splendid.
So, ol' chap's been earning his riches, eh?
I've sold my flat.
Dad had bought it.
Oh.
Alright, I'll get you through to my portfolio,
You can know which shares to purchase.
Just Shehwar Chemicals.
Shehwar Chemicals?
As in, you'd invest everything in Shehwar Chemicals?
Yes.
Did someone tell you to?
I'm telling you.
Its shares have dropped from 60 Rupees to 12.10 in 6 days,
And it's likely that it'll drop below face value.
It won't drop below face value.
How do you know?
Gut feeling...
Oh!
You're telling me!
Alright.
Not bad.
Even if you face a loss, it won't be too much.
I said I won't face a loss.
Mustafa!
How much for Shehwar Chemicals?
11.20 Rupees.
Ask him to purchase as many shares as 7.8 million can get.
Wait for 2 hours, boyo,
It'll come down to face value.
It won't.
Tell him not to wait and buy them.
Right,
Purchase 700,000 shares.
I'm saying, purchase them.
How much?
Don't look at me, just tell me the amount.
7.740 million Rupees.
7.740...
And your commission?
Shut up, boyo...
You can get this cheque encashed.
What's up with you?
Why have you left your job?
I thought that when everyone's earning his riches,
Do I have a screw loose?
And
Who's recommended Shehwar Chemicals?
Some people at the bistro
Where I have my breakfast were talking about it.
I believed what they said.
Rubbish.
Did you ask Mehwish?
I don't ask Mehwish anymore.
Oh?
When did that happen?
Ever since she divorced me and left.
What?
What's this cod? Where is she?
With someone else.
I'll take my leave.
What are you saying? Who's she with?
The owner of Shehwar Chemicals.
She's marrying him.
Well, if it isn't the Reverend from our University!
How are you?
And how is that bonnie lass?
I have to go, Ayesha...
Where do you have to go? Sit.
No --
Let him go today.
Don't stop him today.
We'll meet again.
Alright?
Goodbye.
What's happened to him?
That which should never happen.
The two have been divorced.
Mehwish and Danish?
I don't believe you...
She's marrying the owner of Shehwar Chemicals.
Hello?
Hello...?
Yes?
I'm getting calls from America on the landline.
The bell rings, and I answer it, but nobody says anything.
Where's Diwan?
He'd be somewhere around here.
Alright, disconnect.
Don't answer the phone if you get a call again.
Why?
Didn't I just say, don't answer it?
Yes?
It's down to 10.30.
So?
There's still time. Bear this small loss and sell them.
How long before the market closes?
2 hours.
Then, ask how much the share costs when the market closes.
See you.
Goodness...
Yes, Mr Mushtaq?
It's 2 right now; I'd be there by 3.
I'll look for it.
Alright, bye.
Come.
You won't find a 500 sq. yard furnished home in Karachi at this rate again, M. Danish!
I can give it in writing.
150,000 a month?
Yes.
As if it's a small amount!
Plus, 11 months' worth of advance...
Don't you like it?
I do like it, but...
It's tiny.
This 500 sq. yard home is tiny?
Well, it'd do. It's fine.
Seal the deal for ten days from now.
But you'd said you're in a hurry.
I'm saying it because I'm in a hurry.
Here...
Here's 50,000 in advance.
Just a minute.
Hello?
Yes, Salman?
Honestly,
Who told you that the share would go upwards?
I'd told you, some people at the bistro were talking about it.
Why, what happened?
2.50 Rupees!
Sell them, Danish.
Sell them right now!
Whoever gave you that membership, mate?
You say, 'Sell them' when the share goes up,
And 'Sell them' when it goes down.
Just wait and watch what happens.
I'll sell them after 8 days.
How much is the rent for this again?
-150,000 a month.
For a 500 sq. yard furnished home...
-Yes.
It's a trifle, Mr Mushtaq.
English translation: J. Mir