I'm whilin' sleepless nights waitin' for you,
Eyes searching just for you,
I know you're a-mine
It's destined by the Divine,
My Sweeting...
I've got nothin' but you...
I'd die without you...
Episode 1: (Un)Real Dreams
The Royal Family is known for timeless love stories, the best-known of which is perhaps Prince Charles and Lady Diana's.
And it appears this young man has picked up the baton.
His is a fairytale of a Prince falling for an ordinary girl and making her a Princess of the United Kingdom, and the Queen of his heart.
The Royal Family won't let the world forget the story of Charles and Diana.
Blimey, they all want to be TV commentators these days.
Just look at his atrocious English!
He doesn't even know that Harry's sixth in line.
He's as likely to be the King of the UK as William is to grow hair.
Lovely comparison.
O Lord! Bless my daughters too!
Doesn't she look much older than him?
She does. Because she is.
She looks so... Ordinary. But Diana! Ahh... She was one graceful lady...
I'm watching, Mum...
Who's stopping you?
I'm listening, too.
-It's all so wrong... Everything he's said.
'A tale of undying love! Prince Charles and Lady Diana'? Oh, please! He doesn't even know how many times they had a domestic! And the divorce! Jesus...
That's what happens when you don't listen to your parents! All this love story balderdash... It ain't no good!
Not again...
The lights gotta go off whenever I want to watch telly!
How 'bout a nice cuppa on that note?
My one purpose in life, innit? Get yous alls a nice cuppa.
Nah, get me some fritters too if you like!
Everyone else has got a UPS!
Hear that?
It's so costly! But I'm sure Salahuddin will work something out. If only she could learn to wait!
I wonder what kind of girls get to live out a fairytale with their Prince Charming...
What are you thinking, Salma? You've got to live out the tea girl's life!
I was wondering who it could be...
Blimey, you're nearly blind already, but you'd still rather be at this computer at midnight!
I had my glasses on until just now...
Anyway, what's all this craze about? I mean, they got married... What now?
It's their wedding.
-It's over. What's next? You droppin' them home?
I wish...
Shut it down. Right now. You're at this computer all night! You have no idea about the electricity bill, do you?
I guess I'm gonna have to fix it tomorrow.
I'm whilin' sleepless nights waitin' for you,
Eyes searching just for you,
Every breath eager for you,
Gettin' by on memories of you...
Hey, Sohail!
Come in, Your Majesty! With due respect, may I say that you're late again?
-Proper mess last night, I tell you!
A bunch o' terrorists abducted me Dad! We looked for 'im all night... The cops found 'im this morning!
You ever ashamed of yourself?
You're late everyday. But you had to get your Dad abducted this time!
Ask anyone you like. They got on 'is rickshaw and took 'im to the National Stadium at gunpoint!
What've you been watching these days?
-What?
I swear to God --
-Oh, can it... Just get me the laptops that came in yesterday. 'I swEAr tO GoD'.
Lemme finish it!
-How 'bout I boot you out and finish it for you?
I forgot two screws... Sorry!
Just a second...
You better not be late again!
Guess what I'm gonna give you on your birthday?
Yeah?
Glasses that don't look from the previous century. I mean, who in the world wears that?
They're priceless. Dad got it from the US. Mum says you can't get one like it anywhere.
That's because it's ancient. By the way, why does your Mum have to give you all the old stuff? You look, like, ten years older!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © ZEE5