Mum...
You stopped Malika from going to university?
Yes.
Because I don't trust her anymore.
She's very upset.
I know.
She's upset that her Aunt's coming.
Do you think she'd give in if you forced her?
She's been engaged to him for years. I've just got to convince her for the marriage.
I don't think she'd give in.
Wake Her Majesty up. Tell her breakfast's ready.
I'm taking it to her room. I don't think she's coming out today.
Okay. Keep it there even if she refuses.
So that she knows we don't care if she refuses anything. Anything, get it?
Yes.
Here's your breakfast.
No thanks. Take it back.
Hello? I said something.
Mum told me to keep it here even if you refused.
Oh?
She wants me to know she doesn't care, right?
You're upset because Aunt's coming, right?
No. I'm upset because Mum's invited her!
You've been engaged. You'll get married to him soon.
Engaged? I don't accept it!
Everyone else does.
And who do you think could be better than Asim?
Why?
What've I done to deserve someone like Asim?
Please don't say that. It angers the Lord.
No idea why Dad named me Malika [Empress]!
For all that barbarism, I'm sure he would've named you Anne Bonny!
Ha ha ha, get this vaudeville outta here, or you're getting a proper pasting!
Malika, my dear... Please get this hatred for Asim out of you.
He loves you so much. He'll take care of you!
Gordon Bennett! You know everything!
You're quite the diviner! Go and ask Mum to put up a board outside. 'Zahida the Augurer'! 'We tell girls in the mire their destiny'!
Let me be very clear - my dreams begin where Asim's end!
Don't you realise you're driving a wedge between Mum and Aunt?
-So I should take the fall! You can't be serious!
Who'd you marry if not Asim?
I'm sure there's someone the Lord would've destined for me...
Aye, but you're not ready to marry him.
Shut your gob! Take this breakfast and get out!
Can't you hear me? Take it back!
Growing insolent every day!
I was thinking...
Yeah?
I'm going to Dubai for work.
What?
What about me? If you're not here...
Just let me finish.
I think it'll be fabulous if you came with me.
Me?
Yeah.
It'll do you good to go somewhere for a change.
No way.
Why?
You know I don't want to stand in your way.
You know it hurts me when you say that.
I want to tour the world with you.
Dubai's just the beginning.
Okay...
But we aren't really... You know...
We can't go out together until we take things forward.
You're the only one stopping things from going forward.
Just leave it, will you?
Do you know what's the best time for me?
When I'm with you.
Like right now.
I'm having my best time.
How smooth...
Well, at least say yes to this...
Yes? What is it?
Take the bike. Use it.
I can't.
My family asks me so many things if I do.
I've got two sisters who haven't been married yet.
I worry more for them than roaming around on a bike.
You're right...
You've got a lot of responsibility.
But we're together... I'm sure we can solve any problems that come up.
Trust God.
Okay?
And leave your bike here if your family asks about it.
Keep the keys. Use it when you like.
Yes?
Thank you.
Sure you're not coming to Dubai? Oh, I was just kidding.
Please don't mind my asking, but you said Malika doesn't want to get married a few days back. How'd you convince her so quickly?
Aqil thought she should get married. She can continue studying from over there.
But why? Didn't you always oppose him?
Because you're not well.
Please. Don't let emotions make you take a decision which could cost Asim and Malika later.
Don't you want Malika to be your daughter-in-law?
-What are you saying?
You know I was so delighted at the engagement! More importantly, you know how much my son loves her! Despite all her bitterness and spite!
So, what's your problem?
-Aunt...
We need to talk.
Go in!
We're talking about something important.
It's my future you're deciding. I have a right to speak!
Yes? Go on.
Mum thinks I'll run off with someone if I went to university.
But they don't know that one could run off on the day of the wedding.
Mind your tongue!
All I want to say is... If you tried to force me, you better be prepared to never see my face again!
I wish He'd never given me someone like her...
Don't worry. You won't have to do anything of the sort because of Asim.
It's up to you.
Hello, Aunt! What a pleasant surprise!
Hello! How are you?
What's up with her?
Nothing. Just a bit worried about Malika.
I've told her not to worry about anything.
Everything will be taken care of. Just fix the date.
We're not ready for the marriage just yet.
We're not fixing the date until she's done with her studies.
But you said it yourself, Aunt...
It occurred to me it'd disturb Malika if we got about with the wedding and all...
Okay, then.
I'm sure you would've thought about it...
Mum... Ask Munni to get me some black coffee.
Okay.
Alright, I'll go change. Take care.
Salma...
Why didn't you tell Aqil?
I'd rather keep it between us.
Aqil's a man... Malika's brother. He wouldn't be able to take it if he heard what she said.
It can't be hidden for long...
May the Lord guide her... I won't tell Asim how much the love of his life despises him either.
And... Let destiny unfold...
Asim?
Everything alright? You look worried.
I'm good. Everything's okay.
Are you sure?
Yeah. All good.
Hello?
Hello.
Who is it?
You're the only girl I ever gave my visiting card.
But you ask me who I am?
It's you!
I'm sorry but I didn't save your number.
I wasn't expecting that.
Anyway...
I want to meet you.
Haven't you thought about it long enough?
You don't get such a chance twice.
People long to get a chance all their lives...
I don't get it.
-That's why I want to meet you.
I'll tell you everything you need to know.
I can also pick you up if you want.
I'll let you know.
Quickly.
Your luck's in but it may be out any moment.
Sir?
Bye.
But how'd he get my number?
Well, what do I care?
I told them we're in no hurry.
Malika can finish her education.
Was she at home?
Yeah.
Aqil's said she can only go to university after her marriage.
Blimey, the twit...
Sometimes, the most unexpected people can be the most wise.
What is it?
What's happened?
It's not like they'd tell us.
Remember - nobody would tell what's up with their daughters.
Mum...
Why do I feel there's something you're not telling me?
You deserve better, Asim.
Did she refuse?
You ask as if you hope she won't.
I hope you had no trouble finding your way.
Of course, Aunt. I used the map.
You could've asked Waqas to pick you up.
I didn't want to disturb him.
I'm sure he would've loved to.
You're right, Aunt, but I don't like to depend on someone so much.
Okay. I get it...
But we're here for you. Let us know if you need anything.
Thank you, that's really sweet of you.
You could've brought Faizan along.
He left for work. He had a meeting.
-Oh...
Hey!
What a surprise! How are you?
Very well. How are you?
Great. Never been better! You look nice.
You look awesome as well!
How'd you come here?
-On my own.
On you own? You drove all the way?
Yeah, what are you so intrigued about?
Aunt was surprised too.
Because you mentioned the traffic here...
Nothing's impossible.
I even said I'll find my way!
You could've told me.
Hear that?
You just need to ask.
I've got to take this call. I'll be back.
Know what?
Mum never talks to me so softly.
Aren't you always fishing for sympathies?
I know she loves you so much.
How say you love me too... A bit?
Bli --
Why, is it --
Wait a minute.
Hey, buddy, what's up?
Hi.
I was coming over. I thought I'd check.
I'm home, but busy.
What do you mean?
We've got guests.
Who are you kidding?
Just say Novera's there.
Alright, see you at the gym in the evening.
Bye.
-Bye.
Sorry. One of the lads.
Why'd you say no? I was about to leave.
But why?
No way, you're not allowed to go. Not just yet.
I'm sure Mum would rather you have lunch...
Absolutely. No one's going out. I've prepared your favourite Thai dish.
Thank you, Aunt.
-We're having lunch together, okay?
Just perfect!
-Thank you, very sweet of you!
Where are you going?
I'm coming in a minute!
-Okay.
So...
I talked to Mr Atif...
He says I should be thinking about your marriage.
Atif said that?
Of course.
I just meant -- What's Atif got to do with my marriage?
He's divorced his own wife, set himself free... And worrying about my marriage!
What's up with him? I'll talk to him.
Don't you dare!
Don't you dare say a word to Mr Atif!
Why?
We've got no right to talk about his personal life.
If Atif cares about my marriage so much, he should give me a room here.
I wouldn't keep my wife in this servant's quarters in the basement, after all!
Why?
If your Mum can live here, why can't your wife?
Mum...
Not everyone settles for small things like you...
Well, Noriyan, life would be too difficult with anyone who doesn't.
She's very nice, Mum.
Mum...
If you met her, you'd realise she's all I need to light up my life.
So Mr Atif was right!
What?
Don't you like your Uncle's daughters?
Uncle's daughters?
No, Mum, I like someone else!
What about her?
She can't live without me.
A fellow student?
Yes.
I want to take you to her.
Please tell me you're coming.
Once I'm back from the village, okay.
Thank you, Mum!
Honestly, though...
Atif's a bit strange.
If he cares so much about my marriage, why did he send his wife away?
You can be whatever you want...
But you'll have to do just as I say.
That's why I'm here, Atif.
Good.
I can take you to heights you've never even dreamt of.
Magazine covers, fashion shoots, films, dramas - you name it. You'll have it.
Do you live alone in this mansion?
Yeah. Not counting the maid who lives here, yeah.
But don't worry.
She's a servant.
She lives on my money.
She's got a son, too...
I'm supporting him too.
I told you...
You have no right to say anything about Mr Atif's life.
Better stay quiet.
Okay.
Sorry.
Turn off the pool filter, get it covered. Do something about the mover or there will be flooding. And keep the bags in the car. Not this --
-Okay.
Good evening.
-Good evening.
-Blimey, Zahir!
Where've you been?
No call, no text...
Mum's back from London. I was busy with her.
Oh... I totally forgot! Why didn't you tell me?
What else do I have to tell you? And for how long?
What is it?
Angry with me?
Why would I be?
You didn't even bother to call and ask me where I am or how I'm doing, or what I've been up to... For three days!
You know what I'm like... Forgetful, messy...
You weren't this way. But you're staying this way.
You shouldn't be saying that. Come.
Let's go see Aunt.
Mum's not home. She's gone for lunch with friends.
So that's why you're here. Okay.
I'm here to tell you I'll be joining you in Dubai two days later.
What?
Why?
But you were so excited about the Dubai distribution!
-I know. I was excited, wanted to come and all...
But something's come up.
Anyway, I've talked to the folks over there, they'll take care of everything without me.
I'll take care of everything else when I get there.
Look after yourself, I'm off. Bye.
But -- Hey -- Zahir -- Za --!
What's up with him?
At least ask Mum!
-She ain't even talking to me!
Do you think she'd talk to you if you had your way like this?
I have to go, Munni.
Okay, have your breakfast.
No way, I'm late!
It's ready!
I'll miss the bus!
-Let her go.
If she missed her 'bus', we'll regret it the rest of our lives.
I have to go, Mum.
I'll tell you everything when I'm back.
Should I get breakfast, Mum?
Hello!
Come, I'll drop you.
I don't need any favours from anyone.
It's no favour, Malika. I want to talk about something.
What is it?
I want to tell you something.
I've already told Aunt all I have to say about it.
You could've just honoured my love...
Mum always thought you hated me and you proved her right.
Believe it if you still can't.
And you better not stand in my way like that again.
Mr Asim!
The boss is calling you.
I'm coming.
Ayesha, please email these.
May I come in, sir?
Yes.
Good morning.
'Morning.
You wanted to talk about something?
Yes sir. I heard there are a few openings in marketing. I wanted to talk about that.
Yeah. A few people left the job... Know someone you can recommend?
Yes, sir. My cousin. He's done a BA.
I'm sure he's got some experience?
No, sir. He doesn't have any experience.
But I'm sure he'll do well. He works really hard.
He isn't really qualified for this job... But I trust your judgement.
Bring him tomorrow. I'd like to meet him.
Thank you, sir. I'm on it.
Good. You may go.
What's his problem?
Yeah, Asim?
I'm sorry, were you sleeping?
Did you call to ask that?
No, I called to tell you that I've talked to my boss.
He's called you for an interview tomorrow.
Interview?
Yeah. Tomorrow. And I'm 100% sure you'll get this job.
Good.
Alright, if you're so sure... I'll be there.
Okay. Good. See you tomorrow.
Oh, wow... What a surprise!
Good morning.
-Good morning.
How'd you get my pictures?
If I could get your number... Getting your pictures is no big deal.
Don't take me wrong.
It's my job.
Telling people who have no idea their true worth.
And, believe me, you're worth it.
Please, take a seat.
Thank you.
Tea or coffee?
No, thanks, I'll be leaving quickly. I've got to go back.
Blimey, you've barely come here and you're in a hurry to leave?
Just a second.
Two cups of coffee. Quick.
Please shut it down, will you?
By the way... I like your personality.
Why did you want to meet me?
Malika... As pretty and proud as your name...
That's a good one!
I'm serious.
I knew the moment I saw your pictures that the camera will fall in love with you.
You could be the next superstar in modelling or TV.
What happened? Why so nervous?
I can't get into what you're talking about.
Just one photoshoot.
That's all it takes to change your fate.
I won't be allowed to.
Who do you need to ask?
Family or someone else?
I mean, you're so lovely... You must have a boyfriend.
Or a lover whose happiness means the world to you.
Yeah, right.
Think again.
I'm sure he can't help you live out the kinds of dreams I can.
That's right, but...
I don't want this to drive a wedge between us.
And if I promised that nothing of the sort will ever happen?
Keep it here.
Thank you.
You happened to come when I was looking for a fresh face.
For an international brand.
Imagine the exposure...
Imagine, that's your first chance.
It's just like a dream come true for you.
Okay...
If it doesn't suit you, you may leave...
I'm really surprised, though...
Why'd you come here in the first place if you had all these problems, didn't want to do it?
Please, sit.
Sit.
Someone so lovely and beautiful as you...
Couldn't possibly miss this chance!
Thousands dream of this.
You're the one who gets to live the dream.
I'm worried about my family.
They won't allow me.
-Don't worry about that.
No one will hear. Trust me.
It's an international shoot. It isn't even for the local market.
But --
-Just a minute.
Here's your advance.
Think carefully.
If you said no, I'm cancelling the cheque, and if you said yes, you're getting double this amount at the end of the shoot.
Think about it
And let me know.
Malika ain't here!
It was yous twos yesterday... Just her today...
What's up, mate?
No idea about today. She did text she's busy.
And yesterday?
Where were you two?
No secrets from friends!
I swear it wasn't planned!
Now you're suckin' diesel!
So, did you say it?
Obviously, they wouldn't have just stared at each other.
C'mon!
So did you tell her your secret?
Did you?
-So?
Did you tell her?
I couldn't talk about it.
Worried she'd leave you if she found out?
She loves me, she can't just leave me!
-Go and tell her, then.
What's your problem?
-Jeez! Be done with it!
Tell him to watch what he's saying!
-You can't watch what you're doing!
What's your problem? If you said anything of the sort again, I'll forget you're my friend!
Splendid...
Hammer some sense into him!
Just look at him! So much for friendship!
We try to talk some sense into him, but he has a problem with it!
-Just don't say anything then! You always mess everything up!
He's our friend!
He's got trouble coming his way if he doesn't listen!
Jeez, mate, calm down!
He's realised he was wrong to hide his reality from Malika.
Just give him some time to fix it.
Just pause and think.
I tell you, you're made for this field.
When I first saw you --
I'm sorry...
You can take your call. No problem.
Hello?
Blimey, Malika, where are you?
I've been texting you for ages, why don't you reply?
I told you I'm busy. I won't be coming today.
And I wrote so much after that! Why didn't you reply?
I told you I'm busy.
I'll talk to you later. Bye.
Hello? M --
Who were you explaining yourself to?
I think you should stay at an arm's length from whoever makes you explain yourself.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV