How do you like it?
Just fantastic!
I can't even believe that's me!
Why?
Hasn't anyone ever told you you're so photogenic?
The mirror tells me everyday.
I don't need to bother asking anyone else.
Blimey...
That's some real attitude.
I like it.
Sit.
Thank you.
Do you know that being so lovely has its benefits?
You can get a lot if you know how to use your charms!
I can't be that special.
No.
There's something about you that pulled someone like me to you.
And I really mean it.
You're too kind.
What does he do?
Who?
The one you're thinking about.
Oh, forget him...
No, seriously.
I'm jealous.
I hope you wouldn't mind it...
Yes?
How say we go out for lunch today?
Please, don't bother yourself, it's okay.
It'll be my pleasure.
Okay.
Thank you.
And sorry, but I nearly forgot.
You forgot to sign the contract. It's just a formality. Sign it.
The other two pages as well.
That's nice.
Thank you.
We can go tomorrow if he's really sick.
I talked to Uncle. He's better now.
This headache won't go away so easily... It bothers for days and days...
Why don't you go today?
We can visit him again in a few days.
I'll take you to the doctor.
He'll give me the same pills.
There's no other way.
Your Aunt called to inform us. It won't look proper if neither of us went there.
Okay...
I'll go.
But I won't stay there too long.
Be back by the evening. Don't hurry so much that they mind it.
Of course.
Get some rest.
But of course...
I'd cooked lunch for Mr Atif last night.
I've taken the pills. I'll get some rest.
Mum...
I don't want to go alone...
It's not like he'd eat you...
You don't know how much he loves you.
I know, Mum.
That's why I don't want to go alone.
Everyone would be asking about you.
Call me when you get there. I'll talk to him.
I'll tell him about this headache.
Go.
Okay.
But please don't get back on duty when I've left.
Good Lord, get going. You'll get late.
Go...
Okay, I'm going.
If you don't feel better, just ask Uncle to take you to the hospital.
-Yeah, I will... Go, now.
Bye.
What kind of music do you like?
Depends on the mood.
I listen to what I feel like.
And what do you feel like listening to right now?
I'm good with what's on right now.
Want to come over to my place?
Sir?
I forgot some of my papers. I'll go get them, and you can have a look around. What do you say?
As you say...
We'll be stopping at my place for a while.
Over here.
This here's the drawing room. That's the dining room.
How do you like it?
Lovely.
Indeed it is today...
Please, sit.
Isn't anyone else around?
Now that you're here, I don't need anyone else.
You totally forgot! You'd come here to get some papers...
Ah, yes...
You said you make a fantastic coffee?
I'd like to try some.
The kitchen's that way.
Okay...
Hey...
He lies when he calls you.
Only I can you your dream life.
You're still here?
I was a bit sick, so...
I came here when I heard the car stop. Thought you might need something.
Anyway... My apologies...
I'm sorry, she's our maid. She lives in the basement.
She won't be coming back. Sit.
No, I think we should get going.
I told you, she won't be coming back. Have some coffee?
Some other day? Let's get going -- Please?
Okay...
Come.
Aunt!
Hello!
Hello, my dear.
Here.
-What's these sweets for?
Because I'm done with my exams! Right?
I've bought a car.
Bless you. Bless you, my dear.
Bless you, Asim.
But you've got to take me for a ride!
Anyday you want, Munni!
-Done.
Hello...
Hello.
-Hey.
Malika...
Asim's bought a new car.
Lemme guess. The four-banger parked outside.
Yeah. How do you like it?
You're not leaving before having some tea.
Have some of this.
I think I'll pass. Besides, I'm on a diet.
I'll bring these on a plate.
Malika...
At least congratulate me, will you?
Congratulations.
I bought a car because you didn't like my bike.
Changing things you don't like. Good for you.
Please, could you not be offhand for a change?
Don't expect any love from me.
Everyone's got the right to wish to live, and you're the only reason I'm alive.
Jesus, be done with your cornball dialogues already.
Please don't try my patience.
I think I'll pass, Aunt. I got to go.
Why'd Asim leave so suddenly?
Good for him...
If he's not respected...
You won't change!
I'll get your tea.
Congratulations. God bless you.
Amen.
Get ready. You're the first one to get to ride it. You got to do as I say!
No, you're so tired. I'm not going anywhere.
So you don't like the car?
What are you saying, Asim? Who'd like it if not your mother?
Okay, then, get ready quickly. I won't take a no this time. In fact, we're eating out today, and I'm taking you shopping!
Do you think I should be roaming about at my age? How say you take Mal --
She can ride all she wants when the time comes. But it's your turn today.
Go and get ready quick.
-Okay, give me a moment. I'll go change.
What are your hours like? It's so late in the evening!
You don't worry about hours when you're making a bundle.
You may be making a bundle, but it doesn't mean you have no schedule!
These overheads are not for our work, but to shut us up.
So that we can't turn them down or object to anything.
Had your lunch?
Yes.
The least one could do is be happy for someone else.
Asim had come here to celebrate with us even after he was practically thrown out.
He doesn't want to celebrate with us.
He wants that I should smile, laugh and live for him and him alone!
You don't know it... But that's his love.
It ain't no love, Mum, he's so pig-headed!
You're pig-headed!
You can't even be happy for someone.
They were all wishing you well.
Thank them all...
Uncle's much better now.
He even said he'd be coming here to see you.
God bless him, he's so nice.
May He bless his children.
Amen.
He told me he didn't really feel like sending Noriyan back. Didn't he ask you to stay?
How'd you even think I'd stay there when you're unwell?
Hey! It was just a headache! The pill worked and it's gone.
Anyway...
How are Naazi and Ashi?
Naazi's fine. Prepping for her private FA.
And I didn't even see Ashi.
That's great... Bless her!
That's how a modest girl should be!
Honestly, though, Mum... I didn't really like it.
I told you...
I don't want to...
You should've told Uncle.
It'd be too bad if he hoped for something.
Your Uncle is hopeful you'd do as he wishes.
But I can't marry Ashi!
But why?
Just say it, will you, Noriyan?
You're my only son.
I have to do what makes you happy.
I love someone, Mum.
She's very nice.
Aye...
The one you love can never be bad, innit?
She's really nice, Mum!
Should I bring her here?
-Don't even think about it!
I won't like anyone coming here with you before getting married to you.
I mean --
Would you be any different from --
Mr Atif?
What?
Did Atif bring anyone here? A model, maybe?
No idea...
Someone like himself, maybe.
Soaring too high in her dreams...
Don't take it so wrongly... It's his profession... She must've been here for some work.
No idea how her type can forget about their parents' honour... Or even their own!
Gotta say, Atif's very smart.
He brought her here when he thought you won't be around.
Just great...
Oh, please...
It ain't good at all!
I better not hear anything about it again.
Here.
Thanks, Mum.
Zahida called. She congratulated me.
She's as delighted as you.
She said she'll be coming, but I know she won't.
Why?
She's embarrassed because of Malika's refusal.
Tell her she's got nothing to be ashamed of.
I'll go and get her here myself.
Where does Sana live?
-No idea, Mum.
I never asked.
And you never will. I'm sure you would never have asked her to sit like I did.
Why should I? She was there for work.
But she stopped to congratulate me.
You seem a bit too interested in her.
She's so nice, if you ask me. Almost like family.
Aye, she's nice. Cares for everyone at the office.
Including you?
Bring her here someday. She said she'd come.
She just said it, so to speak.
Whatever...
Bring her here if she wants to.
Let's go for dinner today.
No, I have to go. I got late yesterday.
You got to forget about the time if you want to get where you want to.
Yeah, but Mum doesn't really know about what I'm doing.
Well, then, just tell her. It'll ease her worry.
Not just yet...
I haven't even told the one who will support me.
Who? Your boyfriend?
Good.
You can't be sure he'll support you.
He loves me so much.
A man fears for his honour when his lady tries to race ahead.
He forgets everything about love.
No way.
Besides, his Dad's a big businessman.
Oh?
They're not conservative like my family.
He'd be glad to know I'm doing something big, something good.
Ever met his family?
No. His parents don't live here. He'll introduce me to them when they're back.
How innocent...
Anyway... Good for you...
Don't tell him anything about me or the shoots until his parents have been to your place.
Why?
There's some things you need time to find out...
Just wait and watch.
He's very nice, Atif. He's not like that.
Let's just say that for now...
I'm sure time will tell if we're right...
Anyway, don't worry. Cheer up.
This ain't the time to get worried.
Have your coffee.
I've finished.
What's your surprise? Tell me.
Guess who I saw when I went shopping yesterday!
Looking at your excitement, Asim! Was it him?
Not just him. His Mum, too!
She's such a nice lady! So affectionate! Almost like family. It didn't feel like I'm meeting her for the first time!
Apparently, it's a case of unlike mother, unlike son!
I mean, just look at how you crave for Asim's affection!
Kinda...
But...
Asim didn't feel very good about it. He was like, 'Where'd you drop in from'?
But Aunt invited me. She wanted to sit with me for a while.
Wow... Really?
Because nothing in the world could make Asim say that!
Thought about what you're going to wear?
Not yet...
A man fears for his honour when his lady tries to race ahead.
He forgets everything about love.
Don't tell him anything about me or the shoots until his parents have been to your place.
Malika!
Where've you been? I've been calling you all day, but your phone's been off!
I was busy, Noriyan!
No idea where...
Do you ever think about me?
Of course. That's why I'm calling you the moment I'm free.
Okay...
I've got good news.
I've told Mum about you.
Really?
When's she coming here?
Soon. Very soon, I promise.
Could you meet me at the university?
-You don't need to ask.
I miss you so much when you're not there.
Bye!
I told you to stay back after class!
I don't want to talk to you.
It's nothing like what you think. We're good friends!
I'm sure Farhan's sent you.
No, man! As if he'd say and I'd do it!
I said what I thought was right that day.
You're my friend! I'm so worried to see you like this.
I don't like anyone saying anything about my personal matters.
Okay, I promise I won't.
C'mon, fix your mood.
My mood's good. At least think of what you're saying.
I swear, mate, I won't say anything. Okay?
I'm invited to the wedding, right?
My wedding?
I'm sure it ain't that far off! You look so good laughing!
-Jeez, mate, back off. Enough, now...
Please, think before saying something.
-Alrighty. Smile now, will ya?
C'mon, now, let me play!
-As you wish!
Good morning, everyone.
Good morning.
Asif, I'd like some coffee.
How's Aunt?
Good. Better now.
Nice to meet her.
In that case, I'm sure you should see her again sometime. What do you say?
She was pleased to meet you too. She said she almost felt like you're family.
Of course. Sana's so nice. Don't you agree?
Noriyan...
I'm sure your Mum would've asked about me.
Who I am, where I live... About my family?
She doesn't care about any of it. I'm her only son. She just wants to see me happy.
I got a bad feeling about this...
Why?
I'm afraid of losing you.
How can you even think about that?
Noriyan...
Never leave me, okay?
What are you saying, Malika?
Is it your love you don't trust, or mine?
Your love gives me hope...
What happened? What are you thinking?
Malika...
If you ever had to choose between my love and your happiness... Which would it be?
You say that as if they're any different.
They're the same to me.
Malika...
Things don't always stay the same.
I've got this mansion, cars, riches... Everything.
What if I lost it all tomorrow?
Would you still carry on with me?
What are you saying? That's impossible!
Just imagine it did.
-But why?
It'd be so difficult to choose between my love and my happiness.
You could've just said it for me... 'I'll always choose you, Noriyan'.
You can't seriously expect someone whose Mum's worked all her 'humble' life sewing to choose love.
She'd want her happiness at all costs, Noriyan.
Don't worry.
I'll keep you happy.
So, Granny, how was your journey?
Great, but blimey, so tiring... It's such a headache, waiting it out in the plane!
You don't look well.
But of course... What else do you expect at my age?
And how's Aunt?
She's great. Everyone's having a ball over there.
Doesn't she want to come here?
They think with their brains there. Not their hearts.
They've got their hands full there... Never mind if they don't want to come here. I love to come here for my grandson and daughter-in-law.
Speaking of which, where's she?
Salma!
She's cooking something for you.
You're here after so long, I'm sure she's planned a real treat for you.
Oh, you don't know how I've lived so far from you so long.
You're here, now, Granny, and I won't let you go.
I didn't come here to go back. Not until you've brought your bride, Malika!
You can't seriously expect someone whose Mum's worked all her 'humble' life sewing to choose love.
She'd want her happiness at all costs, Noriyan.
What happened?
Something worrying you?
No...
Nothing at all...
I can totally believe that.
What's her name again?
Malika [Empress].
Sounds nice.
I hope she doesn't act like one!
Mum...
Do names affect how we act?
Not really, but...
Sometimes...?
So...
When are you taking me to her place?
What is it that's troubling you?
Tell me. I can help you.
Mum...
I've lied to her...
About?
She thinks I'm rich. Very rich.
It shouldn't be too difficult for you.
What?
Just tell her the truth.
I can't do that...
I've told so many lies to hide this one.
Tell her the truth. Make up for every time you've lied to her.
She'd be hurt.
Hurt, or... Leave you?
No way, Mum, she won't leave me.
She loves me.
Really.
Well, then, just tell her.
What's the worst that can happen? She'd be cross for a few days, maybe?
I don't want her to be cross with me.
You shouldn't have lied to her in the first place, then!
I tried to tell her the truth many times... But I couldn't do it.
You've got no other option, Noriyan.
I can't talk about your marriage until you've told her the truth.
Okay, Mum...
I'll tell her...
Hello?
You're not here. What happened?
But the shoot's done. Why do I have to come everyday?
Not even if I wanted?
What do you want?
I want to see you.
Why?
If you need a reason to see me... How about another shoot?
Sir?
-Yeah.
Come here tomorrow.
I've got an international client. It's a high-profile shoot.
But...
-You'll be making a lot of money...
Don't think so much, Malika.
I told you, you were born to rule this field.
You'll be getting a lot of offers. Get used to it.
Okay...
I'll be there.
See you tomorrow.
Bye.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV