♪ Tears drip slowly... ♪
♪ My eyes grow lonely ♪
♪ Yearning to see you ♪
♪ Come here, my dear ♪
♪ Yea, just you... ♪
♪ You illuminate ♪
♪ All my dreams ♪
♪ Let us live them out ♪
♪ Together... ♪
♪ With teary eyes ♪
♪ Teary eyes ♪
♪ I've lost everything ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ With teary eyes ♪
Your Majesty! His Honour hath summon'd the condemned.
Pray reconsider thy decision, Your Majesty.
Thou hast no shortage of devoted slaves who would
Take thy crime 'pon himself and, with gladness, ascend the gallows.
I have always seen Your Majesty stand for Justice.
For probity, my love I'd have to cede...
O Lord! Never could I have conceiv'd...
Your Majesty...
So blinded by thy love I cannot be
To do what would in my subjects' eyes disgrace me...
Your Majesty...
Thy love shall always make me proud...
She texted, Mum... She's coming.
I told her not to take part if it'll get late.
She leaves us all worried!
Munni...
Get my cloak.
Where are you going?
I thought...
I'd go check.
The bus would leave her at the stop. It's so dark. I'll get her.
Why are you so worried? She'll be on her way.
Thank goodness Aqil isn't back yet!
If he found out Her Majesty isn't back yet, I tell you!
Go and get my cloak, Munni.
Tell me, Mum...
Has he ever been back on time?
Enough talk. I asked you to get my cloak.
Alrighty...
Good Lord, what's up with her...
She's such a bother...
I get so worried...
What's up, Your Majesty?
Happy the play ended before your punishment?
Did you see them praise us, Noriyan?
I had no idea they'd laud us so much!
Did you see their reaction? It was phenomenal!
I mean -- They actually felt that you were about to be punished!
And...
So did I, for a moment... I felt that I was being separated from you forever...
Indeed! I could see the fear, the grief in your expressions!
That's what I was thinking when I did that.
How I'd feel if we were separated forever...
Really... It felt like...
It might just kill me...
Your Majesty...
Reality check!
No one can separate us!
Jeez, Malika...
As if I'd let anyone!
Blimey, Noriyan, I'm so late...
What's the hurry, Malika?
'What's the hurry'? Go and change!
After you.
-Don't worry about me. Go!
I'm good as dead today...
It's so late...
Hello, Aunt.
-Hello there, m'boy.
Great that you're here.
Could you get Malika from the bus stop? Her bus would be there any moment.
Where's Malika been?
Her university group had put up a play.
Alright. Don't worry. I'll get her.
Wanna have something?
-An earful, please!
What do you mean?
I'm late, Noriyan. Mum'll give me an earful!
Just another day at the office for you! What's the big deal?
You don't know how angry she'll be! I almost couldn't convince her to let me perform!
I even told her it's an all-girls event... The actors and the audience!
Whoa, you're quite the bluff master...
I had to! To fulfil my dream that people admire me, clap for me!
And that you confess your love for me before everyone!
I don't need to bluff for that!
-Aye, but to proclaim it to the world!
I did today!
That wasn't you.
That was King Arthur's dearest Guinevere!
Who could be the king of this Guinevere's heart...
...But the one and only Noriyan Ali?
You better be ready to tell your family with the same confidence!
I will, but please drop me home!
Okay. We're on our way. We had some proper fun today, mate.
Yeah. And... This car!
Woo hoo!
Didn't you go?
I saw Asim. He's gone to pick her up.
Mum...
You're right.
God always sends Asim to help us.
Yes...
He's such a lovely lad...
May the Lord bless him.
I didn't even ask him where he was going.
Just sent him to pick Malika up.
Just pray she comes back with Asim.
Just drop me around that corner.
Let me drop you at your doorstep. I won't come inside.
-No! I can walk! Just drop me here.
Jeez, mate...
-Stop already!
Alright, as Your Majesty wishes. Can't say no.
You've got your whole life to have it your way.
I think I'll be done with this life before that happens.
Oh, please... I'm late! Bye! See you!
Hello...
Hey!
Goodness, you're so late! You said it'll be over by 8.
Blimey, Mum... Trying me the moment I've stepped inside!
It gets late in these kinds of functions.
Your phone was off too! You could've kept that on.
You have to switch it off to enter, and -- I forgot to switch it on...
If only you felt that your Mum's worried, waiting for you...
Alright, how was your play?
Splendid! They praised us so much... Clapped for me so much! You can't imagine!
But...
Where's Asim?
Isn't he coming in?
Asim?
Yes. He'd gone to pick you up.
Didn't you see him?
No?
He would've passed right by you and you wouldn't have seen him!
Munni...
Call him. The poor lad would be at the bus stop.
Okay.
Hello?
Yes, Munni?
What?
She's back?
But I'm at the bus stop...
I didn't see her...
Alright, I'm coming.
You've got to show me today's pictures!
Sit down!
Here!
You look so lovely!
You could've taken me along... I would've loved to watch everything!
I was already getting late...
-Hello.
Hello, Asim.
Hello there, m'lad.
She showed up after you went to pick her up. Didn't you see each other?
My class fellow dropped me here. She was driving.
And your innocent lad Asim hasn't got an eye for the ladies!
Bless him. May the Lord give everyone such a dutiful child.
I get so worried...
No girl should be out -- so late...
Splendid...
You get worried about your daughters... How about an ounce of that worry for your son who isn't back before 3 a.m.?
Malika...
Please.
I worry for him, too.
But I'm helpless.
I'll get some tea for Malika. Have some before you leave.
-Alright.
Did you have to say that about Aqil?
You know he doesn't listen to her.
Wrong number. Go and boss over those who don't listen.
Asim!
Look at Malika play the Empress!
No other role would suit her. [Malika = Empress]
What's with the hot water in this?
At least keep some cold water here...
-I'll get you some.
Janey Mac, Malika...
Do you have to be angry every moment?
Don't even think about any romance while Munni's away.
Malika... Aunt was worried...
About how you'd come back from the bus stop alone.
It was late.
Thanks to you and her. Happy?
Aunt wanted that your ride home be ready the moment you got off from the bus.
Did you just call your clunker a ride?
I know that my clunker doesn't suit my queen, Malika...
I told you not to act like I'm yours!
We're just cousins. Get it?
'Sup, mate!
How's it going? How was your performance?
I've never experienced anything like it, Atif!
The curtain was raised and there was the audience, right there! And I had a sword!
You should've been there, mate!
I would've told everyone - 'This is Atif, my brother'!
Everyone would've been green with envy! I'd be so proud...
I told you we're shooting these days. No time at all...
But it's good you're taking part in every play your university folks put up.
It'll build confidence and give you valuable experience. Keep it up!
I'm just following my passion, Atif.
Ain't it wonderful if passion builds perfection?
Anyway, you need to watch my performance.
I've learnt everything from you, after all!
Learnt acting from me?
Confidence, Atif. Confidence!
Aye. Anyway, I'm starving. Coming with me?
In a while...
Good evening.
-Good evening.
I'm literally starving. What've you got today?
Pasta.
Oh, nice!
What's up with Noriyan? He seems happy as Larry.
Please don't give him your car for so long.
He left in the morning and came back just now.
It's no big deal.
It is.
You can't stand getting jostled about in buses when you get used to riding cars.
Why do you think so much about any of this?
You've got to, when nothing seems to go right...
Anyway, I'll go and change. Then, we'll have dinner.
I'll get your dinner in five minutes.
Ayesha!
Here, take this.
Alright, buddy, let's go.
Seriously?
Knackered in 90 minutes?
It's been much more than 90 minutes.
Well, go on if you want. I'll get going.
How about you go back on your own?
Jeez...
Hey! Wait!
You snooty blighter!
Stuck-up because of your status, eh?
At least it makes you come running!
You know me inside out!
You'd be at the gym all day if I didn't play driver.
Fair enough!
So it's my job to play your taxi!
Hello there!
Juliet's calling!
♪ You're here, your eyes are looking into mine, so baby, make me fly... ♪
Please talk to her. She's been calling you for so long!
-Blimey...
I've told her not to bother me when I'm at the gym...
She can be such a bother...
Mummy's more like it.
Oh, please...
Tell her again. Talk to her. Please.
Hello...
I was just thinking of you...
Thinking of me or talking about me?
Thinking of you and talking about you...
One and the same.
Not quite.
Unless you're talking about me because you're thinking of me.
I was thinking of you and talking about you.
Well, then, didn't you think of your promise to teach me new meditation poses?
Oh...
Sorry... I forgot entirely!
So, coming today?
No...
I'm very tired, Zoha.
See you tomorrow.
-Okay.
Get some rest.
See you tomorrow.
Thanks.
You understand me so well.
Bye.
Way to go, tough guy!
How flattering!
Ain't no flattery.
She really looks after me.
Besides, at her age, she should worry about God. Not any of this.
No way.
She ain't that old either.
The two of you are really made for each other.
Oh, seriously!
You know I don't like to hear that. C'mon.
Done?
-Yes.
Well done.
This is perfect.
Alright, you may go. Finish it tomorrow.
Good night.
Can anybody 'round here fix this button here?
I'll do it in a while.
Leave it be. I'll do it myself.
Munni's better than you. Studies hard and helps me, too!
Of course. She loves stitching, just like you. I don't.
Have some shame, Malika.
It's no picnic.
But I have no option.
Forget her, Mum.
I'll do it.
You never let go of a chance to score brownie points, do you?
If it isn't your dearest!
Alright, Munni, fix this button...
I'll prepare dinner.
He would've had dinner.
Heya, Mum.
Hello...
Waqas said hi.
Bless him.
Why must he?
It isn't something you 'must'.
You send greetings so you can get blessings.
He never bothered to show up. Just sends his greetings.
Should I bring him here to meet Mum?
Why not?
Don't you loll about his place all day?
You haven't seen his place.
People can get lost in that mansion.
I'd invite him to this ramshackle shanty, Mum...
Where we've got these scruffy curtains to hide the grotty doors and creaky windows... Oh, please!
Just -- Leave it.
Fix the button... I'll get you dinner.
-I've had dinner with Waqas.
Told you.
He gets to loaf about all day...
And of all the people in the world, you've got Asim for me.
How many times have I told you not to talk about Asim like that?
Please, Mum, stop hoping I'd ever say a single good word about him.
Munni...
Fix the button. I'm going to the kitchen.
Gently, Zahir...
Thank God it'll be off tomorrow.
Why do we need a trainer when I've got a physiotherapist?
-He's just coming to see you. He'll talk about a few things. That's it. See him.
I don't want to see anyone.
-Stop behaving like a kid, Zoha.
You need one. Doctor's orders.
Hello?
Hey!
I hope I'm not bothering you.
Obviously...
Look at the time.
Forget the time, look at the weather!
What happened?
It's raining! It's looking gorgeous, Aqil.
Okay...
Enjoy the rain. Cheers.
Just filthy puddles for me here.
Honestly, I love the rains only when I'm over there.
Then come over.
Sorry, but...
I can't come right now.
How about...
You imagine I'm with you in the rains and enjoy?
Okay...
Alright, listen...
Yes?
I love you.
Bye.
Got a class today?
Yes.
You'll ask for a car again?
I don't need to ask bro.
He's not your brother.
He's the master of this house, and us. We're his servants.
That's the limit.
Always asking for something... Cars, clothes, boots, and...
Look at what you've got yesterday...
-Mum...
Only the Lord is our Master.
He thinks of me as his little brother.
Who gets these comforts in a servant's quarters?
Besides, he's given everything.
I don't ask him.
Comforts don't make a servant's quarters into a palace.
What's up with you?
If he gives you all of this, just turn him down!
Is this what I've taught you?
He's got three cars, Mum. So what if he gives me one?
As if you'd be a beggar without it!
It's his love, Mum...
Why does he love you?
Tell me. Why?
Because you've looked after his parents all those years.
Atif was so busy with his job in advertising that he just didn't get the time.
You ran everything here.
Madame and Monsieur had but one complaint till their last breath...
That their son's got no time for them.
Wealthy people have everything, Mum...
Except time.
Because they know what will happen to their business if they wasted any time on emotional matters.
And how would they earn anything if their business shut down?
They know that money is power. Money buys respect.
Just pray that I become a great businessman like Atif!
And earn a lot!
God forbid!
What do you mean, Mum?
So that when I'm old,
Sick, and on my deathbed,
You don't have time for me either?
Mum...
How did you even think of that?
I can sacrifice my life for you.
Mum...
Aqil...
Going somewhere?
Yes.
Don't ask where.
No.
I stopped asking you long ago.
We need to talk.
Yeah?
Your friend Waqas has got a flourishing business.
Can't he give you a job?
What's up with you, Mum?
He's my friend. He loves me so much!
I'd go to him asking for a job!
Fair enough...
He loves you...
...So much he can't give you a job?
That doesn't mean I start working for him.
There's a respect for friends, a --
-That you'd lose if you asked for a job? That it?
You hardly lose your respect when you ride his car, wear his clothes, and enjoy dinner when he pays!
Let me tell you!
-Aqil!
Ask her to get out of my sights, or I'll clobber her for real!
Back to your room.
I'm very worried because of you, Aqil.
Come here.
Here. Sit down.
-Where are you taking me?
So, why are you worried?
So you think there's nothing to get worried about?
Everything will be alright, Mum.
Don't worry.
If only problems could be solved by not worrying about them...
As if my worrying about them will solve them!
-What are you doing?
Be happy. I'm going. Bye!
-Aqil!
He won't change...
Alright, you may go.
Hey, Atif! Good morning!
'Morning.
Here.
Keys, Atif?
Don't you always take them?
Please don't embarrass me by saying that...
I didn't mean it that way. Take it easy.
I'm hosting a talent hunt.
I thought I'd come to your university.
Wow! What an idea.
Atif...
I think you should go somewhere else. The Dean at my college is proper grumpy.
Well...
We need young faces. Anyway...
We'll see in the evening.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
How are you?
I'll get going, Atif.
Meet Sanam, our talent hunt coordinator.
-Hello.
Hi.
Grab a pew.
-No, Atif. I'm in a bit of a hurry.
Wish me best of luck. Bye.
-Bye.
Nice to meet you!
Yes?
Who's this handsome guy?
Our maid's son.
He's the maid's son?
He's cute, by the way.
Let's talk business, shall we? Show me what you've got.
Who is it?
Who did you expect?
Wow... You're actually here.
I thought you'd find some excuse again...
Oh?
So I...
Make excuses?
Did I say something wrong?
I don't.
I look for excuses to meet you.
Why do you need excuses to meet me?
You know that our match is a little bit odd...
So...
I have to...
I don't get it.
I mean... When we've got an understanding, a connection...
Age shouldn't matter...
You don't know how much I love you, Zoha.
I don't care about any of it...
How much do you love me?
If, after all this time, you couldn't even see how much I love you...
My love has been meaningless, Zoha...
Please... Don't say that.
What do you want me to say?
I'm proud to have you...
And you say you don't know how much I love you...
Wow...
I mean, curse your love, Aqil!
You're mad.
I'm just kidding!
God... I thought -- What are we even talking --
The thing is, you couldn't know me.
You almost killed me there!
I love to fool around with you.
Always the naughty kid, eh?
What good is growing up, anyway?
Anyway... So what's on the menu today?
Your favourite, obviously.
Ghulam Hussain!
My favourite...
And what would that be?
I don't need to tell him.
Everyone knows your favourites.
You're family.
Really?
Good...
That's cool...
Asif...
Who left this here?
I did...
You didn't go for lunch. I thought I should give it to you.
Thank you so much, but I'm not hungry.
My Mum's made meatballs. She's quite the cook.
Try and tell me if you like them.
Thank you so much, but...
Seriously, I'm not hungry at all.
Mum says you don't give the food someone's sent you back. Please, have it.
But your mother didn't prepare it for me.
I've had what Mum packed for me.
Please, have it. And if not, take it home.
Someone else will.
Sent the video to Atif?
I'm sure he'd love it!
Oh?
Put plainly, you wanted to show your performance off!
I like it when Atif praises me.
You're so lucky.
You live in Atif's mansion even though he's no one to you, and get loved like a brother!
Not just love...
He gets pocket money too!
Which is exactly why Her Majesty's head over heels for him.
Excuse me!
How'd you find out if she's head over heels for him, or he for her?
It's one or the same.
-Not quite, m'boy.
Girls today are smart when it comes to love.
The love is as deep as the boy's pockets!
Malika's not like that, my dear.
That's where you're wrong, my friend.
She hasn't the foggiest.
Oh?
So you mean she'd leave me if she found out?
Absolutely.
-Absolutely.
Love is blind to status, mate.
Well, in that case, go and tell her who you are.
Don't even think about it!
We're just kidding. You took it too seriously!
Mate...
I think you're right...
I should tell Malika the truth.
No way, mate. Please. Don't.
You're mad when it comes to love.
She can take it,
But you can't.
3, 2, 1...
♪ I'm longing for your love but you are moving away ♪
♪ So don't leave me behind still words I want to say... ♪
You've been changing the channel ever since you got in. Talk to me for a change, maybe?
What else do I do? I thought I'd listen to some music I like... It's a long ride and I'd get bored...
So my company bores you!
No way, mate.
Anyway...
When are you taking me to your place?
Tell me.
Malika...
Oh, muck...
-Oh my God...
What'd you do, Noriyan?
He's coming, Noriyan...
-Relax.
Think you'd show it off to your girlfriend?
-Mind your tongue.
Just get out. I'll show you how much you've damaged my car.
-No, Noriyan!
I'm leaving if you got out.
Please get going!
-Hello!
You coming?
Can you wait until I park it?
I'm coming.
Go park.
What were you thinking?
Were you just going to fight him like a chav?
As if you've got a shortage of cars!
If I don't, it doesn't mean I can go about ramming random cars on the road!
Can't you look where you're going?
It's not that...
It's not my car... That's why...
What?
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV