Why did Noriyan lie to me if he knew her so well?
One should only fly as high as his wings can take him.
Didn't I tell you I can't carry on like this?
You may not know it, but there's others here who have hopes from you.
What do you want?
Should I waste my life living up to their hopes?
And grow restless?
Alright, then...
I'll just think I've only got two daughters.
Mum...
You know I don't want to worry you.
But...
I don't like it when you object to everything I say.
Nobody's told you, perhaps, but a mother's got the right to object.
What'd he say?
The same old. He just doesn't see sense.
Anyway... Have your lunch.
Who knows when Malika will be back.
Call her friends, Munni.
She isn't back yet. I'm so worried.
Okay.
Hello?
Hello, Rabia.
It's Minahil. Malika's sister.
Yeah...
Yeah, she's...
Sleeping. She was unwell.
Okay.
Who's unwell?
Malika didn't go to university today.
Where could she be?
Don't let Aqil hear you.
Isn't Malika back yet?
She gets late sometimes.
The traffic, you know.
But her class is over at 2.
It's 4.
If only you cared!
I say, get her out of university. She better stay home.
Something seems off.
Sisters are best sent to their homes.
-What's stopping you? Get to it.
'Get to it'?
Tell Aunt to take her 'pearl' with her quick as she can.
What'd they say if I sent her empty-handed?
'Her father may have died, but his mother and brother didn't give her anything'.
Just fix the date. Everything else will be okay.
But how? It's not like the angels will come to our help!
Blimey, Mum, always so hopeless!
I'm not.
That's why I tell you there's still time.
I'll stop telling you when I'm hopeless.
Excuse me...
There's something I need to talk about...
Yes?
Are you actually cross with me?
No.
I didn't know you'd mind it so much.
Please don't feel embarrassed.
I just want to tell you my side of the story.
Yes?
I respect women a lot.
I respect you a lot.
I know that women are generally forced by fate to work.
I wouldn't have liked it it you'd paid the bill.
And, as a colleague, it was my duty to pay the bill.
I hope you understand.
I understood it already.
Don't take Farah so seriously. I don't feel bad about it at all.
Thank you.
And...
For what?
For caring.
Thank you so much.
'Thank you'?
What for?
For spending time with me.
I want to spend my life with you, mate.
Blimey, I long to live that life...
So, when do I bring Mum?
Malika...
Bye.
I'm back!
-'Evening.
-Bang on time!
Your bus ain't normally so late.
You don't know the bus route.
Ain't I always back around now?
Not so fast.
Do you always wear so much makeup?
Makeup?
Blimey, it's just a spot of lipstick... A friend put it on me in the bus...
She ain't going to university again, Mum.
Why?
Why not?
Go in, Malika.
Just tell him, Mum... I don't want to drop out!
I'll complete my Master's!
-Be my guest.
In fact,
Be Asim's guest!
I have no problem with that.
No way!
See that?
Something's off, I tell you. Get her married ASAP.
What kind of a mother are you, really?
Mothers shield their daughters.
Aqil mouths any guff he wants!
What's his problem?
I don't know about him, but I have a problem with you.
Lemme guess. Your sister sends her greetings.
Nothing from her.
But I've got a sign from the Lord.
If the daughter didn't go to her home this time, there's no way I can't lose face.
Wow...
So Aqil's been slagging off behind my back!
Honestly... Where were you?
What?
Don't even try to lie. You didn't go to university.
I'd gone over to Rabia's. Her Mum's not well. I thought I'd meet her.
Really?
Okay...
Take me to her in the evening.
I should see her.
What? You're still doubting me, Mum?
Because Rabia asked us where you were.
That's how you're rewarding my trust?
Why are you so worried, Mum? I was going to tell you...
Oh?
When?
After slipping away with him, maybe, never to come back?
No way, Mum! What are you saying?
Noriyan's so nice!
He even wants to meet you!
This is the first time I've slapped you, Malika. You'd do well to remember it before talking about him again. And try, if you can, to feel the pain.
Over here.
Right here.
I'll take care. Go.
I wanted to talk to you about something...
Have you thought about Noriyan's marriage?
I have, but...
Let him finish his education first.
Get a job...
No worries. I'll get him a job somewhere once he's graduated.
His Uncle's got two daughters. Both homely and comely.
And I'm sure he won't like either of them.
How'd you guess, sir?
I've never really talked about it, but it seems you're right...
Kids these days... It's better if you talk to them.
Get to know what they want.
What he wants?
Did he tell you something?
Not really...
We've never talked about it, but I'm sure he'd have someone...
Hello, Mum. 'Evening, Atif.
'Evening.
You're back early?
I thought I'd talk to your Mum while you're hanging out with friends... Nothing special, really.
Talk about what?
Dropping a dime on me?
I wouldn't dare.
I was talking about your future.
I'm sure you would've clicked hundreds of selfies today. Show me, will ya?
Atif...
I didn't take a single picture...
Really?
Never mind, then...
You look tired. Get some rest.
Right...
Atif...
Do you doubt Noriyan?
No, not at all...
Just talk to him.
And if he didn't tell you...
You can always check his phone...
I'm sure it'll tell you everything he won't!
I don't know how to check these phones and all...
I do. Feel free to give me.
I'd rather die than live like this...
Why do you say that?
You're such a fighter!
You can't give up just like that!
Everyone's got problems...
We just have to figure out how to deal with them...
What do you want me to do?
I'm tired of explaining myself.
I don't even want to live in that shack.
I've got sisters who'd like it their way... And Mum!
She's got a problem with me all the bleedin' time!
I'm sure you can support them even if you're not living with them...
What do you mean?
I don't know if I should say it...
But you can shift here. Use whichever room you want. No issues.
Zoha...
They look at our relationship
The wrong way. Get it?
Don't you think it'd reflect too badly on me
If I came over here?
No one's stood by me like you.
Our relationship isn't so complicated.
Who cares what they think?
We know better.
I'm sure we're close enough to share everything with each other.
I don't care what they say.
Listen...
It may be okay in your society.
But I'm not okay with it.
Besides, I don't want to stand in your way.
I'd rather we don't talk about it.
Okay... Have your coffee?
That's great, Faizan! You should've told me!
No.
I don't like this surprise one bit.
We could've helped you!
Waqas and I will be there. To see Novera.
Alright. We'll be coming.
Okay.
Bye.
Where to? You seem so happy! What's up?
I'm very happy.
-What happened?
Did Novera tell you when she's coming?
No. She's always into 'surprising' me!
Surprise, then!
They're here!
What?
Don't tell me! Really?
-Yes! Yes!
Your Uncle just called.
What are we waiting for? Get ready, we're leaving!
You seem more eager than me!
Because why not?
Think again.
What if she refused?
She's smart.
I'm smart too, okay? Why would she refuse?
She knows I like her.
Okay. Let's get ready. Let's go.
-Okay. I'll call her, okay?
Hi!
So you found out!
Hey... Yeah, found out!
Quite the surprise, believe me!
I do what I say. You better take me seriously.
Mum and I are coming. Okay?
Great! See you!
See ya!
-Bye.
Hurry up, Mum!
So, how does she like Pakistan?
Lovely, Aunt.
Like home.
But there's just one problem.
What?
The traffic! So wild and confusing!
-Ah, yeah!
I mean, they jump the light when they feel like and nobody bats an eyelid!
You'll get used to it.
Yeah, she was so worried. The rush is mad and all of that. And I was like, 'You'll get used to it'...
Yeah, you'll get used to it.
Have you warned Waqas to stay quiet or...?
No. Nothing like that...
But we'd start if you're done complaining.
You're just complaining since you've been here!
Well, I'm so sorry. I didn't know you're so patriotic.
Well, ma'am, I am a proud Pakistani. Always have been.
So, Mr Proud Pakistani, how's the business going?
Everything's fine, Uncle.
Good.
I pray you become a successful businessman like your late father.
Well, I'm trying, Uncle, but I don't think I'm really coming up to Mum and Dad's expectations... Which is why I sometimes get roasted.
Really?
Wow...
Please call me the next time you scold Waqas, Aunt. I'd love to see it!
Well, I've had enough. How say you take up this responsibility?
I'm sure he'll become a great businessman like his father. I wish you all the best, m'boy.
Well, that's some support at last... Let's pray...
By the way, Novera, he's very excited to see your work.
I hear you've featured this house in a magazine?
No, Aunt, I didn't have it featured. They picked it themselves.
They all know interior design's my passion.
Come, let me show you around.
Sure.
But I've got to talk to him first.
But I can see you've got a lovely taste.
Thank you, Aunt.
Why don't you show Waqas around? He loves to see your work!
Sure. Coming?
C'mon. Let's go.
After you.
-Thanks.
I'm so happy Novera likes Pakistan.
Aye... It's good...
But you know, we've got to come back home sometime...
She's been so responsible since her younger days...
The home... Me... After her mother...
She'll take care of everything.
Indeed. I'm sure she'll adjust.
She's so wise, so lovely.
Okay, now check this zip...
Mum! Did you talk to Asim?
Yeah. He said he can come and help you anytime. He'll bring his computer.
Okay.
It's called a laptop!
What are you even paying for? Don't they teach you anything at the institute?
There's some things I didn't quite understand. I thought I'd ask Asim.
He's so skilled. I'm sure he can help me.
Sure, go and learn from him.
No.
He's coming here.
And no one's gonna have a problem with it. Okay?
Here.
He's just looking for excuses to come here.
He doesn't need excuses.
Asim's my son as much as Aqil.
Jesus... I would've been better-off if you'd found a 'son' better than that pleb!
It's up to God to give wealth to whoever He wills.
And it's better to be poor with dignity than filthy-rich without!
Keep thanking Him for your dignified deprivation. As if I care.
You haven't seen deprivation.
Don't you dare think of my simplicity as deprivation.
Have I ever let you starve for a single day?
By the way, your Aunt's coming to fix the date for the wedding. You better fix that mood.
So there's no way you're getting out of this dream house.
Why not?
You just told Mum you can't drive in the traffic here.
Excuse me, I didn't say I can't drive in this traffic.
I was just saying that nobody follows the rules here, which makes it really difficult for me to drive.
I follow the rules.
All of them. By the way, you can also use it to your advantage.
That's so sweet of you! But my driver's coming tomorrow.
Think again, ma'am. You're getting this driver for free.
Well, I don't want a driver who talks so much.
Well, then...
How about a life-partner who talks so much?
I hear the girls love partners who love to talk.
You've missed one bit of it. That kinda girls don't like to hear anything except compliments!
I have no problem with that.
You don't have to...
I mean, I never asked anyone to compliment me. I'm not the type who just loves to hear compliments.
You know what they're talking about, right?
I've literally got no idea.
You're kidding, right? Playing around with me?
I can guess what my Dad could be saying about me.
But I've got no idea what your Mum thinks about me.
What am I here for?
-Not so fast, okay?
Just calm down, relax. Take your time.
I'll ask you later. I've got to explore Pakistan! There's so much I've got to do, you know!
Do you doubt Noriyan?
No, not at all...
Just talk to him.
And if he didn't tell you...
You can always check his phone...
I'm sure it'll tell you everything he won't!
I don't know how to check these phones and all...
I do. Feel free to give me.
By the way, your Aunt's coming to fix the date for the wedding. You better fix that mood.
I want to spend my life with you, mate.
Where've you been? Mum called you so many times!
But you didn't even bother to answer! Look at the time!
I don't need to tell you anything. Okay?
Good morning, ma'am.
-Good morning.
I'm sorry for last night, Zoha.
I'm leaving the bike and the keys with you.
I can't live on your favours anymore.
Reza! Where's Aqil?
He left last night, ma'am.
Okay.
Get me some coffee.
Aqil!
What's the meaning of this?
Come here now!
I mean right now!
Did you forget what Aqil told you?
I've got an important class today.
You're not going anywhere. I hope I'm clear.
Why don't you get it? I've got to go.
I told you. You're not taking one step out of this room. Or I'm telling Aqil.
Also, Salma's coming. I told her you're home.
What do I care if she wants to come? I don't have to be here.
Forget about university. You're going straight to your home.
Did you see my phone?
Mum?
What are you thinking?
Nothing really... Just... What if you didn't get what you're so happy about?
Why are you always so downbeat, Mum?
Aunt wouldn't have invited you for nothing.
Let me be clear, Asim.
I'm not fixing the date if I caught so much as a whiff of apathy in Malika's behaviour.
Malika would be at university, Mum.
I'm sure Aunt would've asked her before talking to you.
No. She's home.
Your Aunt told me in the morning.
Okay. But please, don't worry.
It's better that I worry now than give both of us a lifetime of worry.
Anyway, finish your breakfast. You're late.
So he's human after all! He worries for you!
Sure he is. Very caring, too.
And very loving, innit?
Oh, c'mon...
I say you talk to him. Because he won't have a clue unless you told him.
I'm sure he'd sense my feelings if he's destined for me.
No way he's sensing your feelings.
He'll look you in the eye but fail to read them!
He's always lost within himself!
Good morning.
-'Morning. (He's here!)
I'd like a cup too, Asif.
Blimey, this colour suits him so much!
I'm sure he wouldn't even have thought about it! Gee, Holy Joe's so boring!
Not at all.
Definitely not boring.
That's what I love about his personality. He just goes about his work.
Fair enough! But don't you think he should worry about those who just can't go about their work and can't remember a thing? It's been half an hour and you haven't given me the file!
Give me a minute. I'm working on it.
Your lawyer called in the morning, sir.
What is it this time?
It's about the model who had started working for Event 4 while contracted by us.
She wants to withdraw her complaint and negotiate with you.
Did you think I wouldn't know?
I'd tried to make her understand, but she didn't, and...
Shot herself in the foot by working for another agency while contracted by us.
The lawyers, the media... They've only reviled her all this time.
No surprise, after what she did.
Some models think they're the best after one or two ad campaigns.
They don't know what's coming. She didn't know what's coming.
Exactly. Who knows what's gotten into their heads! Girls these days, I tell you!
Anyway...
Ask Mujtaba to get ready for the shoot.
Okay, sir.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV