What were you thinking?
Were you just going to fight him like a chav?
As if you've got a shortage of cars!
If I don't, it doesn't mean I can go about ramming random cars on the road!
Can't you look where you're going?
It's not that...
It's not my car... That's why...
What?
What do you mean?
I mean -- It's Mum's car... She'd be furious...
Whatever.
Drop me at the bus stop. I'll walk home.
Alright, sorry. Why are you getting so angry?
We'd just started on our long drive!
Spend a little time with me?
Alright.
But promise me.
Promise that you won't create a scene on the road like that.
Look at your status, your background... It just doesn't suit you!
Alright. Sorry. I promise I won't do anything of the sort. Please fix your mood.
These are some of the faces that would suit our requirements, sir.
They're good, but I don't quite see the innocence we need in any of them.
I'll show you some other portfolios.
We're short on time...
I understand, sir... I'll do something.
Please. Double time.
Hello?
Atif...
I hope I'm not disturbing you...
No. What happened?
Atif...
I made a small mistake...
Why are you so confused? Go on.
I --
I had an accident... It isn't serious, the car's -- But I swear it wasn't my fault.
-No worries.
You're safe, aren't you? That's what I care about.
Surely, you aren't angry, Atif?
No way.
We'll talk in the evening.
Thank you, Atif.
It's okay, mate.
Relax.
How will I tell Mum...
Yeah, it's one of my favourite movies.
I bet it'll win an Oscar.
I haven't watched one in so long...
Half-and-half popcorn.
What?
Seriously?
No...
That's too sweet.
Half-and-half's best. Trust me.
Yes -- H -- Hey! What are you doing?
Give it to me.
I won't.
I've been calling you for an hour!
But you're busy, as usual!
Do you remember we're having lunch with Mr Ahmed from Lahore?
I totally forgot...
You know I'm careless with my phone...
You're only careless for me.
You answer Aqil's calls in less than a moment. You don't keep him waiting!
Help me up.
Seriously, Zahir...
-You don't keep him waiting one moment!
You're so predictable.
I knew you'd find some excuse to bring Aqil up.
I don't need to bring him up. He's already here.
In the family, the partnership... And between whatever's left of our friendship.
Okay, my dear cousin and business partner. Enough for a day.
Tea or coffee?
Neither.
I'd have brunch today.
Asian style.
Egg, paratha, tea, and chicken karai.
I'll have only one paratha because we're going out for dinner.
I think it's time you got married.
You sound like the typical Asian glutton!
Order your lady around like that.
No way. My lady couldn't stay for a year!
Women can be so demanding... I'd rather keep my distance.
Big words...
What does it matter?
I can guarantee that Aunt will get you married the moment she comes from London.
By the way, Aunt Pakiza's daughter, Alizé - She's gorgeous!
A complete psycho if you ask me.
What?
Know what, she talks to her dogs.
And her dogs talk back.
Are you serious?
She even told her dog everything about our lunch date.
I've really decided to keep my distance.
You'd better stay away from her type too! Stay happy, stay single.
In other words, Alizé didn't reject you.
Her dog did!
Ghulam Hussain!
This is what I always warned you about! It's a long way down...
How will we pay for it?
But Mum...
You should be happy I didn't get hurt.
But you're right...
I'll be more careful now.
What?
You'll keep your hands off anything that's Mr Atif's!
And if you did, I'd leave this place and my job that instant!
I mean it!
I'll talk to Mr Atif.
Mum...
I've talked to Atif. He's got no problem.
He's very kind...
But you should know your place.
He's our master.
Why can't you see it?
Because I can see that he doesn't think of himself as a master.
-Enough, Noriyan!
Just because you get to eat with a silver spoon, don't think it's yours!
You better know your place or you'll pay for it.
What happened? Why are you so angry?
I was just trying to get some sense into him. I'll get your tea.
-It's no big deal.
I've told him. He'll be careful. Right?
There. Take it easy. Go.
Thank you Atif.
Come.
What's up?
What is this?
Don't you know how to come to your sister's room?
I've got my eyes on you.
You better watch out...
Or there will be trouble.
What've I done now?
It doesn't suit any half-decent girl!
I've told you so many times! But you!
Look...
What you're always up to is pure lewdness.
Get it?
What do you think about yourself?
What's going on?
What is it with the two of you?
Jeez, Malika...
What've you done? These were a part of the order... I've told you so many times...
You've always got your eyes on others' things... Take these off before you spoil them!
Take them off!
And what's up with him? What'd he say?
Just what I absolutely hate!
Alright, take these off.
Before you spoil them.
She just doesn't understand...
I've just put them on...
There goes the mood...
Asim!
Come here, dinner's ready.
Coming.
I'm starving.
Come.
What've you got?
Pilaf, vegetables...
How are you?
Better now.
What happened?
-My blood pressure was high in the morning. I took a pill. I'm fine now.
Don't have this, then, Mum.
It's no big deal. I'm just having a little.
You don't look after yourself.
Well, in that case, get me the one who'll look after me.
Let her be done with her exams.
Are you sure she'd come once she's done with her exams?
Aunt's given her word. I don't know why you're so worried.
She thinks of me as her son.
Zahida thinks of you as her son because her son's a layabout.
As for her word, Zahida's given hers...
Looking at Malika... She doesn't seem the right type...
It's nothing like that. Just empty fears.
That's why you're always sick.
It isn't an empty fear, Asim.
I haven't seen an ounce of love in Malika's eyes.
Girls never get tired of rejoicing when they're betrothed.
And Malika... She doesn't even greet back.
No, Mum, it isn't like that.
Anyway. Your food's getting cold.
I know you don't want to hear a word against her. That's why I'm tolerating her.
Malika...
Get us another chapati.
Coming.
Here.
Bon appétit.
Asim called in the afternoon.
Yes. I talked to him.
He mentioned one of his colleagues. Said he's from a good family. He wanted to talk about Munni.
Talk what about who?
He's found a match for Munni. He cares for us so much.
Like a son.
Hey!
Finish you dinner first!
I'm coming.
-Aqil!
Naturally. When the son's useless, his type have to fill in.
What do you mean 'his type'? He's family.
I don't consider him family just yet.
Please tell him to stop looking.
He can only find plebs like himself!
Blimming friendly-neighbourhood go-between.
May the Lord hammer some sense into you and your brother. You two will kill me!
No idea why the internet slowed down when you came here.
I think it's a problem with your laptop.
Why don't you order a new one for me and take mine?
Your laptop's quite expensive, Atif... Please, give it to someone else.
Who've I got except you?
You're my brother. I'd love it if you use it.
Splendid...
So that means you'll also leave me a share in your will.
Blimey, I'm rich!
Aye...
Atif...
I hope you didn't mind.
Why would I?
Seriously... If anything happened to me...
-What are you saying, Atif? God forbid! I was just kidding!
You got so serious...
The download's complete!
Well, then, What are we waiting for? It's show time!
Zoha!
I'm here.
Zoha?
The guests are waiting for you!
What do I tell them?
I'm waiting for Aqil.
He's not here, he's not even taking my call!
Please, Zoha, not today!
Can't you stay away from him for a day?
They're all here for the gossip.
I don't care.
I'm upset because he's not taking my call!
Oh -- Yes...
Thank God...
Where are you?
The guests are here. I'm waiting for you.
I'm waiting for my cab. It's late...
Oh... You've ordered a cab...
Alright...
Get here quick.
I'm coming. Okay.
-Okay. I'm waiting. Bye.
He's coming.
Okay...
-Yeah?
Keep an eye on him.
He better not start getting too cosy with the ladies.
Try to keep him away from the guests.
I've called him here so I can introduce him to all my friends.
Zoha...
You're giving them the gossip yourself...
I really can't help you...
They're gonna gossip anyway.
They just need an excuse.
Aqil's coming! I'm so glad!
Alright...
Oh...
Over here.
The salad is different today.
-Hello, Mum.
Hello.
-Hey, Atif.
-Hey!
You're back early.
Yeah, I didn't have much to do today.
Did you check your WhatsApp?
How was my performance?
Your performance? Well -- It was... Brilliant. Very good.
You're quite the actor, mate!
Oh...!
And... How was my dance?
Your dance... Was also -- great. I loved your moves... Never knew --
-Yes! You are so busted!
I didn't dance at all, Atif.
Blimey...
Mind your tongue, Noriyan...
Why are you scolding him?
Seriously, mate. I didn't get the time. But I'll check it out today.
You won't leave me until I have.
Sure. You know you can't lie to me, Atif!
Aye, I can't lie to anyone...
And he is sooo busted...
Noriyan...
Yes, Mum?
Aren't you ashamed of yourself, talking to Mr Atif like that?
It was just a bit of banter!
You'd do well to know the difference between his place and yours.
I don't like it one bit. You called him a liar?
Because he was lying!
Whatever!
We're his servants.
Who are we to 'bust' him?
We're servants, Mum... Not slaves.
There's a difference, sweet Maman.
Whatever.
I better not catch you talking to him like that again!
That's the bleedin' limit...
Done scolding him?
He had it coming...
He forgets his place.
Please don't scold him.
He's my son. He'd better remember his place.
It's better that I remind him, before anyone else does.
And so you leave me speechless so often...
Ayesha!
Sweet Jesus!
God bless you. May you go on a pilgrimage soon!
May your beloved over you swoon!
Your English rose, the envy of the moon!
I'm blessing you so much. Won't you give me something?
Look at him blush at the mention of his English rose!
Take these blessings and flowers, and delight Shamim Ara!
Flowers are an ode to love.
I'm sure she'll be all yours!
Really? I never knew these flowers could be so powerful.
Aye, prince charming! I'm sure she'll be enchanted!
Give me something, will you?
Be done with it already!
Shamim Ara's as happy as Larry!
♪ This love is like fire and ice... ♪
♪ This love is like rain and blue skies... ♪
Malika...
Malika!
Let's go over to Aunt Salma's.
Why? What's there?
You shouldn't be saying that!
You've got your world there.
I don't want the 'world' you're talking about.
Why do you say that?
Asim loves you so much.
To the dickens with his love.
Can a man who juggles two jobs be one bit romantic?
You ain't gonna change...
Anyway, let's get going. Asim told me Aunt's not well.
How much younger than Asim are you?
Why?
Looking at your care for her, you ought to be her daughter-in-law!
Have some shame, Malika.
He's your husband to-be!
Have some respect.
I've been telling her Aunt's not well for so long... But she just won't budge!
Yes. Your Aunt's really unwell.
Come with me, Munni.
Leave her to herself.
I know it very well.
You want to get me married to that Asim!
That's why you want to take me there.
Nothing can fix you.
Seriously...
Why the devil do you keep lecturing then?
-Get my wallet, Munni.
You don't take care of yourself, Salma. You don't take your pills on time.
That's why your BP's never normal.
Aunt's right.
She doesn't take care of herself. She stops taking her pills when she gets better.
This is very bad. Don't be so cruel to yourself.
The pills are so expensive... This poor lad's already juggling a job and tuitions...
I just do it to save something...
Aunt...
Did you hear that?
May the Lord provide for him.
Who else would care for you?
Alright, I'll go and iron my shirt for the morning.
I'll do it, Asim. You can talk.
-No, Munni.
You work at home, too. I'll do it.
-It's no big deal.
Give me any other shirts you have as well. I'll iron them all.
Give her, Asim. She's your sister.
Who else would care for you?
She'll do it.
Alright, come here. The iron's on the stand.
I'll go freshen up.
Here.
You could've brought Malika here.
She was tired when she got back from the university.
I thought she'd better rest.
Ah, the love of the child... It makes you lie to your sister...
I know she doesn't want to meer her Aunt. That's why it was just you yesterday.
It's not like that, Salma.
She's so close to you now.
I don't think she feels anything for any relations, Zahida.
Mum...
You know the university's so far away.
It's a long way home!
Malika always asks about you when I go there.
So you were listening in on us!
No one backs Malika like him!
I dare not complain about Malika.
You're not wrong here...
Malika's coldness worries me, too.
I guess Her Majesty's just living up to her name!
You're just getting worried for nothing.
What do I do with him! Madly in love with Malika.
May the Lord keep them happy.
-Amen.
Girls today are smart when it comes to love.
The love is as deep as the boy's pockets!
Malika's not like that, my dear.
That's where you're wrong, my friend.
She hasn't the foggiest.
What're you dreaming of?
Who else, but you?
Really?
What's this spell you've cast on me that makes me think of you even when you're not with me?
Seriously?
You're happy to hear it?
Obviously.
And I'm nervous...
Nervous?
Why?
Malika...
I want to ask you something.
Go on.
Grab a pew.
How much do you love me?
Do you need to ask?
I'm serious, Malika. Tell me.
If I asked you how much you love me?
I love you so much that I can give up everything for you.
I've been doing a lot for you as well, Noriyan.
If you know what I'm saying.
Alright, tell me. What kind of life do you want with me?
What do you mean, 'what kind of life'?
I'm serious, Malika. Please, tell me.
Obviously, a life of comfort, luxuries, serenity... Love...
And if you got a life...
With just love?
No comforts... No luxuries...?
What's up with you?
Why are you scaring me with this nightmare?
Anyway. I'm here to study. I don't want to think about any bad thing.
Keep at it if you want.
Thank you.
Where are you?
I'm right here.
I'm sure you haven't even started reading this.
We're submitting this presentation tomorrow!
There's so much work!
It's so boring...
Why don't you go? I don't want to.
I know what you want. And let me tell you, you won't get anything.
It's all your loss.
Why are you talking about losses and gains?
It's not a business transaction.
I'm in a relationship with Aqil!
What kind of a relationship is this?
You're the only one in it.
He's nowhere!
Is he ever there for you when you need him?
Even though you've done so much for him!
You're just not getting it!
How do I tell you that Aqil is --
Profit and loss, eh?
'Never calls me'?
Excuse me.
Blimey...
Hi!
Aunt!
Mum and Munni aren't home.
Aqil's gone somewhere too.
Hey...
I got these for you.
But why? You know I'm allergic to flowers!
You never told me about what you like...
How'd I know you're allergic to them?
If you're here to talk about all of that, you better leave.
Come back when someone's here.
Can't you talk softly to me, Malika?
Just humour me and say that you like the garlands?
I got engaged to you to humour you and the family! What else do you want?
So you got engaged just to humour me?
Of course!
Malika...
What do I lack?
I respect you, love you...
I'll keep you happy all your life.
Asim, I can't stand this blather.
You better show up only when you can get gold bangles instead of these garlands.
And don't go back to Mummy crying about what Malika said!
The door's that way.
If anyone saw you around, it's me they'd be after!
Go!
Bugger off already!
Yes, Atif?
Yes, Noriyan...
Who's this girl onstage with you?
She's a class fellow... What happened?
She's the perfect face for my new project.
But I know her, Atif...
She won't be interested.
How do you know that?
By the way, she's just your class fellow, right? Or...
Yes, Atif. She's just my class fellow.
How can you be so sure she won't be interested?
She may get interested if she heard my offer!
She's from a very conservative family, Atif.
She can't even think about it.
Forget about that. Just give me her number.
Hello?
What happened? What are you thinking?
I haven't even got her number, Atif...
What?
You've got this lovely lady in your class, and you haven't even got her number?
What'll you do, Noriyan...
Anyway, get it and send it to me.
Alright, Atif, I'll find out.
It's urgent. I'll be waiting.
Bye.
-Bye.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV