Hi!
Hey...
I thought I'd call and ask if Monsieur's fixed his mood, but thought I'd rather drop by.
You don't need to ask.
-That's why I'm here.
You get angry for nothing. Like a kid.
Know what?
Mum says you should be thankful if you've got someone who's angry with you.
But don't you think you should be all the more thankful if you've got someone ready to make it up to you?
Isn't that what you do? When you've made a mistake? Because it's your mistake?
But what've I done that you're so angry about?
I should've been angry with you, because you left me alone. I had to go there alone! Without you!
Why'd you have to go at all?
Because I'm not like you, okay?
You should be sorry you couldn't attend the wedding of your best friend's sister, but you're angry because I went there?
Wait...
Why should I be sorry?
Aqil doesn't give two hoots if I attend his sister's wedding or not.
In fact, they'd be glad I didn't show up. I know what it's like. If I drop by, they get worried where they could have me sit!
And... He was never sorry living on my money!
Don't say that about your best friend.
He's my best friend. I know him inside out.
He didn't even bother to ask me why I wasn't there! He never forgot to come to me when he needed help!
That's oh-so-lovely of him!
You positively hate everything about him! How is he your best friend then?
And you can call him your best friend. He's been to your place. You've talked to him about me. How could he be your friend if you loathe him so much?
He never said one bad word about you. He speaks quite highly of you.
It pains me to see how you want to show off that you've helped him arrange his sister's wedding.
It's true...
What are you looking at?
I'm looking at my future. Would you have me account for everything after our marriage, too?
So you won't even listen to me after our marriage?
So it's just the wife's duty to obey orders, while the husband can order her around as he likes, pull her up when he wants? Is that what you're telling me?
That's how it is here.
I got you! See!
Don't take it seriously, I'll be a good, understanding husband.
Are you sure?
Yeah. I'm sure.
Let's go have something. I get this peckish feeling when I'm angry.
No, thanks. I don't feel like eating anything right now.
See?
You're angry. Cheeks -- Going red -- You -- You're getting angry now!
C'mon, let's go.
You created quite a situation, though...
I'm not afraid of any 'situation'. I trust the One who can help us out.
No way you're working now, Mum.
I've talked about tuitions. I should be able to start in a few days.
Focus on your studies.
I've got a good job at the factory. No issues there.
But Mum --
-We need a long-term solution, Noriyan. Focus on your studies for now.
Look for a job later.
As if I'd get one anytime...
It takes years, if not months, to find a good job.
I'm sure the Lord will help you.
I want you to start doing something before Ashi comes here.
Ashi?
Jesus -- You're still thinking of her?
Who should I think of?
Certainly not the one even you've got no reason to think of now!
I don't want to get married, Mum. I'm not thinking of anyone!
Have it your way... When I'm not around. But while I'm hanging back, let me tell you - Ashi's the one for you.
But why, Mum?
Because I've got only one son, Noriyan,
And I can't see him become a hermit because of some snooty Malika.
I've ironed my clothes, Mum.
Give me yours.
I don't really feel like going... Haven't got the courage.
Don't you always talk about being brave? And -- What'd they think?
-She'd hate it if I were there.
Mum...
I don't want to go either. But what about Asim? And Aunt?
If we didn't even show up at the reception, they'd think we were just waiting to get rid of Malika!
They're wise. I'm sure they know everything by now.
Who'd hold a daughter who's disgraced the family dear?
Mum... Please get ready... Or Malika will be certain that we despise her.
She ought to drown in shame than think that her mother could despise her.
Kids may fall from grace... But their mothers never despise them.
Then please get ready, Mum... And bless her.
She thinks they're like curses...
She'll grow to think of them as her most valuable gift one day.
Besides, Aqil already said he's not going.
We ought to. C'mon. Get ready.
Ah...
Mum!
-Munni!
Mum! What happened? Sit.
Heavens...
Lie down.
Aye...
What happened?
Water...
What happened, Mum?
-I'm fine...
What happened?
Just got a bit dizzy...
-I'll call Aqil...
No need... I'm fine...
-No, you're not.
Something wrong with the network... Can't even get through now!
I'll be fine, Munni...
-Look at yourself, Mum! You're so cold...
Novera...
Hello?
-It's Minahil.
Hi, how are you?
-D'you know where Aqil would be?
No. What happened? Everything alright?
Mum's not well. Got no word from Aqil...
-Don't worry. I'll get to him...
Okay.
Mum...
I'll get you some lemonade...
Okay.
Hey! Going somewhere?
Yeah, Dad... Minahil just called... Aqil's sister? His Mum's not really well... And he's not home. I gotta go. They're so worried.
Wait. Why do you have to go? Just call Waqas.
I think you're right... I'll call him...
-Okay.
I'm not satisfied with the sales team's performance. Always making excuses about the competition...
Excuse me...
Hey...
-Waqas...
Minahil just called. Her Mum's not really well.
Minahil?
-Munni! Aqil's sister.
Why'd she call you?
Aqil's not home. Do you have any idea where he could be?
No, but let me try.
-I already did. His phone's switched off.
Novera... I'm in a meeting right now... Give me a minute...
Okay, bye.
Dad. I have to go myself. Bye.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV