By the way, everyone's talking about you.
Me?
I'm so lucky!
Do the girls talk about me too?
A few, yes...
Not all of them.
Zoha...
I get so insecure sometimes...
I mean...
What'll happen to me if you left me?
You think I'd ever leave you?
But why?
Why not?
Look at yourself.
You've got no shortage of men...
Besides, the likes of me can only dream about everything you've got.
Honestly, even if someone like me worked all day and night, he wouldn't get a fraction of what you've got...
Perhaps we can talk about marriage when I've... You know...
Why are you so grim again?
I'm not being grim, Zoha... Just... Realistic...
I don't get what you see in -- I mean, you can marry any rich man you want.
Yes, I can.
But there's something about you.
I like being with you.
My pocket's empty.
-Empty pockets can be filled.
I've asked you to manage the Dubai branch with me.
No. I can't work with you. It's too big a responsibility. Besides, your partner, Zahir... He doesn't like me one bit!
C'mon, Zahir's a sweetheart.
D --
Does it hurt your male ego to work with me?
Jeez --
-Alright, then.
Our marketing and financial division's yours.
-I told you I can't work with you.
People already think it's too odd... The two of us...
You want me to work for you so people can say I'm using you?
Jesus, mate...
Well, then --
-I'm leaving.
Aqi --
She's the perfect face for my new project.
But I know her, Atif...
She won't be interested.
How can you be so sure she won't be interested?
She may get interested if she heard my offer!
What kind of life do you want with me?
Obviously, a life of comfort, luxuries, serenity... Love...
And if you got a life...
With just love?
No comforts... No luxuries...?
What's up with you?
Why are you scaring me with this nightmare?
What's up?
What are you worried about?
Asif and Farhan said you've been very worried of late.
Had a row with Malika, maybe?
No...
What, then?
Who called you?
Atif.
He would've called to ask you how you are.
Why are you lying, mate, it was obviously Malika!
No, it wasn't!
But it was about her. Atif asked for her number.
Why? What'd he do with it?
He's got wind of your romance and wants to take things forward!
Am I right?
Oh, please. I haven't even told Mum about Malika. How would Atif find out?
What does he want, then?
The thing is...
Atif wants to offer Malika a commercial...
Wow! That's brilliant! She'll be an overnight star!
Blimey -- Be done with it already...
-Please ask him to give us a chance, too!
After all, we're quite handsome ourselves... Photogenic, innit?
Of course.
And my last selfie got so many likes!
I'm dying of worry and you're laughing it off!
What do you mean 'laughing it off'? We're damn serious, mate!
I don't get what's with this sad face!
You know Mum doesn't like this field one bit.
Mum had Atif swear she wouldn't let me get into modelling. She hates it!
So don't do it. Give us a chance. Or Malika.
If Malika got a chance, there's no chance I'm getting her!
Hello! Get some sense into him.
Hey!
I get it now...
What?
He doesn't want Atif to meet Malika because if he gave her a chance, Noriyan's Mum will never accept her as her daughter-in-law.
No need to go to those stony broke plebs!
Why didn't you stop Mum?
Not all of us are uncouth like you.
You're so lippy!
Have you ever thought about your future?
At this rate, you'd just be leaving one coop for another!
I don't think like you.
Don't dream too big for your means.
Besides, I can't say no to Mum.
Ready?
-Yeah.
Yeah.
-Bless you.
No need to give them any hopes, Mum.
I mean, they even look like plebs!
Why? What's wrong with them?
They're family. Upright. What else do you want?
Families and uprightness don't fulfil dreams.
Keep these dialogues to yourself.
And keep your voice down. What if they heard you?
What'd they think of us?
Munni,
Bring tea when I call you.
Okay.
BrINg tEA wHeN I CaLL yOu.
God knows how you like any of this.
Go and serve them tea. Like a humble slave.
To the dickens with you...
♪ Why do you have to be a heartbreaker, ♪
♪ When I was bein' what you want me to be? ♪
Jesus...
It's her again!
And you won't answer because it hurts your male ego! Innit?
'I knOW... iT hURts yOuR MalE eGO'.
Blimey, I don't even know what male ego is!
I'm starting to get it when you told me.
She prates about 'male ego' all the time... Let her have it, then!
I can't help it.
Think again.
What if Madame didn't call again?
Listen...
There's many 'Madames' like her.
Why can't I see your Facebook ID?
I deactivated it.
Why?
Jeez, I have to tell you everything...
Alright...
How will Zoha feel any guilt unless I cut off every way she has to reach me?
Block her, maybe?
Jeez...
You're so kiddish... College-level at best...
Look...
If I blocked her, she'd think I'm cross with her.
But when I deactivated my account, she'd realise how much she's hurt me.
Get it?
Oh...
Ho ho ho!
Where do you get these ideas from?
No idea...
You can learn a few too...
-Nah, bro...
I don't even know the A, B, Cs of relationships...
I like listening to your stories.
Alright, then, get your bard some coffee.
Okay.
Cappuccino!
-Okay!
Nasrin!
Nasssriiiiin!
What happened? Why are you shouting like that?
Mum, ask Nasrin to get some coffee.
Don't tell me he's still here.
He is.
Blimey... That ne'er-do-well!
He's my friend...
So?
He's useless. God knows if he'll ever do anything!
-Hush! He may hear it!
He's our guest, Mum...
-Not like I'm saying anything wrong!
Don't his parents worry about him? He's here all day!
He isn't just anywhere. He's with me. Good.
Please ask Nasrin to send a cup of coffee. Thank you!
She's from a very conservative family, Atif.
She can't even think about it.
Forget about that. Just give me her number.
I haven't even got her number, Atif...
What?
You've got this lovely lady in your class, and you haven't even got her number?
What's your problem, Noriyan?
I've told you not to call me when I'm at home!
I called you because it's important.
What is it?
Delete your Facebook account. Right now.
What?
But why?
What happened? Are you in your senses?
Can't you do me this little favour?
What is up with you, Noriyan?
What are you saying? You neve --
-I've never had this trouble before!
What kind of trouble?
Just do as I say, Malika.
Please try to understand.
What's with that smile? What's there in my laptop?
The mad woman. I was checking Zoha's ID.
Guess what...
She's filled her entire timeline with depressed, emotional, teary stuff... Told the world she's sad.
Look...
She's suffered depression before.
You're being too mean. Stop it and talk to her.
You've got even. Made her feel too guilty. I think you should talk to her now.
Please, Monsieur,
No lecture today.
Gotta say...
Madame's mad for you.
No way she isn't.
If she were, she'd never ask me to work for her.
So you say she should've made you a business partner.
-Of course.
That's what they do if they're mad in love.
Way to go...
Novera seems to be missing you a lot!
Didn't I tell you not to poke your nose everywhere?
Novera's the one I told you about.
My cousin.
Oh...
I get it now...
Mlle Novera l'Aloé Véra, innit?
Aye.
That'd be her.
She's coming to Pakistan and everything will be settled then.
Good luck, mate.
There you are, Noriyan!
Mr Atif was asking about you.
Please don't call him Mr Atif like that!
You say he's like your son, but call him Mr Atif!
Besides, he doesn't consider you a servant.
Did he ask you to do something?
Yes...
Why didn't you get back?
What could I say? He asked for a girl's number.
Who?
A class fellow.
Why did he want her number?
Something about his work...
A photoshoot or something.
How does he know her?
I'd showed him a video of the play...
She was with me in it.
Why'd you have to show it to him?
What do you mean, Mum?
Let me be very clear.
I better not hear that you introduced any girl to Atif.
I don't want anyone to work with him because of you!
Mum...
Why do you hate Atif's work so much?
Look at how much people admire him, respect him... Look at his influence!
-Enough.
I'm interested in his work too, Mum.
You haven't seen what I have, have you?
I know the job very well...
It's okay in this profession.
-Oh, please!
I don't want you to be a part of anything Atif does!
And keep those you know away from him!
I don't like it one bit, okay?
Just --
Tell him...
You don't have --
Her number...
Alright, but...
Don't think so wrongly about his work.
A bit of it is no big deal, Mum...
C'mon, babes...
You know how this industry works...
None of those newcomers have the experience and skill you have.
Know what, you've been my personal favourite...
And of course, yes, my crush...
Excuse me, Atif...
Just a minute.
Come in.
Mum asked me to meet you...
You sent for me?
I'd asked you for something.
I couldn't get her number, Atif...
You know it sounds so awkward to ask for someone's number...
Awkward, is it?
You must've rehearsed so much with her... Acted with her... But it's awkward to ask for her number, eh?
She won't be on Facebook either, right?
She's a real odd sort, Atif... Doesn't talk to anyone.
Not you, evidently...
Know her name? Or is it you couldn't even ask that?
Ah, yes, her name...
Malika... Yes, that's her...
Malika, huh?
Interesting...
Malika... Alright, go...
Okay. Thank you.
So where was I?
Sorry but I forgot...
Ah, yes...
What's with all this grief?
Who's died?
Not today, Zahir...
I'm very serious.
Sweetheart...
I bring excitement in your life.
Get up! On your feet!
Aren't you coming to Muzee's party?
You've been invited too!
I'm in no mood for any party! Go and enjoy yourself. Leave me alone.
I'd left you alone...
When I shouldn't have.
I'm paying for it with these moodswings...
You start on the same old thing every time...
I told you, I don't want to go anywhere.
Give me your phone, will you?
Let me hammer some sense into that twit.
He's wrecked our happy life!
He's made a tragedy queen of a woman who was so full of life!
When was I ever lively?
Don't find excuses to start about him...
Fine...
The party's cancelled. I'm staying here.
Let's listen to some laments together.
Seriously?
Do I have a choice?
Alright, what'd you like to have?
You know it very well.
My favourite basil soup.
It's basil curry.
So I've been having curry, thinking it's soup all along!
Zahir!
Stop watching it. If Aqil caught you, I tell you!
Why?
Is it a crime?
Don't you remember how he caught you that day?
So he can gad about but we can't even do this...
Please, for Heavens' sake...
Why do you want to create a scene?
Why'd I have to be born in this blasted coop!
Their families don't stop them, do they?
But ours can't even let us watch!
Watch all you want over at Asim's.
No one will stop you.
Don't even mention his name before me!
But he's so nice...
How say you marry Mr Goody Two Shoes when I've gotten married?
But you won't marry him just like that, would you? You've got to do the whole thing...
Laying the tray before them, acting coy and all before getting married... Innit?
Just my two cents, but... Such pride doesn't suit anyone.
You just need something to be proud about!
Ms Sana looks so delighted today!
Looks like your report's been passed.
The boss has praised it too!
Oh my God! Congratulations! You finally got to hear some praise after all those earfuls!
Thank you.
And thank you, too, Asim.
For?
For your guidance.
It's nothing, really.
Just a few basics... Your report was fine.
Look at what you're saying, Mr Asim...
Ms Sana doesn't give credit to others just like that! Take it while you can!
Alright, if you say so.
You're welcome.
By the way, I'm right here if anyone needs anything.
I really need your help.
Yes?
Sana's got to give us a treat. No way she's giving us one if you don't help us!
Alright, I will!
You're too kind.
It's nothing.
I'd be glad to celebrate this with my friends.
Alright. Tomorrow. Lunch's on me.
We can have lunch again today if you say! We're all ready.
Aren't we, Anoushay?
Oh, sure, you will, Farah... But what about Mr Asim?
Tomorrow. For sure.
Okay, ma'am...
As you wish.
I hope it's okay, Asim?
Yes?
Okay...
Yeah?
Hello...
How are you?
I was waiting for you.
Me?
I don't know you.
I saw your performance.
I must say you've done a great job.
-Oh...
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Here.
Take my card.
But why?
I need you.
I can drop you if you don't mind.
We can talk on the way.
I don't even know you...
Getting in the car with a stranger...
Sorry.
I'm sure we'll get acquainted on the way, Ms Malika.
How do you know my name?
You couldn't have any other name.
What an attitude...
Befitting none but an Empress [Malika]!
This is gonna be fun.
Take my card.
But why?
I need you.
Alright, you may go...
-Hello, Aunt.
Hello, m'lad. Bless you.
Mr Sharif from the general store sent this.
Alright. Thank you so much.
I'll get going then...
Didn't he send the bill?
I paid him.
I had the money...
Alright, how much did you pay him?
-Way to go, Aunt...
You call me your son, right?
And that this is my home?
What's the big deal if I got some groceries?
It was just a small amount anyway.
That's alright...
But every now and then... It doesn't seem right...
Alright, Aunt, pay me back when Aqil starts earning.
That day may never come...
He's not the type who'd take up any responsibility...
Aunt...
Why do you worry so much?
The Lord will ease things for us...
Asim...
You're not just his cousin but also his brother-in-law to-be.
Why don't you try to tell him?
I would if I ever saw him here!
I haven't seen him in months!
Right...
He's on his laptop all night and gets up in the evening.
God knows where he is all day.
No idea...
Tell me...
What does he do on his laptop all night?
It's a disease that's spreading so fast, Aunt!
What do you mean?
-Social media!
Everyone's on social media these days.
Busy on their phones and laptops.
Alone even in 'gatherings'.
Right...
But what is this social media thingy?
Hey...
I'm sure Malika can tell you better.
I'll get going.
Alright.
What good is all you education if you can't even greet a guest back?
Don't expect any civilties from me if the first thing I saw in here was your nephew!
Have some shame, Malika... He's your fiancé.
That's what he thinks.
I don't accept it at all!
You've been engaged for seven years!
Look at what you're saying!
I didn't get to choose seven years back.
Seven years is a long time to have second thoughts.
Oh?
What's your choice then?
Let me be clear -
I don't want to hear anything from you on this matter.
It's my life, Mum, and I won't let anyone ruin it just like that.
Who's ruining your life?
Asim's so nice. Why do you hate him so much?
Because I don't want to stifle my life!
He earns a good salary. They've got a home. Juggles two jobs. What else do you want?
How can a man who juggles two jobs keep me happy?
'Their home'! Which is chock-full of Aunt Salma's dowry!
And -- His clunker tells me just how much he earns!
As if we've got anything better! All this furniture was my dowry!
Thank God, because there are millions who don't even get so much.
And there are millions who've got everything, and more...
Aye. A few hundred. A few thousand, maybe. Thoughtless, all the rest!
Don't keep your head stuck in the clouds. It's a long way down.
My sweet Mum, if I've got my head in the earth, I'll keep sinking lower.
I want to soar high.
I hate those who crawl on the ground.
Malika...
I'm very worried...
Jeez, you're always worried!
I'm sick of you too!
Sorry. The number you've dialled is powered off. Please try later.
The number you've dialled is powered off.
Why are you here?
I didn't expect this from you.
You shouldn't have come here.
I hate those who turn tail.
I'm not here to upset you, but you're ignoring me.
Zoha...
Go. Please.
I'm telling you...
They're all talking about why you're here.
Please, get going.
I'm going. But come over.
I'll be there. Go.
'You should be a model, Malika'.
Madame quite literally barged in!
'Barged in'? That moron...
No way. You're made for each other. The perfect pair.
Jeez, mate, I'm exercising!
I bet she ain't gonna leave you.
As if I want her to!
Why do you hurt her so much then?
I don't hurt her!
I just remind her what I am to her!
She's getting a bit rusted in the head with age.
What'd you two talk about?
-Oh, she doesn't talk!
It's a blimming speech! You don't know nothing!
Honestly, she's a headache...
AqiL, i DiDn't mEaN tO hUrT YoU... PleASe...
Jesus, man...
You're quite the clown yourself!
I mean...
Forget it... Back to your weights.
Don't even start...
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV