This is for my girl.
You're too kind, Salma...
Zahida... I'm her aunt, after all!
Who else would get her a gown for her mehndi?
They're both just lovely, Aunt!
Where's Malika, by the way?
She was here just now! I think she went out.
How say you give it to her?
She -- Had a -- headache, Mum...
She took a pill and went to sleep.
How'd she fall asleep in this noise?
C'mon, let's give it to her.
Hello, Aunt...
Well, hello there...
Would you look at this lovely mayoun gown! From your aunt!
May the Lord give her good fortune. I thought I'd give her these and bless her.
Munni told me you had a headache. You could've told me. I would've made you some tea.
Tea ain't gonna cure this headache.
Take a pill.
I'll do with your blessings for a start...
I say you should get some rest. I'll get going, Zahida...
Bye, Aunt.
-Bye, my dear.
A little more?
-No, thanks.
You should've told us. Noriyan would've brought you here himself.
Of course. What if you got sick on the way?
I'm fine now. Don't worry.
You shouldn't have come alone.
Aye, Sakina, but I thought I'd come here, get myself checked up. I've heard a lot about this doctor.
Of course, Uncle... Ain't never a good idea to ignore your health.
Tell your Mum. She looks so weak...
I'm fine.
Everyone's got blood pressure and stuff these days. Anyway...
I won't let you go so quickly! You've got to stay here for a few days!
Just a few days?
Stay here as long as you want!
How say you put Mum's complaints to rest, Uncle? You're staying here at least a week.
Aye.
You're family. I want to stay here, too. But you know about your Aunt and the kids...
They're all alone. Things ain't really good at the village. Robberies and all.
May the Lord protect us all...
-No excuses, Uncle. Please.
Okay.
Did you stay with us? Remember how much I asked you?
If only Mum weren't here alone!
Let's just say it's the same with me...
Anyway, check this out.
-Aye, I almost forgot.
Leavin' already?
-Yeah, in a bit of a hurry.
Just wanted to tell you Malika's getting married tomorrow.
Congratulations!
Why'd you fix the date so suddenly? All good?
-Yeah, it's her in-laws. Blimey... Just had to do it.
You coming?
-Of course.
Come with Aunt.
I'll tell her, but...
I can't guarantee she'll come.
She's back. Why don't you invite her yourself?
-Hello, Aunt. How are you?
Hello.
Guess what, I was just here to invite you.
-To?
His sister's getting married.
-Oh.
Congratulations to your family.
-Sorry but I haven't got a card. Everything happened so quickly we couldn't even get the cards ready.
It's okay. Waqas'll be there even if I couldn't.
Okay, I'll get going.
-Okay. Take care.
Take care.
Get me a glass of water, Nasrin.
-Mum...
What is it?
Why'd you say I'd be there if you couldn't?
Aren't you going?
Of course I am, but I wanted to go with you.
You know I don't like your friend one bit.
So please don't insist.
Mum...
It's his sister's wedding. Please.
Stop it, Waqas.
Hey!
-Hey!
Hi, how are you?
I'm good.
Going back?
Yeah, just droppin' by to invite Waqas. My sister's getting married.
That's really exciting! I love weddings!
You do? So... Would you like to come over to my place?
I mean, just think about it... I live in L.A.
Really? You live in Los Angeles?
No.
L.A. - Liaquat-Abad, Karachi.
Blimey, you folks've got your own L.A. in Karachi!
I read that one in a Kamila Shamsie book... Kartography. Very thoughtful.
I know what you're saying.
You're talking about the social divisions around Clifton Bridge, right?
But I don't believe in social divisions.
It'll be my pleasure to be there if you invite me.
Think again.
Because I'm your typical middle-class local guy.
I don't care about any of that.
-Sure?
Bye. Take care.
Hey!
Hello, Aunt!
-Hi, how are you? I'm good. You?
Great.
-Sit.
I never knew we were invited!
You know you sound like a typical Paki right now?
Who told you?
I think she's talking about the wedding of Aqil's sister.
-Yeah.
He invited you too?
-Yeah. He met me at the door and invited me.
Just like that. How convenient! I'll leave you to yourselves.
What's up with her?
Mum doesn't like how casual he is.
Oh... I see...
You going?
I've got to.
Okay, then. I'm coming with you tonight.
The wedding's tomorrow.
But the mehndi's today! I'm coming with you! I'm so excited!
Trust me, it ain't nothin' like the movies. Just a small function with the family. Nothing exciting about it.
But I still wanna go! And we're going!
'We'? It's a ladies' function. We're going to the wedding together.
Okay, if you don't wanna go, no issues. I can go alone. Give me the address.
Okay... No problem... I'll give you the location.
You'd get bored there though.
Why?
Without me?
Don't worry. I'll enjoy myself.
I'll be really good.
How could you not come to my mehndi, Granny?
It's nothing serious really... Just my blood pressure... I'd rather stay avoid from the crowds...
Don't worry. I'll be there for everything else.
By the way, your Mum went to give Malika her gown.
She wasn't in a particularly fine mood.
Granny...
Mum's mistaken. That's all.
I told you Malika loves me.
I mean, why'd she accept the proposal?
Look...
I've not seen the kind of happiness you'd normally expect around now on her face.
Granny...
You've started thinking like Mum.
Please, get some rest.
Anyway...
Did you invite Sana?
I've invited all my colleagues... Including her.
She called to congratulate me. I've invited her.
I don't think she'd be there...
I asked her to pray for Asim if she couldn't come...
-Anyway... How d'you like this?
My dear Asim looks gorgeous in whatever he wears. God bless you.
Thank goodness your reports are all fine.
Thank God...
I really wanted you to stay here tonight.
I wanted to stay here too, but I've got to go.
How say you come over with Noriyan for a few days?
Sure.
When the time's right... Sure.
What do you mean?
When I can go there with respect...
C'mon... You're my sister. You'll always get respect at my place.
Shall we?
He doesn't need to... I can go alone.
You came here alone, but I won't let you go back alone. Besides, it'll be so late when you get there...
Well, then, tell him he's staying with me for the night.
I'll stay with you as long as you want, okay?
If only he listened to me so much!
Don't say that. I'm sure he always listens to you.
You've gotta give that in writing, Uncle. So I can show Mum whenever she doubts me!
Bless you.
Anyway, Sakina. Bless you. Take care.
-Give my regards to everyone. Lots of love to Ashi and Naazi.
Come.
Hey! I can't believe -- Guess who's here, Mum!
Hi, Aunt. This is for you and your daughter.
How are you?
Mum, Novera. Waqas' cousin. I invited her in a hurry. Can't believe she's actually here!
Bless you.
Novera, Minahil. My sister.
Hi! How are you? Good to see you.
-Munni, Novera...
Take her to Malika.
-Sure. Come.
-Take these.
So it's her.
Yeah, Waqas' cousin, remember?
She's lovely... She looks well-to-do.
Aye... She is, yeah...
Alright, I'll leave you to welcome the guests. Got a lot to do.
Let me know if you need anything.
-Okay.
Malika... Meet Novera. Aqil's friend.
Hi, how are you?
You look nice.
Everything's so beautiful! I love it! Oh my God, these are so pretty!
This here's my work.
You're so creative!
I would've come earlier if I knew... To help you, you know.
I would've asked Aqil to bring you here if I knew about you!
Know what, he didn't even invite me. I invited myself.
No way. I know everything.
What?
Aqil likes you, of course!
What? Who told you?
Who talks about these things? It's all about reading the signs!
Look at this.
Lovely, innit?
You shouldn't have let Novera go to Aqil's.
She wanted to, Mum... Why should I stop her?
Blimey, he's after her like mad!
It's nothing like that, Mum...
Oh, really! He took her along for some ice cream that day, and now invited her! Why didn't he invite you?
It's her mehndi... Just for the ladies...
I've never been to his place... It'd be so awkward if I...
Anyway... Call and tell her to go home quick.
She'd be on her way.
Okay. Give me your phone. I'll call her.
No, I'll talk to her.
Are you sure?
Of course. Okay.
-Call her right now.
Excuse me.
Thank you...
Excuse me...
Hello?
Yeah, Novera. How's everything?
Great! I'm having proper fun here!
I think you should go back...
We're really enjoying ourselves... Don't you think it's too early?
Yeah, but it's so late... It ain't safe. I say you should get back.
Okay... Bye...
Lemme guess. Waqas.
-Yes. And now, I gotta go!
Going back already?
-Actually, I think it's quite late.
But I had proper fun here. Thank you.
You have no idea how we feel. You coming here and all!
Yeah, I understand... I could sense it.
I'll go see Aunt.
-Yeah, sure.
Bye!
Don't worry. You can always come to me.
Who could it be?
Hello?
-Hello... Am I talking to Malika's mother?
Why are you calling me at this hour?
You don't look at the time when your honour is at stake.
Who is it, again?
Noriyan's mother.
Why are you calling me right now?
I'd begged you to spare my son... You'd been kind to me... I thought it's time I repaid your kindness.
Some other day, perhaps... Please...
-I don't know if she's asked you or told you about it...
But, seeing her at a stranger's doorstep like that at midnight, I felt she'd made a run for it.
What?
I thought I'd tell you.
Malika!
Munni!
-What is it, Mum?
Where's Malika?
Right h --
-Goodness...
Aqil!
Yeah?
What is it?
M --
Malika's run away...
Where?
Noriyan's mother called... Come with me. Quick!
Get me my shawl, Munni.
My Lord...
You know what forced me to do this.
I would've been chained to that Asim forever if I didn't...
Don't worry.
You're safe here.
I've put everything on the line. Because I trust you.
Do you regret it?
Not at all.
I don't regret it one bit. But please...
Never let me regret my decision...
I hope no one saw you coming here?
No...
Nobody knows I'm here.
Good. Very good.
What's with this mehndi... This gown?
I had to... I could never break free if I didn't...
And Asim!
I can't even imagine living with him!
And me?
I dream of it...
It's what gave me the courage to do it...
If you're worried, if the guest room feels suffocating to you... Feel free to come to my room.
After we get married, sure. I'll live out my dream life with you.
Ah, yes... Of course... We'll get married.
Keep Malika safe, O Lord...
Blimey, Malika, what've you done?
I swear I would've called the cops on you if I didn't care about my honour!
Keep your voice down.
Keep at it and I can call the cops on you too. For bulldozing me.
Where's Malika?
I'll effin' kill you!
Hold it!
-Don't you dare touch me! Get it?
-Aqil!
Take that bloodthirst somewhere else.
I'll break every bone in your body if you so much as touched her here!
I never thought I'd live to see this day!
Were it not for my honour, I would've choked you right here!
You choked me the day you shut all happiness out of my life!
I mean -- Asim! Ych a fi! I'd rather be buried alive!
Just wait until we get home! You may just get your wish!
Home? It's a blimmin' crypt where I've buried all my dreams!
Fine by me. I'm calling the cops.
What're you gonna tell them, eh? What've I done?
I'm grown-up now! I can do as I chuffin' want!
You still wanna call the cops? Be my guest! They'd love to feel your collar for forcing me!
Just stop it!
I see... So it was all planned...
You pick out the big fish, send your daughters to them in the middle of the night, and come knocking when you know you have him! Shame on you!
Shut your gob! You come on to innocent girls and have the nerve to accuse us!
I didn't call her here.
She came here because she wanted to!
I just let her in so I can take her back first thing in the morning and save you from this humiliation. But you! You accuse me!
What are you talking about, Atif? I -- I'm here to get married -- to you!
Are you out of your mind? You better know your place!
I didn't call her here. There's nothing of the sort going on. She's all yours.
Get a move on, already! Before they kick you out!
Don't you dare even talk to Malika again.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV