I told your Mum to keep an eye on her son.
Why should she?
You're here now.
It's your turn.
I love you so much, you little twit!
You're just like your Dad. As smart and cultured as he was.
All thanks to your blessings, Granny.
I came here, but you were busy talking to Mum. I thought I'd rather not interrupt.
Your Mum's like a daughter to me.
Who would a daughter talk to but her mother?
So she's started complaining to you the moment you came here?
Nothing of the sort, m'lad.
Always remember that she only wishes for what's good for you.
I know, Granny.
She thinks that Malika doesn't feel the same way about you.
Why are you worried, Granny? I'm sure time will fix everything.
May the Lord will so...
I'm going with Salma to your Aunt's tomorrow.
Sure.
She was asking about you. She said she'd come here to meet you.
Your Aunt's so wise and brave...
After her husband's death, she's raised her children all by herself.
But Salma told me Aqil's the same old carefree, irresponsible lad?
Aunt tries her best... But he just doesn't listen.
It pains mothers so much when their kids are so irresponsible.
May the Lord makes things easy for her.
Amen.
Granny...
You should get some rest. I'll get some sleep too.
Okay.
-Good night.
Good night.
Don't forget to take your pills.
-Bless you.
I'm just waiting for you to fix the date.
Are you crazy? I'd get married at this age?
Blimey... I'm talking about Novera!
Ah, yeah...
Aren't you doing things a bit too quickly?
I don't think so!
I'd always thought of making Novera my daughter-in-law.
When I got word you're shifting here, I decided that the first thing I'm doing is asking you to fix the date.
That's what I want too, Sumeyra, but I think we're taking things too fast...
That's what they want, too! They look so good together!
Ever noted how they have an understanding?
But of course... They're cousins, after all!
But I don't think they see each other as husband and wife...
What do you mean?
I want what you want, but marriage is a big decision. You got to think. It takes time.
Take your time.
But I'm sure we can get them engaged?
Yeah, that's good.
Okay, then. Talk to Novera and tell me the date.
Hold your horses, again. I'll talk to her and get back to you.
You got to decide in my favour.
I'll do my best. The rest is up to God.
I trust you.
-Have something.
I'm sure Mum would've talked about the wedding with Uncle.
What? Are you serious?
Yeah. You don't know Mum.
Okay...
In fact, I'm sure they would've fixed the date too.
25th, next month? Yeah.
Perfect.
It's about my life. They won't decide anything before asking me.
Okay...
Call and tell them.
Tell them what you think.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
You're so bold and independent. Just tell them.
Sure am.
So much that I can reject your proposal in your face.
Yeah, right. Good one.
What?
Look at yourself, fraidy cat!
What are you up to?
Let's see...
You're nice...
Handsome...
Wise, too...
But...
-If I'm nice...
Handsome, and wise, what else do you want?
You don't get all of it in one man here! When they get so lucky, girls don't get tired thanking God!
And you're one lucky girl, I give you that!
Poor girls...
They have to compromise on everything.
The poor girls...
Don't even think about it! I'm not one of them.
What was that?
I'll tell you everything.
Let's have something else? Excuse me!
I think these curtains are just too old...
We should change them. How about some new bedsheets too?
And a new fabric on what you're sitting on would make it good as new!
And we should get a new sofa over here.
Everything alright? Sounds like you hit the jackpot.
Something like that. By the way... Aren't these wall hangings, like, ancient?
We should change these too.
If we're getting a new sofa, how about one that's golden and fawn?
Not bad.
-You may go.
Who's getting a new sofa?
Malika. She says we ought to change the curtains too. And the wall hangings.
But why? Everything's great. We don't need any of that.
Nothing's great, Mum. You haven't seen how they all live.
Even small houses look good with expensive things.
Ours is a weird place we can't invite anyone to.
Who do you want to invite?
Noriyan's coming here with his Mum.
Who's Noriyan?
Go and do the dishes, Munni.
Why'd you send her away? What's the big deal if she heard it?
It isn't something to shout from the rooftops either.
When's she coming?
Stay tuned!
Tell them they've got to make do with these sofas.
They're straight out of the top drawer, Mum... And they're coming to ask for your daughter's hand in marriage.
They can't sit here!
Tell them we haven't got a place befitting a royal here.
If they're okay with it, I can go to their place and talk about it.
It isn't, really, but you put it down in the dumps.
Let me be clear - they'll have to sit on these sofas.
Who's doing it for them? I'm doing it for us! It'll earn us respect in their eyes!
Things don't earn respect. Your character, your civility - that's what earns respect.
Blimey, you're so ancient!
Indeed. I shouldn't even be here in this age. But I can't help it. I'll go on as long as I'm alive.
Why do you always say these things?
You know I love you so much...
But I can't talk to anyone else about what I wish for. That's why I sometimes...
I've worked so hard all my life so you never feel in want of anything.
But it seems it's all been wasted. I've failed miserably.
No way, Mum... I have no complaints.
You're so unthankful... But you wouldn't be whining about everything you wish for if you understood any of it!
I'll thank God for everything once I leave as Noriyan's bride.
In that case, I have no problem with your marriage.
Done with it? Show me the scarf.
Know what, I'm really missing you, but you'll have to wait another week. I'm so busy...
I'm missing you so much, and you're 'busy'?
Please don't say that. I asked you to come with me, but you refused...
I wish I didn't...
I know... Same here...
But don't worry. I'll be back soon.
Okay, I'll talk to you later.
It's you! What happened?
I wanted to talk.
What brings you here? So late, I mean...
You wake up in the evening.
Go on.
I told you to go to your Aunt's to congratulate Asim.
I will, when I see him.
You're angry as if it wasn't your fault!
He tried his best to get you a job.
Please ask him not to care so much.
We don't need his favours!
Just tell me what I've asked.
Okay...
I'll go when I get time.
Go, get some sleep. It's late.
Good that I saw you here. I heard something really odd.
What?
Malika's brother - Aqil! Blimey!
What is it?
My son told me he's with a rich woman.
I got a feeling they're already married.
Blimey, Parvin... You say just about anything.
-You don't like anything I say.
Mark my words, time will prove me right.
That can't be. And even if it is, what's it to you?
It's just so wrong!
She's much older than Aqil!
Anyway... Age is just a number when the vaults are wide open.
What if our kids followed in his footsteps?
That's easy. Keep an eye on your kids instead. Make sure they don't follow in his footsteps.
I'm not kidding about it! Really!
Aqil's quick bucks seem to be her gifts!
Women like her control their men with their money!
Blimey, Parvin... Heaven knows what you think...
You've sworn not to believe anything I say. Alright, I won't talk about it again.
It'd be better if you didn't talk to me about anyone else.
Backbiting is sinful. It's best if you kept me out of it!
Fair enough. I won't say a word now. Nothing. About nobody. Good or bad. To the dickens with everyone!
I've got no one else I can talk to, but you've hurt me too.
You didn't go to university today.
I'll be going a bit late today.
Malika... Go in.
But Mum --
-Go!
Why'd you send her in?
We need to talk.
Don't tell me Aunt's asked for the date again.
Don't get your hopes up...
What do you mean?
The other day, Asim and your Aunt --
-Hold up.
Let me say something, Mum...
I'm gonna give that Asim a proper beating if he or Aunt went back on their word!
How dare he reject Malika now?
I'll drag him here, I swear!
Asim and your Aunt have not gone back on their word. Malika has.
What?
How dare she? Malika!
-She loves someone else.
Why didn't you cut her to pieces already?
-Are you out of your mind?
Oh, is it a crime to love now?
-I'll cut that brassy tongue of yours!
Well, what do you think about innocently chatting up God-knows-who behind closed doors all night?
I'll tell you what I think!
-Aqil!
Wait! Let me handle this!
You wanna lock horns with me? Me!?
-I don't need to lock horns with anyone!
I can talk to everyone about him! Can you say the same?
-You ruddy slapper!
-Munni!
-Aqil!
Calm down!
Cool down and think about it. Want to create a scene? Just think about your sister!
What about the scene she's creating?
The family, the neighbours, my friends - they all know she's been engaged to Asim for years!
Things can change...
What?
I can't believe you're saying that!
-Aye. I'm saying that.
When kids start deciding for themselves, they can't see any good in what their parents had decided for them.
-Enough!
She's not going to university again!
I'm sure someone there is leading her astray!
What if I told you she's not being led astray?
His name's Noriyan. He's very well-off.
Malika thinks she can get everything she ever wished for if she married him.
His mother wants to meet us.
That's where she's wrong! She won't never be satisfied!
I tell you - no one's coming here, or there will be trouble! Are we clear? Now go and tell her!
That will be all.
-Aqil!
Aqil!
Out of their bleedin' minds!
Jesus, these two!
Why'd you pick a fight with him? You should've let Mum do the talking.
I know just what Mr White-As-Snow's been up to!
You've been up to the same.
No. How can you forget what he's done?
Don't create problems, Malika.
I'm fine with you being okay with it.
It doesn't really matter if I'm okay with it.
-Why not?
Who the devil is Aqil to go against you? You're our Mum!
If only I were respected so much!
Please be done with it, Mum -- Blimey...
Why don't you get it? You may be done with it, but not Mum. Your refusal's hurt her so much.
Don't tell me a sister's closer than a daughter.
Wrong.
Love and affection draw you close.
Ties of blood become meaningless when they don't give a monkey's about anything.
Wow... Didn't know you were into the art of lecturing!
I'm sure something's forced Mum to think Noriyan would be better for you than Asim. But I don't think you can find anyone better than him.
Jeez, y'alls givin' me a headache!
Where are you going?
-To hell! I don't need to tell you, young lady!
Why do I get a feeling you didn't want to come here?
No, Mr Atif...
'Mr Atif'?
You always call me 'Atif'. What's up with this 'Mr' business?
Talk like friends, mate.
You're such a big name in the industry. I should respect that.
It's so awkward with friends, really... And we're friends, okay?
You mentioned a shoot.
Yeah...
There's this big client...
If this shoot goes well, you can go anywhere you want in showbiz.
But I don't think I can do it...
You know my family doesn't know I'm into this...
But... There's no going back now.
What do you mean?
Relax.
Take it easy.
Don't you want fame?
No.
Just money, then, eh?
That's easy. Just marry a rich guy.
What's his name? Your boyfriend?
Noriyan.
Aye, him. What's his status?
Just what I want.
Will he marry you?
Why not? He loves me.
He loves you. Do you love him?
Obviously. I love him too.
Okay, then...
Marry him...
I don't think he'll marry you once you're into modelling and all...
Why?
You're new here...
There's a lot you don't know yet...
Our industry can be a proper cruel place.
Ties don't matter here. Just... Fame and fortune...
You'll lose it all if you got married.
Anyway... Good luck...
If that's what you want... Take a shot.
Thank you.
Hey...
Join me for coffee, maybe?
A little farewell party?
Okay.
Just give me a minute. Sit.
You wanted to talk about something? What is it?
I think Noor said Malika's not coming to university because her Mum's sick.
Yeah, why?
I saw her on a date.
Hold your horses, bro. I'm sure you saw someone else. She loves him.
No. I'm positive. If anyone's mistaken, it's Noriyan.
Malika's too clever for him. She's pullin' the wool over his eyes. I knew it!
Asif...
This is where you need to stop.
You know he'd mind it.
But... He's our friend. We've got to tell him.
Not a word.
Bu --
-Not. A. Word!
If Malika's cheating on Noor, so is he! They're both in for a surprise.
But Noor's a friend. He should know if Malika ain't serious about him.
Just forget it, mate. Enjoy the dinner. Forget it.
If you say so...
What happened, Mum?
My blood sugar shot up last night...
I'll get the glucometer.
-I checked already. Taken the pill too.
You should've told me, Mum...
Why do you stress yourself?
I'm fine, Asim...
Okay, I'm not going to work.
Don't even start, Asim... I'm fine. Have your breakfast and go.
But Mum...
-I'd feel I'm sick if you stayed here...
I'll check again if I need.
Okay. I'll be back before lunch.
I told you I'll call if I need something... Anyway... Your breakfast...
Easy, Mum. I'll cook something.
-No. Wait. Let me...
Get some rest, Mum. Please.
Breakfast's ready. I'll get you some tea.
Why do you do everything when you're not well?
If you're so worried about me... Get married.
I never said no.
Well, just get over the one who has and move on.
I'll get some tea.
Asim... The boss wants this statement today.
Today?
Yeah... Boss' orders. Any problems?
No... Mum's not really well... I thought I'd go back early...
The boss is furious...
I can't talk to him. Maybe try something yourself?
No. I'll do it.
Okay, thank you.
What happened?
It's nothing serious, really...
I thought I'd get her checked up though...
You could've taken the day off.
No, it's okay... There's a lot going on... The delegation next week, this assignment and all...
Give it to me, I'll complete it.
Thank you, but you've got your hands full already. I'll do it.
No worries. Aunt needs to see a doctor. I'll complete it and forward it to the boss.
Sure, Sana?
I'm sure.
Sumeyra and I have decided to get you and Waqas engaged.
But Dad...
Don't you think it's a little too early?
Wait. I'm not forcing it on you. It's up to you.
Dad... I...
I really like Waqas, but...
-But what? Tell me.
She talked about getting you married. But I said it's too early.
She talked about our marriage?
I can get engaged to him if you say, Dad...
But I need some more time... To know him better, to really understand him.
So you have no problem with the engagement, right?
I'm sure you've thought about it.
I trust you.
Okay, I'll tell Sumeyra. Take your time.
Get to know Waqas. The more you know him, the more you'll like him!
But Dad... Why are you in a hurry to get me married?
It's every father's wish.
It's a responsibility.
Sumeyra's my sister, Waqas' my nephew... I can trust them to take care of you.
Okay, Dad.
If you think it's the best for me, I'm okay with it.
I'm sure you've thought a lot about it.
I totally agree with you.
But you promised me you'd take me on a tour of Pakistan!
How say right now? I can call Waqas and we can all go!
You're tagging Waqas along already! You promised me that you're gonna take me to the Northern Areas!
No Waqas. Just you and me. Okay?
Yeah!
Let me just call Sumeyra.
Okay, Dad.
-Get me some hot coffee, will you?
Okay, Dad, do your thing, and I'll get you a nice coffee.
-Aye, my dear. Bless you.
Here.
You didn't have to take me to the doctor.
I'm relieved now, Mum...
I don't tell you because you get so worked-up.
You came back early and took me to the doctor...
You just do as you like!
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon. It's Sana. Just called to let you know I've completed the report and sent it to Mr Sohail.
Thank you so much. I really appreciate it.
It's nothing. How's Aunt?
She's fine now. We're just back from the doctor's.
Who is it?
You remember Sana? At the office?
Let me talk to her.
She wants to talk to you...
Hello, Aunt.
-Hello, my dear. How are you?
I'm fine. How are you? Asim was so worried about you.
I'm good. But he gets worried sick, I tell you!
Take care, Aunt.
Bless you. Why didn't you come here?
Me?
Yeah.
Come over when you've got some time.
Sure, Aunt...
Asim will text you the address. Okay?
Okay, Aunt.
Bye.
Text her.
Blimey, Mum...
Mum's right...
I ought to tell Malika the truth.
I'm sure she loves me enough to forgive my lies...?
Noriyan...
What's up?
Told her?
No.
Couldn't say it?
She didn't come to university today.
You could've called her.
Her phone's off.
Don't worry... You can talk to her tomorrow.
In fact...
Take me to her place tomorrow.
I'll talk to her myself.
I'll tell her your truth.
This fear of losing her won't let the truth come out of your mouth.
Mum...
She'd be hurt I didn't tell her the truth.
This fear shows your love. I'll tell her about it.
Really?
Mum...
Please tell her that I believe I can give her every comfort in life.
Those who believe in love never covet any other comfort.
Malika...
Aqil's calling. You're going over to Salma's.
Me?
You've severed one tie, but it's not like they're nobody now!
Salma's not well... Just pay her a visit. A short one?
Why can't you go? She's your sister!
I've got a headache. I can go with Munni some other day.
Why don't you send her? She'd be oh-so-eager to go there!
Don't try to have your way every time!
Look. It's not like Aunt'll be pleased to see me. It just ain't no good.
Have it your way.
Hello, Aunt.
-Hello. Come in.
Mum said you're not well?
Yeah, in the morning. I'm good now. I'll get you something.
No. Not in the mood.
Sit. Asim's coming any moment. He's gone to drop a guest.
Well, Aunt, that depends on the - uh - guest. Innit?
She's his colleague, and she was checking on me.
That's sweet...
His colleague... With him for hours, I'm sure.
Blimey, he's got some proper nice female *ahem* colleagues. Comin' here, gettin' cosy and all, I mean.
Sure, she's proper nice. He's proper nice too.
That's why, Aunt, I tell you to keep an eye on him.
I've seen her with him before.
She's with him everyday. At the office.
Lemme get this straight. She used to be with him at the office... And now she's with him in his car. Making progress, I see!
I sent Asim with her. It's nothing of the sort.
It better be nothing of the sort, Aunt.
Because I won't take nothing of the sort.
Take care.
I'll get going.
He can take his sister's refusal but not my son getting in the car with someone!
Hi!
I called to tell you I'm not going to university tomorrow.
Really?
Won't you ask why?
Why?
I'm coming with Mum to your place.
Really?
Yeah!
Don't tell me you're not delighted!
And, Malika... I wanted to tell you something...
Yes?
Malika...
I love you so much...
You're all I want in my life...
I...
I know you'd be hurt to hear it, but...
Munni!
What is it?
Get me my protein shake. Quick.
I'm no billionaire, Malika.
Mum's the maid at this mansion.
And...
I live in the basement with Mum...
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV