I come here to forget all my worries.
I'd rather leave than hear any of that.
Please don't do that.
I don't know what I'd do without you.
Okay... Just relax.
I'm just a bit tensed these days...
That's why I had a go at you.
There, now... Why are you so tensed? Tell me.
Zoha...
It's my sister...
Her engagement's almost broken...
Because...
I can't arrange for her wedding!
I can help.
All that's mine is yours, too. You know that.
I can arrange for your sister's wedding.
Don't worry.
Why do you want to test me?
-I'm not.
I want to get you out of this worry.
-No.
I don't want anything from you.
-Cheque or cash?
Just a sec.
Here's 200,000. I'll arrange for more by tomorrow.
-It's not for you. It's for your sister. It's her wedding.
Aqil... Please...
Take it...
Okay.
Asim... I wanted to talk about something...
Yeah?
Please forget everything Sana said.
I don't get it.
I just mean -- You think she's not the right type -- Always looking for excuses to get your attention...
Miss Farah...
Please don't talk to me about it again. I don't like it.
Why do you always think about yourself?
What do you mean?
Her family's going through hard times. That's why she works here.
So?
She's going to leave the job. Please, try to understand!
What?
Yes, sir!
Strange...
Why's it such a big deal?
Hello?
Zo -- Zoha... It's Aqil...
What happened? Why are you so worried?
I -- Just a few steps from your place -- I -- Some robbers -- Took my bike, the cash at gunpoint -- Everything!
Are you alright?
Ye -- Yeah... I'm fine, but -- They took everything!
Alright, tell me where you are. I'm coming to get you.
I'll send you my location.
Okay. Just wait for me.
Bye.
You called me here?
Yeah. I don't see you around these days. What's up, mate?
Don't tell me you're still grieving over her!
It's nothing like that.
Just felt a bit down...
I'm sure I'll be fine after talking to you, Atif.
How will you move on if you keep thinking about her?
You know about the girls these days... In and out of your life when they want. I'm sure you'll find many others. Don't worry.
And yeah, get some air.
Also... Movie night with me tonight?
Sure.
See you, then.
Here.
Thank God you're safe.
I tried to fight back, Zoha, but --
-Are you crazy? You should've given them what they wanted quietly.
You have no idea what could've happened.
It's already happened.
I've lost everything.
I'm happy you're safe... What if something happened to you?
Anything could've happened.
And guess what, no one came to help me!
Nobody risks his life for anyone.
But Zoha...
The bike you gave -- The cash -- I lost all of it...
So what?
You'll get it all back, Aqil.
No...
I don't want anything from you. That's it.
No.
Don't say that.
You know I'm always there for you.
Who'd care for you if not me?
Yes?
Here.
-Blimey, Mum, so late!
Yeah, we'd gone shopping. Keep it here, and get me some tea, will you? I'm honestly knackered!
I can't even imagine what you'd do when it's time for the wedding.
It's my son's engagement! I'm very delighted. You're gonna love this ring if you saw it! It's so beautiful!
Novera likes it, right? You should've let me pick the ring if you cared about my choice.
Blimey, you're cross already!
No. I'm fine.
Did you want to take her shopping?
So what? You're done now, I mean...
She wanted to go shopping, but doesn't know her way around here. I just thought I'd go with her.
Mum...
I could do that... I've been born here, I know my way around town.
Are you getting jealous of your Mum?
No way...
What is it?
I got a feeling Novera thinks I'm immature.
Who told you you're one bit mature?
-Mum!
Hello?
'Sup, where are you?
Home?
Come out quick. Got a surprise for you.
Surprise? What've you got?
-I can't it to you in there, guv!
'Guv'?
You coming?
Okie doke...
Lemme guess. Aqil.
Yeah.
You wouldn't have such friends if you were mature.
Jeez, Mum...
Let's see...
What's it th -- Whoa! Blimey, man!
This is awesome!
Looks brand new! Mme. Zoha gave it to you, right? Innit?
This bike's just fantastic, bro!
-Your bro's fantastic! Remember that!
Aye, El Fantastico!
Start it, will you?
-Here. I'll show you.
Ready?
-Yeah!
Wanna try?
-Of course!
Your turn!
Gorblimey if I could find one thing kept properly here... His room's a thorough mess!
No idea what he's gonna do...
Where'd he...?
What are you doing?
Where'd you get this?
It's mine.
What do you mean?
I mean...
I've borrowed some money for Malika's wedding.
Who gives you so much money?
I'm dead tired, Mum. Not in the mood for an interrogation.
Munni told me you've got a costly phone. And what about that sports bike down there?
Jesus, anyone else in your place would've hugged her son. Blessed him, prayed that he got more. But you! You're grilling me!
I'd hug you, bless you, and pray for your success the day you earned a single penny you deserved, even if you had to spend it! But don't you dare bring of your 'gifts' here!
Just like your Dad...
He'd always come to me before going to work. For my blessings.
I remember, Granny.
I think I should get going.
I hope Sana's coming to work today?
She ought to.
You know where she lives, right? You'd dropped her home once.
Yeah. Why are you asking that?
Salma and I want to meet her.
Why?
Why not? After all, if she could come here...
Granny...
She didn't come here. Mum invited her here.
It's the same to me.
-But -- Granny...
I don't want her to get so close to you.
You can stay here if you like. We're going.
Granny...
You're not going anywhere.
It's okay if you don't care about me. But just think of your Mum! What about her wishes? Her dreams, her plans for you?
She always wanted to make Malika her daughter-in-law.
Forget Malika.
She never cared about you. Do you really think she'd care about your Mum?
Look... Sana's very nice. I want that your wife should respect you, respect your family...
No idea how you could even imagine that! Seriously!
Just think about it. We've lost all hope from Malika.
I think we should give Malika some time.
I think it's you who needs time. Not Malika.
Granny...
Please...
I'm sure Malika would think over it again...
Anyway, I'm getting late. I'll be back in the evening.
Okay, bye.
-Bye, take care.
Show him the way, O Lord...
We're out of oil, Mum. Just got enough for today. 5 kg?
We just got it two days back! Can't believe we used all of it! Everything seems to be going to waste!
Well... No surprise, really. Not when no one knows where all the money's coming from!
Don't even start...
I told you everything.
What are you looking at? Just thank God we're getting something!
I'd rather be thankful I don't have to depend on you two!
Blimey, you must be the only Mum in the world who hates everything about her kids.
What's up with you? Picking a fight first thing in the morning.
Don't expect me to be all cheery if that's what I hear first thing in the morning!
I didn't say anything to you, Malika.
I wonder if that's a hint of guilt I hear in your voice...
Please, Mum...
I asked Aqil where he got the bike, the phone, and all the money from...
Didn't he tell you?
Do you really think he'd tell me about whatever it is he's into?
What else do we need?
-A packet of Surf.
Hey!
Hey! Hi!
What a surprise!
How come Waqas ain't here?
Why do you think Waqas is always with me?
-He ought to be if he isn't! I mean, he's got such a lovely cousin...
Thank you for the compliment. He was busy at the office. I thought I'd rather not disturb him.
Tea or coffee? I'm not takin' a no. What'd he think if he heard that I didn't even ask you?
Are you sure Waqas won't mind?
-I'm 100% sure. He's an old friend, I know him.
Lemme get you tea.
Après vous!
C'mon.
Sure.
Be done with it quick. But remember that after this I'm not seeing you or taking your call, like ever! And don't you even dare threaten to come knocking!
You'll be knocked for six after what my brother would do to you!
What are you looking at?
Just say it and be done with it!
I think Mum's right, after all...
What?
She said that if I saw you again, I may grow to hate you so much that I'd laugh at my love.
Okaaaay...
Feelin' the hate growin'? About chuffing time!
Good riddance! Bye!
Why'd you do that?
I did it? C'mon, you can't be serious!
This love was rooted in a lie, and the truth's out now.
Malika...
Doesn't true love mean anything to you?
You can't get by on love, Noriyan!
But it's enough for our souls to get by, isn't it?
-Sweet Jesus... Sounds hollow, coming from you!
You'd punish me so harshly for one lie?
-Oh really!
What do you know about punishment? I'm being punished for trusting you, loving you!
You've shattered all my dreams!
No dreams matter more than love!
-That's where you're wrong.
My dreams matter to me much more.
Well, if you're done, I guess I should get going.
Why are you asking me?
You're already gone from my life.
Do me a favour, will you?
If you ever feel that love matters even one bit...
Just call out to me.
Don't keep yourself waiting.
I'm never gonna call out to you.
So, what do you do?
Something really important.
What'd that be?
Lookin' for a job. I'm an MBA.
Yeah, I understand unemployment's a big problem... But I guess it's the same as anywhere?
Nah, it ain't a big problem.
You get a lot of jobs here. But not the one you like.
What kind of job do you want?
-One that makes me independent.
I've got a simple formula. My life, my rules. Their lives, their rules.
Wow...
That's tidy.
Tell Waqas sometime. He doesn't seem to get it.
Really?
I thought he's very broad-minded.
Mulish is more like it.
Mu-lish... Hmm...
I can talk to him if there's any problem. We see each other at the gym everyday.
The thing is, he wants to marry me.
And I just asked him for some time so I can get to know him better...
But I don't know why he's in a rush.
He's going too fast, and I can't figure out why.
Not his fault if you ask me.
I mean, he's got a cousin like you. I don't see why he shouldn't be in a hurry to marry you.
He loves you so much.
I don't believe in love that doesn't care about what you think.
Blimey!
You think just like me! I mean --
I believe there's a difference between love and ownership. You should let the one you love live their life their way. Innit?
You're right.
Alright, how 'bout some snacks? I don't really like the idea of just having tea. What'd Waqas think? Hey!
-Okay...
Feelin' the hate growin'? About chuffing time!
Good riddance! Bye!
Don't keep yourself waiting.
I'm never gonna call out to you.
Hey...
Hello. You're back early.
Mitching today...
Why'd you go then?
I wanted to see if you were right...
I thought I'd see that two-timer...
Turn my love into hate...
And?
What happened?
You're right. She doesn't deserve my love.
Take my hand. Bridge the gap.
There's nothing I can't get you. You can live out all your dreams.
Think again.
Munni!
She's gone with Rashida to the doctor.
She took Munni because no one else was around.
This one goes here, okay?
What've you thought about her, Mum?
Here.
Work on this.
Who cares about what I've decided?
Nobody bothers about what I say!
I'm talking about Malika. You getting her married or not?
You're her brother. What've you thought about her?
You gave her a chance. It was no good.
Just one way out now, Mum.
Call and ask Aunt to take her.
Salma never refused!
Your sister did!
That boofhead!
She's out of options now.
I'm sure she won't refuse now.
Good to see you're back.
I'm sorry for bothering you...
Yeah... It bothered me a lot that you decided to quit the job over this trifle.
You were right... We're colleagues. Just colleagues.
I should not have hoped for anything else.
Miss Sana...
I'm not gonna lie to you...
My mother's honest-to-goodness.
I don't want you to get so close to her that it causes problems for me.
I hope you understand.
I do.
I'll give it to Mr Sohail.
What'd he say?
Reminded me my limits...
Just one photoshoot. That's all it takes to change your fate.
I won't be allowed to.
Who do you need to ask?
Family or someone else?
I mean, you're so lovely... You must have a boyfriend.
Or a lover whose happiness means the world to you.
Yeah, right.
Looking at you, I diagnose you with... Heartbreak!
Heartbreak, you say?
I've been deserted on the first step.
Why?
What'd she say?
She's upset with me.
She thinks I was this rich guy...
Ah, that...
Love doesn't really care about it... But there's always a few gold diggers...
They just want their independence, all that money... You can't help it...
But Malika was not like that! She knows I love her so much!
Do you seriously think she still feels that way?
-Of course, Atif! I love her so much, and I'm sure she'd love me someday!
She's just angry with me.
Hey...
All the best.
Malika, my dear...
If it's your love for your Romeo that's stopping you, allow me to sort it out for you...
Hello?
Why are you not coming to university?
There's no looking back!
You and Noriyan have broken up. They're all talking about it here.
You should've sorted things out. Did you guys have to make it public?
What do you mean?
Who made it public?
There's a few pictures going viral. Is it you or Noriyan?
-What?
What pictures?
Don't you know about your pics with Noriyan going viral?
Check your WhatsApp, I'll show you.
Yeah, send me, double time!
Oh my God!
Jesus, Noriyan!
Hello?
How can you be so low?
What happened, Malika?
-What do you think?
You're settling scores by making these pics go viral?
You don't know what I can do to you!
What pictures are you talking about, Malika? What happened? What do you mean?
That officially does it!
Thank you for being with me all this time, Shakila. I can't turn you down. Not when it's Zeba's wedding gown. You'll get it.
I remember the day you started this, Zahida... With just one sewing machine...
And look where it's got you now! Bless you!
I'm so happy for you. My kids look up to you.
By the way, I almost forgot...
I saw some pictures of Malika on the internet... With a boy!
What kind of pictures?
Zeba told me she saw some pictures of Malika with him on the internet.
I told her they probably study together. Someone must've clicked some pictures in the class or on a field trip and shared them. But they think they're going out together!
I've seen so much that I just can't know what's right. I even asked Zeba to stay out of it.
Anyway, I'll get going. I'll need these two weeks from now. Bye.
Where's Malika?
Malika!
What'd Aunt Shakila just say?
What?
Shakila said she saw some pictures of you with someone on the internet.
Just -- some pictures from a field trip -- and some extracurricular activities...
I know Noriyan's done it! He -- He wants to shame me!
Aqil!
Wait, Aqil!
Who could it be?
Just chill, bro. Relax.
Who had these pictures?
I clicked them and I only shared them with Malika!
Jesus, everyone wants to talk to me.
Give it to me.
Switch it off.
If no one else had these pics, Noriyan, I'm sure no one else could've done it.
What do you mean? I leaked these pics myself?
-Not you! But Malika?
What rubbish! Why'd she even --?
Hello?
Yeah, he's with me.
Don't worry.
I've had him switch his phone off.
It was Naveed. He was worried why your phone was off.
Hey!
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV