My Lord...
You know what forced me to do this.
I would've been chained to that Asim forever if I didn't...
Don't worry.
You're safe here.
I've put everything on the line. Because I trust you.
Do you regret it?
Not at all.
I don't regret it one bit. But please...
Never let me regret my decision...
I hope no one saw you coming here?
No...
Nobody knows I'm here.
Good. Very good.
What's with this mehndi... This gown?
I had to... I could never break free if I didn't...
And Asim!
I can't even imagine living with him!
And me?
I dream of it...
It's what gave me the courage to do it...
If you're worried, if the guest room feels suffocating to you... Feel free to come to my room.
After we get married, sure. I'll live out my dream life with you.
Ah, yes... Of course... We'll get married.
Keep Malika safe, O Lord...
Blimey, Malika, what've you done?
I swear I would've called the cops on you if I didn't care about my honour!
Keep your voice down.
Keep at it and I can call the cops on you too. For bulldozing me.
Where's Malika?
I'll effin' kill you!
Hold it!
-Don't you dare touch me! Get it?
-Aqil!
Take that bloodthirst somewhere else.
I'll break every bone in your body if you so much as touched her here!
I never thought I'd live to see this day!
Were it not for my honour, I would've choked you right here!
You choked me the day you shut all happiness out of my life!
I mean -- Asim! Ych a fi! I'd rather be buried alive!
Just wait until we get home! You may just get your wish!
Home? It's a blimmin' crypt where I've buried all my dreams!
Fine by me. I'm calling the cops.
What're you gonna tell them, eh? What've I done?
I'm grown-up now! I can do as I chuffin' want!
You still wanna call the cops? Be my guest! They'd love to feel your collar for forcing me!
Just stop it!
I see... So it was all planned...
You pick out the big fish, send your daughters to them in the middle of the night, and come knocking when you know you have him! Shame on you!
Shut your gob! You come on to innocent girls and have the nerve to accuse us!
I didn't call her here.
She came here because she wanted to!
I just let her in so I can take her back first thing in the morning and save you from this humiliation. But you! You accuse me!
What are you talking about, Atif? I -- I'm here to get married -- to you!
Are you out of your mind? You better know your place!
I didn't call her here. There's nothing of the sort going on. She's all yours.
Get a move on, already! Before they kick you out!
Don't you dare even talk to Malika again.
Oh my God, it was so fun! I can't tell you!
And Aqil's family! They're really nice. I had proper fun. They were so warm...
Of course. You're my cousin, and Aqil's my best friend.
Of course... All thanks to you!
But of course...
Waqas... They're really nice. Genuinely nice.
You shouldn't have stayed there so long.
I left when you called me.
And if I didn't call you?
What do you mean?
I mean, you shouldn't have gone there.
Okay...
Aqil's your best friend, he invited me, I promised him, I went... What's the big deal?
Let's go to the wedding together. Then again, I guess you'd rather go alone?
What are you saying, Waqas? I can go where I want, right?
Do we always have to contradict each other?
-You're starting it, Waqas.
Your friend invited me, and I accepted it. Big deal!
So you don't care what I think?
I don't know why you're imposing your views on me, Waqas.
Don't you think I've got the right to do as I want to? Like anyone else?
So you actually don't care about what I think...
It's no big deal, Waqas. You're just blowing it out of proportion for no reason.
He invited me, I accepted. It's as simple as that. Please be mature. There's nothing wrong with it.
Okay.
As you wish.
Waqas!
What?
You called me?
Yes.
I'm sorry to say this but I can't have you around anymore.
Work something out.
Okay.
Thank you for putting up with Noriyan and me for so long.
You've chosen it for yourself...
It is something I never wanted...
I still remember my time with your parents...
But...
If it's between living here and my principles... You know what I'd choose...
You shouldn't have called Malika's mother and brother here.
Sometimes, it's better to dare, even if you make a big mistake. At least I can look myself in the mirror.
Okay.
Pack your things.
I did yesterday.
Is Noriyan back?
He called. He's on the way.
What'd you tell him?
Nothing.
I won't tell him what you're talking about.
I didn't bring her here.
If you'd brought her here, I would've thought you wanted her here, wanted her in your life.
But...
Someone who could run away in the middle of the night in her wedding gown can never be the pride of a family.
You'll need some money...
I won't.
You pick out the big fish, send your daughters to them in the middle of the night, and come knocking when you know you have him! Shame on you!
I didn't call her here.
She came here because she wanted to!
I just let her in so I can take her back first thing in the morning and save you from this humiliation. But you! You accuse me!
What are you talking about, Atif? I -- I'm here to get married -- to you!
Are you out of your mind? You better know your place!
Would you like to have something?
You don't feed the dead before burying them.
You deck them up. Just get to it.
Please stop saying that...
Munni! Tell her to get ready. Aqil says she's not going to the parlour.
So it's almost time! When's my funeral?
I hope everyone's invited.
Munni, tell her she better leave this place quietly.
I'm never going to forgive you for this.
-Oh, really!
You brought it on yourself. Kicked out by two men you trusted!
We still want to save your skin.
Leave it, Mum. I'll deck her up.
You've done what you wanted here.
But please... Treat them with respect. They're not just your Aunt's family now... They're your in-laws.
A mother will always forgive you.
You won't have it this easy with them.
What do you think? I'd run away again?
You've fallen into sin. If you found redemption bitter, I dare not imagine what'd happen to you!
Mothers always pray that their daughters only come back for their funeral.
I pray that you don't come back here even for your funeral.
Hey!
Hi!
Coming to pick me up?
Where are we going?
Where you didn't want me to go alone?
How sad...
You can't see how much I love you, how much I care for you...
Yeah. That's actually very sad.
Because your love always takes a back seat.
Are you still upset? Still cross?
Do you care?
Of course I do! That's why I called you.
I don't want to go there.
Are you sure?
Aqil's your best friend. His sister's getting married. Won't he mind?
He wouldn't care.
You should go there, Waqas. Because I'm going.
As you wish. Bye.
Who was it?
Novera.
Don't tell me you had another domestic.
I told her I'm not going to the wedding, but she wants to.
Why not?
Just... Not in the mood.
Because Novera's going?
She doesn't care about me. She could've just said, 'I'm not going without you'.
Why do you always want her to say what you want?
You want her to stay away from Aqil too.
I've got no problem if she's going with you.
C'mon, now. Get up, get ready. Or Aqil will say he's afraid he may have to give something.
He won't. As if I haven't given him enough!
What do you -- What've you given him?
Always a problem!
Jesus, Mum, what happened?
Nothing. I always said we'd have to leave someday. It's time now...
But why? And why so suddenly?
I had my eyes on a place. Now that Aunt Navida's tenant has left...
It's real good. I don't think we're going to get another chance like this. Prime spot, fair price. Obvious choice.
Did you talk to Atif?
-Yeah, I've talked to him. He has no problem.
No way!
I'll go talk to him.
Noriyan!
Stay here if you like... I'm going.
Mum...
Something happened? Between you and Atif?
Yeah... Let's just say something happened.
I'm sure you said something to him!
-So be it!
I can't disgrace myself anymore by living here.
I leave home for a night and you pick a fight with Atif! Blimey...
I didn't start it. I ended it. Forever.
He can live the way he wants.
Mum...
Maybe... Just a little longer?
We can leave once I've got a job.
Don't worry, you'll get a job there. God will bless you just the same.
I've packed your things. Check if I missed anything.
What is it?
I'm just thinking about the new house... All the expenses... I can teach the kids... But how are we going to get by until I've started?
We'll get by.
Aunt Navida's talked about me at the factory where she works.
But Mum...
-My dear...
Would you like it if your wife came here?
Wife? What are you talking about?
Noriyan... Never forget that everything I'm doing is for the better. For you.
Of course, Mum...
Bless her...
It's getting late, Zahida... I think we should finish with the rituals.
Of course...
Looks like you're more eager to take her home than Asim!
Of course. We've all been waiting...
Of course... Munni, get some milk for the ritual.
Okay.
-Let's go.
Hello Atif.
Hello.
Ready?
If you need anything, feel free to ask me. Just like old times?
You've been kind to us, Atif... No idea why Mum decided to leave...
Yeah...
But I'm sure she's thought of something.
I know Mum's decision has hurt you.
But you know her...
She doesn't budge at all.
Didn't she tell you why?
She did, and --
-You know I don't like anyone poking his nose in my personal matters.
Nor do I, Atif...
It's not about you... It's my fault...
Mum thinks I'd always depend on you if we stayed here.
She's your Mum...
She knows what's best for you.
You're her son.
Anyway... I'm just a call away if you need anything, okay? Take care.
Bye.
-Bye.
Hello?
Yeah, we're coming.
The car's here, Akmal. Help us get these in.
Why do you think I'd mind what she'd say?
Because she came here all worked up!
Who told you that?
Well, I'm surprised, to say the least, to see how she left her place... Didn't take her brother's blessings, didn't see anyone - not even her sister!
So that's what Mum's worried about!
-It is worrying.
Do you think no one else would've noticed?
It's their concern. Probably something between the siblings... It'll be okay.
All I'm saying is... Don't mind what she says. If she says anything... You know, bad... Just take it quietly, okay?
Yeah...
Mum wasn't feeling well, so I had to...
It's okay.
For you.
Have a look...
Lovely?
How much did it cost?
I mean... It looks expensive...
The least I could do for you...
The most you can do, more like...
Aren't you happy?
Do you still need to ask?
You wanted to get me. You got me. Congratulations.
What do you care about my happiness? What I want?
Don't say that, Malika...
Your happiness means the world to me.
I wouldn't be here if it did.
Thank you.
Yes? What is it?
Aren't we gonna bring Malika breakfast?
As if she'd be waiting for us!
Forget it, Mum... I'm sure she'll be delighted to see us.
I'm her mother. I know exactly what'd delight her.
What'd Aunt think? And Asim?
They saw everything as they left...
They had a pretty good idea that Malika wants nothing to do with us.
Words, no matter how bitter, can never sever ties, as long as we've got a place for each other in our hearts.
Except we've got no place in hers.
But she's got in ours.
Please, Mum?
Munni...
You better don't say anything to Aqil. He said he won't even attend the reception!
No idea when he's gonna get up! And as for the reception, we're giving everyone a reason to point their fingers at us!
If you can hug Malika before everyone, I'm sure you can attend the reception.
Okay. Make an omelette. I need to go get some things before we leave.
-Okay.
Would you do something for me?
Of course... You've got a legal licence to have everything your way. What is it?
Please don't say anything to Mum that'd make her think you're not happy with me.
Why? Scared she'll pull you up, ask you why you married me at all?
No.
Not that...
Mum loves you so much... I don't want her to be hurt by anything you say.
How much did it hurt to know you're robbing me of my happiness?
Mum didn't rob you of your happiness --
-I'm not talking about Mum.
Hello, Mum...
-Hello. Bless you.
We're almost ready.
-C'mon. Zahida's brought some fine breakfast. Quickly!
Wow...
You're cross with your Mum... But she's brought breakfast for you.
Perhaps there's nothing like a mother's love...
No mother can ever be cross with her child.
She's doing it for me?
Don't tell me she's doing it for me.
She's never done it for me before.
I know I'm like her son, but...
It's your day, ma'am...
They'll be waiting.
Shall we?
Come.
Hello, Aunt.
-Hello.
How are you?
-Great. Bless you.
Would you look at what your Aunt's got!
-Yeah! Seems like we're in for a real treat.
You didn't have to, Aunt...
-The pleasure is all ours, Asim.
Here. I've got this halwa for you.
You didn't really have to show off, you know...
We're not showing off. It's a custom.
Strange, innit? I thought you didn't even want to see me at my funeral.
You could've just donated it to us.
I -- I think I should get going...
Aqil wasn't up -- I'm not sure if I've locked the door... Munni!
-No way. You've got to have tea.
See you at the reception.
-Please, Aunt...
See you in the evening. C'mon, Munni.
-Okay.
Bye.
-Bye, love.
If I knew Malika would upset them so much, we could've gone over to their place for breakfast.
I would've loved to... She's my sister. Whatever's going on?
You're up?
Let's just say your love for Malika opened my eyes...
Why'd you go there when I said she's no one to us?
I forced her to come.
Yeah. Munni said we ought to go. I thought we'd better. Just as a formality, at least?
Go and get breakfast for him.
-Okay.
Did you see her?
Of course.
Bless her. She's very happy.
I hope they had no complaints about the wedding.
I tried the best I could, but still...
Not at all... You've spent so much... How are you going to pay it back?
Bless the Lord, Mum. Your son's not in hock.
Where'd you get the money, then?
-Munni!
Quickly, now! I'm getting late!
I'll talk to you later. Have to dash.
-But...
I'm sure you're coming with us to the reception?
I don't even want to see her face! And you want me to attend her reception? For Christ's sake, Mum -- How could you even think?
If you want to do these formalities, be my guest. Just keep me out of it!
Hi!
Hey...
I thought I'd call and ask if Monsieur's fixed his mood, but thought I'd rather drop by.
You don't need to ask.
-That's why I'm here.
You get angry for nothing. Like a kid.
Know what?
Mum says you should be thankful if you've got someone who's angry with you.
But don't you think you should be all the more thankful if you've got someone ready to make it up to you?
Isn't that what you do? When you've made a mistake? Because it's your mistake?
But what've I done that you're so angry about?
I should've been angry with you, because you left me alone. I had to go there alone! Without you!
Why'd you have to go at all?
Because I'm not like you, okay?
You should be sorry you couldn't attend the wedding of your best friend's sister, but you're angry because I went there?
Wait...
Why should I be sorry?
Aqil doesn't give two hoots if I attend his sister's wedding or not.
In fact, they'd be glad I didn't show up. I know what it's like. If I drop by, they get worried where they could have me sit!
And... He was never sorry living on my money!
Don't say that about your best friend.
He's my best friend. I know him inside out.
He didn't even bother to ask me why I wasn't there! He never forgot to come to me when he needed help!
That's oh-so-lovely of him!
You positively hate everything about him! How is he your best friend then?
And you can call him your best friend. He's been to your place. You've talked to him about me. How could he be your friend if you loathe him so much?
He never said one bad word about you. He speaks quite highly of you.
It pains me to see how you want to show off that you've helped him arrange his sister's wedding.
It's true...
What are you looking at?
I'm looking at my future. Would you have me account for everything after our marriage, too?
So you won't even listen to me after our marriage?
So it's just the wife's duty to obey orders, while the husband can order her around as he likes, pull her up when he wants? Is that what you're telling me?
That's how it is here.
I got you! See!
Don't take it seriously, I'll be a good, understanding husband.
Are you sure?
Yeah. I'm sure.
Let's go have something. I get this peckish feeling when I'm angry.
No, thanks. I don't feel like eating anything right now.
See?
You're angry. Cheeks -- Going red -- You -- You're getting angry now!
C'mon, let's go.
You created quite a situation, though...
I'm not afraid of any 'situation'. I trust the One who can help us out.
No way you're working now, Mum.
I've talked about tuitions. I should be able to start in a few days.
Focus on your studies.
I've got a good job at the factory. No issues there.
But Mum --
-We need a long-term solution, Noriyan. Focus on your studies for now.
Look for a job later.
As if I'd get one anytime...
It takes years, if not months, to find a good job.
I'm sure the Lord will help you.
I want you to start doing something before Ashi comes here.
Ashi?
Jesus -- You're still thinking of her?
Who should I think of?
Certainly not the one even you've got no reason to think of now!
I don't want to get married, Mum. I'm not thinking of anyone!
Have it your way... When I'm not around. But while I'm hanging back, let me tell you - Ashi's the one for you.
But why, Mum?
Because I've got only one son, Noriyan,
And I can't see him become a hermit because of some snooty Malika.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV