Hello?
Why are you not coming to university?
There's no looking back!
You and Noriyan have broken up. They're all talking about it here.
You should've sorted things out. Did you guys have to make it public?
What do you mean?
Who made it public?
There's a few pictures going viral. Is it you or Noriyan?
-What?
What pictures?
Don't you know about your pics with Noriyan going viral?
Check your WhatsApp, I'll show you.
Yeah, send me, double time!
Oh my God!
Jesus, Noriyan!
Hello?
How can you be so low?
What happened, Malika?
-What do you think?
You're settling scores by making these pics go viral?
You don't know what I can do to you!
What pictures are you talking about, Malika? What happened? What do you mean?
That officially does it!
Thank you for being with me all this time, Shakila. I can't turn you down. Not when it's Zeba's wedding gown. You'll get it.
I remember the day you started this, Zahida... With just one sewing machine...
And look where it's got you now! Bless you!
I'm so happy for you. My kids look up to you.
By the way, I almost forgot...
I saw some pictures of Malika on the internet... With a boy!
What kind of pictures?
Zeba told me she saw some pictures of Malika with him on the internet.
I told her they probably study together. Someone must've clicked some pictures in the class or on a field trip and shared them. But they think they're going out together!
I've seen so much that I just can't know what's right. I even asked Zeba to stay out of it.
Anyway, I'll get going. I'll need these two weeks from now. Bye.
Where's Malika?
Malika!
What'd Aunt Shakila just say?
What?
Shakila said she saw some pictures of you with someone on the internet.
Just -- some pictures from a field trip -- and some extracurricular activities...
I know Noriyan's done it! He -- He wants to shame me!
Aqil!
Wait, Aqil!
Who could it be?
Just chill, bro. Relax.
Who had these pictures?
I clicked them and I only shared them with Malika!
Jesus, everyone wants to talk to me.
Give it to me.
Switch it off.
If no one else had these pics, Noriyan, I'm sure no one else could've done it.
What do you mean? I leaked these pics myself?
-Not you! But Malika?
What rubbish! Why'd she even --?
Hello?
Yeah, he's with me.
Don't worry.
I've had him switch his phone off.
It was Naveed. He was worried why your phone was off.
Hey!
What've you told Salma, Zubeida?
What'd I say? Everyone's talking about it. You only need to listen!
It worries me so much...
She left the place so furious... Blimey... Where's she gone, by the way?
To her sister's, of course.
-But why is she so worried? I'm sure it was something you said.
Well, Bilqis, I haven't even started about what they're saying.
By the way, have you broken Asim and Malika's engagement?
It's nothing like that... They just want some time. Until Malika's graduation?
It ain't just about that. Mark my words, there's something dodgy going on here.
What is it?
Haven't you seen Malika's pictures?
What?
Ah yes, you don't use the internet... But I'm sure Asim's seen everything!
What kind of pictures?
She's with someone! And - gorblimey - she's closer to him in those pictures than women would be to their husbands!
You shouldn't be saying that for someone's daughter, Parvin. It's a sin!
Go and tell Malika it's a sin.
I'm sure you're mistaken.
Don't tell me... I just showed Salma those pictures. Everyone else has already seen it.
That's why she's gone over to her sister's.
I say, get Malika out of Asim's heart.
She's unseemly. Wants to soar too high.
God knows where he's gone!
He even left his phone here!
No idea what else she's got in store for us!
Hello...
-Salma! It's you...
What's this I hear?
Here we go again...
That's not how you talk to your Aunt! Go inside!
Got a score to settle with us? I never thought I'd live to see pictures of you with some of the lads going viral on the internet!
Blimey, Aunt, what's up with all of you? Open your eyes!
He studies with me, I've done a lot of assignments with him... But I didn't come on to him, so he edited a few pictures and shared them! How's it my fault?
You should be more careful. A woman's honour is fragile.
Well so is a man's honour. In fact, the bigger the man, the more fragile his ego!
Come. Sit.
Hello?
You sent Aunt, didn't you?
Where?
Here!
Can't believe that's what you think, seeing how you're with women at the office all day!
What happened, Malika?
A class fellow uploaded some pictures he clicked with me.
I pulled him up right away. But I'm being tried here like I've been caught in the act!
But why were there any pictures to begin with?
You take the ladies for a ride, you invite them over, but you have a problem with a few pictures! Just -- Wow, Asim...
I have no problem, Malika. I'm just asking you.
Get some sense into Aunt. She shouldn't be listening to the rumours and accusing me!
Okay, don't worry... I'll do s -- Hello? He --?
Careful...
This way. Mind the step!
Come in, Asif.
Noriyan!
Lie down.
-What happened to him?
-Nothing serious, Aunt.
What happened, Noriyan? Noriyan? Good Lord...
It's nothing, Aunt... Just a dust-up at the university.
He isn't the type!
Don't worry, Mum... I'm fine.
Aye, right, Aunt. He just wants your sympathies. He's acting it out.
He's been hurt so bad... Just look at him!
Don't worry, Aunt.
-We'll get going.
Here's your phone, bro... You better keep it off if you want any peace.
And please don't worry about it too much.
Alright, bye, Aunt.
-Bye.
-Asif...
Tell me - what happened? What's it about?
It isn't about Malika... Is it?
(Tell her.)
-Malika's officially done it.
She sent her brother to the university.
He was furious. He's the one he had a row with.
No idea what Malika told him!
Aye. He beat Noriyan real bad...
Anyway, don't worry. Please let us know if you need anything.
Where've you been? You even left your phone here. I was so worried you may pick a fight with someone!
If I could have my way, I swear I would've killed him!
Aye, killed him and left me to beg for your life!
And why are you here?
Here to thank me for sparing her son apparently!
He won't be so lucky if I saw him again!
Please, spare him...
My poor son's harmless... He can't hurt a fly!
Whatever he may be, he ain't harmless.
What's he done?
Leaked a bunch of pictures he clicked with me to get even!
No.
He can't do that.
He doesn't let me say a word against you. How do you even think he'd...?
You're his Mum... You're siding with him.
She's your Mum. Ask her.
A mother always knows her children. In her heart. Even when she doesn't say it.
My son's just not the type!
Please ask your son to stop thinking about my daughter.
I promise you... He won't even mention her name.
In fact, he's stopped thinking of her already.
I've got no one but him... Please spare him.
I can vouch for him.
Please, spare him...
I won't be able to repay your favour, but I'll pray for mercy for you.
I better not see his face again.
You won't. I promise you.
You'll never see him again. He won't even think about you. I promise you...
Just talk to Aunt and throw her out already!
What? You're still thinking of Asim?
Zip it!
You better not shout at me again!
I don't want to marry him!
-Why?
Why not?
Does she want to mooch about here all her life?
I'm not bothering anyone here!
No... Daughters are not sent off because they bother anyone...
Just a minute...
What do you mean that you're not bothering anyone here?
I've started working. Haven't you told him?
Well --
-Hold on... What does she do? What's she been up to?
I thought I'd tell you... But I thought you'd get angry and stop her from going to work.
But you still let her.
No... I didn't allow her... She decided everything herself! Even got her advance and all...
So that's what I'm worth here!
Nobody asks me about anything!
No way she's going to work!
But she's got a big advance...
So... Where do you work?
It's my friend's Dad... I work for him.
C'mon. I wanna see him. Come!
So you can create a scene there? Don't think you can fool me!
Just take him to your office. What if you needed something?
I wanna see what she does that pays her a hefty advance!
I've left the job!
They don't let you quit the job so easily if they give you an advance! She's lying right in front of everyone!
One step out of the house, and you're dead. Get it?
Why? Just why? You don't earn a penny yourself, but you're bossing around like --
Shut your trap! I'll tell you! Come!
-Calm down, Aqil! Aqil!
-Mum!
-Geroff!
Stop it! Let her go!
-C'mon, now. Out. Quick!
-Mum!
Are you outta your mind!?
What are you doing?
-Open the door!
-Stop it, Aqil!
-Geroff me!
Be done with it!
Open the door, Mum!
-You're being too hard on your sister!
Open the door! Anyone!
-No one opens this door! Are we clear?
Please open the door, Mum...
-Good Lord...
Mum! Please say something!
Hello, swinger!
I thought you'd miss me. But you never called! So I thought I should.
Look at what she's been up to!
Look at all the men who call her!
Send her off right away!
-But how?
I can't force her.
-But I can! And I will!
Where are you off to?
-I'm gonna talk to Asim.
What?
Good Lord...
This is plain cruel. You should've asked him to open the door!
You cage them when you can't cage their brass neck.
Can't believe you're siding with Aqil!
Aqil's done it because of Malika's shameless audacity.
What if she did something?
He locked her in because she might do something.
I don't know why you think so wrongly of her!
Where've you been? Didn't you hear me?
I'd gone to Aunt.
Aunt? Why?
I didn't see her, but I've talked to Asim.
What've you told him?
I told him Malika won't say no this time. They can come and take her anytime.
Are you touched in the head? You want to embarrass me again?
I swear, you won't be embarrassed. If she dared to refuse now, she'll have to face me.
Please unlock the door to her room...
Open the door. She ain't going nowhere.
I better not hear that you took one step out or called anyone!
Are. We. Clear?
Back off! I don't want your sympathies!
Leave her, Munni.
You were sorry for her... But let me tell you, she doesn't deserve it!
It'll only anger Mum and Aqil even more...
I don't care if it does! Get me my phone.
Aqil destroyed the phone. Someone was calling you...
What do I know who it was?
Someone must've dialled the wrong number! Why'd he destroy my phone?
Why does it bother you so much, then?
Please talk to Mum, Granny... I'm sure she'd listen to you.
You know your Mum's got no problem talking about it. But it was always Malika who refused, not your Aunt.
Her refusal isn't set in stone.
When a girl refuses, it's set in stone, so to speak...
Please try to understand, Granny... She's got no problem now.
How do you know? Did you talk to her?
No. Aqil came here last night.
Aqil? When'd he start caring about the family?
I can't believe you're saying that. He's her brother. I'm sure she's told him something.
He can't be making it up!
I'm sure your Aunt would've told Salma herself if that were it.
Granny...
Aunt was embarrassed. That's why she didn't talk about it.
Anyway... Please talk to Mum about it. I'm sure she'd listen to it. Please?
She's started caring for you after shaming you before the world? Seriously, though. You've got no shortage of matches.
Blimey... I can't believe this is happening. Mum's cross now that Malika's got no problem with it.
Salma told me she never cared for you and insulted you so much. That's why she isn't happy about it.
Granny...
I've forgiven Malika.
Please forgive her and ask Mum to forgive her too.
Okay. Don't worry. I'm sure Salma would talk about it, but I think your Aunt should've been the one to say it.
I'm sure she'd be glad to talk about it.
Okay, then... Let's see how it goes.
Hey, man!
Hey there!
How you doin'?
Great.
I saw Novera the other day.
Where?
You're lucky. She ain't crabby like you. I had a blast with her.
I just bumped into her, that's all!
Okay...
By the way...
Don't you think you've started bossing around already?
What do you mean?
I mean... Why do you want her to do as you want?
Did she say something?
No way, mate... She said nothing! But when'd you get so possessive?
It's nothing like that.
-That's what I said! But...
Why does she think that?
Look...
The Waqas I know is usually cool. Okay?
Give her some space. Care about her. That's how you'll grow closer.
What's up with you?
Why are you siding with her?
Great...
I'm siding with her! I worry for you! I'm worried your stupidity may ruin your relationship!
I'm not being stupid, okay?
Yeah, I'll buy that... Can't hide it from your relationship guru.
It's my experience, my dear Waqas...
You better do as I say. It's for your own good.
Okay?
C'mon, now, fix your mood. Back to your exercise. You're here so late and in this godawful mood!
Malika...
Munni called you for lunch twice. You shouldn't be so adamant about everything.
Let me starve to death. I'm sure that's what you're all waiting for!
No, we're not. You're creating trouble for yourself.
Just say good riddance to me!
Malika... God's given you another chance.
Aqil's told Asim you've agreed to marry him.
Whether he or your Aunt believe it or not, Aqil's sure you won't say no.
I'm not his bleedin' slave!
You'll be responsible for whatever happens to you...
What do you think?
Would Asim and Aunt agree after all that's happened?
-Yeah.
They will.
Those who care for their family can forgive and forget everything.
I don't want any favours.
I hope we're clear that I'm never saying yes to him!
-I hope we're clear, too, that I may not be able to save you again.
I've transferred 500,000 to your account. Check that you've got it.
I think I told you something, Zoha.
I think I told you it's not for you, too.
Let's just say it's my gift to your sister on her wedding.
It'll be of use to her.
You'd already given me the money... Just my luck that I ran into those robbers...
Could you please forget it?
Zoha...
Sometimes, I think...
All this love...
Your favours...
I may never be able to pay any of it back...
Just...
Never leave me, okay?
I don't want anything else.
Do you think I could ever leave you?
I've come so far because I trust you.
Thanks.
Just be there for me.
Know what...
I'm so addicted to your love...
That I can't even imagine my life without it...
No idea what I'd do without you.
That's why I say...
Let's end this distance between us. Move in with me...
I'm here every other day, Zoha.
I practically live here.
I mean we should get married.
I never said no.
But, Zoha...
I've got so much on my shoulders right now...
After we get married, I'm sure we ca --
-But...
You won't get it...
So leave it to me.
I'll take care of it.
Why are you in such a hurry?
Okay...
As you say...
When you say...
The definition of true love, that!
It seems so selfish...
You don't care one bit about me... Even after everything I've done for you...
It's all about give and take, you know...
If you ask me, there's a simple formula to fulfil every dream...
Feel free to come back when you've understood it.
What do you think?
Would Asim and Aunt agree after all that's happened?
-Yeah.
They will.
Those who care for their family can forgive and forget everything.
I don't want any favours.
I hope we're clear that I'm never saying yes to him!
-I hope we're clear, too, that I may not be able to save you again.
You're creating trouble for yourself.
Mum's right...
I created this problem...
It's up to me to solve it!
Mum...
Call and tell Aunt...
I've got no problem...
Munni...
Did you hear what I heard?
Yeah.
Call Aunt, quick.
What made her change her mind?
Forget it, Mum! Just call Aunt. Asim would be at home. It'd be great if he heard it too!
I'll call her in the morning.
But Mum... Now --
-I told you I'll call her in the morning. Tidy this up, okay?
Congratulations!
-For what?
Your Aunt called at last!
What does she say?
What Aqil told you.
Malika has no problem now.
Really? Wow!
Yeah.
Let's hope it's the best for all of us.
Amen.
But why don't you seem happy?
That's not it... It's just... A strange fear... No idea why... Ever since you told me she's okay with it...
What are you worried about, Granny?
You and Malika are poles apart! Ask your Mum if you don't believe me!
Blimey... Please don't talk about Mum...
She thinks Sana's the only match for me in the entire world!
Oh, please...
Don't even start...
The last thing I want to hear is you comparing Sana with Malika.
I've never seen anyone like her.
You're just mistaken about her.
I told you Malika'd said it without thinking.
She loves me!
And I'm sure we'd be very happy together.
I know you'd only be happy with her. That's why I always prayed that the Lord show her the way.
I hope your prayers work.
-May the Lord keep the two of you happy.
Amen.
So you're angry because Aqil met me and I didn't tell you?
Yes.
I would've had no problem if you told me, but Aqil! I was so furious when he told me!
'Problem'? What kind of problem? He just bumped into me and couldn't say know, because he's your best friend, right?
Exactly! He's my best friend! What's he to you? Nobody!
What...?
What's this nonsense? I was just being polite?
Okay, Novera, let me try to explain it.
You don't know the people here. You don't know what they're like.
Oh, I don't know what they're like? Or are you just too wrong?
-Blimey, you're out to prove me wrong!
Why are you shouting?
-Cripes! I'm not shouting! I'm not shouting, okay!?
I'm sorry!
I just wanted to tell you they're not what they look like!
You're not trying to explain anything, you're just trying to set my boundaries!
Can you please not be so wrong about me for once?
-You are wrong!
I'm not wrong! You talked to Aqil about us! Told him everything! Why'd you tell Aqil I'm possessive? That I don't give you space, I force my will on you? Tell me!
This is too much! I gotta leave. I just can't understand you. Bye!
Wait, Novera --
Where are you off to?
I just gotta go, Aunt. I've got something important to do. I gotta leave. Bye, Aunt! Take care!
-You can't just leave like that! But --
Something happened here?
Blimey, she's a weird one!
Try to tell her something and she flares up!
Who told you to tell her anything?
I just wanted to tell her not to talk to Aqil about us!
Hold on...
When did she meet Aqil?
Bumped into him at the mall.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV