With teary eyes...
Why do you think she doesn't love me?
I could see all her love shatter when she found out you were the maid's son!
When she found out you were not the rich lady's son as you told her...
When she found out you were just the lowly maid's son!
But you couldn't see it...
Mum...
If --
What if --
What if Malika confessed her love before you?
Would you still have a problem?
Forget about me, she won't even confess her love before you!
Sometimes, you gotta take a chance...
Okay...
Have it your way.
I'd send her off right now if I could have my way!
Where?
-That's the problem!
Can't believe he's panting for someone else after getting engaged to Malika!
Someone else?
-You heard it.
She works with him and she's started paying them visits!
Who told you?
I've seen it myself!
And Salma?
-She knows everything.
She says she's just Asim's colleague. But...
I smell something shady!
Salma wants to make Malika her daughter-in-law.
And I've seen Asim's love for her.
But Malika doesn't care for any of that...
She'll suffer all her life! I tell you!
I never thought Malika's refusal would make Salma budge.
But you've got me worried.
-There's only one way out, Mum.
Talk to Malika. Get some sense into her!
She'll suffer all her life if she didn't listen!
Keep an eye on her.
Make sure she doesn't talk to Noriyan again!
She doesn't even talk about him.
Good.
Yeah?
Malika...
Why didn't you take my call?
I don't want to have anything to do with you!
But why?
Can't believe you're asking me!
Didn't Mummy tell you?
-What'd she say?
But Malika --
There's nothing left for me to say.
Let's just say Malika's love for Noriyan died when she found out who he was!
But Malika, I told you about it!
Don't even try it. I'd never love a maid's son!
Just forget me!
Are you crazy? How could I --
Noriyan, I guess?
Don't even mention his name!
Blimey, that's some real hatred. I thought you said your heart beats to the sound of his name!
You here to rub salt in my wounds?
I just wanted to ask you if you actually loved him or --
I took everything because I loved him!
Lemme get this straight - your love bugged out when you found out he's the maid's son.
Shut up or you won't like what I do to you!
Anyway. I told you Asim's so nice... But you hurt him.
Aunt called just now. Told he's been promoted.
To the dickens with him.
After all that's happened?
Well, newsflash! Mr Goody Two-shoes has already given someone else my place in his life!
No way!
If you can't believe it, sweetie, go and ask Aqil. He'll tell you everything.
I'm sure he's mistaken. Asim ain't that sort!
Honestly? I'm delighted.
Good for him.
In fact, go and congratulate him for me, will you?
She's sorry for everything, Mum... You should patch up with her.
I'll take it that she's sorry when she says she accepts Asim.
I don't think that's ever gonna happen...
Well, I guess she isn't sorry for everything then.
Aren't you going to Aunt's?
I'm going tomorrow. With some sweets.
For Asim's promotion?
Yes.
For the promotion, and because Malika didn't let him take Asim's place.
You can be so strange sometimes, Mum...
Mind if I asked something?
Not at all.
Malika said Asim loves someone else?
I've always seen Asim as a son. I know him. No one can take Malika's place in his heart.
Give it to me.
I tell you, he's hiding something!
I think it's just because Malika ain't here.
Why do I get a feeling he's found out about her?
I mean, just look at him!
He cut classes today!
How say we ask him?
What's up?
Nothing, really...
I don't think Malika's coming to university again.
I think we both know how much she was into studies!
Why don't you call her?
I will...
We're friends. You can tell us about it. What happened?
What?
Well...
You guys were right...
What do you mean?
I thought love was powerful... But she was so put out to hear my truth!
You told her everything?
Yeah...
But I think I should've told her earlier. Maybe it wouldn't have hurt her so much...
Why are you blaming yourself? Big deal. It ain't nothin' she couldn't forgive in love.
If only she took my call... Talked to me!
I can say sorry to her.
I don't think she'll ever talk to you again.
Why not?
She wanted to be with me all her life.
Mind if I... said something?
She didn't deserve you.
-Shut your gob!
-Hey!
Calm down!
-My blood boils when you say that!
Hammer some sense into him!
Always saying the wrong thing!
But why, Zahida?
I was so delighted when Asim called. God bless him.
All thanks to Him.
He brought sweets for us when he got a car.
I thought it's my turn now.
All thanks to your prayers.
He's my nephew, after all. Dearer to me than Aqil.
When'd Asim be back, Aunt?
He'd be on his way.
Here. Try some.
-Okay.
When will Aqil wake up? How can he get to the top if he didn't even start climbing?
I'm tired of telling him... But he doesn't listen... Just like Malika. God, help me...
How'd her exams go?
Great. She's learning sewing and cutting from me these days.
You should let her study if she wants to.
Of course. I had no problems with Malika either.
I had no problems with her going to university. But, who knows...
I'll call Asim. Ask him to get something.
I know you don't like to hear her name.
But I'm sure you can bless her...
What if that's all she needed?
It hurt me a lot, Zahida, but I'm happy it saved us from going the wrong way.
I'm very sorry...
Matches are made in Heaven. We can't help it.
Don't worry. I have no complaints with you.
Hello.
I don't see Aunt around?
My, you're not the lamb you look like!
What do you mean?
You know very well that Mum and Munni have gone to your place. But you dropped in here!
It's not like I have to come here to see you when no one's around.
Let's not forget I never let it be that way.
Anyway, I've been promoted.
This is for Aunt.
Definitely not the lamb you look like!
You never let go of a chance to score brownie points with Mum, do you?
It's my love, Malika. I even got some for you.
Jeez, what are you?
I don't need you or your gifts. Take them away.
You don't bring gifts because they need them. You do because you need them.
Well then, could you please stop needing me? Like, forever?
Goodbye.
Go and give these to your sweetheart who's started coming over.
Who?
Blimey -- Sana?
She's just a colleague!
I don't wanna know!
She was checking on Mum! Just once!
I don't give two hoots.
She's welcome at your place anytime she wants! Give these to her. I'm sure she'd love it!
Blimey, what is he?
Hi!
Hello.
How are you?
Miss me? Or have you been too busy being all lovey-dovey...
Of course. How are you?
All alone... Well, who cares...
Anyway, congratulations!
For what?
Your decision.
You decided to forget your future and get married.
I've changed course.
Really?
I can't believe it.
When do I come?
You don't need to ask. You're always welcome here.
Thank you.
Everything alright? You sound worried.
I'm fine.
-It's okay if you don't want to tell me...
I got a feeling you're a bit sad.
I'll tell you tomorrow.
Okie doke...
A day's wait it is.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Tears drip slowly...
I told you not to act like I'm yours! We're just cousins. Get it?
My eyes grow lonely
Yearning to see you
Come here, my dear
Yea, just you...
You illuminate
All my dreams
Let us live them out
Together...
With teary eyes
Teary eyes
I've lost everything
Everything
With teary eyes
Teary eyes...
I've already told Aunt all I have to say about it.
You could've just honoured my love...
With teary eyes
Teary eyes
Mum always thought you hated me and you proved her right.
With teary eyes
I've lost everything
Believe it if you still can't.
Everything
With teary eyes
I'm sure I'll find my Prince Charming if you kept your doomy self at an arm's length.
Slowly
We've grown apart
How will I cross this new divide?
Slowly
You've slipped from my hands
How did we drift so far away?
Glancing you even from this distance
Makes my heart skip a beat...
You illuminate
All my dreams
Let us live them out
Together...
With teary eyes
Teary eyes
I've lost everything
Everything
With teary eyes...
Asim, I can't stand this blather.
You better show up only when you can get gold bangles instead of these garlands.
Don't expect any love from me.
Everyone's got the right to wish to live, and you're the only reason I'm alive.
Bless him.
He's such a lovely kid.
He's only been hurt here... But he never leaves us out...
I pulled him up today. 'You never let go of a chance to score brownie points with Mum, do you?'
I dare not imagine what you would've said to him!
Blimey, he's so pig-headed!
What'd he get you?
So he told you already!
No. He didn't.
But I know he can't forget about you.
Aye, pig-headed as I told you. Brought something junky, as usual.
Hello?
Hello, Aunt. It's Sana.
How are you?
Great, Aunt.
Congratulations on Asim -- uh -- Mr Asim's promotion. Gotta get used to calling him 'sir' now!
That may be, but you'll always be like my daughter.
Thank you, Aunt. You're too kind.
I just called to congratulate you.
-Thank you.
Bye, Aunt.
Bye.
Hey...
Where've you been?
Just thought I'd get some air.
They've been congratulating me, but you don't look like you've been promoted.
I'm delighted, Mum...
Zahida called me. She said you'd gone over to her. What's it with Malika this time?
I'll go change.
-Sana congratulated you too.
But she'd already congratulated me.
-Not me though!
How'd she get your number?
I gave her my number when she came here.
You're back?
Yeah...
Want to have some lunch?
Not hungry...
I hope she hasn't mocked you for being a maid's son!
She already did, that day...
How does she know you're the maid, though?
Ask her.
She doesn't even want to talk to me.
Mum...
Does love really care about status so much?
No.
If it is indeed love, no.
But when someone uses you to live out her dreams, know that she loves her dreams and not you...
I think Malika just loved her dreams...
She could've given me one chance! Just one... I could've fulfilled every dream she had...
If she had to depend on you for it, believe me, she would've wanted everything in one shot! She was not one who could wait!
Mum...
She knows...
She knows I can't live without her...
I can't believe --
She never felt any pity...
When a son starts crying for someone like that before his Mum, she loses her faith in her son.
I had so much faith in her...
I trusted her!
I told you she doesn't deserve your trust!
But you didn't listen to me...
Mum!
Life tires those who give up in times of trial. You can't rebuild if you don't learn from it. Okay?
Mum...
Please...
Pray for me...
Pray that she changes her mind...
I will pray that the Lord change your mind.
I can't live without her.
You got to live without those who were never destined for you willy-nilly.
Like, seriously?
I thought you'd come here, Mum would fix the date, and we'd get married.
Why are you in such a hurry?
Because I love you?
Well... That's quite a shock...
What do you know about me that you love me so much?
What do you mean?
Don't you love me?
Don't you want to marry me?
I don't know.
I like you, you're honest, nice... That's why I decided to get engaged to you.
Why not get married, then?
I just need some time?
How much, and why?
I mean, if you wanna get engaged, why not just get married?
Why are you in a hurry?
I've just come here.
Give me some time to settle in here, figure things out...
There's so much I have to plan.
So you don't love me?
I like you. You're my cousin.
I've decided to get engaged to you too.
But marriage... It's such a big commitment! I need time to think.
Hey, Waqas!
I saw your car outside, figured I should check if you're on a date or something...
She's -- Novera -- Uncle Faizan's daughter...
Novera?
You mean her?
Mlle Novera l'Aloé Véra?
Hi!
Hi...
Meet Aqil. My best friend.
Blimey, what's with that drab voice? Starvin', eh?
Lemme fill you in. He ain't just my best friend. He's my only best friend!
We're gym buddies too. No secrets from each other. Which is how I know all about you.
Including that all he's been dreaming of since you got here... Is getting married to you!
I know...
My bad.
I think I'm disturbing you...
Just saw the car outside and thought... Enjoy the date!
Bye.
I guess he was so blunt because he's your best friend?
I'm sorry... I'll talk to him.
About what?
This kinda banter... Not good.
Aqil's your best friend... I don't think it's bad...
I'm sure he's so frank with you because you're so frank with him.
And I'm also sure you talk to him about everything.
No.
Not really...
He just says anything sometimes... Most of the time...!
Okay... So you mean you didn't talk to him about me and he was lying.
No...
I do talk about you sometimes.
Okay.
Pray tell what you say about me?
You're confusing me.
Shall we?
Hey! How are you?
Hey, sweetheart! So you're back!
-Yeah. Just landed.
Called you first thing.
Thank God...
Felt like it's been ages!
I missed you so much!
Really! I missed you too.
Well, then, get back quick. I'm waiting in your lounge.
I've got to stop at Bukhari for half an hour before I get back.
Blimey, Zoha... Back to work before you're back here? What about me getting bored to death here?
I won't take too long. I'll call when I'm free. Okay?
Bye.
Look at the timing! We got here at the same time!
Been waiting for me?
Obviously.
You're back after ages.
I've missed you so much.
Same here.
Don't tell me.
You were busy every second.
That's why I wanted you to come with me. You could see how busy I was!
What do you think, Zoha? I didn't want to come with you?
If it were up to me, I'd spend every moment of my life with you.
That's what always draws me to you.
Sometimes, I think... How can you even love me so much?
Because you make me want to live...
You make me feel important, valued...
I feel special.
-You are special.
Very special.
I don't know what kind of moron would not love you.
The shopping -- Was fabulous.
So you went shopping?
No. Just a bonus.
But, blimey, the trip was so productive!
Yeah... By the way, was Zahir with you?
Zahir's vanished into thin air! I'll ask him when he's back.
How's it going with your sister's marriage?
Zoha...
We're meeting after ages...
Can't we just talk about us?
Sure.
Come in.
Bring the table here.
-Yes, ma'am.
Let's have lunch here.
Please get us our lunch here, Ghulam Hussain.
-As you wish, ma'am.
I knew you'd pick that. Your favourite.
You know me so well.
Yeah, and so does Ghulam Hussain!
'With BEST WISHES'
'CONGRATULATIONS SIR.
~FROM SANA.'
What is this, Sana?
A small gift, sir. On your promotion.
But why?
As a colleague, sir...?
Blimey, Sana... You're giving me gifts now... Coming to my place... Getting close to Mum... 'As a colleague'? Seriously? Just -- Why?
I'm sorry, sir.
Aww... C'mon... No need to cry.
Please get her some water, Asif.
Know what...
Last time you were here, I wanted to stop you.
You should've stopped me.
But how? You were so intoxicated with love!
My biggest mistake!
What? He deserted you?
No. I deserted him!
Oh... That's really sad.
Wicked!
He didn't deserve my love.
Really?
I always thought he's lucky.
Mind if I ask something?
Do you love anyone else?
I mean -- Would you allow anyone else...?
What do you mean?
I mean...
If, somehow, we had an understanding... That... Perhaps, somewhere down the line... Gave way to love?
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV