♪Tears drip slowly...♪
♪My eyes grow lonely♪
♪Yearning to see you♪
♪Come here, my dear♪
♪Yea, just you...♪
♪You illuminate♪
♪All my dreams♪
♪Let us live them out♪
♪Together...♪
♪With teary eyes♪
♪Teary eyes♪
♪I've lost everything♪
♪Everything♪
♪With teary eyes♪
♪Teary eyes...♪
♪Teary eyes♪
♪With teary eyes♪
♪I've lost everything♪
♪Everything♪
♪With teary eyes...♪
I'm true to my name -
An Empress.
Such heavenly touches ne'er touched earthly faces.
♪Slowly♪
♪We've grown apart♪
♪How will I cross this new divide?♪
♪Slowly♪
♪You've slipped from my hands♪
♪How did we drift so far away?♪
♪Glancing you even from this distance♪
♪Makes my heart skip a beat...♪
♪You illuminate♪
♪All my dreams♪
♪Let us live them out♪
♪Together...♪
♪With teary eyes♪
♪Teary eyes♪
♪I've lost everything♪
♪Everything♪
♪With teary eyes...♪
Look at where you've ended up, chasing your dreams! So brutal to yourself...
Honour was all I had left, and you didn't even spare wagering it!
It's my life, Mum, and I won't let anyone ruin it just like that!
I wish He'd never given me someone like her...
You don't know how much I love you, Zoha.
I think Malika just loved her dreams...
Everyone's got the right to wish to live, and you're the only reason I live.
Don't expect any love from me.
♪Like faint footsteps♪
♪That soothe me...♪
♪How do I speak my heart out?♪
♪With playful squalls,♪
♪Gently peering from behind curtains,♪
♪Yea, that's the breeze called love...♪
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV
♪Glancing you for a moment♪
♪Makes time slow down...♪
♪You illuminate♪
♪All my dreams♪
♪Let us live them out♪
♪Together...♪
♪With teary eyes♪
♪Teary eyes♪
♪I've lost everything♪
♪Everything♪
♪With teary eyes...♪
'Wings'