Blimey, Malika, where are you?
I've been texting you for ages, why don't you reply?
I told you I'm busy. I won't be coming today.
And I wrote so much after that! Why didn't you reply?
I told you I'm busy.
I'll talk to you later. Bye.
Hello? M --
Who were you explaining yourself to?
I think you should stay at an arm's length from whoever makes you explain yourself.
I don't think it's bad to explain yourself in love.
Very intelligent, and very confident. I like it.
Well...
Give me some time to think, maybe?
Sure, take your time.
I'm sure you won't turn me down.
Bye.
-Bye.
If I had a problem with Malika studying, I would never have allowed her.
But...
I'm just asking you to keep an eye on her.
You know how it is these days.
If only she listened to me...
Okay, if Aunt doesn't want to go forward with the wedding, let her study.
Let her finish her studies.
You were shouting as if you'd never let her go to university again!
Jeez, Mum... I was furious at her makeup that day.
Just ask her to cover her face when she goes out.
That's how it's proper. That's all.
And yeah, I almost forgot...
Asim called me. He's talked to his boss.
He's called me for an interview.
God bless him.
I'm sure he'd fulfil his promise.
Jeez, you're excited like I've got the job already.
I've just been called for an interview.
Who does anything for anyone these days?
It matters.
You're right...
But I'd only be happy when I get my first paycheck.
May God bless you, and may that day come soon.
Just great, my dewy-eyed Mum... You're just happy about my first paycheck.
Your son's got the riches of paradise destined for him.
But you're just happy about one paycheck.
Told you!
The riches of paradise... Destined for your son!
It's for an international brand.
Imagine the exposure...
Imagine, that's your first chance.
It's just like a dream come true for you.
Think carefully.
If you said no, I'm cancelling the cheque, and if you said yes, you're getting double this amount at the end of the shoot.
Think about it
And let me know.
Hello?
I wanted to tell you...
That I accept your offer.
That's you.
You're intelligent.
When's the shoot?
Not right now.
But you'd have to come everyday.
But why?
Why, it's obvious... You're going to need some grooming, after all.
But don't worry. You'll be paid for it.
But what'd I tell them? At home?
That's your problem. Not mine.
But, if you like, I can hire you permanently.
Anyway...
See you tomorrow.
Bye.
And this goes here...
This one on the sleeve...
Just say it all and be done with it.
No need for this act.
Mum...
I wanted to talk to you about something.
I don't want to hear anything about anyone.
Not anyone. I want to talk about myself.
I didn't go to university today.
Besides, is it wrong to dream for a good life, Mum?
Where were you?
I got a job offer.
A job?
Are you out of your mind?
One of my professors got me a job at her Dad's office.
I have to go from tomorrow.
You accepted it without asking or talking to anyone?
What about your studies, that you were so horrified to leave?
I won't get a job half as good even if I finished my studies!
Don't even think of telling your brother.
Or he'll box your ears!
Oh, he won't!
Besides, he doesn't earn a penny.
He'll tremble before doing anything of the sort.
He's going today.
Asim's talked about him.
Donkey work, no doubt.
So what if it is?
If it's respectable.
Anyway.
I can't turn it down.
I've even got an advance for two months.
Want to see it?
Just a sec.
Give this cheque back, and tell them your family doesn't want their girls to work.
And they'll say, 'I'm sure they would've changed their minds if you'd shown them the cheque'!
Who could be so kind? And how?
You don't get stuck up in whys and hows when someone's been kind. You thank them. And Aqil?
I can talk to Aqil myself.
What'll you be doing?
Nothing much, really. Just proofreading some books. I can even attend classes when I'm free.
Think again, Malika.
Trust is hard to come by.
Just trust me, Mum.
Leave everyone else to me.
Hi!
Where are you, Malika?
Just... Busy with some things...
So busy that you forgot me?
What's up with you, Noriyan? How could I forget you?
I've been longing to talk to you all day.
I'm sorry.
I've been so bored without you here.
Well, then, get used to spending your days without me.
Why are you saying that?
Because I won't be coming to university for a few days.
But why?
I'll be busy elsewhere, Noriyan...
So busy that you'll forget me?
You're being angry for no reason.
I will be for real if you didn't come.
Well, in that case, I know just how to make it up to you.
Although I'm sure that won't be necessary.
You're taking me for granted, Malika?
I mean, don't you care that I'd be angry?
You don't know, Noriyan... Mum's not well...
And Minahil's got exams... So I won't be able to come.
Oh...
What happened to Aunt?
Nothing too serious. But I have to stay with her.
Okay. Let me know if I could help.
No. Thank you for asking.
Okay, I'll talk to you later. Bye.
I'll surprise you once I'm done with this shoot, Noriyan!
Thank God you're not middle-class like me...
So different from me.
You understand me so well...
Hey! Where are you?
In your heart.
Good one! I meant, are you at home?
I'm here for an interview.
Where?
Just forget it, will you?
I'm just surprised you didn't even tell me.
Anyway, I wish you the best of luck.
Come here after the interview.
Okay, bye.
I've talked to the boss.
He's waiting for you.
Alright, listen.
Speak confidently. Don't worry about anything.
I ain't worryin' at all.
Stay tuned, you're in for a real spectacle.
Come.
Did you call me here to stare at me like that, sir?
You don't look that type... But you've got no manners.
I'm sorry, I didn't get it.
You ask before entering someone's office. I didn't ask you to sit down, yet here you are!
You're asking for respect in advance! I mean, you haven't even given me the job yet...
Please, start the interview. We'll talk about it later.
What do you think?
Do you think I'd need an interview after what you've done?
You know better than me, sir.
-You may show yourself out!
Okay, sir.
Thank you.
God knows why these bosses like to think they're gods!
Okay, calm down.
How can I?
My blood is boiling!
I know you better than you. I told you you can't do this job.
Work with me. We can work together. But your male ego!
It ain't about male ego.
I don't want to mix my personal life with my professional life. There's a difference.
Yeah, but I know your temperament so well.
You've got leadership qualities. Why do you want to trap yourself in some lowly job for a few bucks?
Asim had asked me.
That's why I went.
Who's Asim?
My cousin.
My brother-in-law to-be.
If I didn't go, everyone would've said I did it on purpose.
Okay...
Cool down and listen to me.
Seriously, we'll make a good team and take our business places.
We'll have more time to spend with each other.
And I thought you were actually worried for me.
Look at you!
You're looking for what suits you!
Doesn't it suit you? Don't you want that?
What about Zahir?
I don't think Zahir would want to work with me.
Why?
Had a row?
Nothing of the sort...
But I think he wants to start his own business.
Great!
All the clients in the market know you. You've got a great network.
Good for you.
You're right. It's my business, after all. I've got to worry about it.
Anyway, are you coming to see me off tomorrow?
Where?
You forgot again?
I'm going to Dubai tomorrow.
Ah, yes...
I remember.
I was just kidding. I remember it.
Scared you!
You called me, sir?
You'd recommended that lad, right?
Yes, sir.
He doesn't even know how to talk! And you recommended him for marketing?
He's my cousin, sir... My aunt worries a lot for him. That's why I talked to you.
I don't want a stuck-up snob who doesn't even know how to talk to take up marketing for my company!
I understand, sir.
You may leave!
Are you alright?
Yeah.
Why do I feel the boss has told you off?
So you're a seer, are you?
I'm sorry...
I don't mind it.
But you're almost right.
Hello, Aunt.
Hello, m'boy.
Did Aqil come there?
Yes.
I was worried whether he'd even go there.
The interview's over.
So... Will he get the job?
Aunt...
I can't lie to you.
I've been embarrassed today. The boss called me and insulted me, too.
He said he hasn't seen a man more uncouth than him!
Anyway, I'll talk to you when I get back.
Novera called.
She wants to go shopping with me.
What did you say?
What you're expecting.
I said, 'Why don't you go with Waqas?'
Why doesn't she talk to me?
You better not start over this!
I won't. But I'll ask her.
Okay.
By the way, I thought I'd talk to Faizan.
About the marriage?
Your engagement, for now. And your marriage, later on.
Mum...
I'm your typical Asian boy... I wouldn't dare turn you down!
Okay...
You're quite the actor! I give you that!
Get ready, she's waiting!
'Bonsoir, Madame'... What else do they say? 'S'il vous plaît'. 'Merci beaucoup'! 'Je vous en prie'... 'Intimité'!
You tried your best. But it just wasn't destined for him...
I have no idea why he had to do it.
The boss said he's very rude.
His friends' flattery and infinite favours have spoilt him...
I mean, what's the big deal if he earns some 20,000?
But he doesn't show any sense...
You're right... That's why we're worried.
You've got to humble yourself to work...
Of course.
...And you have to live your whole life that way.
And my brother would rather hold his head high.
Humility isn't disgraceful, Malika.
It's quite the opposite.
I'm sure the boss didn't deserve the respect Aqil didn't give him.
Enough. You can see what spoils him...
Asim, would you help me with this question? I don't really get it.
Really?
Here.
'Three common managerial'...
Asim...
Yes?
Have dinner here.
No, Aunt, I'll have dinner at home. Mum's waiting.
Munni, be done with it already!
Someone's got to go home.
Thank you so much.
I'll get going, Aunt. Okay. Bye.
-Thank you. Bye.
-Bye.
It's better to stay quiet than say something so mean.
What were you thinking, Aqil?
You know I'd talked to the boss for you.
You were so rude to him!
He's my boss! He could've fired me!
Listen.
I wasn't rude at all.
I could see right through that man. I don't want to work for a grouchy man like him!
More like you don't want to work at all, if you ask me.
Exactly! I don't want to work at a place where I have to say 'Yes sir' and 'May I, sir' to a grumpy old crab for a couple thousand!
It pains me so much.
Honestly?
It pains me too.
Did you want me to be insulted?
What?
I'd want you to be insulted?
Are you out of your mind?
Your boss was talking as if he had to give his company to me.
He's the boss! He can talk the way he wants!
But I --
But you know I can't take it, Asim.
No good talking to you.
Hey, listen to this!
Let me get this straight.
I don't want to debase myself for a lowly job.
You talked to him about my job. Thank you. Thank you so much.
But please, don't. Ever.
I can see people for what they are.
And I can't bow my head before a stuck-up old geezer.
Anyway...
You must be in a hurry. Take care.
Hello, Mum.
Hello... I've been waiting all day, you could've call --
-Please don't ask me anything about the interview.
They'll call me if it went well.
Asim told me everything.
That's the bleedin' limit.
Did you think they're just waiting to give you the job?
-Not at all.
I did think Asim would find a job that suits me.
Not his fault, though, Mum.
He's got his own world.
He wants to imprison me in it.
Heard that?
That's why I say I'm tired of living like this! Like Asim!
Praise the Lord. He's living a happy life, and I'm sure it's staying this way.
But I don't want to live this life.
And I've already taken the first step to live the life I want to.
I'll take you all the way...
All the way to Heaven...
Hello?
What were you doing?
Nothing, really.
Know what I'm watching right now?
No?
Your shoot.
How do I look?
You might not believe it's you!
I told you. You're worth it.
How flattering!
I don't lie about anything. I say just what's true.
Can you send it to me? I want to see my pictures.
I can't send you the shoot. You know it belongs to the client.
Hey! Why can't I see my own pictures?
I'll show you when you come to office tomorrow.
Okay.
I'll be there.
That's done.
I'll get your payment ready.
Okay. See you.
Bye.
-Bye.
So he says you're almost right? But he can't see what's right in front of him!
I think he's never really thought about me.
Then why are you after someone so stone-hearted? Seriously, Sana, I don't really get you...
Because I like him, Farah.
Of course... You can't help it...
He looks good... He's nice, and all of that...
But I've got a problem because you can love him but can't express your love.
Get it?
Hello? Anyone there?
Yeah?
I say, tell him everything. At least you'll find out how he reacts.
Whether he's delighted or sad... I mean, he's totally unpredictable! You just can't guess!
That's why I don't say anything, Farah.
What do you mean?
I won't be able to face him if he minded something I said.
C'mon, Sana. It ain't no crime to love.
That's why I love him.
But wouldn't it be a crime to love him if I told him and he just refused?
Wow...
Her unrequited love for Asim's sharpened her wits! Gotta say, I'm impressed!
Hold on... Here's a little round of applause for you!
Let's get back to work, shall we?
Of course. You're lost in your thoughts all day. Even your tea's lost it.
Mum...
Remember the loan I'd applied for?
It's been approved.
We'll get a car in a few days.
Congratulations, m'lad.
Honestly, I was very worried.
I didn't think the boss would approve it after everything Aqil did.
Please don't mind it, my dear...
But you shouldn't have talked about Aqil in the first place.
He's my sister's son, but he doesn't deserve any favour.
I did it for Aunt.
If only Aqil could feel his mother's worries...
At his age, boys are mature... They become responsible... But he doesn't bother!
At his age! Well, maybe, if his father were with him...
Responsibilities make one wise. But not everyone's like you.
Mind if I ask something, Asim?
Not at all.
Are you buying a car because you want to, or is it something else?
What else could it be, Mum?
I'm sure Malika didn't demand it?
I need more sugar.
It's so worrying!
Yea -- No... I'll -- talk to Noriyan and work something out. I'll get back to you. Bye. Tell him I send my greetings.
What happened? You look worried.
It was my sister-in-law. My brother's really sick.
Oh...
Why don't you go meet him?
I can't do that. Who'd cook for you?
Please don't embarrass me like that. He's your brother. Go to him for a few days. I've got many around here who can help.
I won't be going for a few days. I'll leave in the morning and be back by night.
Shall I serve dinner?
-Yes. I'll go change.
Rosy...
You forgot everything now that your cousin's here!
What's up with you? You're here after ages!
What's cooking, mate?
-Nothing, really.
I'm going to office regularly these days. And I've got to take Novera somewhere in the evening too...
Blimey... Take that drama somewhere else.
You say Novera calls you, but it seems you're actually dying to go with her.
Something like that. Aye.
We're preparing for our engagement.
Really?
Splendid.
Congratulations, hero.
Thank you!
When are you introducing me?
I will, what's the hurry?
What 'bout you? How's Madame Zoha doing?
She's gone to Dubai for some work.
I'm surprised you didn't go along!
I refused.
Really?
You refused and she was okay with it?
Sometimes, I feel like closing this chapter forever.
You've tried before. She won't leave you so easily.
I don't think it's that simple.
Aye, but I tell you... She'd be dying to hear my voice the day I decided to put an end to it.
She won't see me again.
So, I'm thinking of doing everything I can, settle some things, and do it sharpish.
Know what I think?
What?
I sometimes feel that you're the Devil dressed as a man.
Really?
I can see the Devil in all his red glory somewhere else.
Just brilliant.
Fantastic.
Seriously. Don't get into any trouble.
You know I won't.
And if I ever did, what good would friends like you be?
Aye, what good would friends like me be?
Hello, Granny!
How are you?
I'm great. How about you?
What?
Really?
That's great!
I can't tell you how much it delights me you're coming!
Did you tell Mum?
Okay, then, please don't tell her.
Let's surprise her.
Also, I'm not going to let you go back this time.
Yeah. You're not leaving us again, Granny.
Okay, love you. Bye.
You look so happy... Looks like it was someone really special!
It was my Granny.
She lives in American. She's coming here after ages. I'm really excited.
Of course...
Lucky you!
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV