It seems so selfish...
You don't care one bit about me... Even after everything I've done for you...
It's all about give and take, you know...
If you ask me, there's a simple formula to fulfil every dream...
Feel free to come back when you've understood it.
What do you think?
Would Asim and Aunt agree after all that's happened?
-Yeah.
They will.
Those who care for their family can forgive and forget everything.
I don't want any favours.
I hope we're clear that I'm never saying yes to him!
-I hope we're clear, too, that I may not be able to save you again.
You're creating trouble for yourself.
Mum's right...
I created this problem...
It's up to me to solve it!
Mum...
Call and tell Aunt...
I've got no problem...
Munni...
Did you hear what I heard?
Yeah.
Call Aunt, quick.
What made her change her mind?
Forget it, Mum! Just call Aunt. Asim would be at home. It'd be great if he heard it too!
I'll call her in the morning.
But Mum... Now --
-I told you I'll call her in the morning. Tidy this up, okay?
Congratulations!
-For what?
Your Aunt called at last!
What does she say?
What Aqil told you.
Malika has no problem now.
Really? Wow!
Yeah.
Let's hope it's the best for all of us.
Amen.
But why don't you seem happy?
That's not it... It's just... A strange fear... No idea why... Ever since you told me she's okay with it...
What are you worried about, Granny?
You and Malika are poles apart! Ask your Mum if you don't believe me!
Blimey... Please don't talk about Mum...
She thinks Sana's the only match for me in the entire world!
Oh, please...
Don't even start...
I don't want to hear you comparing Sana with Malika.
I've never seen anyone like her.
You're just mistaken about her.
I told you Malika'd said it without thinking.
She loves me!
And I'm sure we'd be very happy together.
I know you'd only be happy with her. That's why I always prayed that the Lord show her the way.
I hope your prayers work.
-May the Lord keep the two of you happy.
Amen.
So you're angry because Aqil met me and I didn't tell you?
Yes.
I would've had no problem if you told me, but Aqil! I was so furious when he told me!
'Problem'? What kind of problem? He just bumped into me and couldn't say know, because he's your best friend, right?
Exactly! He's my best friend! What's he to you? Nobody!
What...?
What's this nonsense? I was just being polite?
Okay, Novera, let me try to explain it.
You don't know the people here. You don't know what they're like.
Oh, I don't know what they're like? Or are you just too wrong?
-Blimey, you're out to prove me wrong!
Why are you shouting?
-Cripes! I'm not shouting! I'm not shouting, okay!?
I'm sorry!
I just wanted to tell you they're not what they look like!
You're not trying to explain anything, you're just trying to set my boundaries!
Can you please not be so wrong about me for once?
-You are wrong!
I'm not wrong! You talked to Aqil about us! Told him everything! Why'd you tell Aqil I'm possessive? That I don't give you space, I force my will on you? Tell me!
This is too much! I gotta leave. I just can't understand you. Bye!
Wait, Novera --
Where are you off to?
I just gotta go, Aunt. I've got something important to do. I gotta leave. Bye, Aunt! Take care!
-You can't just leave like that! But --
Something happened here?
Blimey, she's a weird one!
Try to tell her something and she flares up!
Who told you to tell her anything?
I just wanted to tell her not to talk to Aqil about us!
Hold on...
When did she meet Aqil?
Bumped into him at the mall.
You must've introduced her to him.
How many times have I told you to stay away from him? He's a proper clever lad!
-Please stay out of it, Mum... I'll talk to her!
I better not hear you've had a row again!
-Yeah yeah!
You gotta listen to those you love, Novera...
But Dad...
What if they're just plain wrong?
You could've made him understand. You didn't have to be angry with him.
But it's so irritating, Dad...
Well, what if he feels the same way?
Anyway... Just hear him out, and try to tell him your side of the story, okay?
To get angry and leave is the coward's way out.
Just be brave and make him understand.
Okay...
Come here. Sit.
I know you're very wise...
But you're not at that point in life where you have to compromise on your principles for someone, give up your independence to show you're serious about your relationship.
Yeah, Dad, but don't you think it's a bit too early?
He expects so much from me... I need some time to understand him.
Do you know why?
He loves you. Loves you so much, I tell you! You're his world!
I mean... Just look at him! He's so excited!
He already thinks of you as his life partner.
Just try and understand his point of view, his side of the story too.
There's few who love you so much, and fewer who'd face any challenge to get you with a smile.
Just because they love you.
You have to understand his point of view, okay?
He tried to explain it to you because he loves you.
Okay, Dad... I'll say sorry to him.
That's my girl.
I'll be back.
-Okay.
Alright...
Hello? Yeah, Sumeyra!
Hello.
Is Novera back?
Yeah, she is.
Did she say anything about Waqas?
Don't worry. It happens with the kids...
Thank you.
I was so worried you may be angry.
-What are you saying?
Waqas is just like my son!
Waqas says he's hurt her. He'll say sorry to her.
That's what Novera thinks too! She'll say sorry too!
Good they've patched up. I'm so relaxed now. Thank you.
Don't worry. All will be well. Thank you. Bye.
I couldn't believe it when Asim told me why Aqil had come!
I can't believe how it happened either...
Let's fix the wedding date. I say you shouldn't wait around too much.
Any day you say.
Let's see... It's Tuesday... How about Friday?
They can get married in the morning and you can take her home by the evening.
This Friday?
Yeah, there's so much to do!
I think we ought to hurry up, or you'll get busy arranging for her dowry! No way I'm allowing that!
He's right. I told you I want nothing.
Okay, but I can't send her off empty-handed.
Don't worry, Mum. I've saved enough to get everything she needs in a day.
But we've got to invite everyone!
Just call them!
He's got a point. We shouldn't wait around too much.
Please, explain it to Mum.
I'll get going. Okay, Asim?
-Okay.
Aqil's right. You can call them. We're going to call everyone too.
As you say...
Munni! Get us some tea, will you?
Sure, Mum.
Double time. I ain't leaving before we've all had some sweets!
I haven't seen Asim and Aunt so happy before.
Why not? They're gettin' more than they ever deserved.
Blimey, Malika, I can't believe you're still saying that!
Hey...
Still gonna ignore me?
I want to see Aunt.
And me?
I mean, who am I to you?
What is it?
I just wanted to thank you.
For honouring my love.
I've won your love.
You haven't won my love.
You've just had your way.
Out of my way.
I can't believe you're still in touch with Zoha.
Just came across her today.
You shouldn't have come with her.
I don't think she's done anything to me that I should've refused... In fact, if you ask me, I don't think she's done anything to you...
What do you mean? She left me, left this place! What hasn't she done to me?
I'm sorry but I never saw you sad that she left you...!
I'm not the type who'd show their wounds to the world.
I wish you'd shown her this wound. Perhaps she would've realised you needed her.
She was the lady of the house. My wife! I didn't have to tell her I needed her!
You can't be serious!
Remember when you'd brought someone here the day after she left you? I tried talking to you about it but you pulled me up and asked me to stay out of your personal life...
I think you should let me stay out...
Nobody would've come here if she hadn't left me.
And she would never have left if you'd given her her proper place.
I'm not gonna take you siding with her before me.
But Granny...
Mum's worried for no reason! She's still got her doubts!
How could I be happy if she's not happy for me?
I think Salma's right, Asim.
Malika giving in so suddenly... Aqil fixing the date... Don't you think something's off?
They're very upright, Granny... They're worried about the thing with Malika's pictures, the rumours... So they fixed the date quick. It's okay.
But Salma told me Malika didn't even talk to you.
You should've come with us. Believe me, they were all so happy!
I'm talking about Malika. I'm not talking about anyone else.
Why'd Malika agree if she were not happy with it?
Believe me.
Please, get these doubts out. And explain it to Mum.
I pray we're mistaken.
I'm sure that's it. I know her.
Hello! How you doin'?
'Sup? Where's the others?
Busy with the assignments... And Farooq's Dad isn't well. So, just the two of us!
We should go and check on his Dad.
Aye, right.
By the way, I wanted to talk about something.
Please don't mind it.
Why would I?
It's been ages since I saw you so relaxed!
Yeah...
I had a lot going on...
But it's over now...
Now I'm so relaxed...
Seriously. Good to have you back, mate.
And mate... I'm sorry too...
I always thought you're turning me against Malika.
C'mon, mate, let's not talk about her.
Seriously!
Remember you always said she's ambitious? Overambitious, in fact!
She just uses people as stepping stones to get what she wants!
What'd she care about a loser like me?
That's why I said, let's not talk about her!
There you go again!
Nah, I'm fine.
Well, now that you've seen everything... There's something else you should know.
I wasn't mistaken one bit about her.
What do you mean?
Asif saw Malika at the restaurant, and, Jaysus, her squeeze was no ordinary man.
Why didn't he tell me?
We thought we would, but Asif thought we shouldn't.
You should've told me.
You loved her. It would've hurt you.
No way, man. You should've told me!
The love for her in your eyes, I mean...
Anyway...
Let's play.
Mum's got some real lovely dresses for you! Come and see! I'm sure you'll love the designs!
Not interested.
Mum and Aqil are also getting your jewellery. Mum really wants you to queen up! I asked them to get a maroon and golden gown! I'm sure it'd look lovely!
Jesus Christ, Munni, bugger off!
I thought you'd like it golden and maroon!
Get me a ruddy coffin!
Please don't say that.
What do you want to hear? Bury me in a coffin proper than bury me alive in a gown and jewels! Save your money!
But you were so happy about it!
Bug out! I'm sure you've got loads to do besides getting on my wick!
I...
I think I took it a bit too seriously...
I'm sorry.
Don't say sorry. I should say sorry.
I forgot that every girl's gotta ask her life partner before doing anything here.
I should've asked you.
Please don't embarrass me anymore! It's okay!
Who knows what Aunt would think!
Aunt?
Aren't you worried about what I think?
Okay then.
What do you think?
I think I gotta be conscious around my life partner, because folks really get triggered these days!
You? Conscious around me? I can't even imagine that!
I think you just say anything you come up with!
Ehh?
-Yeah.
I ain't even that careless.
-Oh?
How careless are you, then?
Stick with me and you'll find out!
I'm gonna tell your friend Aqil that you had a row with me.
Yeah, go on. What's the worst he can do?
Stay tuned to find out!
I see Asim's been going back early these days.
Yeah?
I hope Aunt's fine...
Don't worry.
C'mon, mate... She's really nice.
Yeah, she is. She's very happy, of late.
What do you mean?
Sana... Don't think so much about Asim, okay? Because he's out of your life.
When was he ever in my life?
I just wonder why he goes back early these days.
Okay... So you want to hear it...
Alright then...
He's getting married.
I had no idea. Mr Sohail told me.
But you know you always get to hear these things...
No... It's good.
I'll wish him.
Munni...
Look at these lovely earrings! Malika would look stunning with these!
Of course.
Show these to her and let me know if there's something she doesn't like. I'll be busy tomorrow.
Call her here, Munni. Why's she in there?
What's up?
She isn't happy about it, Mum...
What is it this time?
It's nothing like that...
She's leaving her home, all of us. Don't worry, I'll talk to her.
You'd better.
If there's anything else on her mind, get it out of her.
Don't be angry now, Aqil. She's just here for a few more days.
Munni... What'd she say?
I don't really get her... I showed her everything, but she just wasn't interested.
Put these in order. I'll show it to her.
I hope you're not busy.
No?
Farah told me about your marriage.
Congratulations.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
There's some things you can share with your colleagues.
Well, Miss Sana...
I was about to tell you. In fact, I even told Mum she can ask you for help if she needs anything.
My pleasure. Let me know if I can help.
Thank you so much, Sana.
Once again, congratulations.
Sana...
-Yeah?
Malika's my Aunt's daughter...
And my love.
Good for you!
Come here, Malika. Look what we've got for you! I'm sure you'll love everything!
My, I wonder what it could be!
Blimey, that's what you're crowing about!
Have some shame!
Just for the sake of our happiness?
Jeez, I'm about to crucify myself for your happiness. What else do you want?
Get her out of my sights, Munni. I don't want to see her face.
Not fair.
But remember.
You'll regret it.
Pack it all, Munni.
Could she possibly be any more thankless?
Mum...
Some of the neighbours asked when the dholak's gonna be.
Invite them to the dholak and the mehndi. Tell them the dholak's this evening.
Pack everything.
Where'd I keep it?
It's Malika...
I'm in trouble, Atif.
What kind of trouble?
My family's busted me!
Don't worry. You can always come to me.
They're getting me married off!
What are you doing with my phone?
Calling a friend.
Why?
Inviting her, of course.
Why'd you hang up?
I was done.
Call her again, will you? I'll talk to her.
She said she can't be here.
Give it to me.
Okay.
Tell her it's your mother's number. She better not start calling me.
Can't believe you didn't invite me to your sister's mehndi!
You know why I didn't.
I would've loved to meet your Mum, your sisters.
Yeah, sure...
So that we could've never met again.
You can't be serious.
I know how good you are.
My sister and Mum don't.
They'll just see an old woman controlling a young man.
Does love care about these things? Age and all...
No, but...
Mum and my sister won't get it.
Our society doesn't.
What if your family never got it?
Don't worry... I'll talk to them.
Yeah, keep me waiting...
C'mon, Zoha... I'd rather leave than hear that.
I think it's time we sorted a few things out, Aqil.
What?
Like -- moving in together. Getting married.
What's up with you?
Are you okay?
I was here because I may not be able to see you for a few days.
But, blimey, you're so worried and making sure it catches on!
I've always tried to ease you.
-Okay...
Okay, but...
I'll tell you when it's time.
Okay?
C'mon now.
Mate...
Smile. We're celebrating! My sister's getting married! Don't be all serious-like!
Good girl.
Now would you please get me some tea?
Sure.
Malika! Come with me! It's so fun!
Don't even start, Munni... Go away.
Everyone's singing, dancing, celebrating. They're waiting for you! Why are you still here?
I don't like your blasted singin' or your chuffin' dance one bit!
Why do you want to pick a fight before you leave? Can't you just be happy... For us?
Who cares about me here? Why should I be happy for any of you?
Why'd you accept the proposal if you're not happy with it?
This is for my girl.
You're too kind, Salma...
Zahida... I'm her aunt, after all!
Who else would get her a gown for her mehndi?
They're both just lovely, Aunt!
Where's Malika, by the way?
She was here just now! I think she went out.
How say you give it to her?
She -- Had a -- headache, Mum...
She took a pill and went to sleep.
How'd she fall asleep in this noise?
C'mon, let's give it to her.
Hello, Aunt...
Well, hello there...
Would you look at this lovely mayoun gown! From your aunt!
May the Lord give her good fortune. I thought I'd give her these and bless her.
Munni told me you had a headache. You could've told me. I would've made you some tea.
Tea ain't gonna cure this headache.
Take a pill.
I'll do with your blessings for a start...
I say you should get some rest. I'll get going, Zahida...
Bye, Aunt.
-Bye, my dear.
A little more?
-No, thanks.
You should've told us. Noriyan would've brought you here himself.
Of course. What if you got sick on the way?
I'm fine now. Don't worry.
You shouldn't have come alone.
Aye, Sakina, but I thought I'd come here, get myself checked up. I've heard a lot about this doctor.
Of course, Uncle... Ain't never a good idea to ignore your health.
Tell your Mum. She looks so weak...
I'm fine.
Everyone's got blood pressure and stuff these days. Anyway...
I won't let you go so quickly! You've got to stay here for a few days!
Just a few days?
Stay here as long as you want!
How say you put Mum's complaints to rest, Uncle? You're staying here at least a week.
Aye.
You're family. I want to stay here, too. But you know about your Aunt and the kids...
They're all alone. Things ain't really good at the village. Robberies and all.
May the Lord protect us all...
-No excuses, Uncle. Please.
Okay.
Did you stay with us? Remember how much I asked you?
If only Mum weren't here alone!
Let's just say it's the same with me...
Anyway, check this out.
-Aye, I almost forgot.
Leavin' already?
-Yeah, in a bit of a hurry.
Just wanted to tell you Malika's getting married tomorrow.
Congratulations!
Why'd you fix the date so suddenly? All good?
-Yeah, it's her in-laws. Blimey... Just had to do it.
You coming?
-Of course.
Come with Aunt.
I'll tell her, but...
I can't guarantee she'll come.
She's back. Why don't you invite her yourself?
-Hello, Aunt. How are you?
Hello.
Guess what, I was just here to invite you.
-To?
His sister's getting married.
-Oh.
Congratulations to your family.
-Sorry but I haven't got a card. Everything happened so quickly we couldn't even get the cards ready.
It's okay. Waqas'll be there even if I couldn't.
Okay, I'll get going.
-Okay. Take care.
Take care.
Get me a glass of water, Nasrin.
-Mum...
What is it?
Why'd you say I'd be there if you couldn't?
Aren't you going?
Of course I am, but I wanted to go with you.
You know I don't like your friend one bit.
So please don't insist.
Mum...
It's his sister's wedding. Please.
Stop it, Waqas.
Hey!
-Hey!
Hi, how are you?
I'm good.
Going back?
Yeah, just droppin' by to invite Waqas. My sister's getting married.
That's really exciting! I love weddings!
You do? So... Would you like to come over to my place?
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV