Who're you talking to?
You have no idea...
I thought it's Asim.
You don't know me if you did!
Mum...
Malika can be so brutal...
What happened?
I mentioned Asim.
She got so rough...
I mean, just look at how much Asim and Aunt care for us.
They're so nice...
But Malika... She doesn't have a care in the world!
She just doesn't listen...
Munni...
I hope she's not seeing anyone else?
How'd I know Mum? It's not like she'd tell me.
But I suspect it sometimes... That she's... You know, seeing someone...
That's why she hates Asim.
I have no idea, Mum... Why don't you ask her yourself?
I will.
What'll you ask?
Nothing.
If what I think is true, I swear, I'll cut that sharp tongue!
You better not ask me then.
If you liked or commented on her picture again, I'll feed you your teeth!
Go and ask Malika not to put such pics up! You can't even control your girlfriend --
-Hold it, Noriyan! Leave him.
-Noriyan!
What happened?
-Get off!
It's all because of you! You love to show everyone your charms, don't you?
Go and get into modelling or something! But forget me!
What's up with him?
What's up with you, Noriyan?
Why did you create a scene? It's just a picture!
So much for love! At least you could've find a half-decent excuse to leave me!
I told you to deactivate your Facebook account.
You want to control me?
I uploaded the picture because I liked it.
What's the big deal?
It's a big deal because you don't listen to me at all.
You know I don't like it.
You just like to keep me caged...
I can't live freely at home... And now... Even you...
Malika...
Please don't cry.
You know I can't see you crying.
You can't see me in tears but you can hurt me.
Everyone would be laughing at me... That my boyfriend can't trust me.
Just one pic and he created a scene...
I wish I'd never met you!
You're just like my family... You want to keep me caged... Can't let me be free...
Malika...
I didn't mean to...
I didn't mean it that way...
You want to upload pictures? Post whatever you like. I won't stop you.
But...
Take care that...
People don't respect you just because of the pictures...
But because of who you are.
Well that's what I am!
Alright...
Just be who you are. No worries.
I'm here for you.
I don't want this cruel world to lay its eyes on you.
I just want that you do whatever you do for me.
Fix your mood, will you?
Munni!
Yes, Mum?
What are you doing?
Aqil gave me these clothes to iron last night.
I've told him not to borrow his friend's clothes so many times. It doesn't look proper.
No need to tell him.
-What can I do?
I'm his mother. It hurts me...
But he never listens to me...
And it hurts me when no one listens to you...
You must be really strong to try to get some sense into him everyday.
I figure someone's been scoring her brownie points...!
Ever thought about my strength? I take earfuls everyday!
You couldn't care less!
Quick, Munni. I gotta go.
Care to tell where?
Jeez, why do you ask me everyday?
What do you want? Stay home like girls all day?
I've told you not to borrow your friends' clothes.
It doesn't do you any good but humbles you before them.
It's okay among friends.
Sharing is caring, and it's very common among friends.
Waqas himself says these branded clothes and this colour suit me better.
This flattery costs us so dear so often...
What do you mean?
Doesn't your son deserve the compliment?
Leave it. Don't say anything. Ruined my mood...
I told you, Mum...
It's no use...
Hop on. I'll drop you.
No. I can walk.
What's the problem? I'm your cousin.
I know. But you sometimes forget you're my cousin.
I forget it?
No, you do.
We've swor --
-For God's sake, I've told you I don't accept what we'd sworn!
My Prince Charming can't be someone like that, okay?
Malika...
You only find 'Prince Charming' in dreams.
Open your eyes and you'll see he's gone.
I'm sure I'll find my Prince Charming if you kept your doomy self at an arm's length.
What do you want, Malika? I can give my life to win your love.
For starters, you can try changing this outdated clunker-of-a-bike.
Then, we'll talk.
Work on the contouring, Mosin. And we can't do with this hairstyle. We're doing the first style I showed you, remember?
I'll have a look and check again. Fix the contouring. Everything else is fine.
Okay, sir.
-Quickly. We don't have time.
-Thanks.
Yes, what've we here?
-I think this look won't do.
It's you, Noriyan!
What brings you here? Come.
You asked for the keys, Atif.
Why are you here? Where's the driver?
His son is sick.
Why are you getting so worked-up? Take a seat. The shoot's about to start.
We're shooting a very interesting video.
No, Atif. I'll leave you to yourself.
Sure?
As you wish...
Okay, back...
Mosin?
Yes, sir?
We're doing this look. Do this hairstyle, okay?
Okay sir, no problem. I'll get to it.
Hey, Mum.
Hello, my dear...
Munni!
Malika's here. Heat the food.
I've already heated it.
Your Majesty could've called before coming.
I could've served Your Majesty at the doorstep!
Oh, really! That is oh-so-kind of you. It's not like you've got ten dishes for me.
I was just kidding...
What's up with you the moment you step in?
I'm reminded my place!
You should thank God rather than complain.
He eases so many troubles...
What do I thank Him for?
He's made you complete, made you so beautiful...
We've never lacked anything...
He found such a lovely match for you in Asi --
-Gorblimey, Mum...
What do you want, Malika? I can give my life to win your love.
For starters, you can try changing this outdated clunker-of-a-bike.
Then, we'll talk.
I respect you, love you...
I'll keep you happy all your life.
Asim, I can't stand this blather.
You better show up only when you can get gold bangles instead of these garlands.
♪ With teary eyes ♪
♪ Teary eyes ♪
♪ I've lost everything ♪
Asim?
♪ Everything ♪
Mum?
What happened?
♪ With teary eyes... ♪
You look worried.
No, Mum... Just thinking about... Things...
Asim...
Don't lie to me.
I'm your mother. I can see that you're worried about something even when you don't tell me.
I was thinking of buying a car.
A car?
-Yeah, the bike's getting old...
Ah, yes, so it is...
Your Dad bought it when you were in college.
It's very old.
I've saved some money. I thought I'd get some from the office.
We can get a car on instalments.
But must you get a car right now?
Everyone's got a car now.
Just look around. Everyone's got a car here.
I've lent some money. You can buy a car when I get it back.
But you've saved it for my marriage.
I have, but I can lend again.
Besides, I don't think Zahida will be getting Malika married this year.
Why?
Did you talk to her?
-Yeah.
She changed the topic.
Take me to her tomorrow.
I'll ask her what she wants.
Please, don't talk just yet.
Let Malika finish her studies first.
She can continue her studies when she's here. It's not like we're stopping her.
Alright, Mum...
Let me get a car first.
What's a car got to do with any of this, Asim?
Let me get things straight with her.
I still can't believe it.
Our brand and products are so famous!
Remember when we announced our business partnership, Zahir?
Your Mum thought we wouldn't be able to do a thing.
She still doubts us. 'How can anyone get rich growing plants'?
I've thought of sending her a hamper with all our products.
When's she coming here?
Tomorrow evening. And you're coming to the airport with me.
I can't. Not tomorrow.
Why?
What is it?
Not another excuse!
It's no excuse...
I'm getting Aqil a sports bike. I'm going to a few showrooms.
What?
Are you out of your mind?
Why?
What's wrong with that?
You're buying him a bike?
As if you haven't done enough for the loser already!
Please, Zahir...
Why do you talk about Aqil like that?
I do all of this for him because it makes me happy.
Alright, tell me - midnight blue or gun metal grey?
I value your tastes!
Bro...
Your girl's crazy. Get it?
She called me.
Why'd she call you?
You don't answer her calls, you've deactivated your Facebook account... So that just leaves me, doesn't it?
Good... She ought to know what it means to yearn for your love...
She says big words about love.
Be done with it, mate... How much more will you punish her?
She'll be out of my control if I didn't.
What do you mean out of your control? She's a woman, not a bloomin' machine!
Here's a tip. Call her and ask her to jump from the second floor.
-No way...
Why just the second floor? Why not the third or fourth floor? Good riddance for me forever!
What if she left a note? 'Mr Aqil made me do it'?
-Anything, really!
Like seriously, why would she name me?
I didn't promise her anything.
Do what you like... Just get me rid of her. Talk to her.
Why isn't he getting up?
I think he forgot it!
Then go and remind him!
What if he refused, Farah?
Congratulations! You would've met the first man in the world to refuse a party!
Alright...
I'll go talk to him...
-Aye.
You sort it out with him. I'll place the order.
Alright... I'll talk to him...
Now's your chance to say it to him!
C'mon, Farah. I'm not going to talk about anything like that to him...
Oh, really? So you're throwing this party for me?
Alright.
I'll talk to him...
Best of luck!
Uhh... You seem to be forgetting something...
What?
We were going to have lunch together?
Oh...
I'm so sorry, but I told you not to bother about it...
You're embarrassing me by asking me not to bother about it. It'll be my pleasure.
Please don't mind it...
I'd mind if you refused...
Alright. I'm coming.
Okay.
Shall we go together?
We're just going to the nearby restaurant.
It was Farah's idea --
I said we should get something delivered here, but --
Shall we?
And yes, I almost forgot...
She was asking for your address.
I hope you didn't give her!
I had to... She was almost pleading...
Jeez mate, are you touched in the head? What if she came knocking?
Won't it be great if she met her in-laws? It's a bonus if they like her!
Mrs Zoha Aqil...
I'm gonna whack you with this dumb-bell!
Jeez, mate, what are you?
Got me in this mess!
Honestly...
Mrs Zoha Aqil...
I like the sound of it.
Great. She's well-off, too.
You think we're so greedy?
-Can't I fool around with you?
Just call and ask her if she went there!
I ain't asking anything.
I told you there's no need to invite them here.
They didn't have a penny, but had the guts to say we're not their class! Sweet Jesus...
It's a way to refuse, Malika...
Besides, Munni's so simple and homely.
Everyone would like someone like you...
That's why I asked you to get Munni into university. She'll open her eyes. But no...
You'd rather be pure as the driven snow!
I think someone's poisoned their ears.
-To the dickens with them.
It's good we aren't marrying Munni off to him! Our Munni's perfect.
I'm sure, she'll find someone rolling in it!
Hopefully...
I'll go check.
Good afternoon.
Does Mr Aqil Ahmed live here?
Yes.
I'm from Bike House Showroom. I've brought his sports bike.
Sports bike?
Who bought this?
Sorry but I can't tell you that. Please sign this receiving letter.
My men will park the bike in the compound.
Thank you, ma'am.
Who was it?
Someone bought Aqil a sports bike.
Good Lord...
It costs 1.4 million!
What?
The showroom folks parked it in the compound.
But who -- ?
Someone he talks to all night behind closed doors, I'm sure!
Come, let's have a look!
C'mon, Munni!
Hey!
That's your cousin, innit?
Aye.
He's following in your footsteps, by the looks of it!
-Put a sock in it!
Let's get going.
Good afternoon.
Hello?
Yes, sir.
I'll email you right away, sir.
Yeah.
Right away, sir.
C'mon, Asim. Give it a break. After all, it's your lunch break.
It was the purchase department. They asked me to email this right away. It's important.
Okay. Farah ordered what she wanted. I didn't know about you, so please order what you like.
Thank you very much. I'll have whatever you've ordered. It's fine by me.
Sometimes, it can be hard to guess what someone would like...
Innit, Sana?
Please don't worry about me.
I'm the proverbial dervish type... I am thankful for whatever I get.
Of course.
Sana always tells me you're so nice and, yeah, the dervish type.
One should be humble.
Someone who's humble is the most satisfied person in the world.
Yes, Mr Farooq?
You haven't received it?
I sent it right away.
Alright, sir... I'm coming...
In a minute, sir. Okay.
What happened? Have your lunch...
Mr Farooq's been calling so many times. He needs some important data.
Some other day maybe?
I have to go. Thank you.
Okay, bye.
-Bye.
Just here for a sec. Don't close the door.
Malika!
Go in!
Quickly...
C'mon, Sana... You didn't say a word on the way?
How could I? I didn't get a chance. Mr Farooq was after him every other second.
He's such a weird guy... Can't he switch his phone off when we're going out?
How about you tell him that when we get back?
Lovely. You know I won't stay quiet.
Good luck with that...
Your parathas, ma'am...
Please send the bill.
-Your bill's been paid.
Who paid it?
-The man with you.
Good. Saves you some money. Relax.
But lunch was on me!
What's with that bike?
-They delivered it in the morning.
I asked who'd sent it.
But they didn't tell me.
All his friends are proper dossers! I saw one of them outside, too!
Enough!
No need to use your brain.
He doesn't realise he's wasting your time...
Understand the distance between you and Waqas, Aqil.
I'm not asking you to end your friendship, but think about your future.
They'd buy us with these gifts!
Waqas didn't give me this bike.
Who, then?
-Take it easy.
I'm ashamed to see how you think.
Don't make me regret coming home early.
You better know that I'm the only one who can get you out of this shack. I'm the only one who can get you into a palace.
We have a right to the riches you talk about. It's our money that makes them rich!
No self-respecting man builds himself on the money of others.
Just look at Asim...
So honest, self-respecting, hard-working...
He's built everything with his hard-earned money.
He cares for us all. His family, all of us...
I wish you'd follow in his footsteps.
Well, I've seen your saintlike Asim today...
I know what he's really like...
Christ knows when he'll see sense...
He's right.
Our money makes them rich.
The Lord's given them much more than they need.
And Christ knows when you'll see sense...
Hi!
How're you doing?
I haven't heard from you in a while.
I'm very thankful for what you've done.
You're still angry with me, Aqil?
You're one of very few I can never be angry with.
But I don't think...
I deserve you.
The way you care for me...
It seems like you can feel what I wish for...
I don't think I deserve this love.
Please don't say that...
You deserve much more.
Why are you embarrassed? You know I don't like it.
You were right...
When've you ever been right?
I don't deserve this gift...
I do like it very much,
But I can't accept it...
I'll send it back tomorrow. Bye.
What?
No -- Aqil!
Aqil?
Hey Mum! Ahh! Strawberries!
Where've you been?
I asked you something.
-What happened?
Didn't I tell you it's very important that you go to office today? I needed your sign on these files!
I am so sorry...
I'll go tomorrow. I promise.
You're becoming very careless.
This business will shut down if you keep it up!
Mum...
I'm genuinely sorry. I won't do it again. I'll go tomorrow, I tell you.
And your friend! He's a ne'er-do-well. Corrupts you too.
For God's sake, just ask him to start doing something.
Know what, he's looking for a job. I told him to come to my office, but he said it'll affect our friendship.
Don't even think of letting that sort of dossers near your office.
-Mum...
He's very good.
He's a nice guy. You'll realise if you talked to him!
Acta, non verba, my dear!
Well, to change your life, you need to work. And to get work, you need skills. And your friend's got none.
Go over this file and sign it.
Can I?
-Yes.
And I want it right now.
Hey, Aunt.
Aqil! That can't be! Am I dreaming?
You're embarrassing me...
I was just kidding. Please, sit.
Isn't Asim here?
He'd be on his way. Must've stopped to pray.
Sit. I'll get you a cuppa.
Aunt...
Is he...
Always so late, or is it just today?
You know about the traffic. It gets late sometimes...
Your son's too upright, Aunt.
Keep an eye on him.
I'd hate to see him led astray.
My son's as wise as he's upright.
May the Lord protect him.
And look who we have here! Hello, m'dear.
-Hello, Mum.
Hey there, Aqil! What a pleasant surprise! This is quite the occasion.
-Indeed it is!
Alright, I'll get you a cuppa. Sit.
-No, Aunt -- I'm in a bit of a hurry.
I had to talk about something to Asim.
What happened? Everything alright?
So far, aye...
Come with me? We need to talk.
Sit down and talk. I'll go get you a cuppa.
C'mon, grab a pew.
Why are you so nervous?
Why'd I be?
You're my Aunt's only son, Asim.
Mum loves you so much too.
Yeah, she does...
We're also related in another way. I hope you remember that.
You're my brother-in-law to-be.
Yeah. You don't need to remind me.
I saw you with someone, Asim.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV