Noriyan...
What's up?
Told her?
No.
Couldn't say it?
She didn't come to university today.
You could've called her.
Her phone's off.
Don't worry... You can talk to her tomorrow.
In fact...
Take me to her place tomorrow.
I'll talk to her myself.
I'll tell her your truth.
This fear of losing her won't let the truth come out of your mouth.
Mum...
She'd be hurt I didn't tell her the truth.
This fear shows your love. I'll tell her about it.
Really?
Mum...
Please tell her that I believe I can give her every comfort in life.
Those who believe in love never covet any other comfort.
Malika...
Aqil's calling. You're going over to Salma's.
Me?
You've severed one tie, but it's not like they're nobody now!
Salma's not well... Just pay her a visit. A short one?
Why can't you go? She's your sister!
I've got a headache. I can go with Munni some other day.
Why don't you send her? She'd be oh-so-eager to go there!
Don't try to have your way every time!
Look. It's not like Aunt'll be pleased to see me. It just ain't no good.
Have it your way.
Hello, Aunt.
-Hello. Come in.
Mum said you're not well?
Yeah, in the morning. I'm good now. I'll get you something.
No. Not in the mood.
Sit. Asim's coming any moment. He's gone to drop a guest.
Well, Aunt, that depends on the - uh - guest. Innit?
She's his colleague, and she was checking on me.
Fair enough...
His colleague... With him for hours, I'm sure.
Blimey, he's got some proper nice female *ahem* colleagues. Comin' here, gettin' cosy and all, I mean.
Sure, she's proper nice. He's proper nice too.
That's why, Aunt, I tell you to keep an eye on him.
I've seen her with him before.
She's with him everyday. At the office.
Lemme get this straight. She used to be with him at the office... And now she's with him in his car. Making progress, I see!
I sent Asim with her. It's nothing of the sort.
It better be nothing of the sort, Aunt.
Because I won't take nothing of the sort.
Take care.
I'll get going.
He can take his sister's refusal but not my son getting in the car with someone!
Hi!
I called to tell you I'm not going to university tomorrow.
Really?
Won't you ask why?
Why?
I'm coming with Mum to your place.
Really?
Yeah!
Don't tell me you're not delighted!
And, Malika... I wanted to tell you something...
Yes?
Malika...
I love you so much...
You're all I want in my life...
I...
I know you'd be hurt to hear it, but...
Munni!
What is it?
Get me my protein shake. Quick.
I'm no billionaire, Malika.
Mum's the maid at this mansion.
And...
I live in the basement with Mum...
But I promise you, I'll give you every comfort in life, fulfil every wish you have.
You're there, aren't you?
Of course.
I hope you aren't angry with me...
You twit! Why'd I be angry with you? Talk to you later. Bye.
B --
I've told her, Mum!
About our visit?
Yes.
And what I never told her...
So... She didn't say anything?
Nothing.
I was so worried she'd be angry. She didn't even mind it one bit!
Really?
-Yeah.
I'll tell Atif when I go to get the keys from him.
I'm sure he'd want to come along too!
No need to tell Atif about it.
Why?
Why do you want to take him along?
Want to show off how close you are to a rich guy? You twit...
It's nothing like that, Mum.
Anyway... No need to tell him.
And no need to borrow his car. Your bike would do.
Bike?
Who rides a bike to his bride to-be's?
No problem! We can get a taxi!
Blimey, Mum... She lives so far away...
You don't have to be so kind.
If she could come so far, I'm sure you...
I don't like it when my colleagues come here.
You didn't have to invite her.
But I will. I just love her. She's almost family.
What'd Aqil think? I told him I'd be back soon.
I don't care about what he thinks now.
-But I do.
He's seen me with Sana. Who knows what he'd think!
You know what he thinks.
That's why I'm worried.
-Why should we?
We can't keep mourning Malika's rejection!
Please, Mum... Don't take her rejection so seriously.
Don't be mad. The deed is done. And you better take it seriously if you're not.
I've got to think of something for you.
Hey, Atif.
Hello, mate...
You didn't go to university today.
I'm taking Mum somewhere...
Where?
I can't hide it from you...
I'm taking her to your sister-in-law would-be's.
Really?
That's great.
But...
Aunt didn't tell me...
Mum said she'd introduce you to her once everything's decided.
Good.
The driver will be here any moment. You can take my car.
It's your first visit to your in-laws. A bike just won't do it.
No, Atif, I don't --
-Just do as I say.
And yeah, he'll get you some sweets.
Don't worry about anything.
Thank you, Atif.
I'm taking Mum to your sister-in-law would-be's.
Going somewhere?
Yeah.
Sit. We need to talk.
Yeah, go on.
Noriyan and his Mum are coming today.
What?
Noriyan and his Mum?
Didn't I tell you they're not welcome here?
Just stop it!
What's your problem?
I can't believe you're saying that! I mean, what'd Aunt and Asim think?
Nothing.
What do you mean?
Asim and Salma know very well that Malika won't give in.
Malika said that?
How dare she? She wants a piece of me!?
Aqil! Calm down!
-I can't!
She's calling a stranger here and you're stopping me!
-What's the big deal?
What if they're just like Malika thinks they are?
Here's an idea.
Meet them all you want. I don't even want to see their face!
You're her brother.
The only man in the family.
You've got to meet them.
-Well, then, don't complain if I said something real bad!
They're our guests. I know you won't.
You're her brother.
What don't brothers do for their sisters?
Can't you stay here for a while? For her?
Okay, I will. Happy?
Please, go.
It's good that you told her everything.
We have no worries now... No regret.
-Of course.
You've got to win me my love today.
Not so fast!
Malika's happiness would be as dear to her family as my happiness is to you.
Wish me luck!
I swear... Noriyan looks lush.
I'm glad you know there's someone better than Asim here.
Aye. And, blimey, look at his car!
He brought some sweets too! As if Mum's already said yes!
Noriyan said he's not going back until she does!
He sure means business!
Let me do this.
Noriyan's Mum is so excited to see you!
Let me get the tea...
Go. Mum's calling you too. I'll take care of everything.
Okay, but I'm setting everything on the tray.
Hey! I ain't even that bad!
He's my only son. I always wanted someone humble and civil for him.
You're too kind...
They usually look down on anyone below them.
'Below them'?
Well -- It's very kind of you -- to come to a small-town family like ours...
Didn't your daughter tell you?
Hello, Mrs --
Malika... Meet Mum.
Let's get going, Noriyan.
What is it?
-What happened?
Why are you leaving?
I'm sure your daughter can fill you in.
What happened, Mum?
Come, Noriyan. Right now.
But --
-Hey! You can't just go like that!
You think it's funny, eh?
I'm sure it's a mistake! I'll go talk to Mum.
-Aqil!
You're the maid's son?
Yeah, Malika. I told you last night, remember?
Out!
Aqil!
If I saw you trying to see or talk to my sister again, I swear I'll put you down!
Get going already!
-But --
What is going on?
-Satisfied?
Happy now?
Happy to see him?
What in the blazes is going on? Malika?
What the devil is going on?
I don't wanna know!
Mum...
I asked something, why aren't you telling me?
Why'd you do that?
I don't like her.
-No way.
You're lying. Something feels off.
I'd tell you if it were anything else.
Okay, then, why don't you like her? One reason?
Can you tell me why you like her? Just one reason?
I love her... And love needs no reason!
Well, then, there's no reason to reject her.
Just know that you can't marry her.
Let me know if you like anyone else. I can go see her.
But if she, too, is like Malika, know that you've got no option but Ashi.
What do you mean?
What's wrong with Malika?
Please, Mum!
You may be blind to her brash and brazen eyes, but I'm not.
What do you mean? What've you seen in her eyes in a few seconds?
You don't get it.
-That's why I'm asking you!
I can't make you understand!
That's so unfair, Mum!
If you think a mother could ever be unfair to her son... So be it.
I won't accept it!
Just ask her if she'd marry you.
Why's your blimmin' phone off, Malika?
There, now... No need to cry...
Let her cry all she wants, Munni. Let her sentence herself!
Oh, please, Mum...
It'll do you good.
Let her cry all she wants. You won't have to wipe her tears every now and then.
I can't believe they actually did that!
I wonder what pushed them, really...
Is it because his Mum rejected you, or because the rich guy of your dreams turned out to be the maid's son?
The maid? What do you mean?
It's a rip-off! His Mum's a maid!
How do you know if Noriyan never told you?
She's the maid at my class-fellow's... I saw her in a picture.
Fair enough...
But how did she recognise you the moment she saw you?
Well... She's the maid. No problem. She works hard to earn something.
But, Lord... She must be a seer or something!
And how is that?
One look at you and she was like, 'My son deserves much better'!
Just... Wow!
-Mum!
It's your karma coming back.
What goes around comes around.
Someone gave you the big E just as you did!
Aww... Easy...
Not fair. You should talk to Uncle.
We've decided already.
You said you'd talk about our marriage the moment Novera gets here.
Think of this engagement as the first step?
Who gets engaged these days?
Blimey, Novera's got you head over heels for her for real.
That's what you wanted, too, Mum.
I just wanted you to marry Novera. Not be so crazy about her.
Mum...
Please, just talk to Uncle.
I can't talk to him.
I'm sure he's talked to Novera about it.
What'd he think if I insisted?
So you're not talking to him?
It doesn't look nice. He'd think I can't wait!
No, thank you. I'll talk to Novera myself.
-Hey! Wait!
Good Lord, he's crazy...
Hey, Atif...
Hey... Blimey, man, you're stone-cold!
I thought I'd be the first to hear the good news.
Sorry, Atif...
I forgot...
Of course... Who'd miss me now?
Anyway, I want to talk to your Mum.
Mum?
-Yeah. Let me congratulate her.
Why? Wha --
-Why, you're getting married, of course!
Atif...
It didn't really go as planned...
What?
But why?
Mum didn't like her.
Don't worry. I'll talk to her. Convince her.
Okay.
Bye.
Atif called...
To congratulate us...
You should've told him I didn't like her.
I told him.
He asked why.
I'll tell him if he asked me.
Whatever... Your Mum's wise...
I'm sure there's something that made her reject the love of your life.
You know her too!
Who?
-Malika, remember?
The girl I did that play with?
I see...
She's a fantastic girl.
That's what I'm saying! Do you think Mum should've rejected her?
Aye... I don't get it either...
Please talk to Mum, will you? She listens to you!
Noriyan! Just when I was looking for you!
It's not like I'm lost or something!
But keep at it and you risk losing me!
Noriyan's really serious about her.
The halfwit...
Why don't you accept her if she's good?
Because she isn't.
He says she's a real beauty.
He doesn't know that others have their hearts set on the beauties.
So you haven't told him why you rejected her.
I don't want to drive a wedge between you.
It's best if we kept it to ourselves.
I should've been cross.
But I wonder why you are.
Why'd you talk to Mr Atif about Malika?
I wanted him to convince you.
Just who is he?
Why'd he feel for you?
He calls me his brother!
There's an ocean of difference between calling you a brother and being one!
You always speak against Atif!
You have until tomorrow morning. Do you need time or should I tell your Uncle?
Uncle?
You know I love Malika!
No one can take her place in my heart!
I'm sure Ashi can, once she's in your life.
No way!
She's everything your Malika isn't!
-So what?
Malika's everything for me!
And she's nothing for me!
You want to get married to her? Over my dead body!
You know I'll never be happy without Malika.
All I know is you'll never be happy with her!
Mum...
But why?
It'll hurt you, I'm sure...
Not more than you rejecting her?
You don't deserve someone like her! Just try to understand!
Mum...
Who do we deserve,
But the one we love?
You have no idea how much one-sided love hurts, Noriyan!
With teary eyes...
Why do you think she doesn't love me?
I could see all her love shatter when she found out you were the maid's son!
When she found out you were not the rich lady's son as you told her...
When she found out you were just the lowly maid's son!
But you couldn't see it...
Mum...
If --
What if --
What if Malika confessed her love before you?
Would you still have a problem?
Forget about me, she won't even confess her love before you!
Sometimes, you gotta take a chance...
Okay...
Have it your way.
I'd send her off right now if I could have my way!
Where?
-That's the problem!
Can't believe he's panting for someone else after getting engaged to Malika!
Someone else?
-You heard it.
She works with him and she's started paying them visits!
Who told you?
I've seen it myself!
And Salma?
-She knows everything.
She says she's just Asim's colleague. But...
I smell something shady!
Salma wants to make Malika her daughter-in-law.
And I've seen Asim's love for her.
But Malika doesn't care for any of that...
She'll suffer all her life! I tell you!
I never thought Malika's refusal would make Salma budge.
But you've got me worried.
-There's only one way out, Mum.
Talk to Malika. Get some sense into her!
She'll suffer all her life if she didn't listen!
Keep an eye on her.
Make sure she doesn't talk to Noriyan again!
She doesn't even talk about him.
Good.
Yeah?
Malika...
Why didn't you take my call?
I don't want to have anything to do with you!
But why?
Can't believe you're asking me!
Didn't Mummy tell you?
-What'd she say?
But Malika --
There's nothing left for me to say.
Let's just say Malika's love for Noriyan died when she found out who he was!
But Malika, I told you about it!
Don't even try it. I'd never love a maid's son!
Just forget me!
Are you crazy? How could I --
Noriyan, I guess?
Don't even mention his name!
Blimey, that's some real hatred. I thought you said your heart beats to the sound of his name!
You here to rub salt in my wounds?
I just wanted to ask you if you actually loved him or --
I took everything because I loved him!
Lemme get this straight - your love bugged out when you found out he's the maid's son.
Shut up or you won't like what I do to you!
Anyway. I told you Asim's so nice... But you hurt him.
Aunt called just now. Told he's been promoted.
To the dickens with him.
After all that's happened?
Well, newsflash! Mr Goody Two-shoes has already given someone else my place in his life!
No way!
If you can't believe it, sweetie, go and ask Aqil. He'll tell you everything.
I'm sure he's mistaken. Asim ain't that sort!
Honestly? I'm delighted.
Good for him.
In fact, go and congratulate him for me, will you?
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV