Look at the timing! We got here at the same time!
Been waiting for me?
Obviously.
You're back after ages.
I've missed you so much.
Same here.
Don't tell me.
You were busy every second.
That's why I wanted you to come with me. You could see how busy I was!
What do you think, Zoha? I didn't want to come with you?
If it were up to me, I'd spend every moment of my life with you.
That's what always draws me to you.
Sometimes, I think... How can you even love me so much?
Because you make me want to live...
You make me feel important, valued...
I feel special.
-You are special.
Very special.
I don't know what kind of moron would not love you.
The shopping -- Was fabulous.
So you went shopping?
No. Just a bonus.
But, blimey, the trip was so productive!
Yeah... By the way, was Zahir with you?
Zahir's vanished into thin air! I'll ask him when he's back.
How's it going with your sister's marriage?
Zoha...
We're meeting after ages...
Can't we just talk about us?
Sure.
Come in.
Bring the table here.
-Yes, ma'am.
Let's have lunch here.
Please get us our lunch here, Ghulam Hussain.
-As you wish, ma'am.
I knew you'd pick that. Your favourite.
You know me so well.
Yeah, and so does Ghulam Hussain!
'With BEST WISHES'
'CONGRATULATIONS SIR.
~FROM SANA.'
What is this, Sana?
A small gift, sir. On your promotion.
But why?
As a colleague, sir...?
Blimey, Sana... You're giving me gifts now... Coming to my place... Getting close to Mum... 'As a colleague'? Seriously? Just -- Why?
I'm sorry, sir.
Aww... C'mon... No need to cry.
Please get her some water, Asif.
Know what...
Last time you were here, I wanted to stop you.
You should've stopped me.
But how? You were so intoxicated with love!
My biggest mistake!
What? He deserted you?
No. I deserted him!
Oh... That's really sad.
Wicked!
He didn't deserve my love.
Really?
I always thought he's lucky.
Mind if I ask something?
Do you love anyone else?
I mean -- Would you allow anyone else...?
What do you mean?
I mean...
If, somehow, we had an understanding... That... Perhaps, somewhere down the line... Gave way to love?
What was that?
-I know it sounds awkward, but...
I don't think I could've said it any other time...
Not funny!
Not kidding. I'm serious - I really like you.
I mean -- Look at you and look at me, Mr Atif...
Take my hand. Bridge the gap.
There's nothing I can't get you. You can live out all your dreams.
Think again.
Let's get back to the shoot.
The shoot, yeah...
I don't think we're gonna need it.
Why?
It seems so selfish...
You don't care one bit about me... Even after everything I've done for you...
It's all about give and take, you know...
If you ask me, there's a simple formula to fulfil every dream...
Feel free to come back when you've understood it.
Think about it, will ya?
Malika!
Get in, I'll drop you home.
No thanks. I can walk.
-Hey!
Why do you want to walk in this scorching heat? Get in.
Feelin' the heat already?
Oh yeah... With that AC in your car, I mean, like...
Thanks to you! I got this car because you always said that clunker didn't suit you.
Well, in case you didn't realise, even this won't suit me.
Just give me some time.
If you're by my side, Malika, I'm sure this is only the beginning.
In your dreams!
Beat it, amigo!
Not a smile, not a greeting! Making progress, I see!
I didn't see you.
Aye, right, how'd you even know who's around in this château?
Blimey, Mum, you're at it before I've even stepped in!
Go and freshen up. I'll get you lunch.
-I'm not hungry.
What is it this time?
-Jeez, Mum, I just don't want to have lunch.
Had a row?
Who'd I have a row with? Just ran into that blimmin' Asim on the way. He said he'd drop me home.
What'd you say?
-Why'd I get in with him?
You should've told him he's got no right to drop you home when he's dropped out of your life.
Seriously, what is he? He's so pig-headed!
He wouldn't have asked you to get in if he had any shame.
Anyway, freshen up. I'll get you some lunch.
You're late.
-Yeah. Just a tad busy today...
Get ready quick.
Remember it's Mrs Qadir's anniversary today?
We're going over.
I totally forgot!
No problem. Get ready. I'll call and tell her we'll be late.
No way, I'm really tired. How say you go alone?
Alone?
So what?
You used to go alone before your marriage, right?
I didn't get married to go alone.
Blimey, Zoha, what's up with you?
You didn't even come for Zahir's birthday last week.
Jeez, Zoha, we're not teens.
We can't go out on these honeymoon trips every other day.
You've got your own life, I've got mine. Just live and let live.
I don't get it, Atif.
What's wrong if I want to go somewhere with my husband?
-I don't want to. I'm really tired.
But Atif --
Hi, Atif. I just wanted to thank you for the lovely dinner. What a lovely evening!
What happened? Who was it?
Oh, Shazia...
Who you've been with all day...
Jeez, mate... She's just a good friend!
Seriously?
Seriously.
You want me to believe that?
Jesus, it was a business meeting! That's all!
My eyes grow lonely
Yearning to see you
Come here, my dear
Yea, just you...
Why'd you turn off the lights if you're still up?
Just felt like it...
Get yourself out of this darkness, Noriyan.
She doesn't even care about you, but you don't even want to forget her!
What are you looking at?
You know Malika better than me.
I could never really know her...
Well, what've you done now that you do?
You should've thrown her out of your heart like a piece of trash!
-Mum...
Please don't say that...
Really?
Do you really want me to say something good about her?
She was never yours! Why can't you understand?
I don't have the courage...
You had the courage to love someone who never wanted to be yours.
So be it...
Just meet her once, then.
Gather some courage.
You may grow to hate her so much you may even laugh to remember your love.
The way you laugh at my love?
Not your love.
I laugh at how mistaken you were that she deserved you.
Thank you for taking the time to come here.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't take your calls...
I was very busy.
Aren't you a little too busy these days? Like, c'mon, mate, we're family.
We are? Looking at you, it doesn't seem like that!
Okay, Zahir, seriously. What's wrong? Why are you so distant?
As if you care.
You think I'm your enemy.
I've heard that Aqil complain to you about me!
I haven't even told him anything I say to your face. You're just angry for no reason.
Ah, yes, I'm wrong.
I stood by you when your husband left you.
I supported you because I didn't want anyone to take advantage of you. Because you're so nice.
We're not just cousins, Zahir, we're best friends. I know you worry for me.
But I know what's good for me.
Aqil makes me really happy.
My wish is his command.
That's what you used to say about Atif, remember?
But look what happened. He left you alone.
Back then, I felt pity for you.
And it hurts me when I see you with Aqil now.
Because you're making the same mistake all over again.
If you've stood by me because you pitied me, you better leave.
I don't need your sympathies.
You always get me wrong.
You just can't understand, Zoha.
That Aqil's just making you emotionally vulnerable!
-So what? I'm already emotionally invested in him! Why don't you understand that?
Fair enough.
Have a jolly good time with Aqil. But don't come crying when he's deserted you.
Sana's on leave again?
Yes, sir...
But she's never taken a day off before.
You know what happened.
What?
-What you said to her...
Had a go at her, so to speak...
She says she's leaving the job.
Leaving the job?
Because of that? Seriously?
No one's ever told her off. You're the last person she thought who'd... She's just a bit hurt, that's all...
Well, Miss Farah, please tell her this silliness is most unprofessional. I wanted to clear things up, that's all. Please, call her right away.
Alright...
Hello?
Asim's asking about you.
He told me to tell you
That what you're doing is plain silly and unprofessional.
He's right.
You better be here tomorrow then.
But I've applied somewhere...
-Are you nuts? You won't get a job just like that!
I can't face him now...
Why? It was just a gift on his promotion. Big deal!
-Does he get why I gave him the gift?
Good that he figured it out. Because I don't think you would've told him, like, ever!
What good is it anyway?
I can't even say he's got a place in his heart for me to indulge myself...
Did Sana come to work today?
No. Why?
Tell me. Everything alright with her?
How'd I know?
Wow... Anyway, I'll give you her number. Call and ask her.
Why should I call her? She must have her reasons...
I called her twice, but she didn't take my call.
Why did you call her?
-Just felt like I should.
Please try to get it, Mum... She's just my colleague. Don't get so close to her that she starts thinking anything else.
She's unlike most of the girls these days.
Loving, caring, kind...
Can't you understand, Noriyan? I don't want anything to do with you.
Just listen to me once, Malika...
I don't want to hear anything.
Just -- Just meet me once, Malika -- I won't see you ever again.
Are you out of your senses? Who do you think you are? Why should I meet you?
No -- Malika... I want you to see that everything's the same as it used to be. I still love you... I can't imagine my life without you!
Malika... Just give me one chance... One chance to explain myself.
I think I'm gonna have to block your number, because you ain't gonna get it any other way.
If you did that, I'll come over and talk about everything before everyone!
My brother's gonna break your bones!
You've broken my heart... I don't care about a few broken bones...
You're getting yourself in big trouble!
I knew I was in big trouble the moment I realised that one lie drew a wedge between us!
If you know you were lying, why do you expect Malika to love you now?
I'll be waiting for you at the university at 9 in the morning. Bye.
Let me know if you need anything, Granny.
What'd I need at this age?
And who'd I ask but you if I needed anything?
I'd be glad to be of help.
Okay...
Is Sana coming to work tomorrow?
No idea.
What do you mean?
Blimey, you've started asking questions like Mum.
I really like her. She's so nice. Didn't you ask her why she didn't come?
I'll ask her when she's back.
She isn't coming to work. You ought to call and ask her.
I was busy. Didn't get the time to ask her.
Okay, call her. I'll talk.
-Blimey, Granny...
Just call her. What if she needed help?
I'm sure she doesn't. She's fine. Just -- Making an issue of something trivial...
Something you've said, I'm sure?
Let her be upset if that's what she wants.
C'mon, call her. I want to talk to her.
Blimey... I shouldn't be calling her at this hour!
I want to talk to her.
Just... Blimey...
Good evening, Sana.
How are you?
Yeah, Mum and Granny were worried about you.
Yes.
If it was something I said, I'm sorry. I didn't mean it that way.
I just told you what I thought.
Granny wants to talk to you.
Hello. How are you, Sana? Alright there?
I just pulled Asim up about it.
Feel free to talk to me or Salma if there's any problem.
Okay, take care.
Bye.
I don't want to hear anything of the sort again, okay?
What are you looking at?
My, you've started caring for Sana a lot! Just like Mum!
You should care about her too. She's proper nice.
You don't know how you should talk to girls.
Seriously? Me?
I'm talking about Novera. You didn't have to start with your banter in front of her.
What'd I say to her?
I'm not really into this dating thing. Why'd you say you thought I was on a date?
Jeez, mate, I was just kidding... What happened to your sense of humour?
And when did I talk to you about her?
That's not fair.
You're overreacting.
Okay, have you never talked to Novera about me?
I swear I haven't.
Jesus...
You're one tough nut.
You've changed since she got here.
Easy there. I'm at the office until the evening.
And where are you after that?
I request you...
Please control yourself before her, okay?
Fair enough...
So possessive! My, my...
Anyway... Not your fault.
She always looks... Different... At first sight. The most unique.
In time, you realise they're all the same.
Why am I even talking to you? I think I'm wasting my time.
Oh, really! You're wasting your time with me!
Well, then, I guess I should get going. The last thing I'd want is to waste your time.
-Be done with it already, mate.
What'd you like to have?
I'm so worried about you!
What'd happen to you after your marriage!
Don't worry, Monsieur. Please worry about yourself and Mme. Zoha, who, by the way, is gonna pummel you proper, I tell you.
Were it so easy!
Anyway... I really gotta go now.
Where to?
Your Mme. Zoha's back.
Whoa, she is?
Back on duty, eh?
Trust me, she's a real psycho.
You're in for a proper thwacking now!
On that note, cheers!
Have some.
-Not now. I'll get going.
Hello, Aunt.
Hello...
Going somewhere, Waqas?
No, Mum.
I thought you were getting him married pronto, Aunt.
But he says you've only fixed an engagement...
We're doing what's best for us.
Novera's a real gem. Seriously.
Miss her and you ain't gonna get second chances!
Anyway, take care. I'll get going.
Okay, Aunt, bye!
Waqas.
Yeah?
Come here. Sit.
Yes, Mum?
He met Novera?
Ah, yes, yesterday...
Why'd you introduce him to her?
I didn't introduce him. He just bumped into us.
You know I don't like him one bit, Waqas.
I'm tolerating him only because he's your friend.
Please work on your priorities, and keep him out the door.
You don't like him because he's middle class, right?
No.
I would've been okay with him if he knew his place.
Wasn't that your jacket he was wearing?
He liked it, so I gave it to him.
Anyway... He better stop coming here every other day. And don't discuss Novera with him.
Okay, Mum.
I'm not making you tea.
Why?
Because you'd just have your cup and leave.
I'm with you all day. What else do you want?
I don't know why, but I get worried you may not come back...
Jee --
You love me so much. It's only natural.
I can't help it...
I think that was my problem with Atif...
I gave him so much, and whoever loves more gets exploited.
I guess that's why I'm so insecure...
I'm sorry if you feel suffocated...
What happened?
What?
Enough! You better not say his name again.
I'm sorry. I was just explaining myself.
You know I have no interest in your past, and I don't like it when you discuss your ex.
He was my past. You're my present.
I come here to forget all my worries.
I'd rather leave than hear any of that.
Please don't do that.
I don't know what I'd do without you.
Okay... Just relax.
I'm just a bit tensed these days...
That's why I had a go at you.
There, now... Why are you so tensed? Tell me.
Zoha...
It's my sister...
Her engagement's almost broken...
Because...
I can't arrange for her wedding!
I can help.
All that's mine is yours, too. You know that.
I can arrange for your sister's wedding.
Don't worry.
Why do you want to test me?
-I'm not.
I want to get you out of this worry.
-No.
I don't want anything from you.
-Cheque or cash?
Just a sec.
Here's 200,000. I'll arrange for more by tomorrow.
I told you I --
-It's not for you. It's for your sister. It's her wedding.
Aqil... Please...
Take it...
Okay.
Asim... I wanted to talk about something...
Yeah?
Please forget everything Sana said.
I don't get it.
I just mean -- You think she's not the right type -- Always looking for excuses to get your attention...
Miss Farah...
Please don't talk to me about it again. I don't like it.
Why do you always think about yourself?
What do you mean?
Her family's going through hard times. That's why she works here.
So?
She's going to leave the job. Please, try to understand!
What?
Yes, sir!
Strange...
Why's it such a big deal?
Hello?
Zo -- Zoha... It's Aqil...
What happened? Why are you so worried?
I -- Just a few steps from your place -- I -- Some robbers -- Took my bike, the cash at gunpoint -- Everything!
Are you alright?
Ye -- Yeah... I'm fine, but -- They took everything!
Alright, tell me where you are. I'm coming to get you.
I'll send you my location.
Okay. Just wait for me.
Bye.
You called me here?
Yeah. I don't see you around these days. What's up, mate?
Don't tell me you're still grieving over her!
It's nothing like that.
Just felt a bit down...
I'm sure I'll be fine after talking to you, Atif.
How will you move on if you keep thinking about her?
You know about the girls these days... In and out of your life when they want. I'm sure you'll find many others. Don't worry.
And yeah, get some air.
Also... Movie night with me tonight?
Sure.
See you, then.
Here.
Thank God you're safe.
I tried to fight back, Zoha, but --
-Are you crazy? You should've given them what they wanted quietly.
You have no idea what could've happened.
It's already happened.
I've lost everything.
I'm happy you're safe... What if something happened to you?
Anything could've happened.
And guess what, no one came to help me!
Nobody risks his life for anyone.
But Zoha...
The bike you gave -- The cash -- I lost all of it...
So what?
You'll get it all back, Aqil.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV