Why are you so nervous?
Why'd I be?
You're my Aunt's only son, Asim.
My Mum loves you so much too.
Yeah, she does...
We're also related in another way. I hope you remember that.
You're my brother-in-law to-be.
Yeah. You don't need to remind me.
I saw you with someone, Asim.
You were with her in a restaurant.
Blimey, she's my colleague.
She was throwing a party.
That better be it.
Of course, Aqil.
That's what I thought.
I knew that you couldn't do anything of the sort.
Don't think I was doubting you.
No way...
Alright, I've got to go. I'll get going.
Where are you off to? Have some tea first.
Alright, found a job?
I'm trying, mate...
How's it going?
What are you doing?
Working on an assignment.
Your Uncle called.
How's he? What did he say?
You ask as if you care for him a lot!
He's angry with you!
He said, 'Noriyan doesn't even bother to call and ask his Uncle how he's doing'.
Aye, he's right there...
I'll call him today.
He's insisting that I go to the village for a few days.
Everyone's missing me so much...
You miss them, too.
I think you should go.
How can I?
Please, Mum... You promised to Atif's parents that you'd take care of him...
But not that you won't leave Atif even for a few days.
I could've gone easily if he'd tied the knot.
He doesn't need to...
He's always indulging himself and -- just -- having a jolly good time.
When a man without a household is freed from all worries, he starts enjoying his own undoing.
Sure, but why are you telling me?
I'd get married the day you tell me to.
Make a place for yourself first.
Atif said he'd get me a good job once I've graduated.
Why'd you study so much if Atif's going to get you a job?
Just degrees don't help you land the job, Mum.
Atif's got so many contacts...
It'll save me the trouble if he helped me get a job...
I told your Uncle that you're coming too.
Me?
Because why not? He'd be chuffed.
Here's a deal.
I'll borrow Atif's car and take you there, okay?
No need for any of that! There's no shortage of buses that go that way!
I'll get on a bus whenever I want to go. And you'll be coming with me.
Get it?
'Borrow his car'!
What'd Aqil want to talk about?
Nothing, really, Mum.
Don't worry.
It wasn't nothing, Asim.
He had his suspicions...
Suspicions?
What kind of suspicions?
One of my colleagues... She took me to a restaurant for lunch...
Aqil saw us there.
Can't believe a lech who mooches about all day has got the guts to suspect you!
Never mind, Mum...
What do you mean? I'll talk to Zahida. Wasn't he ashamed to even think of it?
For God's sake, Mum, please don't talk to her.
She'd feel just as bad as you right now.
So you actually didn't mind it?
No?
I felt great.
He doubted me because he cares for Malika.
Because I'm her future.
Doesn't Aunt always say Aqil doesn't care about his family?
Have some salad.
Hello?
What's up?
The same as you.
I'm missing you.
I'm missing you, too.
Aqil...
Please forgive me. For the last time?
It's okay.
I can be so sensitive at times...
I thought about it...
All you said...
Was out of love...
Not to hurt me...
I swear, I can't even think of hurting you.
Zoha...
Do you know how far I've come?
So much that I seem to have forgotten the difference in our status.
I forgot that your type
Can buy my love for a few pennies.
Please stop it...
How much more will you embarrass me in my eyes?
You have no idea how much I've suffered.
The one I loved...
Considered my dignity so insignificant...
I'm really sorry...
Really...
Okay.
I'll be coming tomorrow.
And we'll spend the whole day together.
I'll be waiting.
Bye.
Honestly, Mum, isn't his bike just awesome?
He gave me a ride yesterday.
Riding freebies, eh?
But nobody seems to bat an eyelid.
Imagine the stooshie if I'd brought something one of my friends had given me!
But who'll scold sweet little Aqil?
I've never supported anything Aqil does. But the two of you do as you please.
I know who's sent that bike. One of his friends he's up chatting with late into the night!
See that? She knows everything!
But she won't say a word!
That's the difference between a son and a daughter!
I can give Aqil an earful if I want, but I don't want to create a scene here!
Munni!
Get me my breakfast.
Okay.
Aqil! You parked your bike in front of Shakil's home.
His Mum said they're having trouble going in and out!
Can't you be careful?
-They're just envious...
They couldn't even dream of such a bike.
The neighbours and the family.
Not everyone's got friends with benefits...
Shut your gob already...
Go and help Munni in the kitchen.
Good morning.
You weren't here when we got back. I heard you had a meeting with Mr Farooq?
There were some issues in the purchases department, so I was with him...
You shouldn't have done it...
But why?
And what?
Oh --
I had to go because of the call...
I'm not talking about that.
Lunch was on me...
It didn't seem right that you should pay.
You could've refused...
I did, but you insisted so much.
Why do you switch your phone off at home? I want to talk to you so much!
We get enough time here. If someone caught me talking to you, you can kiss your chance here goodbye too, sweetie.
Jeez, your family's so conservative.
So many restrictions... Just... Jeez...
They haven't a clue about their daughter's dreams.
You don't know how hard it was to convince them to let me go to college.
I want to get you out of this jail quick.
If you're helpless too, I don't think I'll have my chance.
Alright, I'll bring Mum to your place right after the finals.
I can find a job later.
Blimey, why are you so much into getting a job?
What about your business?
Touché.
Your ride today?
My bike. Why?
Just askin'.
I can bring my car tomorrow if we're going somewhere.
I want to go somewhere very far away with you.
Free from all worries...
You don't even let me drop you home. That's why I've stopped bringing my car.
You know my situation, Noriyan...
How say I bring my car tomorrow? We'll go somewhere. I'll even drop you home.
How say you take me home?
Sure.
But there's one condition.
I'll tell Mum, 'Meet your daughter-in-law'! She's staying here. Don't let her go anywhere.
You'll get thrown out with me if you said that!
I sometimes wonder what Aunt would be like to meet me...
What if she didn't like her daughter-in-law to-be is so easy-going?
Then again, I'm sure it's no big deal among those of your class.
'Class', 'class', 'class', 'class', 'class'... Jeez, mate, stop it...
How many times do you have to say it?
Just... Put it aside, will you?
Okay, sorry...
So... Where are we going tomorrow?
Chinese restaurant.
My favourite.
Waiting for tomorrow...
Hold on...
I'd briefed you on everything the client said. You know what kind of a face we want for the brand ambassador.
Do you think any of them could be our brand ambassador? Not one, innit?
Everyone's into acting these days.
After all these years with me, I hope you have a good idea of how we select.
But you've wasted your time doing all of this...
Please, wrap it up.
Okay sir...
No idea why you just don't seem to understand...
I thought Malika would be back by now.
She'd be on her way. Munni's inside, studying. She's joined this computer institute.
-Really? Wow...
I'll ask her to get tea.
-Please, Aunt, let her study.
Besides, I'm not in any mood for tea.
Asim told me Munni's a good student.
She works hard.
May the Lord reward her with success.
I'm sure she'll ace her exams with straight-A*s.
I'll get her into university.
Indeed.
Did Aqil try for a job?
You know him. He won't settle for any job.
But that's plain silly! He's your only son. It's his responsibility.
Not everyone's like your son...
All thanks to your prayers. He's your son, too.
Of course...
-By the way, when did Aqil buy that bike?
He -- no -- It's his friend's.
Where's Aqil though?
He went into his room after breakfast.
He just woke up!
I'll go meet him.
-Tell him his Aunt's here. I'll be coming in if he doesn't show up!
Sure.
He can be such a bother...
Seriously though, Zahida, if he's friends so well off, why can't he ask for their help in getting a job?
He feels ashamed to talk about it.
Zoha...
I thought we'd visit Lahore this weekend.
There's a lot going on that I have to resolve personally.
I think that's a great idea. I want to see Mr Ahmed too.
What do you say? Should I book tickets for Saturday?
Just give me a day.
Let me settle some things here.
I'll tell you tomorrow.
By the way,
You've been busy talking to Hassan yesterday.
If you're serious, just get things going!
Are you crazy?
Can't you find anyone better than that loser?
You don't know, he's so negative!
Oh?
So you've been talking to that loser who's always negative all night?
I was just being a good host!
Ah, yes, I can see that...
By the way, did he tell you why he left his second wife?
He didn't.
She ran off!
With one of her servants!
What?
Oh my God...
Hats off to her though. She put up with that madman for so long...
Who knows what might've pushed her...
Nothing pushed her.
She ran off because she wanted to.
And this loser tells everyone, 'So what? We just didn't get along'!
And you want to make your cousin his third wife?
Crazy...
He's quite the character, I tell you.
-Yeah...
Going somewhere?
Yeah.
Where are you all day? Not a clue here...
Asim...
You're too upright...
You won't get it.
Aqil...
Aunt worries for you.
I know.
I can't solve her worries.
If I got a good job, it's not like I'd let it go!
Until then... Isn't some job better than no job?
So... What do you want?
Wanna see me as a salesman? A watchman? Maybe at a service-station?
Why are you so negative?
Because they're just mocking or lecturing all the time.
Aqil...
I'm like your brother.
I know, Asim...
I'm not talking about you.
But everyone else... They just say one thing every time.
'When are you getting a job'?
Aqil, they care for you.
They know what your Dad used to do. What your Mum does. They know she works so hard.
They just try to open your eyes.
'Care'!
That ain't no care.
Jeering is more like it.
Folks just need excuses...
Anyway... How say... I check where I work?
Why not? I'll take it if it's good.
Alright. I'll get going.
I'm sorry, Zoha...
You were so disturbed because of me...
You punished me for too long...
I guess it was my fault...
No. You never punish those you love.
Our bond is so unique...
Can't live together, can't live apart...
What do you mean?
Why not together?
Don't you trust me?
Tell me...
You felt bad I came to the gym.
Yeah...
Know why?
Because they were all looking at me?
Not just looking.
I was worried their gaze may curse us... Our love...
I didn't expect that from you...
Zoha...
There's a lot going in my life...
A lot of worries...
I guess that's why...
I'm too harsh on you...
Please... Don't mind it...
I'm always with you, Aqil.
Never think you're alone.
Thank you.
I have no shortage of girls, Zoha. Really.
Thousands would die to be friends with me.
But...
I never think of them.
Know why?
Because...
I've got my one.
Who stands by me. Always.
I'm always with you, Aqil.
Enough already, Zahida. I want to take my jewel home.
No, Salma... I can't send her just yet. I haven't got anything.
What are you saying? It's not like Malika will ever be leaving home.
She'll just be leaving yours for mine. Don't worry.
It doesn't seem right to send her empty-handed...
You've worked hard to educated your kids.
I don't think there can be a better gift.
I might've been less worried if Aqil had done his part...
I'm telling you, Zahida, I don't want anything in dowry.
Asim's salary and my savings should be enough to get some new furniture for them.
But...
-But nothing.
I just want to take Malika with me.
Okay, but let her finish her education...
It's not like I'm stopping her.
Hello, Aunt.
Hey there, how are you?
Long time no see.
I'm coming.
I'll be back...
What's the meaning of all of this, Malika?
Why'd you dart in like that?
Looking at her, I know what she's up to!
'Up to'?
She was talking about your marriage.
Plotting against me, so to speak!
Mind your tongue.
Go and tell her to forget about it.
Do you want to drive a wedge between me and my only sister?
Don't your children matter to you?
No.
That's how I feel sometimes.
You better go and tell Aunt --
Tell me what? Was it something I said?
No, Aunt...
Go and help Munni in the kitchen.
What's up, Zahida?
Just tell me. As my sister, not Malika's Mum.
Malika doesn't want to get married just yet.
Don't worry though.
Just give her some time...
Don't worry, everything's gonna be alright.
Malika...
I'll ask Asim to get some bread. Meanwhile, you can fry these kebabs.
Still hanging about?
I thought I'd pay a visit when you didn't come...
But I got back from the university early.
I'm not talking about university. I'm talking about home.
Mind if I say something?
Not at all.
Such a shoddy attempt at romance!
Why must you insult me every single moment?
Blimey, I was just being honest.
If you find it insulting, I can try lying.
What a bike ride!
You seemed more afraid than me!
No, I wasn't...
Yeah, I was a bit afraid for you... You were on a bike with me for the first time.
What if something happened?
I wasn't afraid at all.
I knew you wouldn't let anything happen to me.
Aye.
I'll always care for you like that.
More than that.
That's what I want... To be with you forever.
Don't worry.
We'll be together forever.
By the way, the food's delicious.
Specially for you. All organic, made by me.
Because I know how much you care about your health.
Zoha...
You care for me so much.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything.
Just a second.
I won't settle for just a thanks. You have to promise me...
Yes?
Promise me you'll never be angry with me.
But that depends on your behaviour.
What've I done that you're so angry about?
-I'm just kidding, mate...
You better be.
There's one last gift I've got for you... My favourite...
I hope you like it.
Open it!
But Zoha... This is very expensive...
Not more valuable than you...
Yeah, but still --
-No. Please. Put it on.
How does it look?
This is so beautiful.
Suits you.
Thank you.
You're most welcome.
Cheers.
-Cheers.
Forget it, Mum...
Aunt says she'll talk to Malika.
Malika's hurt me so much.
Such pride!
She'll come crashing down, Asim!
She's just naïve.
No. She doesn't care for anyone in the world. She didn't talk to me for a minute, and told Zahida she doesn't want to get married just yet!
I told you, too.
I think she doesn't intend to get married, like, ever.
It's not that, Mum...
She just wants to finish her education.
Splendid... I wonder what kind of education it is that's making her lose all respect for elders!
Please, Mum, just leave it... Let it go...
If they don't want her married to you, they better come out openly. There's no shortage of matches for you.
But Mum, why'd Malika --
-You can get to buying your car. I'll get my money back in a couple of days.
I thought I'd save it for your marriage, but I don't think it's on the cards anymore.
Good evening, Atif.
Good evening. Come, it's dinner time!
I'll have it later.
Just sit down. Get a plate for him.
What's up?
Nothing special. How about you?
Just fantastic...
-Noriyan...
I asked him to sit.
Come and have dinner with us.
Thanks, I'll pass.
How's your semester going?
Great, Atif.
Could you do me a favour...?
Yes?
I'd need your car tomorrow. The small one.
Where are you going?
-Not too far. Just near the highway. With some friends.
I'll be back before the evening.
I have no issues. It's parked at home all day anyway.
You can take it everyday!
You're the best, Atif!
I know!
Busted.
Here. Try this.
Trust me, Mum, Atif told me to sit down!
And you did.
You know I can't turn him down.
Lying again!
I know you won't let go of a chance to sit with him, have dinner with him... Behave like his equal!
It's nothing like that, Mum!
However did you think I want to behave like his equal?
Didn't I tell you not to ask Atif for the car?
Isn't it enough that he's given you a bike?
Mum...
I need a car tomorrow.
Why?
I'm...
Taking your daughter-in-law to-be...
On a long drive.
I'm kidding!
I'm going out with friends.
You can ask Asif and Farhan if you like!
May I?
Malika...
What are you doing?
Isn't this...
What Asim's given you?
Why are you taking them out?
Put a sock in it already, you blimmin' Old Bill!
And yes, it's his. I'm throwing everything out.
But you've had these for years and -- they're from Asim!
Munni, I don't give two hoots about your sweet Asim's gifts.
I have no interest in any of these or him.
I'm stashing them away in the loft.
Mum!
Go and put my pot on!
Poison Mum's ears!
Did Asim say sorry, Sana?
What for?
You're angry with him!
No, I'm not?
Oh, you aren't? Lunch was on you, he paid the bill and all, remember?
I talked to him about it.
-And he didn't get a clue you're angry with him.
Blimey, Farah, I told you I'm not angry with him.
Good. You should only be angry with someone who'll make it up to you.
That man's got no feelings!
That's what I like about him...
He isn't bold like most men.
C'mon, Sana... A man should have the guts to realise he's liked!
But he's got a heart of stone!
Hem hem!
What happened?
Nothing?
Don't you know Sana's cross with you?
No! Not at all. You know she says just about anything! Give me the file over there. Quickly!
Malika...
Have some breakfast.
You skipped it yesterday too!
You don't leave food like that. It's so disrespectful.
Blimey, Mum... Sweetening up to me first thing in the morning, eh?
I'm your mother. Not your enemy.
I only want the best for you.
I want you to be happy.
That's why I'd gotten you engaged to Asim.
I know everyone's got dreams... Wishes...
But, believe me,
My experience tells me
You'll be happy with Asim.
You'll get to live out all your dreams, fulfil all your wishes.
Believe me.
Experience, Mum, can be sooo misleading at times.
That's what I think in Asim's case.
I've seen enough.
Anyway. I'll get going.
I'll be late today. I've got extra classes.
Okay. Finish your breakfast. Don't leave it.
Malika...
Time flies when I'm with you! Really!
Time flies at its own pace, sir.
But I want time to stop.
Right here. Right now.
You're going to introduce me to Aunt, right?
Mum?
Yeah. We're going to your place, right?
I talked to Mum... She said she'd come to your place to meet you.
She said she'd rather not that you come to our place to meet her.
You told Mum about me?
Everything!
I even told her I'm going on a romantic date with her daughter-in-law to-be.
What?
What'd she think?
That university's just her daughter-in-law to-be's excuse to date her son?
Malika...
We're all rebels in love.
So, when should I bring Mum to your place?
Not now, Noriyan.
Let me convince Mum first.
Here's a tip. Just let Mum and me come.
We'll convince your family.
Don't even think about it, Noriyan.
My Mum's not like your Mum!
It'll be quite the job to convince her.
Just try, Malika!
Yeah, but I'm afraid...
She may just get me out of university!
C'mon, Malika. It can't be that bad. Just take one step.
The two of you will bring shame on me one day!
Mum...
You're never happy, are you, Mum?
It's such a nice bike. You should be blessing me, praying that I climb higher, but you... Jeez... Lecturing and lecturing and lecturing!
'Climb higher'?
What do you mean?
New friends, new troubles?
It's Aunt, Mum.
Hello?
Yes...
What are you looking at? Go.
A Zoha was calling you.
How many times have I told you not to check my phone?
But you!
Just let it ring!
Get going!
Why did Noriyan lie to me if he knew her so well?
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV