Grandpa! Please! Open the door! Please give me a chance to explain...
I never cared one bit about the ways of this village for you...
I sent you to London to study when no one sent their daughters even to Karachi!
My heart says you haven't done anything... But my eyes and ears testify against you... It feels like someone torched everything I've built before my eyes... Disgraced me...
Please, Grandpa... Open the door! Grandpa!
Grandpa! I haven't done anything, I --
Grandpa!
I --
Grandpa...
By your love... I don't even know who he was!
I just heard some noise... And saw him with Roshni wh --
Enough of your lies!
Enough of your big, bad, white lies!
I can tell you, Dad... We didn't tell you the story so it doesn't trouble you... Let me tell you what I saw her doing!
Aunt!
Easy there, girl... Let me do the talking.
I heard the flowerpot fall. I walked slowly...
I heard laughter as I approached...
I leaned from behind the wall...
And saw them holding hands...
He freed one hand, swept the hair on her head aside, and leaned closer...
Grandpa!
G -- Grandpa!
Are you alright?
What happened?
Grandpa... Please!
Hang in there, I'll get the doctor!
Dad?
I haven't told you my story to let my tears give you company when you're out...
Wipe your tears...
Eyes on your destination...
Take it slow...
The devil wins when you get too hasty...
Asher Khan and the devil are inseparable bedfellows...
Take it slow...
And I'm sure you'll win...
Yeah, you will...
I'll free you.
I don't want to be free.
Not now...
I'll be happy to hear your love story didn't end so...
Tragically...
'It is time'...
My breaths tell me everyday...
Any breath could be my last...
Any moment...
My time...
But you...
Time is on your side...
Be patient... And don't make haste...
Don't... Make haste...
You'll prevail...
His blood pressure dropped...
It could've been dangerous...
If I got late...
He's safe now.
Get these pills. Make sure he takes them on time.
He's fine, isn't he, doctor?
-Of course. Except circulation, that is...
His heart isn't pumping as hard as it should.
But don't worry. I've given him a pill for it. Don't worry.
I'll take my leave.
Take the doctor to his car, Munna.
Please...
Grandpa...
Something going on here?
Who told you?
No one. You're gonna tell me. What happened?
Nothing.
Munna... Back to your room.
-Ma'am...
Bless you.
His blood pressure dropped? That all?
Yes.
For a moment, I thought the codger got his ticket...
I know just what can put him to sleep... Awaiting orders.
No...
Not just yet...
My husband goes first.
It's nearly this man's time anyway...
Goodbye.
Take care.
Back off!
Get away!
Grandpa...
Get out!
Out!
But -- Grandpa...
-If you value my life, get out of my sights!
Out!
Anything you need?
Saqib was here to see me...
But Mehek's been disgraced...
I'm responsible for what happened to Grandpa.
I should tell him everything...
Or my guilt won't let me sleep...
What were you thinking?
I asked you something!
Nothing...
Itching to tell the truth, eh? Your guilt led you downstairs, didn't it?
How much do you value my life?
What are you saying, Mum?
Mum...
I swear, I'll slit my wrist if your dratted affair tainted my upbringing!
What can I do?
-Well, shut up, for starters!
Guard my honour in exchange for a life with him.
I told you I'll see him.
A life without guilt... Or without him...
It is up to you.
Back to your room!
Anything you need?
No.
Want me to rub your feet? I'm sure the exhaustion's bothering you.
I told you. No.
Okay...
Oh I'd love smothering you!
You've killed every trace of humanity around you!
Well, guess what, your downfall's coming with a wedding procession!
You thinking what I'm thinking?
What?
Like... Look at what this trifle did to your Grandpa...
I mean... I know it ain't really a trifle... A young girl getting caught seeing her lover at her place...
I've heard people die for it... I've seen people kill for it...
But looking at your exploits in London... Getting married, having a son... Your husband running away...
Looking at all of that, this is kid stuff...
Newborn baby stuff, in fact...
Innit?
Give it to me... I'll take it...
Grandpa...
It's time for your medicine...
Here.
I don't need it.
Take it back!
Munna!
Clean up this mess, will you...
Good morning, sir!
'Morning.
How was the journey?
Long... But effortless...
Good news, sir.
Yes?
Shayan's given in.
Okay.
Set him free tomorrow.
I want him just like he was...
The lad's back home after ages... It'd be a shame if it didn't look that way!
As you say, sir.
So it's you!
Yes.
I never thought you'd be here.
Your mind would scare you... You'd think we may do something to you. You'd give in and turn off your phone.
I'd wait a while before going back.
You're right... My mind tried to scare me, and I gave in.
But...
But?
My heart...
My heart didn't.
It doesn't give two hoots about what the mind says... Or what I think... Or what my enemy may do.
It knows that we all gotta die someday.
So, I disappointed everyone but my heart and came here...
What d'you do when you don't blither?
Love and care for your daughter... And long to make her mine...
I meant your job.
I've got a job at this office...
How much do you earn?
-Around 40K.
That's enough for you to get your two square meals, dress up like this... And live comfortably?
And enough for me to be thankful to God.
Blimey... I'm sure you won't stop praying for a moment if you got one million to get out of my daughter's life.
You're wrong.
Or... I can give half a million to any helpless bloke 'round here and get you out of the way.
I'm staying away from sin.
I told you. I don't fear death.
But... I might give it a thought... For 2...
I knew you'd say 2 if I said 1, and 4 if I said 2...
So...
Here's 2 million for you.
Leave this place!
Easy there... Lie down.
Worst thing you can do to your health right now, Mr Malik, is get angry or worried...
I'm writing some pills for you... Don't forget to take them.
But remember they're only gonna work if you're at ease.
I hope you won't need it if you take these pills... But you know I'll be here if you need me.
Please let me know if you need anything.
Okay.
Take care.
Wonder what you're looking for...
Nothing?
Just...
Just... Looking around.
No you ain't. Looking at you, you're looking for something, you are!
And who'd you be?
-Looks like the poor little answer lost its way between the questions...
You don't look like a servant...
But then... Who are you? A guest?
Why don't I look like a servant?
-You'd be quieter if you were.
All these words and questions would've died before they could come out of your mouth.
So... Who are you?
Look for me the next time you're here. I'm sure you'll find me. I'll tell you who I am then. Deal?
Are you alright?
Yeah...
Why are you crying?
I'm fine... Back to your studies... Don't act like Mum.
He got stuck on the way...
He called yesterday to tell me Shayan's coming back.
Wow! I've been waiting to see my bro for ages!
Come here...
I've told you not to call him 'bro'.
Why?
I can't tell you... But your Mum can. Go out and play for a while... I need to talk to her. Here.
-Okay.
You're a cold-blooded snake... Who else are you gonna bite?
There's something you must know...
Yes?
I've decided to get Masooma and Shayan married.
Didn't you think about their age for once?
I'd listen to you if I were asking...
But I'm just telling you my decision.
Prepare for the wedding.
Want something? I'm starving.
Okay, I'll go have something...
Where are you off to?
-I was hungry... Thought I'd have something...
Mum!
Here...
Did you see him?
I went there...
And?
He wasn't there...
What do you mean?
I went where he asked me to come...
Called him like 50 times in half an hour... He answered at last... And said, 'I don't want to see you'.
I asked why.
He said... 'I don't want to', and hung up.
This number is switched off.
-I tried his number many times... But he didn't answer.
I tried his number many times... But he didn't answer.
But why?
I don't think he's the right man...
No way, Mum!
No way... I'll die without him...
I'm doing my best. Always have been, always will be.
But he's running away from us.
Okay... Try calling him...
And don't worry... I'm always here for you.
This number is switched off.
I heard the flowerpot fall. I walked slowly...
I heard laughter as I approached...
I leaned from behind the wall...
And saw them holding hands...
He freed one hand, swept the hair on her head aside, and leaned closer...
If you value my life, get out of my sights! Out!
I don't get it.
Look...
I'm not accusing anyone or holding anyone guilty...
But the walls of this manor which have stood testament to the honour and integrity of our family...
Have been defiled by the filthy footsteps that dared to vault them.
I couldn't sleep last night...
I've decided to get Roshni and Mehek married off as soon as possible.
At the earliest.
Find someone for Roshni.
I know a match for Mehek.
I can get all the phones in the world now...
I've been so relieved today that you're gonna be free...
And now...
I've troubled myself by thinking...
How?
Who'd be here with me after you're gone?
Just these walls, I'm sure... I'll celebrate your freedom with them...
But... These walls will never say a word...
My loneliness will remind me of being here...
But your happiness matters more...
No...
You don't see it, but you're getting out with me.
Don't be silly...
Don't think or do anything that doesn't get you closer to your wife.
I ain't so fortunate...
You'd lose your battle if you chose to help me...
And you're not supposed to lose this...
You're not...
Supposed to lose...
Surely, not this one...
Please, Saqib...
Please talk to me...
Adam!
Adam... My...
My son...
Please save my son...
Please...
Adam...
Here so late?
Everything alright?
Grandp -- Mr Malik wants to see you.
Right now?
-Yes.
Go. I'll be there in a minute.
-He asked me to bring you along.
Right now?
Okay.
This number is switched --
Why d'you want to waste them?
Wipe your tears.
You don't know how invaluable a woman's tears can be.
A few drops have toppled kings and emperors...
You have no idea what a woman's tears can do to the mother who's raised her son...
Hmm...
It takes just one drop to make brothers mortal enemies.
Yet here you are...
Wasting the force that can drive the world for nothing!
What are you saying?
I know he was here to see you.
I can see the fear that he may betray you in your eyes... This restlessness tells me everything...
But let me tell you. Those who put their lives on the line to vault walls never betray.
I'm with you.
I'll help you.
Don't cry.
Good girl.
Roshni!
Listen to me...
I'm here with you.
I won't let you two be the next Romeo and Juliet.
Just... Don't believe anything your Mam tells you, okay?
Go.
Go!
Sweet Iesu! It'll be proper good fun if your daughter ripped through your veil of honour!
What's with the 'if', though, Guddi? Pray that it happens!
You wanted to see me, Mr Malik?
Bless you.
Everything alright? I mean... You called me at this hour...
Do I have any right over you, Adam?
'Any' right?
You have every right over me, Mr Malik.
Your wish is my command.
I don't have the courage to hear you turn me down...
So... Should I ask for it?
I hold you in the highest regard, Mr Malik.
It'd be an insult to my respect to hear you ask me for something.
Well, then... I say...
Marry my Mehek.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe