Not so fast!
Where are you off to?
Home.
-Home.
Just... Wow... So you'd celebrate with wide smiles and a truckload of makeup, but leave your grieving friend all alone when things go south?
Aye, we should see Roshni...
What was that?
It took me a lifetime to earn this honour... And you stained it in a moment!
I've saved it!
My daughter's eloped with someone, bearing the pall of your honour and ours!
I saved it before they could start gossiping how Mr Malik, the guardian of everyone's honour and dignity, couldn't guard his own from his granddaughter!
Mr Malik!
-Grandpa!
On the chair... Quick...
Sit...
I'll get some water.
Grandpa...
Mr Malik...
Please, calm down...
For your health... Grandpa... Please...
Upstairs?
Yeah, she's upstairs. Double time.
Wait.
Where are you going?
-We thought we'd see Roshni...
You want to see her when she's so troubled?
Don't even think about it!
Please calm down, Grandpa...
Please...
Here. Have some water.
Slowly...
In the Lord's name...
Qutb...
Get Adam...
Quickly...
-Right away.
I'll call him.
Are you better now, Grandpa?
How was the show?
I have to admit, lies suit you like the air of Heaven suits the lungs!
If you're telling the truth, it is my duty to help you...
If not...
I stand with you regardless...
Because...
I'd rather believe someone's plea and leave the matter to the Lord than start suspecting him... It sounds so much more reasonable...
It's the police!
Quick! Come with me! To my room! C'mon!
Inside!
Search over there.
It's...
It's okay...
Sit here... I'll be back in a moment... It's safe... I'll go have a look...
Aye, hello?
I'm at the station. Just got here...
Got a lead on one of Saqib's friends.
If they're here, they won't slip past!
We can use him to make him fall right into our trap!
Tell Qutbuddin to get here with his guards right now.
Fear insults love.
My love commands immense respect in my eyes.
Get it?
You're still here?
No, I'm waiting for the chief inspector.
I told you he'll be here in three hours. Go.
I can't go out.
Why?
My life's in danger.
Who could it be?
I said I'll talk to the chief inspector about it!
Have it your way...
Seen her?
No, sir.
Take a good look.
I'm pretty sure, sir. We just sold three tickets today.
And you?
If you find out anything about her, know that I've got 50,000 in my wallet ready to help a poor man in need.
Anyone?
I'd like to take another look, sir.
Here's my card.
Here.
You stay around here?
Yeah, he lives in a room back there.
What are you afraid of so much...
That a lifetime with me can't help you get over?
I'm not afraid for myself.
I buried that with my parents' honour.
I'm afraid they'll kill you...
They'll try to keep me alive to save their honour and they'll fail... I can't live without you...
If nothing else, I'll kill myself...
Embrace the unending punishment than live an unending life...
The fear of something happening to you won't let me be happy just yet...
Everything will be alright.
Sure?
Saqib...
Everything's fine... Don't worry...
Just... Some people looking for you.
The train's late, as usual.
What do we do?
There's --
There's a bus stop by the station.
Go and get a bus... Don't wait around here!
So... Where is he? I know he's been with you for a year! Works with you, too!
B -- By the Lord -- I have no idea... I haven't seen him for a week...
You've got two hours. Do whatever you must and tell me where he is!
Our family's honour - and my claim to office - breath their last...
If anything happens to either...
I'll make sure you stop breathing too!
Keep at it until he spills the beans!
Remember...
How you'd ignored my words of love the first five times?
Not just words... I remember everything I ever thought about you as if it were just yesterday.
The fifth time was when you stepped out of the bus...
I thought you didn't deserve a place in my heart after that...
What changed your mind?
Nothing.
What about the five times that followed?
I thought just that the moment you turned me down... And started on my way home...
Barely took a few steps before I realised... My heart's empty...
There's nothing in it without you...
A few more steps, and I realised that all it ever beat for was you...
I could go to a carnival of lovers and get nothing for it.
No one would want a heart so lifeless, so worthless... So... Empty...
A year and a half?
Yes, sir. And his old friend for 14 years...
Death claimed him before he could...
I always suspected Asher Khan...
Sergeant!
Sir?
Get the car out. We leave at once.
-Sir.
Come.
Hello? Aye?
Shayan's run away, sir!
My helpless body...
Stands before you...
Crushed by calumny...
My pride, my honour, and if you will...
My soul...
Lie dead and abandoned out in the open for them all to see...
She trampled everything under her feet...
Order me, Mr Malik, and I'll do it.
Before the stench spreads far and wide...
Birthing whispers and canards all around this place...
Find Roshni, will you?
Please...
Mr Malik...
I may finally die in peace... I may...
Mr Malik!
Qutbuddin!
Get the car out! Quick!
Grandpa!
Mr Malik?
-Grandpa...
Mr Malik...
Grandpa?
Saqib!
Hey!
Finish the story, will you?
Which one?
You know, just now...
The Ten Expressions of Love?
Not cricket...
You're laughing at my question... And my love...
I'm not laughing at anything...
It's just the delight of having you right by me... Always...
Did you think I'd be deaf to your sinister silence all these years?
I can hear the storm raging, defiant and rebellious as always, even as we speak!
You helped him run away!
No, Mr Khan -- I --
Shut up!
I could walk the road to becomming the mightiest of the Khans because of my brains...
Give me a name and I can give you everything that ever goes on in his head with the utmost precision...
You're my wife...
That was no mistake...
It was your sin!
But I'll deal with you later...
Get out!
Out!
Guards!
Sir?
Surround this area. Let no one in.
Yes, sir.
Let no bus, wagon, rickshaw, taxi, or truck pass without being checked.
Sir.
-Sir.
I want Shayan... No matter the cost...
Thank you so much, Uncle.
-It's nothing...
The bus stops there very briefly... 3 minutes, at the most... Go, now, quickly...
Leave for your destination. The train's too big... They'll be suspicious...
'Thanks' can't do justice to the favour you've done...
Don't say that, m'lad...
A man shouldn't have to live to hear words of gratitude...
Never forget that...
We don't help others... At the end of the day, we're all just helping ourselves...
He alone can help... The Lord... The Almighty...
Ask for His help - His help - if you must... He will listen...
Don't do injustice to His favours by thanking people around... Just... Ask Him... He will help... Come...
He's had three heart attacks...
His condition's serious...
We're trying our best...
Get these medicines as soon as you can.
-Right away.
Hello?
Mehek?
Your Shahmir's throwing up. He's got a burning fever too. I'm coming to the hospital.
God help us...
Hello?
Hello? H -- ?
Yeah, I'm coming to the hospital. Don't drive me up the wall!
Not a bone left in him now...
He said the same before and after we broke each one... 'I don't know'.
I've searched every corner of this city...
Honestly, it just makes me wonder if the air of righteousness around...
Actually, never mind...
I've uncovered many secrets tonight...
As for her, I think she's left the city...
What do I do...
Adam!
Adam... Shahmir's all out of sorts... Guddi's coming here...
But I can't even see my son... Please...
Take care of him, will you?
Got it?
-Here.
Just a minute...
Hello?
Sorry if I've disturbed you, mate...
-Not at all. What is it?
We've found the man you were looking for... Shayan...
He's the nephew of one of the biggies here, Asher Khan.
Okay, text me the rest. I'll get back to you.
-Okay.
Mehek...
I know this is neither the time, nor the place, but...
You got to know this...
Congratulations... We've --
Your Grandpa's losing a battle for his life! Never thought I'd see you two going all lovey-dovey here!
Come!
Shahmir...
Blimey, he's burning for real...
Mehek...
Your Grandpa may well be breathing his last...
The doctors trying to save whatever's left of him! Could you not be so cold-hearted for a change?
Come with me!
M'bo -- Sh --
Come with me, sir.
Stop!
Orders, sir?
Surround the mansion. I want a man there, there, and there... Everyone else, form up on me...
-Come, Inspector.
Step aside. Wait here.
Come.
Where are we going?
I've got an Aunt 'round here. Thanks to her, I never felt like I'd lost me Mum and Dad...
I never felt alone because I always had her.
She's been waiting eagerly for you.
Me?
Yeah. She knows just how much I love you.
I say we get married as soon as we get there.
Today?
Yeah.
I'm impatient to hear you say 'I do' and become mine forever.
I'll be back.
Okay.
The doctor says he's fine now. His fever's not coming back.
Thank God...
May God give you everything you've ever wished for.
How's Grandpa?
Thank God...
The doctor says he's better... He'll come to by the afternoon.
You've been kind, O Lord...
I've been praying for his health all night...
But... Where's Guddi?
Sleeping... She found an empty bed around here.
The doctor says we can take him home.
I've sent Aunt home too... To get some rest...
Take Guddi and Shahmir home...
-Okay.
I will not say 'thank you', for your favours are too great for any amount of gratitude.
I bless you every time I pray... Every single time...
I'll go check on Grandpa.
We've found Shayan.
Congratulations.
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
Hush, now... Everything's fine...
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
You seriously here to arrest him, Inspector? Seems more like you're droppin' by for a nice little cuppa! Do you think he'd come and surrender just like that?
He'd run away, sir!
My men have surrounded the mansion.
Khan's got a reputation here...
Besides, he's only been accused... Got to show some respect... For now...
Grab a pew and don't you dare lecture us.
Where'd you go now?
Home.
And then, to Shayan...
Mind if I ask something?
Not at all.
How do you think he could bring himself to leave you for so long?
May I speak freely?
You don't need to ask.
My eyes have longed to see him and my ears to hear the news that he's been found... I'd been standing in the searing sun, last in a long line...
When Grandpa's grief overtook me and stopped my feet from inching closer to the glimmer of hope...
Find Roshni first...
I've just thought about myself...
It's time I changed things...
Before my fear of losing my own becomes my reality...
Please...
Find Roshni...
As you sa --
Dyw, what a lovely twist in our love story... From romantic to tragic!
She's got tears in her eyes... He's got some too, but of happiness... Seeing his love up close, after all!
I'm laughin' at the clouds so dark above... Get ready to be singin' in the rain!
I'll get going...
Your tyranny ends today!
This man held his old friend captive for 14 years, and me for a year and a half!
Arrest him right now! Right now...
Good morning, sir.
How are you, Mansoor?
-Never been better, Mr Khan.
I must say, sir, the kid's more than a bit hot-headed... He doesn't have the foggiest that we take orders from you...
Oh, the lies he told about you...
His audacity made me tremble...
I felt like giving him a proper pasting until I tired of it...
But... He's family...
I couldn't help but kill my anger...
You deserve a handsome reward.
Thank you, Mr Khan.
You betrayed me!
Always a pleasure.
For what he's done for us, I'd gladly offer him my life.
No, Khawar... Please... Wait! For the love of God... Don't do this...
Tauqir!
Sir?
Get them all a cuppa...
Don't take my kids away... I'll die without them!
Get away!
-Shayan!
Please... Please stop him... He's taking my kids away... Says I'll never get to see them again... Please... Stop him...
Please, Khawar... Don't do this to me... I haven't dared raise my voice... For my kids... What've I done?
Mr Khan's orders.
Khawar!
Divorced her yet?
-You didn't order me to.
Do it.
I, Khawar Maqbool Hussain, do s --
-No!
Please, no... Don't do that to me...
Please... I'll do what you say... Please... Stop him... Uncle... Please save my family...
You don't need to do anything...
Only your brother can save you now.
Tell him to do as I say.
Just do as he says... Save me... My family... My kids... Please...
Where's her cupboard?
-There.
Adam...
Promise me...
Do whatever you must...
To bring Roshni back...
Mum says...
If Roshni didn't come back...
She'd kill herself...
I'm very scared...
'For my Roshni'?
'Lots of love, Saqib'...
That's him?
Yes.
If there's anyone more loyal to Mr Khan than his dogs, that'd be me.
I owe 80% of my body to Mr Khan's favours.
Your sister and her kids are just my duty.
Don't ever think of me as her husband or their father, for I am nothing but Mr Khan's humble servant.
Don't you fear the Lord?
You don't have permission to ask questions.
Do as Mr Khan says, or my tongue only needs one order from him to divorce her.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe