The most priceless of trust is that between husband and wife...
Cursed are those...
Who leave this world, unaware that their wives...
Chose to two-time shamelessly right under their noses...
Why'd you stop at wives?
I've seen a few cheating women...
But countless more cheating men...
Only because...
I'm talking about my wife...
She's a woman...
You're her means...
You're the chance she got...
That her cheating self seized, ripping through her honour.
But I want to thank you with a hug, Doctor... You've been kind.
Most welcome, Mr Malik... You are most welcome...
You know...
What this is?
This toxin will spread through my body in a minute...
And I'll be flailing on the floor as it destroys my body...
But I've got...
Enough time -- To deal -- With you!
Back when... You couldn't even get up --
Remember when you heard a glass break in your room...
And you asked your wife who it was...
And she said it's her...
G -- Guess what?
I -- I heard -- it too that night --
You bloody lech!
-You...
You may've killed me...
But I've killed your honour a thousand times!
You're furious now --
But when you cool down -- Your conscience -- Won't let you sleep!
Your wife's betrayal...
Will always be there to bug you... Gnaw at you...
Your wife...
Your lovely wife...
Has been mine...
All this time...
I've said it a hundred times... I won't tell him anything!
You never cared about relations... But I still respect you.
Promise me.
How's she?
She doesn't need your fake sympathies, you vile two-timer!
It's not fake... I swear!
I've asked the winds, the walls, and my memories how she is all this time!
K -- Kill me if you want... But tell me how she is.
-She's dead.
She's dead.
Waiting to be buried but not quite ready yet.
Because her heart still beats for you.
Her corpse lives to see the day you come back...
Why?
-What could I do?
Why'd you get married if you couldn't fulfil your vows?
-What the devil could I do?
I was leaving after Mum's funeral when...
-Not a word!
Don't make me send you to your lonely Mum!
You're the only man in the family.
I'm sparing your life in exchange for your acceptance!
Jesus... Why've you locked it? Guards!
Break it open!
-Mehek!
The name's Asher Khan. They call me the fortunate one.
Those who take up arms against me aren't so fortunate.
Lock him up!
What?
I said lock him up!
And?
I broke out...
You're coming with us!
Step on the gas!
How could you get married again?
Huh?
In your place, I would've chosen death!
You got a sister?
Yes.
Khawar!
Divorced her yet?
-You didn't order me to.
Do it.
I, Khawar Maqbool Hussain, do s --
-No!
Please, no... Don't do that to me...
Please... I'll do what you say...
You don't need to do anything...
Only your brother can save you now.
Tell him to do as I say.
Just do as he says... Save me... My family... My kids... Please...
What if it were you and your sister instead?
I would've chosen death, Shayan...
Because I can't be so cruel as to marry a 12-year-old! You're a sinner!
No.
I don't believe any of it.
Believe it...
Believe it... Or kill me.
Mehek wants a divorce.
Sign it.
Don't worry.
There are no conditions...
Except one...
You will never see your son.
My son?
Yeah.
Your unfortunate son.
Sign it.
No... No way...
I can't...
What d'you want?
I want --
To be with Mehek... As long as I live...
You ready to leave all of this behind and come with me?
-Yes.
Yes.
Go, then.
Go set the little girl free.
Beg her forgiveness.
Okay...
Go.
And...
How many guards has he got? And where?
Two at the gate... Outside...
And... Two inside... At the back...
Armed... All of them...
Go.
Pack your bags.
Free her.
I'll take care of the guards.
Munna...
D'you know a lion hunts here at night?
What? A lion?
It devoured the kids of two labourers very recently.
Then -- Why've you brought me here?
Munna...
I've got a question...
Satisfy me...
And we go back...
Y -- Yeah? Ask away...
Who's Guddi's fancy man?
-No idea... Really... I don't know...
No idea... Really... I don't know...
Alright... Keep your secrets...
I'll get going. Nope! Just me!
You're spending the night here... With the poor little starving lion... Bye!
Hey! All I know is Guddi looks after Adam a lot! Made him dinner last night... That's all I know...
Shh...
Good boy.
And...
One more thing...
I don't want anything... Just want to go home... Just let me go...
Easy, mate.
Come with me. Don't worry.
What have we here?
Eh?
Why's everyone here?
Tyranny has to end sometime.
I get a feeling it ends tonight.
What?
-You heard me, old man!
Masooma... Come here...
C'mon.
I'm so sorry...
What we've done to you...
Deserves no forgiveness...
But if you forgive me...
Perhaps the Lord may hear your innocent prayers...
What was that guff?
Masooma...
I divorce you.
-Don't you dare!
Masooma... I divorce you... I DIVORCE YOU!
-Tauqir! Tauq --
-Shayan!
Uncle!
Dad!
-Uncle! Are you alright?
-Shayan!
Dad!
-Help!
-Uncle...
Dad!
Go... I'll take care of things here...
-Call someone! Uncle!
-Dad...
Dad...
-Help! Uncle...
Dad... Mum?
Dad!
My son's a young man...
So I showed up without thinking of the time...
I only realised it's late when I got here...
Adam told me everything...
I felt a bit angry when I saw you feeding my son last night...
But when Adam told me everything... I was glad to know someone loves him so much...
Unlike Mehek... She just uses him...
She has her reasons...
-Whatever.
I just thought I'd let you know...
You're never poor, helpless and alone...
For you've got me...
It's the Scrooges who are broke...
I've seen the richest of men serve those who can love gladly.
I'll get going...
Take care.
Allow me.
Good night.
What?
-Divorce papers.
Aye, why'd I need them now?
That's it. You don't.
Who are you?
-Adam.
You risked your life to save me.
You're driving so fast... But not running from them... No, you're eager to get there...
So... Once again...
Who are you?
Who's Mehek to you?
Just a neighbour...
Who feels for her...
A friend, if you will...
Haven't seen people who feel for others gather so much courage...
Feeling their pain gives me courage, Shayan.
Mind if I said something?
Your son's so cute, mate...
I pray that I blink and what I see on your forehead vanish like the illusion it is.
What d'you see?
-Waiting for that vile man.
You're just seeing things.
-No.
By the Lord, I'm not.
My sixth sense has always served me well...
Every time I saw things like that...
The wretches turned out to be true...
Okay, yeah...
I hate him for his betrayal...
Detest him...
I know it was Dad's fault...
And it was my fault that I'm his daughter...
But why'd he make my pure and innocent love suffer like this?
Guddi!
What is it?
Ie?
Ad -- Adam's had an accident! He's in hospital!
What?
Jeez... My phone died...
Adam...
In the car. Quick!
To the hospital. Double time!
G -- Gu -- Guddi...
What's up with your phone?
Adam...
Faster!
We're almost there.
Just about an hour away...
From the purest and most beautiful moment of your life... Holding your son for the first time...
May the Lord will so.
-Amen.
Where are we? That sure ain't the hospital.
Hello?
Who -- What are you doing?
Where are you taking me?
Geroff me!
My apologies...
For squeezing your hand...
And pulling your wrist...
When I brought you here from the car...
I'm sorry I had to trouble you...
Perhaps even hurt you...
But I swear it hurts me much more to think how much you've suffered!
At this speed, they think I'm too eager to end your story...
But...
I swear I'm not...
In my two years on that bed...
I've lost whatever little faith I had on everything...
Who knows...
Today might be the last day I walk on my feet... Or walk this earth...
I don't want my longing for you to bother me in my grave...
Which is why...
The Reverend's coming here after Mass to get us married.
May the Lord bless us...
Tell me...
Yeah?
Just say Adam's fine and you lied...
Of course he is.
I lied.
Thank you, my Lord...
Alright, then, old man...
Princes and peers have turned into puny paupers after I'm through with them...
Failure's eager to see you like family on Christmas.
Guddi can only be Adam's, Malik!
You bloody...
You bloody treacherous...
You bloody treacherous wretch!
My heart never listened to my mind... What d'you think it'd listen to you?
Come.
Here.
Give it to me... Freshen up. Over there.
Shayan...
You're where you belong.
Just a little while before daybreak...
She'll be right before your eyes soon.
I pray...
Where were you, Adam?
I've been up all night waiting for you!
Uhh...
My sister...
Say hello to Shayan.
Hello.
Hey.
Get something for him.
Okay.
(Call to prayer)
God is the greatest...
I bear witness that there is no god but God...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe