I don't have the courage to hear you turn me down...
So... Should I ask for it?
I hold you in the highest regard, Mr Malik.
It'd be an insult to my respect to hear you ask me for something.
Well, then... I say...
Marry my Mehek.
Sir?
I can't tell you how I've gathered the courage to say it...
His name's Shayan. Studied with me at University. Yeah... We got married...
Aren't you happy to hear me say it?
-No...
No... I mean, I didn't mean... Like... 'No'...
It's just... I didn't expect you'd...
My age and my relation to Mehek won't let me talk to your family about your marriage...
But...
I'm sure you can ask them to come here with a proposal.
But... So suddenly...
Is everything alright, Mr Malik?
Of course.
Everything's good...
Just... It isn't the right time...
I need your help...
And you have the right to refuse...
But everything would be fine if you accepted it...
Did you ask Mehek?
She won't have a problem.
Give me a day.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I...
I'll take my leave...
Good night...
I've got word at last...
Shayan's Uncle... Asher Khan... Lives in Rajanpore...
I don't know... But I got a feeling Shayan's somewhere there...
Please do me a favour...
Find him...
A million people live there, Mehek...
It won't be so easy...
It isn't impossible either...
Please...
Please... For me?
Do you have a picture?
Yeah... I do... On my phone...
Here...
Any other?
-Yeah... This one... Look... Here...
Yeah... This one... Look... Here...
Send them to me.
But what'd Mr Malik just tell me?
I'll talk to you later...
-But -- Hey!
Mum!
What are you doing?
You out of your mind?
What happened, Mum?
I told you... Parents' Day at our school. I'm playing the bride in this drama...
Ah, yes...
I forgot...
I thought...
What?
Nothing...
Seeing you like this after all this time...
Felt... Nice...
You look good...
He's here...
Tauqir!
Give him something nice to wear.
Give him something too... He's an old friend...
I'd hate it if he didn't join in the celebration.
Get ready.
Close the door.
Put it on...
Or... You'll catch a cold...
Brr... It kills me...
Starve yourself...
If you think that's gonna make him come back to you, be my guest.
Ever thought how your mother would feel if she saw you like this?
He's not cheating on me...
I'm sure he has his reasons...
That's your pure and innocent heart shutting up your mind and speaking out.
It's shutting your ears!
He called me.
What'd he say?
He refused.
He said...
'We're just friends'!
I begged him... I pleaded with him not to ruin my daughter's life...
But he said he doesn't want to say anything else and hung up.
Mum...
No...
-Calm down...
That's not like him, Mum... I know he's not like that!
-There, now... Come.
Come with me...
Sit down.
No need to show the respect you clearly don't have...
Getting up won't prove that you respect me one bit...
How do I prove it, Grandpa?
You'll tell me the truth when I ask something...
And do as I say.
So...
Was he here to see you?
I swear by you...
I swear by my late parents... No!
Then you should have no problem in doing what I ask you to...
-Your wish is my command.
I've decided to get you married...
I've decided to get you married to Adam.
If you can bring yourself to it...
Save my last breaths, my last moments...
From disgrace.
Anyone in your place - including me - would've found it difficult to believe me...
Anyone would've thought I'm lying. But...
Sometimes, a bit of hope is all you need to go on. And I can see you desperately need it.
I'm sure you can see I ain't giving you just a bit of hope! I'm giving you your life.
Believe what?
Your Mam's lying.
Shut up!
Ie... Anyone would've shut me up...
But when someone so close is trampling your happiness under her feet...
And family ties blind you to everything...
But someone else tries to open your eyes... It is quite natural to shut her up!
Give me his number.
If I couldn't see right through him in a moment, I'll shut up for the rest of my life!
So?
Welcome back, m'boy! How are you?
Everyone kills time when waiting... But waiting for you nearly killed me!
Look... They've all been waiting to welcome you!
Come.
Welcome.
How are you, Shayan? Bless you.
How was the journey?
-Great...
Come. Your sister's waiting for you... You're in for a real feast!
Welcome, Mr Khan.
-How are you, sir?
Mehek?
What happened?
Aren't you happy to see me?
How could I be anything but happy to see you?
I'm just asking because I can't believe my eyes.
Is Adam around?
-He's in his room.
From my earliest days...
My youth...
To my waning...
Wrinkled state now...
I don't remember apologising to anyone for my biggest sins...
Not truly, at least...
But today... I apologise from the core of my heart...
To you... And to myself.
I know why only too well...
But I wonder why you're apologising to yourself.
My worry for you gave me sleepless nights all this time...
I don't know how many lies I had to tell myself to comfort me...
I'm sorry for all of that.
That's why...
I'm apologising to myself...
I've accepted it...
So you might as well...
Way to twist my arm!
A bit of arm-twisting's gonna save you from every trouble headed your way.
Think of it as a godsend,
And it'll ward off every fear, pain, and punishment...
What if I didn't?
Good one.
What if I'm serious?
Let's just say your death's gonna give me sleepless nights...
C'mon... Enjoy the feast!
Adam...
Mehek?
Please, sit.
You didn't tell me what Grandpa asked you to do.
I felt it was more important to listen to you...
Mind if I ask you something?
-Go on.
Do you ever get punished for being innocent?
May I ask you something?
Sure...
After telling me...
Happiness can be very high-headed...
Before coming in, it likes to make sure you've paid its price by suffering enough...
May God will that is so...
What is it?
Why is life more harsh on me than my feeble heart can take?
Feeble hearts need someone's mercy to beat.
It pleases the Lord when they do...
And He is fair and just.
He doesn't want to leave them without reason to be rewarded on the Day of Judgement.
That is why He tests them by going harsh on them.
And the Doomsday we live to see in this world?
It'll be the day we are rewarded...
It's just... Trying times...
Jesus... Just how...
Just how do I face everything?
I've been trying to gather the courage to turn Grandpa down, but it slips from between my fingers like grains of sand...
Okay... I'll just text him a 'no' and leave this place for no less than a year... I can't live here...
You'd leave me alone?
I can't help it, Mehek.
Won't you stand by me?
When'd I say that?
What do you want?
Just say yes...
You're married to someone. How can you get married to me?
You've just got to say yes... Because if you don't... He'll get me married to someone else...
What happened, Mehek?
Someone... Someone came to see Roshni... But Aunt blamed me! I have nothing to do with it!
Halt! Mr Khan's orders!
Javed! Hanif!
What orders?
Mr Khan asked me to stop you if you set foot where you are, threaten you if you didn't stop...
Aim for the head if you didn't listen, and shoot you the moment you took a step out the gate.
It'd pain me, sir, but no pain would let me disobey Mr Khan. I'd pull the trigger.
Okay... Have it your way...
That's why I want you to talk to your Mum... Come over with a proposal before I'm married off somewhere else...
Adam!
-Yeah?
Mum wants to see you.
I'll be back.
Don't worry. I'll be waiting...
You don't know how much you've delighted everyone here!
What do you mean?
I heard the thing about the proposal.
Hey!
Blimey, are you coy!
I'm sure Aunt's shamed and disgraced tears would calm the wildfire craving for revenge a bit if Roshni eloped with her lover!
But first, I need to get to him!
Didn't even smile.
-Got anything better?
-Just poor jokes, I tell you!
-Lemme tell you about --
You know the bank 'round here? I went there with some money...
-Okay, back to the game, mates...
-Aye...
Hello?
Wow... You sound as pure as a mother's love for her son...
Who is it?
Someone who's witnessed tears in Roshni's eyes.
Who?
A friend.
Why aren't you taking her call?
Why do I need to tell you?
-You don't.
Just listen to what I say.
One, she's about to commit suicide and I'm stopping her.
What?
You heard me. Now, don't answer if you get a call from her number. Her Mam calls you to check.
And why should I believe you?
-Your problem. Figure it out.
Just take my call. I've kept Roshni alive on half-truths and white lies.
How's she?
Take my call and she'll be fine.
Hello?
Her lover's asking about his love... It's gonna be a doddle, it is!
Yeah? Who is it?
Where's Mehek?
Mehek? I think I lost her somewhere in my scarf. Mind taking a look?
What are you saying?
-No, seriously! Take a look! C'mon! Here!
Always lookin' for Mehek!
Where are you going? Mehek!
Home.
'Far as I know, home's that way!
Oh yeah...
Sorry...
I hope Grandpa didn't ask about me.
-He did.
What?
-He asked where you were. I told him you were up in your room.
Thank you.
Anytime.
I've been thinking why my daughter had to go through all of that...
When I realised that she'd seen nothing yet...
But not now... She's safe now...
What if he'd cheated on you after you got married?
I can't understand anything...
I've got this sinking feeling... I'm restless...
Just... Don't do anything that'd disgrace me.
Just accept whatever match Grandpa finds for you,
Or you'll taint both my honour and my upbringing in one stroke. It'd kill me!
And it'd bury me alive!
I'm your mother...
God always listens to mothers.
I'm sure He'll do something for you.
If He listens to mothers...
Pray that Saqib comes back.
I did.
But it was never heard because it was not good for you.
Mum!
What are you doing?
Please don't taint my honour...
Do as Grandpa says...
Water...
Wa -- Water... You -- Tyrants...
W --
Any --
Dry...
W -- Water...
Water...
Bloody -- Tyrants...
W --
All -- Dry...
Please...
Any -- One...
Mum...
Mum!
What happened?
Nothing... Back to sleep...
Please tell me.
I don't know...
I just felt so... Restless...
I feel like we're about to hear some very bad news...
I've felt this way once...
Your Grandpa passed away back then...
It's nothing... I'm with you...
Don't worry...
Lie down...
Easy there...
M -- Mum...
-There, now... Easy...
O Lord...
Hey! Get up and have something!
You heard me?
I'm keeping it here...
He'll have it when he gets up...
Mehek!
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
There, now...
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
It's okay...
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ My resolve faded as an aching wound took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
Hush...
♪ You were distant though so near ♪
♪ You're distant yet so dear ♪
♪ You etched your name on my heart, right here ♪
♪ You forgot me, yet you're dear... ♪
♪ Seeing the raindrops, old memories ignite ♪
♪ These raindrops slowly set my heart alight... ♪
♪ O Mender of every broken heart, ♪
♪ When will You see mine fall apart? ♪
♪ Turn back and take a look ♪
♪ At who you forsook... ♪
♪ My love torments me; ♪
♪ My heart asks Thee ♪
♪ 'If I was destined to break', ♪
♪ 'Why did You create me'? ♪
Sir...
Adam's here to see you, sir.
Send him in.
-Okay.
And... We'd both like some tea.
Sure.
Come in, Adam.
Good morning.
'Morning.
Take a seat.
After you.
How are you?
Same as you left me.
Still waiting for your reply...
Yeah... About that...
Well, Mr Malik...
-Wait...
Wait...
If you're here to refuse...
Don't say anything.
In fact, don't mention it at all...
Just... Talk about anything else...
Have a cuppa, and leave...
I've never heard you turn me down.
I fear my head may bow down in disappointment.
No, Mr Malik...
I haven't come here to refuse.
I'm here to tell you that your wait's over.
Mum will be here with the proposal in the evening.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe