To the devil with you! Just -- Give him to me!
Give you my fortune worth two million in exchange for all the insult? Oh, please! Out of my way!
Guddi!
Gu --
Hello?
-Adam?
The Lord heard my prayers... Bring Guddi and my son back. Quick.
I'm longing to see my son...
Adam? Why don't you say anything?
Hello?
Don't -- Don't tell me you let her go!
Look at yourself!
Looks like someone just robbed your face of its colour, leaving behind a blackened wasteland!
She's here!
The 7 p.m. train's here!
-She comes here everyday!
Thank Heavens!
He gives more when you're grateful! Whether you ask for it or not!
She's here! Chuff chuff!
She's gracing us with her presence! Chuff chuff!
I'm glad you listened to me.
I didn't say anything...
But...
I heard everything.
You never told me so much all these years...
You don't know it, but your decision woke me up.
Yeah...
I'll do it...
I'll marry her...
Mehek!
Yes, Grandpa?
Aye...
Guddi...
It won't happen again... I assure you.
Go... You need some rest.
Mehek...
I hope you're not worried now.
Of course, Grandpa.
Get some rest.
Hey...
I hope you know your place now.
You nearly forgot!
But don't worry. I won't let it happen again.
I'll always be there to remind you.
Go and get some rest in 'your' room...
Enjoy lying down on a proper bed! First time in your life, innit?
M'boy...
Adam!
Mr Malik!
Good morning... What brings you here?
-Good morning.
Good morning.
-Please, take a seat.
I heard you're not well.
Yeah... But I'm good now.
I couldn't come here because I was busy, but I was worried about you all day.
Thank you so much, Mr Malik... But I'm going with you to the factory... At Khanpore, right?
You're a lawyer... You've been with me for five years...
I always wonder why...
You don't want anything for it.
I respect you, Mr Malik.
It's an honour to work with you. It's my pleasure...
I'll be glad to serve you as a lawyer when that's needed.
I'll get you some tea... Before we leave.
Guddi!
Eh?
The maid isn't back.
But someone's got to do the dishes. And do 'em properly.
Okay.
-Right.
Right.
Right. Now!
Abdul!
Excuse me!
Ma'am?
I need to take my son to the hospital. I've been calling out but can't see anyone who can drive...
I'll go see...
Whoa...
What happened? Are you alright?
-Just my old age... I'm getting used to it.
I'll get the driver...
No... You need to rest. I'll go get him myself...
-Please, allow me. You've never been there... What'd Mr Khan say if you went out in this scorching heat?
No problem... Mr Khan isn't home. I'll ask the driver not to tell him.
You're not well. Get some rest. Take the day off.
Do these too.
But they're clean.
Well, do them again.
They'll be cleaner!
Ych a fi! Ever bothered to clean that tongue? It's so foul!
There's more...
Wash them quickly and properly!
Tad needs that money... You said you'd send it in a few days.
Five days to go... Gotta give them an advance for the jewellery and furniture!
Tauqir!
Aslam!
Anyone?
Water...
Water! You bloody tyrants...
Water... That's all I want...
I ain't asking you to set me free...
Water...
Wait!
I won't let you get away!
I lose because I love you.
No one can catch me!
Oh, please... You know just as well it's this ring that's stopping you! Try your best!
These red bangles suit you...
Your love colours every bit of me...
How much...
Do you love me?
Can you smell the fields?
They don't smell nearly as sweet as my love for you...
Really?
You're a monster, Asher Khan!
You locked Sajjad in just so you could marry me...
And told me he two-timed me?
That he left me...
He called you a friend!
Oopsie... Clean it again, will you? What're you looking at?
I want it whiter than white!
The doctor's here.
Good morning, doctor...
'Morning.
How's my husband?
Oh, utterly spoilt...
Like a stinking rich man's spoilt brat!
Not easy to fix...
How much longer?
A month... At most...
And then?
Allow me...
Always...
To leave...
Put plainly...
You want to leave me in tears...
I'll take my leave...
-When would you be here again?
My grief longs to know...
If - God forbid - your husband dares get better, I'll be here.
Strange, innit?
I can't even pray for that day...
Come to my clinic sometime...
Tomorrow.
Take care.
See you.
See you...
Hey!
Leave him! We need to talk.
I've been humiliated so much keeping your secret that I think I might explode! Rub my feet, would you?
C'mon!
Mehek...
Madame -- Wants to -- See you...
I'll be there in a moment.
What d'you think you're doing, byt? Back to work!
iN a mOmENt.
I'm putting up with it for you! Normally, I'd...
Ankle!
Harder, byt... Harder... Ie...
I don't remember a day when you didn't speak a word!
The eyes have seen something...
That left me...
Tongue-tied and dumbstruck...
With shock, delight, and grief... All at once...
I've lost the strength to speak and the courage to think...
What'd you see?
Life...
My life... After ages...
Thank God...
She's fine...
The years have taken a toll on her face...
But...
But her eyes are the same old...
Pure... Lovely...
Who?
How are you?
Great.
Tell Mr Khan he's won.
Congratulate him...
Go...
Go and tell him...
I'll do as he says...
He'll be in Karachi for two days.
Oh, lovely...
I'll have two more days of company...
Go...
Come in.
You called me?
Cleaned the kitchen?
Yes...
Rub my feet.
Can't you hear me?
Sure...
Stop clawing at me!
Sorry...
I thought I'd make enough to pay for Chutki's wedding in 45 days and leave...
But I swear by my Mam... Me or my thoughts ain't taking one step out until I've made you pay!
Your downfall begins today...
What'd you say?
What'd you hear?
Nothing...
That's what I said...
Sometimes, you can hear thoughts...
Oh, I wouldn't dare...
Good. Do it properly...
I wouldn't dare just think... I'm gonna make sure!
Two minutes and I'll get you as always!
His name's Shayan. Studied with me at University. Yeah... We got married... My biggest mistake!
Got you!
Please save my son...
Please...
Time to play horsey!
-I got something for you, Mehek! Don't you want to see it?
After your sentence!
-You're really gonna love it, Mehek!
No excuses!
Okay...
Clippety-cloppety, clippety-cloppety!
I haven't done my time yet, Mehek... Who am I, but a prisoner?
Your cruelty has blinded you!
You'd kill me if you knew I found out!
It was never love, Asher Khan... You were just being bullheaded as always! What've you done?
And I lived so many years thinking Sajjad had cheated on me!
Kept comforting myself by cursing him...
Can't give up sweets, eh?
If you can't, you can give up coming here.
It won't let you live much longer.
Save yourself from paying my fees and leave it for your kids instead.
Jesus, why can't you understand?
Take these pills on time, okay?
Take it in the morning, afternoon, and evening.
-How much?
How much?
-200.
Well...
Take these...
Take these with some milk...
Take these with some milk on an empty stomach.
Thank you.
What's he doing?
Someone's been calling you for ages. Why don't you take the call?
That isn't my phone ringing, Shamim... It's my value rising every moment... Let me max it out...
Okay... Doctor's orders...? Next!
He promised to see me today!
But he isn't even taking my call! I've called him like 5,000 times!
Qutbuddin!
Yeah?
I'm...
I'm not really well...
Take me to Dr Rana's... Get the car out...
Okay.
Who's this?
Hello?
Hello... Roshni...
It's Saqib.
I've been trying your number since yesterday! I haven't had anything!
Where are you? How are you?
The cops gave me a bad beating... Took my phone... Got me out of my job... Threatened to set me up for something really bad if I didn't leave the village in a week!
Did you have anything?
I don't have anything... The landlord threw me out...
Good Lord... We don't have classes for a week either...
Could you come here?
What if someone saw me?
Come in from the backyard like the other day.
I'm more worried about you than my dignity or life.
If anything happens... I'm sure we can take care of it...
Come here at 1 a.m. Everyone goes to bed by then. I'll be waiting.
Okay... This isn't my phone... I've borrowed it... See you at 1.
Okay.
Okay...
We pulling an all-nighter...?
Are you asking or saying, sir?
No, sir, I'm requesting.
I thought... Madame's in here... She's left already?
I'm sorry... I didn't see her leave... Or... I would've cleaned up the place.
Shamim...
Remember that when it's an affliction of the body, they come in where you just came in from, and go out the same way.
-Of course...
But when it's an affliction of the heart, they come in and go out by the back door.
Turn off the lights...
Close the doors.
You're alright, aren't you, Saqib?
Please, tell me... I'm so worried when I look at you...
It's all because of me...
Look here...
It hurts, doesn't it?
Yeah...
May their hands break!
Here's 20,000.
Take care.
Go.
Heavens...
What was that?
W -- What's going on?
Who are you?
Who was that?
Who was that with you, Roshni?
Oh, can it!
We don't want your lies! We heard you with your lover, but you have the nerve to slander my innocent daughter now that Dad's here!
What?
What did you say?
-Only what I saw...
But no longer...
And I'm glad I saw it with my own eyes!
Because you look so eager to slander my daughter and taint her forever!
Roshni... Why don't you tell her I just came here?
Put a sock in it!
If Dad were not here, I would've cut that lying tongue of yours!
Grandpa...
I swear by the first steps I took holding your finger...
I don't -- I don't know who he was...
But Roshni w --
-Shut up!
Not another word!
Let her try and clean up her mess with her lies... Come!
Grandpa... I...
Please, Grandpa! Grandpa! Wait... No!
I thought her Grandpa's greys reflected some experience!
I could see 'GUILTY' written all over Roshni from here...
But he couldn't see Mehek's innocence from up close!
You disappoint me, gramps!
Who was that?
I want an answer!
S --
S -- Saqib...
How long do you know him?
Ten months...
Please, Grandpa... Open the door! I beg you!
Please hear me! Grandpa!
Grandpa...
Please don't do that, Grandpa... Just listen to me...
Grandpa... Please... No...
Grandpa... Please...
Grandpa... Open the door...
Open the door... Please...
No...
Grandpa...
I can't live without him.
-Shut your trap!
If you said another word or tried to tell them he was here to see you, forget living with him... I'll make sure you don't live another moment!
I'll see him in a few days.
You better tell him.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe