Come.
Munna!
Grandpa?
-Come here.
What is it?
N -- Nothing?
You look upset. What is it?
Not upset... Just hungry...
Go. Have something.
I can't bring myself to eat anything.
That's weird...
You look upset too. You hungry too?
No.
I'm not hungry.
Just...
A bit upset on the inside...
The last time I felt this way...
Was when Mehek had gone to London for her PhD.
She'll be back in two days...
But...
I have this sinking feeling...
May the Lord do what's best for her...
Amen.
Done your homework?
No...
Why?
Forgot it...
Go. Do your homework! Focus on your studies, okay?
-Yeah. Okay.
We can't get everything we want, Mehek...
There's always something...
And quite often a lot... That we don't...
'Everything'... That can only describe the Lord...
If a man feels he's got everything he ever wanted, it's a sign...
That he's about to lose it all...
That he'll be pushed back to having nothing...
We only saw Guddi's bitterness...
Because we didn't like it one bit. Couldn't take it.
No one...
Including you and me...
Never tried to find out why...
But it's quite simple, really...
An ounce of bad times is all it takes...
To embitter the softest of hearts forever.
Don't even think about pitying me.
Running from pity has led me into the abyss...
No...
I don't pity you, Guddi...
I'm just telling Mehek...
You ought to thank her, Mehek...
She hasn't just helped you...
She's done you a favour.
And what about your favours?
'Favours'...
I've done myself favours...
What?
I mean --
Nothing...
Just 10 kilometres away!
From your son's Dad, and your honour, your love...
Congratulations.
Doc...
I'm not sure if I should be saying this, but...
As someone who's stood by you for ten years...
I think I ought to say this...
So... Without worrying about what you'd say...
I'd like to tell you what I think...
Yeah?
You're being used, Doc!
And --
It doesn't...
Suit you...
Stop --
Stop...
What happened?
-Water... Air...
Here.
-Can't breathe... Water...
What happened?
-Nothing -- Just this -- fear --
Alright now?
Yeah...
Better...
Here we are. Home.
Welcome back where you belong.
Welcome back among those you hold dear.
Adam...
For God's sake...
Please don't say 'thank you'!
Go.
Aren't you coming?
No. I'd rather -- stay...
Out here...
I'll be --
Waiting to see a broad smile on your face when you come back...
Okay...
Even if she's too happy to come back...
Stay here...
Wait for me.
I'll be back...
I'm right here.
Ma'am?
Here for Mr Shayan.
-Just in time. It's nearly time for the wedding. Wait in the first room to the right...
Just in time. It's nearly time for the wedding. Wait in the first room to the right...
Okay.
C'mon, Mehek...
Shayan and Masooma Asher... Have you come here to enter into Marriage without coercion, freely and wholeheartedly?
I have.
Are you prepared, as you follow the path of Marriage, to love and honour each other for as long as you both shall live?
I am.
What happened?
What is it, Mehek?
Why are you crying?
Mehek?
For goodness' sake, say something!
Guddi?
What's up with her? Why doesn't she say anything?
I'll sort it o --
-No.
You're not going in there...
It's a funeral and they're singing a dirge for my love...
-Good Lord...
What happened to Shayan? Everyone alright?
Oh, he's fine...
The blasted cheat...
I felt like strangling him with the garland he was wearing!
Garland?
What garland?
Oh, I don't know, maybe one he's wearing to celebrate his marriage to his new love...
Marriage?
He off his head?
Lemme see what --
-No...
Please, for God's sake... Don't go in there...
By my misfortune...
Just let him go...
And let me go with him.
I've got a few nice things I'd like to say to him...
I've got curses for him...
Before I give him his kid. Here. Give him here.
W -- What are you saying?
C'mon.
He's my son -- I won't -- I can't let anyone take him away!
I'm doing what every woman should. Except fear, disgrace, and shame hold every other woman back.
I can't let him ruin another life!
Please, Adam... Just... Take me back...
I beg you...
Before...
I die of what I've seen...
Take me back...
Back home...
Please...
I'm so helpless...
My daughter's life has been ruined before my eyes...
But I couldn't stop it...
No...
I'm cruel...
Silent witnesses and bystanders are cruel...
I am just as guilty...
But what could I do?
He's a mad dog...
Asher Khan...
I never cursed you because you're my daughter's father...
But I do today...
For all your pride and conceit...
May God condemn you to helplessness!
Mr Khan...
You alright? Mr Khan?
Hmm?
You alright?
-Yeah...
Just a bit... Dizzy...
For a moment...
My body felt lifeless...
First time I've felt that way...
But I'm fine...
Just get me some water.
-Sir.
Mum...
Mum!
Mr Khan...
Yeah?
I don't like to see you worried.
It pains me.
Everyone except you...
Thinks badly of me...
But I don't care what anyone else thinks.
Care begets worry.
Why worry if you don't care?
For this estate...
My grandfather...
Got my father's only sister...
Married to the Bible...
I've seen my Aunt...
Breathe her last in great pain...
And my grandfather, perhaps much more...
I can't do the same...
That's why...
I want to secure my daughter's future.
You?
Why not?
Here?
-Yeah.
Can't believe it?
I couldn't believe it too.
But that's why we're different.
I'm right here but your lying, deceitful self can't believe me!
And I believed every lie...
Every fairytale, every illusion you conjured...
Like a divine revelation!
How'd you get out?
The Lord God...
The Lord of the Worlds...
Who makes the night fall after day...
Who gave us life...
And will give us death...
He said 'Let there be light', and there was light to light up my endless night...
And sent one of His most devoted and fearless servants...
But why are you here?
I'm not here to beg for your love...
Love isn't even on my mind right now...
It's long dead... Buried...
You killed it.
It can rest in peace, knowing it will be rewarded.
I just thought I'd let you know...
In case you've missed it, He's angry with you.
I don't think He's gonna spare you!
What've I done?
I just got even.
An eye for an eye, and a tooth for a tooth... Honour for honour...
I just did to you...
What your old man did to my sister!
You think you're the lord of this world?
'Settling scores'?
Taking His matters into your hands?
You think you can satisfy the Most Generous and Merciful by settling scores?
He's going to fill your rusted old begging-bowl with restless disgrace...
And leave room for nothing else!
What'd I do to earn any of it?
You got even with my Dad by punishing me...
Was I there with him back then?
Did I do anything back then?
I was just a girl... Little and innocent...
Probably somewhere else playing with my toys...
I curse you for playing with my life...
May He never have mercy on you in this world or the next!
Please --
Don't say that --
It's scaring me...
I'm afraid...
He's already heard it by now...
Who is it?
It's me, Saqib!
Would you like some water?
No, thanks...
Was anyone here?
I think I dozed off...
I did too...
But I'd know if someone knocked or rang the bell...
I'll have a look...
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
Prepared, as you follow the path of Marriage...
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
I am.
But seeing your Tad sleep peacefully three days ago...
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
I knew something was off...
Peace announces grief's visit here...
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ My resolve faded as an aching wound took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ You were distant though so near ♪
♪ You're distant yet so dear ♪
♪ You etched your name on my heart, right here ♪
♪ You forgot me, yet you're dear... ♪
Jesus...
What happened?
An animal...
I -- Is it alright?
Aye...
Inside!
C'mon! Double time!
Here! Sit!
Sit if you don't want a bullet in your head!
S -- Saqib...
Shut.
Shut. Up!
First rule of business: Never trust anyone.
I broke that and the second rule for you.
I paid you what you asked for.
But you!
You didn't even think what Ruby could do...
If you turned traitor, did you?
I didn't betray anyone!
-Shut your gob!
You sold her to me...
And then sent a merc to set her free?
I sent no one! I swear!
He won't spill the beans...
He won't spill the beans... Make him!
Stop!
If it's true...
Take your money...
I don't need it!
Where've you kept it, eh?
AYE, WHERE'S IT?
Keep your voice down, my sister's laid up.
Aye...
Where've you kept it?
The room back there...
Under the bed... The suitcase between the crates...
It's all yours...
Go get it.
Double time.
Did you think you could betray Ruby so easily?
Found it yet?
Open it!
That's that sorted out...
Now...
It's time you paid the price for your betrayal.
Give him what he deserves!
I want to hear him scream!
Just like that!
Break every bone in his body if you have to! Make sure he suffers!
No one can escape Ruby!
What?
What is it?
I'm scared...
What happened?
I hold Mum's hand... Or lay my head on Dad's chest... When I go to sleep...
I'm very scared...
Don't worry, I'm here...
May I...
Hold you hand?
Go...
Just -- Go...
GO!
Mum...
What happened?
You alright?
Mum...
I was so scared...
When I asked my b --
Shayan...
If I could hold his hand...
He --
He kicked me out of the room...
M --
Mum...
God settles all debts, doesn't He?
Good and evil?
Doesn't He?
Yes...
He'll make him pay, won't He?
I'm sorry we couldn't save her...
I know it's hard...
But it's what the Lord willed...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe