Good day, sir.
Good day. Hello... Come here, love. Bless you.
Sit.
It feels so good to see you.
Thank you.
Thank you for considering me worthy of respect.
Hello, Uncle.
Bless you.
Sit.
What happened?
Why are you crying?
I'm waiting...
For what?
For Shayan.
Yeah... I live in wait of seeing him...
I used to be hopeful that he'd come back...
But now...
There, now... Calm down...
Your Aunt's been waiting for you.
Go.
Orders, Mr Khan?
My ears have longed to hear your orders, and my hands to carry them out.
Go to the lock-up.
Threaten him.
Make him understand.
Press him.
Show him his sister's nightmarish future.
Do what you must to make him give in.
I will always serve you, and your descendants after you, Mr Khan...
Don't even think about running away with him.
I have the power to do that...
But He never gave me the will.
I'm taking both of you back.
Why should I believe Mehek sent you?
Do I look like a fibster, a trickster?
Oh, you look worse...
What do you mean?
Those who look like fibsters and tricksters are really just badly off...
That's why they never get a chance. Everyone's too... Careful around them.
They can't even sell their truth for spare change.
It is your innocent-eyed courtly ilk that can strike heads off without a mouse stirring!
You can call Mehek.
Call her my foot!
After all I had to go through to help her, I'll make sure her past catches up to her and erases her future!
And how do I know that snaky old hag hasn't sent you?
Where are you?
I'm with her.
Please don't let her go...
I'll fix everything here...
Just let Grandpa come back...
Good luck.
Gonna need it...
Yeah?
-Helo...
What is it this time?
You didn't get back.
-What do you want me to say that'll satiate you?
You want the money, you'll get it. Even if I have to sell my hide.
Why are you so angry?
You ain't tasted my anger yet... I'm just saying what you want to hear.
Aye, I'm a bit rough, but to the devil with that! Be glad you heard what you wanted!
All wrapped up in your chuffing selves!
You never bother how I'm doing, do you?
Where'd you get the money?
Doesn't look like you've got it.
Your promises were but a sandcastle...
The waves of time reduced it to rubble in moments...
Blimey... How you said...
I'm here to stop those tears.
I'm here to give you every happiness in the world.
I'm here to stand guard around you;
Always ready to face any sorrows coming your way.
I'm here to keep those eyes shining bright with glee;
I'm here to stop your tears from drowning it out.
Hello?
Grandpa...
It's getting late... I'm so worried you aren't back.
Don't worry, love. I'll be there in half an hour.
Okay...
You left everything unfinished...
And never came back...
He'll be back...
I assure you.
Just... Pray...
You never told me you're your oppressor's blood.
Is he really your Uncle?
I used to say it proudly when the blood was warm... But silence took over when the blood turned cold.
What's wrong with you?
Aye, I'm a hustler. Taken many for a ride.
But not for myself.
There's three of us. Me, me sister, and me brother.
Tad never bothered to get his girls educated...
He spent everything for his son.
Thought he'd become a great man... Support them when they're old... And guard his sisters...
So... Didn't he become a great man?
Oh, he's a great man... Very great, in fact.
Too great to even remain...
Too great to even remain... Human.
He got married...
And jetted off to Dubai with his wife.
And so my parents remain waiting for Godot...
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Are you, really?
Now imagine living it.
Tad always reined in on us. Made sure we grew up to be upright.
But with each cough in the middle of the night, the reins slipped from his hand as he reached for the pills we could never get him...
Until one day, the neighbour refused to give me sister a piece of bread. She fainted...
That was it...
The one moment, the spark...
That charred the reins forever...
I forged a few papers and sold the neighbour's house. Soft target. Lonely, widowed... Thought I'd start with her.
That's when it grew on me... The quest for easy money became my closest friend...
Any way you could... You know... Go back?
Ie. Death.
There's no turning back for me in life. Not after everything I've gone through.
Hey!
How long before the train gets here?
It's two hours late already!
This isn't a big station. It's one for us plebs.
The toffs chuff chuff past this place, choking this puffed-out place! They don't stop for us!
Except one poor rustbucket...
Full of decrepit men, famished kids, and their Mums on their uppers!
Just that one! No one else stops here for the plebs...
It broke down...
Over there near Sajjanpore.
No idea when it'll be here. In the morning, maybe? Come...
Absolutely no idea...
I'm not letting you go.
Who are you to stop me? Me oul' fella? I wouldn't care if you were. I don't even listen to him now.
Don't you need money for your sister's wedding?
I do.
-I can give you.
When?
-Right now.
I've asked someone to do something... He'll be here shortly.
The lengths you'd go to for Mehek!
Who's she to you?
♪ Not once did I ever speak, ♪
♪ But it's her my heart and soul seek, ♪
♪ Chanting on the rosary her name, ♪
♪ Keeping my yearning aflame... ♪
Grandpa!
What are you doing here? Out!
Grandpa! What took you so long?
I was so worried!
She was my responsibility...
She's got a wee kid... What if something happened to him?
Slow down... You're losing me... What happened?
Ready?
Aim for her head.
Come! Get out!
-Forgive her, Aunt!
For the love of God, Aunt... Please forgive her!
-I'll show you!
Get lost!
-Guddi!
Your sister's been most insensitive...
-Aye...
Sometimes, I feel the same.
Don't worry.
I'll talk to her.
We'll go bring her back ourselves.
Promise.
-If the Lord wills!
What are you doing, you mad woman? Get down! Qutbuddin! Qutb --
Get some sense into her!
-What happened? Zulaikha?
Roshni...
Roshni!
-Get her down! Get down! Qutbuddin!
Hammer some sense into her! Qutbuddin...
-What are you doing? Zulaikha! Get down!
What's that?
-Qutbuddin!
-Get down, Zulaikha!
Malika! Aliya! Roshni! Mehek! Come here!
Aunt!
-Mum!
-Get down!
-What are you thinking?
-Back off! Geroff me!
Aunt!
-Mum!
-Stay away!
Go away!
-Please, Mum...
-Aunt...
-What the devil is going on?
What do you think you're doing?
-I know you're here to order me to forget my humiliation and let that bloody maid stay!
Over my dead body!
No, Mum!
-Please, Aunt...
Okay! She's not coming back! Happy?
Please, Mum... Get down... Here...
Mehek!
Call the doctor! Qutbuddin!
-Right!
Mehek!
Open your eyes!
-Mehek?
Mehek! Open your eyes!
What happened?
-Water... Get some water...
Mehek...
I thought about it while you were away.
What?
Which of the money and my humiliation do I care about more.
Which one is it?
-I'm not going back.
Your sister's getting married. You've got to give them 600,000 by tomorrow.
No problem if it took another day...
I'm sure this lad's worth two million. At the very least.
Many childless couples are looking for a way to kill their loneliness...
I know just where to sell him for a proper fortune.
That it?
Not even spare change if you ask me.
-300,000 for now...
No one gives an advance that big when you've struck a deal for 600 grand in 60 days, my dear Guddi!
Oooh...
If it isn't the wily fox peeking from behind that innocent face!
600 bags right now...
Plus 400 for the humiliation.
That makes one million.
Deal.
300K right now...
300 on your sister's wedding...
And 400 after 58 days.
I need a moment to think.
How's she, doctor?
Her blood pressure dropped quite alarmingly...
Her life was at risk, but don't worry... I've given her a shot. She should be fine now.
Please make sure she doesn't get stressed out.
Thank you very much, doctor.
Get him to his car, Munna.
-Sure.
Good night.
-Good night.
Mehek...
Had a row or something?
-Why do you ask?
Just... Asking?
And how's your master?
Worse.
It'll take time...
But he'll be better...
And how's the lady?
Fine.
Alright. Give her my regards.
I'm sure the pain is crippling...
But if you give up, you'll be here all your life like me...
She'll think you two-timed her and become someone else's.
Never.
You can't help it.
What's the best you can do?
Bang your head against the bars, the walls? Kill yourself?
There's nothing you can do.
She's like a sister!
Like a sister, yes...
Not really a sister...
Marrying her can be your way out.
It's a bitter pill you have to swallow if you want to get to your wife.
I can see you want me to be mean...
You want me to ruin her life to break free! She's just a kid!
Look...
Asher Khan thinks after he acts.
If he wants you married to his daughter, then so it will be!
And if not, he'd much rather keep his daughter with him as a lonely spinster...
Don't be so cruel to yourself... Or your wife!
Every restless twitch, every teardrop, every sigh of hers weighs a ton on you!
Every rustle gives her hope that you're back...
You've got this chance...
Think about yourself... And her...
This is no sin...
It's the road to freedom.
It's up to you.
It's up to you, mate...
You wanted to talk to me, Grandpa?
I heard you want to be a politician?
Not just! The Prime Minister, no less!
Hardly different. You got to start somewhere.
The village council has an election in three months.
Three villages will be voting.
I thought I should put you up for election this time.
-Please, don't just think. Decide and tell me anytime in the next three months!
You can't just charm the public like that.
You haven't heard me speak. But the mirror in my room has. I address a rally before it everyday.
I bet it would give me a standing ovation if it had hands and legs!
Alright... But there's a test. I'll put you up for election if you do well.
Aye aye, sir! Where's the strike?
Monsieur!
Mehek's come to!
Deo gratias...
She's just saying, 'Don't let Guddi go'...
Okay. Go.
Sir.
Well, Qutbuddin... I want you to convince your sister to let Guddi come back.
Ain't easy.
You're practically asking a winning candidate to surrender before his weak rival the night before the polls!
It wouldn't be a test if it weren't tough.
Promise me you're putting me up for election if I succeed?
Promise.
Go.
I've never had a moment's peace after you...
If only I had one chance... To tell you... Why I'm not back... That I'm not two-timing you... That I'm incarcerated and helpless...
You've brought me on my knees... I can't take a stand for anything...
The sweet redolence of your tresses... The feeling of you eyeing your love... The memories are still green...
Green...
These memories keep me going...
I've grown weary of waiting...
Too tired to go on...
Please... Hear me still thinking of you... And come back...
Before grief claims my life...
Come back...
Don't be so cruel to yourself... Or your wife!
Every restless twitch, every teardrop, every sigh of hers weighs a ton on you!
Every rustle gives her hope that you're back...
You've got this chance...
Think about yourself... And her...
This is no sin...
It's the road to freedom.
I talked to Mehek an hour ago.
She said Grandpa's back.
I'm surprised she didn't call again.
She's not answering...
Do you think I'm waiting for her?
Aren't you?
I can't take my eyes off the rails. I'm waiting for the train...
You just struck a deal with me!
I'm giving you one million!
I'm sorry, I teeter a lot! Didn't I tell you?
Know why?
Lady Luck is as adamant as you are. Be too sure and things never change for you.
You gotta shilly-shally sometimes to have it your way, you do!
Did you think I'd give up this fortune worth two million in two minutes?
One million for 60 days of insult... Not on your nelly, guv!
Excuse me! Where's the train?
-On its way...
Is it?
Okay... Have my number.
Do drop by if you come to Karachi.
I'm very different from this stone broke state, I assure you!
Fancy a taste of Manna and Quail? Come over sometime. Bet you won't feel like going back.
I'm gonna smash this jug into your head so hard it's gonna shatter like the jug!
How dare you ask me to change my decision?
I'm not asking you... I'm just negotiating... Making peace. You're free to refuse. But I'm sure if you made peace, you'd find some small measure of it yourself.
Go against my ego? It only troubles me more!
It's no good sitting in the Parliament all by yourself, is it? Seeing a parliament without the Opposition is like... Being thirsty but getting no water!
Get straight to your guff, I don't want a blimmin' news bulletin!
You made her homeless in a second!
It doesn't suit her, does it? Certainly, not just that! No... Bring her back. Insult her everyday.
Beat her with a different boot everyday.
Find peace everyday. Oh, lovely!
I'm sure you'll love it too!
Go and ask Dad to call her back.
I'm fine with it.
Okay.
Quickly. We're just stopping for five minutes.
-Okay.
Hush, now!
Please don't do that. That's someone's life you're holding in your hands.
Fair enough. What about my insult?
I'm in for more of the same if I go back.
Aye, I've never done anything respectable. That doesn't mean I don't care about being respected.
Guddi!
I let Guddi take my son!
What could I do? Tell Aunt he's my son?
What could I tell her about his father?
I don't care about my life... It's my son --
-Mehek?
Come in.
Mehek...
Don't worry.
Bring that smile back.
What?
She said she'll let Guddi come back.
Really?
-Yeah.
Yeah.
Thank you so much.
Anytime.
My phone...
For God's sake, Guddi...
Don't leave. It may kill someone.
Felt nice when you...
Held my hand so gently...
I thought I'd stay for a while.
If I felt you're anything but this gentle, I'd scream so loud all the men would rush to help.
Men love to help a lonely girl, they do! Who doesn't want to be a poor lady's knight in shining armour!
Leave me alone!
He botherin' you, ma'am?
-Na, thank you... Nothin' of the sort...
Yet... See that? One knight errant!
The louder I scream, the larger their horde will grow...
So... Get off me!
To the devil with you! Just -- Give him to me!
Give you my fortune worth two million in exchange for all the insult? Oh, please! Out of my way!
Guddi!
Gu --
Hello?
-Adam?
The Lord heard my prayers... Bring Guddi and my son back. Quick.
I'm longing to see my son...
Adam? Why don't you say anything?
Hello?
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe
Don't -- Don't tell me you let her go!