Come in.
Don't be shy...
Greet him.
Good day, sir...
Adam...?
You know him?
I should never've gone out of the way...
Every time I've done that, it's come back to haunt me...
Why'd I stop them from searching you?
Losing your wits... The first sign that fate has abandoned you. About time you accepted you've lost.
How'd you get here?
How'd Roshni get here?
Yeah?
I've bought her... With my hard-earned money!
The more I've struggled, the more I've learnt to value money!
I ain't gonna let you take her away just like that...
-Oh, I won't mind shooting you right now!
Lemme go! I ain't so mad or stubborn as to lose my life so easily!
Come in! Quick!
C'mon, now! In here!
-Guards!
Don't be stupid.
I've got guards armed to the teeth down there.
Don't even think about it.
I left second thoughts and the fear of death on my way. If your guards tried anything, I won't think twice before putting a bullet in your head!
Ma'am...
Ma'am?
Ma'am... This arrived by the post... For Mr Malik... I forgot to give it to you because Guddi sent me on an errand...
Last chance...
Don't do anything stupid, or my guards would love to break your bones! Guards!
Drop your guns or I'm firing on three! Do it!
Just let him go! She ain't more valuable than your life!
One...
Two...
Drop your guns!
Here.
Over here...
Anyone else? Come with me if you want.
Me...
Oooh...
You're making a big mistake...
You don't know who we work for.
If you made it out of here alive, I'm sure you'd be found dead on the way...
And if you're lucky to get home in one piece...
Be prepared to pay ten times the price...
We'll kill you... And your family!
-Empty threats! Come! Back off!
Back off!
Yeah... Back off...
'Ahmed Malik' (...) 'Mir Adampore'
My dearest foe...
By the end of this letter, you'll know who I am.
I was very young when, eight years ago,
You gave me wounds too deep for my age.
Remember Nadia?
The girl you sought to defile?
The girl who valued her honour more than her life and jumped from the balcony?
She's been in a coma since then.
Everything's finished, except her breaths...
That I've been guarding for eight long years,
Stoking the flames of retribution...
I hear you're laid up... Can't walk, can't even get up...
But that isn't nearly enough for you... You deserve much more...
So I took your daughter and sold her off to a whorehouse.
At long last, I've settled the scores.
Now, all that's left...
Is ashes... Cold ashes...
I pray you go to sleep every night praying it's your last...
Sorry...
It took me a while...
Take him away! Lock him up!
Thought you could get away, eh?
Don't even think about it!
You! Run away from Ruby? Impossible!
Looks like karma finally caught up, Ahmed Malik!
You are responsible for our disgrace!
Just you!
Here! Look at this! Look at what you've done! Look at where you got us!
Your lechery has cost us all our honour!
Your filthy past caught up with my innocent daughter and devoured her!
Mehek!
Madame's beating Mr Malik real bad! He's screaming!
Take care of Shahmir...
I'll go look...
She's mad! Put that down!
-I'll kill you!
I'll kill you!
Stop! Put it down!
-You destroyed everything!
I'm gonna kill you!
-Aunt...
Geroff me!
-Stop her!
-Please, Aunt... For God's sake...
For God's sake... Please... Don't...
I talked to Adam... He's found Roshni!
Adam's promised me he'll bring her back... Please...
Please stop...
-Roshni...
He'll bring her back...
Roshni...
Aunt...
-My girl...
My little girl...
What've you done...
Such cowardly courage...
Couldn't last a moment, eh?
Tied... Captive... Free no more...
Look who's talking... The one who had to strike from behind!
My hands are tied...
Not my mind!
I'll take her with me...
Or die trying...
Leave.
Her fancy man, I presume?
Oh, Madame Ruby... There's a lot more to life...
I know men inside out.
I know them better than a mother knows her kid.
You've never met a real man before, have you?
If you had, you would've been his pride, his crown jewel... Not out here in the market like this!
-Shut up!
Shut your gob...
I've seen the most upright men who take pride in their loyal wives enjoy themselves in the dogbox!
Thousands...
Thousands of men.
Not one of them a 'real man', you say?
-Just one.
If only you'd bother to look in front of you!
Chained and courting death... But as upright and honourable as always!
Tell me...
All of this...
Don't you think it's... Wrong?
It's your son, innit? Over there?
So...
How'd you kill his conscience? His honour?
Eh?
How d'you get him to sleep in peace?
How can he live with the knowledge...?
What does he think of what his Mum's doing?
Oh...
So this is wrong...
What about...
My life in that shambly shack...
Cramped... Broken windows... Cracked walls... No money to fix any of it...
And the men... Staring like a pack of hungry wolves as I cooked and cleaned and swept the floor... What d'you say about that?
And you better know this...
My son was not so low-down as you think...
Just... Hungry...
Whenever his conscience cried out... I'd shut him up with a piece of bread...
He was low and vile!
Honour burgeons on virtuous hunger, not sinful nibbles!
Oh, can it!
Lemme turn off the lights and fans... Give you a taste of it...
Lemme see how upright you are when your throat dries up and your stomach starts growling...
N -- No!
Please... No...
Don't leave us here...
Please...
Help...
I want to go home...
Just a few more days...
Get back on your feet and get even!
And, if you start havin' fun, get more than even! It's only fair!
There was a princess... Her brothers, the 7 princes, decided to go huntung...
So she started nagging them...
Still up?
-Yeah, Dad.
Wait...
We need to talk...
You're all grown up...
Is that you telling yourself or us?
Both.
Masooma...
There's something you must know...
Yeah?
The marriage is in a few days.
My doll's getting married?
-No. My doll's getting married.
Your doll?
Masooma... My little doll...
You're getting married...
You're getting married to Shayan.
Easy there.
She's not going anywhere.
She'll be here. With you.
Get her jewellery and her gown tomorrow.
Good night.
Please don't cry...
Still up?
This nightmare won't let me sleep...
Good that you're here...
We need to talk.
The Reverend's coming the day after tomorrow.
Everything else is ready for the marriage.
You're getting married.
We've got to account for our deeds before our Lord...
What d'you think you'd say?
I'll tell Him I've done a father's duty in finding the best match for my daughter. He will reward me.
No more questions.
Get ready...
Shayan!
Did you see Khawar around?
I've been calling him but he's not answering.
I'm sure he's around here... Get some rest. He'll be back.
Chutki isn't used to sleeping without him. She likes to lie down on his chest.
She falls ill if he has to go somewhere. Gets a bad fever.
Mind if I ask something?
-No?
If you had to choose between your husband and your children...?
Don't you fear God? Even sworn enemies won't say that!
I can't imagine living without my husband.
And my kids... They're a bit of my soul.
If I had to choose...
If I had to choose... I'd pick death.
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
One hit... That's all it took! That gun in your hand gave me some courage... But just my luck...
Shahmir...
Boyo...
How you doin'?
Munna...
Yeah?
I need your thoughts on something...
My thoughts?
Mum, Granny, my sister, and Dad always told me to ask my elders before doing anything.
But why are you asking little me?
You're the only one who knows my secret.
I'm thinking of telling Grandpa everything.
Tell that he's... My son...
Mum says that this inner voice is God's... You should listen to it.
This number is not answering your call.
This number is not answering your ca --
What's up, Adam?
I hope he's fine...
O God... I'm sure you're thinking that this girl's always cursed others... But they were evil... More than me, at least...
But he's a nice man... So I pray You... Protect him, my Lord...
Amen...
Okay. I'll tell Grandpa everything.
Today... I can't wait any more.
Munna! Out!
On your feet!
Close the door behind you!
Go to the devil! And see your Shayan there. Because I know he's with the devil!
But I pity the kid who - forget feeling his warmth - has never even heard his Tad's voice!
You love to wound others and rub salt in them, don't you?
Curse your wounds and the salt!
I speak the truth. Ain't my problem if it wounds you or rubs salt in your wounds. Sort it out with your truth. By the way, when'd you talk to Adam?
In the afternoon.
You've got no shame... You threw him into the maw but don't even bother to ask if he's even alive! His phone's been switched off for five hours!
Yeah?
Adam's phone is off. Did you talk to him?
It's been five hours since I talked to him... Mum's worried too...
Don't worry...
I'm sure he just... Got tired on the way... Dozed off or something...
I pray that's it... Hope we hear from him.
Hope so... Bye.
O Lord...
Keep Adam safe...
Amen.
First time I've felt like saying 'Amen' to your prayers, by the way!
I've got to tell Grandpa everything...
Before the weight of my lies kills me...
Grandpa...
Are you alright?
A man's alright...
As long as the shroud of honour...
Worn by his pride...
Is unsoiled...
And if anything...
Smirches it...
What follows...
Is war...
A war between...
Honour and life...
Roshni's blackened it...
Completely...
Honour may lose this one...
And death prevail...
God forbid anything happen to you.
You're my strength.
Don't give me a fright.
Got word on Roshni?
Yeah. I talked to Adam.
He says he's found her... Promised me he'll bring her back...
Before anyone else got word of any of this...
No one will see the smirches...
Your honour won't be stained...
I wish your words...
Godspeed...
To His ears...
Amen.
Grandpa...
There's something I need to tell you...
Yes?
Promise me you'll forgive my first and last mistake.
When daughters were born...
People used to mourn her birth...
I despised them...
More beasts and devils than men and women, all of them...
But today... I know what they feared...
They didn't fear their daughters...
They feared disgrace at the hands of their daughters.
I feel like going back...
Embracing them... And joining in...
Anyway... Go on...
What is it?
G -- Grandpa...
My --
T -- This son --
Guddi --
The doctor's here to check on Grandpa.
Call him in.
-Come in, doc!
Good evening. Come in...
-'Evening.
How do you feel now, Mr Malik? Better?
A bit...
-Great.
Munna... Get him a cuppa...
Thanks, I'm in a bit of a hurry.
Doctor...
How's he?
Better...
-Thank God...
I'm changing his medicines... Come.
-Alright...
To be honest, he isn't all that well... Keep him well away from stress and trauma.
Take care. Good night...
-Good night...
God forbid that I tell him...
He's my son and not Guddi's...
Whoa...
He wants to hear my story too...
Fair enough...
You ain't the first...
Every man who came here seemed to love sympathising and saying that they cared...
Easy for them to shield their own sins that way I guess...
I don't need to shield anything.
Because I'm not a sinner.
You want to get out. I know you didn't come here because you wanted to.
The 'f' in 'women' stands for freedom here.
But the 'e' in 'men' sure screams 'entitlement'.
Anyway, here goes...
Paw lost his eyes in an accident.
They said there was no one to sustain us...
Because I've got no brothers...
Paw's eyes - as long as they were of any use - searched for means to make ends meet by day...
And watched out for the lecherous gaze of the pervs by night...
He lost his eyes. We lost our means... And our safety...
The village head sent me to her sister's to earn what I could...
I met a man there...
He didn't dare lay an eye on me for eight days... His wife was around him...
Until one day, his wife left for her parents'. She got out of the house. His lust got out of its prison of 'modesty'.
He tried to force himself on me...
But... I managed to run away...
I bumped into a good Samaritan on the way...
He seemed only too willing to help...
And I was a woman...
Women see one good thing in a man...
And think he's everything they need...
Two days, he took to ensnare me. Four days, he fooled me with his 'love'. Come the fifth, and the bad Samaritan sold me here for five hundred bags.
I've broken out twice... But come back again...
I seem to forget that the men who come here... Come from out there...
Roshni's way more lucky.
You came here to save her... Even if it means dying for her...
So many died for us...
But not to save us...
Want me to go on?
-No... Please...
You aren't taking Madame's calls! I don't bother, but she's so worried!
But I do bother that you're making a big mistake!
What?
I don't grow close to anyone. I don't even let the thought grow close to me.
But I've got to stay here. And you've got to come here to see me because you want it.
Guess what, Madame's your key! So could you please keep things going and not change overnight?
Your eyes have clouded my mind...
Afflicted my heart...
The doctor's fallen sick himself! You can't seriously expect him to treat others!
Come see me tomorrow morning and get your dose. Take care.
Bye.
Flippin' Fakespeare...
Madame!
Madame Ruby!
I've come back before! Why've you kept me in here?
Jesus... Can't even scratch my head!
Madame Ruby!
Hit the hay, I guess... Easy for her...
Easy money eases sleep...
Would you help me?
Blimey, I can't even scratch my own head. How d'you expect me to help you?
-Untie my hand.
How? By lookin' at it?
Looks can only untie chained hearts...
I'd need my hands for this...
What's the matter?
Untie me and I'll untie you.
Naw, mate... I can't do it...
I can't even untie myself...
Wait... Lemme help you first...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe