Thought you could get away with it, eh?
Hello? Yeah, Mam?
Hello. It's been a month since you talked to me. How are you?
I'll get back later.
-Wait...
Don't hang up...
Who knows when I'll get to talk to you again.
Yeah?
You asked me to get Chutki married...
And told me you'd send me some money in a few days.
Her wedding's in five days. I've got to give an advance for the jewellery and furniture tomorrow.
And the caterer's asking for two hundred thousand!
I prayed that I don't have to ask you...
But I'm out of time... I couldn't help it. Your Tad's worried too.
Did he say something?
No.
But he didn't have anything since yesterday. Just half a cup of tea.
That's how I know. The worry's starving him.
I hope you didn't tell him I said I'll send money.
You off your head? He'd kick me out if I said that!
I told him your Uncle's helping.
Just pray for me... I'll do something.
-What do you mean?
Don't you have anything right now? When will you get it?
-I told you, I'll do something. I'll get back to you.
Okay... But... You've only got today...
Help us, O Lord...
How are you related to Malik Nureddin?
He's my Grandpa.
Please, take a seat.
Sit!
He's such an upright man. A saint!
Didn't you think about him for a moment?
Do you know him?
He's been very kind to me.
He's the kind who guards the honour of others... And you!
Please, I beg you... Don't tell him anything. Please...
Okay.
But promise me you won't stain his honour again.
Promise me it won't happen again.
I promise. Never again. I'm so sorry this happened...
You'd let Saqib go, won't you?
It's not his fault...
It's been 35 minutes. I won't wait a minute more.
Please don't leave Roshni here... I'm sure she's just gone to buy something...
I can't wait here. You're free to wait here.
-Please, Uncle... Just a few more minutes?
There!
Where were you?
I needed to get some books...
-Splendid... About time we got a move on.
Shahmir!
Munna!
Munna...
It's been 30 minutes! Go to the station, before my misfortune follows her there!
And... Here. Shahmir would be starving. Get him some milk, okay? Get something for Guddi too. Do whatever you must... Just... Don't let her go. Grandpa would be here any moment.
Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
Quickly.
-Munna!
Remember your puny place here before you even think of doing anything like that!
Poke your nose where it doesn't belong and I'll chop it off.
Back to work!
Come with me.
You're staying here.
Sit!
For Thine is the kingdom,
And the power,
And the glory, for ever. Amen.
Excuse me...
It's still four hours before the train gets here.
If it's on time, that is!
If things go as usual, you're five or six hours early, if not more.
Why?
Got a problem?
Is it illegal to wait that long? They gonna flog me?
Be my guest.
-Of course not... You don't get it...
I just meant... The kid's on the bench. The hard bench. It'd hurt him.
D'you think he'd be quiet if it hurt him?
It's comfortable enough for him.
Nah, you don't quite get it...
Please... Don't start telling me... Not feeling myself. Dreadful day... For me, and for you if you don't shut up!
Okay... I get it...
I can totally hear your worry...
I don't mind anything... Just...
I'm 'round here. In case you, you know, need anything.
It is He who helps, but if I can be His instrument, it'd do me good too.
Salve, Regina, Mater misericordiæ...
If only you stopped doubting my capabilities... I swear, our world would be so different.
What do you mean?
I want to stand for election.
I swear... The problems that ail this place will turn to dust.
Forget pits, you won't even see a pebble on the roads...
It'll save so much trouble on the roads...
Wait...
Hello?
Grandpa... Where are you? I've been calling you for so long.
Why are you crying?
Aunt beat Guddi badly and kicked her out!
But why?
Just... Come back...
Where'd she go with the wee child?
I'd be to blame for anything that happened to her...
She's out of her mind. Let me talk to her.
Okay...
Aunt... It's Grandpa. He wants to talk to you. Please open the door.
Don't!
-Aunt!
For God's sake, open the door!
Just talk to him!
Aunt...
She isn't opening the door, Grandpa. Not saying a word.
Don't worry.
I'll be back in the evening.
It'll be too late by then.
You'll have to wait a while...
Open the door, Aunt! Please...
Aunt... Open the door...
Munna... Go and open the door.
Munna...
Open the door...
Good Heavens... What are you doing?
Everything alright?
Yeah.
Wait until we get back...
She's alone with the kid... She doesn't know this place, Aunt... Please... She was my responsibility...
Heavens, Zulaikha... Open the door!
Get up!
Hey... Getting ready at this awful parlour... You won't believe how hideous I look... The other parlour's really good, but expensive... Why don't you talk to Mum? She won't say no if you said it. Please, Gu --
Hmm... Should I call Mehek?
Not so fast...
She'll think I'm helpless.
Let her suffer with me. Suffer the pain of parting with your son. Taste an ounce of my pain at my humiliation!
If you ask me, you've done worse than murder.
For you've murdered your family's honour.
For the love of God, Guddi...
For the love of God, Guddi... Don't punish my son for what my Aunt did to you.
Punish me, thwack me if you want... But please... Don't go...
Grandpa will be here any moment... I'll do something... Bring you back. I'll even give you the money if you want. But please, Guddi... Don't go anywhere...
Shahmir...
Your Tad's worried too.
You told me you'd send me some money in a few days.
Her wedding's in five days. I've got to give an advance for the jewellery and furniture tomorrow.
My Lord... It's a doddle for You... Will You?
When I open my eyes, may I see my Mehek --
-Adam!
Adam!
Thank You!
-Adam!
Adam... My...
My son...
Please save my son...
Please...
Your son?
Is it that she's not his mother...
Or not human?
Sir...
Excuse me, sir...
Could you get some milk for him?
-Of course.
I'll be back now... In a moment...
Guddi's reckless when she's angry...
Her anger kills every other emotion in her...
I'm so worried that she left Shahmir somewhere and --
-Guddi? Who's Guddi?
The girl who said she's here as my maid.
I lied to hide it from my family.
I told them Shahmir's her son.
Where'd you find her?
Karachi.
How long do you know her?
Just four days...
Please... Save my son...
You're the only one who can help me...
You trusted a stranger with your life in just four days?
It takes the rest of us our lives to earn someone's trust!
What could I do?
I was out of options.
My visa expired. I had to come back!
I just got on my plane and came here without telling anyone.
I even got the train ticket back home.
Here.
Sir...
Ticket to Mir Adam, please.
That'll be 940.
Here.
Here's the change.
I started waiting for the train.
My mind was black. Paralysed.
It just thought itself to death...
The train stopped. Everyone was getting off... But my legs refused to support me.
It felt so... Suffocating...
As if I'd left my courage had abandoned me on the way...
I bought tickets, but my fear tore it.
I prayed for a way out all night.
I kept praying...
What happened?
You look so worried.
Everything alright?
I'm running away from some folks. Would you happen to have some spare clothes?
I don't think they'd recognise me if I put on a veil and sat with you.
It may save my life.
Wait.
Here.
Cover your face.
Thank you.
I was looking for help...
But when she asked for help, I couldn't refuse.
I would've cried for the walls to hear, if no one else... I felt so helpless...
She was much more... She was human. I told her everything.
She looked into my powerless eyes for some time, before saying...
Do as I told you. They'll think he's my son... And you'll have 60 days to look for his Tad.
Trust and honour are priceless. That's what my Tad said. That's what makes them so... Profitable. That's what I believe.
Surely, it's not dearer to you than 600 gee?
I'm helping you for half off today. Because you helped me.
I bought two tickets again...
The train left for here in the morning.
What've you done, Mehek?
Please...
Do anything you can... Just... Bring them back... I beg you.
Please... Don't...
Give me a moment to take everything you've told me...
It'll only hurt more if you beg me...
I'll do what I must.
For you.
And I promise I'll bring them back.
Easy.
Guards!
-Ma'am?
I told you to stop Mehek from getting to the station!
Why didn't you?
I haven't taken my eyes off her for a moment. She's just gone over to Mr Adam's.
'HavEn'T tAkEN mY eYEs ofF Her fOr a mOmENt'.
Useless idiot!
What are you doing here?
I thought I'd see Guria...
I know you inside out.
Always known you as Adam...
But it appears time has changed your name!
Guria, is it? Lovely...
Where are you off to?
Why?
I asked you why.
I want an answer. Not a question.
Mr Malik asked me to get some papers. May I?
That better be it.
I don't want you coming back with a wedge to drive between us forever. Get it?
Looks like he plans to kill us today...
He seems to have sent us our Last Supper!
Hello?
You there yet?
Yeah.
Don't tell me you don't see her around.
I think I see her...
Pink scarf. Holding a baby.
-Yeah... That's her!
Please... Don't let her go... Please stop her...
Okay.
Okay...
Thank God...
Got a problem?
Well -- I...
Aye, you what?
Lemme make it very clear to you. If you tried to paw me or ask for my number, I'm gonna smite you proper! Now bog off!
We need to talk.
Hmm...
'Need to talk', eh? Feel like coming on to a poor little lonely girl, eh?
God damn your 'talk' to hell!
-Mehek sent me!
Mehek sent me!
Mehek sent me here...
Please... Enjoy the meal.
I don't feel hungry.
But I am...
Bimey, my tongue hasn't tasted this fortune in ages!
I'd rather not turn down His gifts...
I wonder why you're being so kind...
He's my nephew.
Oh...
So... It appears you don't even spare family...
Can it!
Give me a moment...
I'll take anything you throw at me after I'm finished...
I can see the true purpose of this feast peeking from behind the curtain of care...
Go on... What do you want?
Tell him...
He thinks I've got some pity left for him in my heart that will come out some day...
Tell him he's waiting for the impossible.
Your ruthlessness is as clear as the day...
I don't need to tell him...
Look into my ageing eyes...
They bear witness to your tyranny.
Look at my unkempt beard, my scruffy hair...
No words can speak more clearly...
Don't start with me.
Tell him.
Tell him he better...
Get married to my daughter.
But --
She'd be barely 13!
Aye...
How do I know...
It's been 14 years...
I've been in here 14 years...
Take it away. They're not getting anything for three days.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe