What happened?
Too crippled by your repentance to look me in the eye?
True...
I've always been true...
To my love for you...
To the flimsy illusion you conjured up...
And to myself... All my life...
But you...
Like every puny liar before you, you tried erasing my truth with your lies...
Here to say sorry, I presume?
How selfish of you!
I swear you're not really sorry or something... You just want to ease yourself...
Ease the burden that won't let you live in peace or die in peace...
By somehow 'earning' my forgiveness.
All I see is a selfish man, veiled behind regret, seeking to achieve another one of his ends.
That's true too...
But there's one more thing...
Something that I value more than my regret or easing the burden of my sin...
I loved you --
-Enough... Just... Shut up...
Love has been helpless for ages...
Don't insult it anymore.
The walls have ears... So stop it before they two-time the ground beneath them and crumble.
I'll answer everything you said...
I loved you too...
You were my first and last love...
Because I gave you...
Everything...
But now... I hate you...
As purely as I loved you.
Because there's no truer hate than what follows true love...
Forgiveness is too valuable...
It's all I've got left...
So don't even think I'm gonna forgive you...
Big words...
When you've been betrayed, shaken... But somehow take it all in...
18 years starts to feel like 80...
May I look at you one last time?
-No!
Go!
Don't even leave your filthy footprints here!
I was so scared... He threatened to kill me... Told me there's a lion and all... Believe me!
Any idea where he could've taken her?
-To the estate.
What've I told him...
'Adam <3'
The Reverend's here!
Just say 'I will'...
And many congratulations will reverb in this room...
Refuse...
And gunfire will reverb here.
Bring the Reverend here!
... follow the path of Marriage, to love and honour each other for as long as you both shall live?
In this life and the next... I'll love and honour no one but my Adam!
What d'you think you're doing?
Sort it out between yourselves before calling me, Mr Malik.
Get out!
Lemme tell you...
Don't even think about it!
I'll kill myself than let your sinful hands touch me! Back off!
Guddi!
Guddi...
Going somewhere?
Yeah. Just pray for me, okay?
Breakfast?
No, thanks.
Just... Pray for me.
Guddi!
Almost at the hospital... You'll be fine!
The doctors will save you... I pray you live long! Guddi!
You'll be fine... Guddi...
Guddi!
Guddi...
M'boy... Hush...
Yeah?
Does Mehek live here?
What do I tell her?
Tell her someone's dying to see her.
Okay...
You can't be --
S -- Shahmir's Dad?
Shahmir... Lovely name...
Come in!
Doctor... How's she? Please... Tell me everything... She'll be fine, right?
She needs blood... O-. You wouldn't happen to know --
-I'm O-, doctor!
Give her every last drop of blood within me... But I pray you... Save her...
Okay...
Nurse! Come here!
Take him to the lab and check his blood group.
-Okay.
-Which way?
In the Lord's name...
-Mehek!
Mehek!
What happened?
-It's -- Shahmir's Dad! He's here!
What?
-Yeah... Shahmir's Dad...
Shayan...
C'mon!
Quickly...
What happened? Why'd you stop here?
You sure it's him? Shayan...
I've waited so long... I can't believe it...
I've started seeing things... Hearing things... That made me come here like this... Only to find no one...
My heart is weak...
If he isn't here... My heart may not survive the pain...
I'd die...
No, Mehek...
I swear by Shahmir...
How are you?
I'm fine but... How's she? She'll be fine, won't she?
-Let's hope...
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ My resolve faded as an aching wound took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ You were distant though so near ♪
♪ You're distant yet so dear ♪
♪ You etched your name on my heart, right here ♪
♪ You forgot me, yet you're dear... ♪
Pull me up...
Curse me...
Grab my collar and ask me...
Slap me if you want too...
But please... Don't torment me with this silence...
All of that is done...
To those who matter...
Your love makes you do it...
But... You don't matter to me anymore...
Your betrayal smothered my love.
I or my son don't care about you one bit!
You've wronged us both...
And this is your sentence...
Go. Just go!
I swear it's not my fault!
Fate has been unkind...
Too unkind...
Almost...
Like a mortal enemy...
Every moment I've lived without you, I've prayed to get to see you again...
Begged the declining dusk, the endless night, and the blinding day...
To have...
To have just an ounce of mercy...
It's not my fault...
But fate has been unkind... To both of us...
Then... Tell me... Give me reason to believe you're innocent! Tell me what happened!
My loyalty warns me against listening to a cheat like you...
Reminding, cautioning, screaming, and begging me not to fall for your lies again...
Alright...
I've never asked for anything in life...
Didn't know... Didn't want to know how...
You're the first thing I'm asking for, Guddi...
I've lost a lot in life...
A lot...
But you...
You're the first reward that's truly and sincerely mine... Let me reap it, mate...
You're fine now, Guddi...
So get up, byt. C'mon...
How's she, Doctor?
She's safe now. She'll come to any moment.
Thank you, my Lord...
Thank You...
Doctor...
If she's fine now, could I go? Got something to do...
Of course.
You may go.
Thank you.
-Okay.
I beg you... And my son...
To forgive me... For giving in...
For not being there for you... When you needed me the most...
My heart wants to believe everything you've said... It believes every word you've said...
But my mind warns me against it... Against falling for it again...
How do I pay a deaf ear to my mind?
It's suffered a lot...
Suffered a lot...
If you don't believe me... Ask Adam.
He got me out of that place.
What?
A -- Adam got you out?
Don't worry... Daddy's here...
Shahmir...
Enough...
I'm tired of living a suffocating lie...
I've got to tell Grandpa everything...
Gotta tell him...
Everything...
Yeah, Kheru?
No one here, Adam...
No one? Where'd he go?
Malik flippin' Jr!
Mehek... I made a big mistake...
What happened?
Malik Jr!
Where's he?
Enough, Mehek...
Enough...
Adam won't 'yes' you this time. Where's Malik Jr?
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe