♪ I'm a falling star ♪
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ 'The sages all lie', she sayeth, ♪
♪ 'Thou canst not reunite those who've parted ways'; ♪
♪ 'Not one can make him return -' ♪
♪ 'The one for whom I yearn...' ♪
The train's always half an hour late! But it's here!
Maybe one of the toffs is on board...
Or maybe someone's been waiting too long...
Aren't you here to work?
They'll come to me when they need me.
There's three porters around... And a lot of passengers! They get to decide how much they're gonna pay!
Be grateful for what you can get, or the Lord takes everything from you! Amour, cœur, and grandeur!
See you!
O Lord... She's back...
My girl...
Mehek...
Realising my dreams;
My prayers have borne fruit.
My Lord, Thou art great because Thou art just.
It would be injustice to all of mankind if I, the lord of this bourg, chose to remain blind to injustice.
She never let the battle for justice cease after my son's death...
She's earned the highest degree in law as I wished.
You heard my prayers.
You grant the wishes of those who ask for Your help.
So I pray Thee - never let my daughter weep, O Lord. Never...
Right or left -- Oops! That was close!
Hello?
Qutbuddin? It's Mehek.
Mehek! It's Munna!
Qutbuddin's reading the news. I nicked his mobile to play games. Please don't tell him.
I won't. Don't worry. I called Grandpa but he isn't answering.
Tell him I'll be there in 20 minutes.
You're coming? Grandpa was praying. He was about to go pick you up!
But wasn't your train supposed to come at 7?
Yeah. Got here early.
You promised you'd get me a touchscreen mobile.
Yeah. I've got you.
Really?
Really.
Okay. I'll go tell Grandpa.
Everyone's suspecting each other
Because they've seen you on that bike follow our bus!
So what?
I wait all night for the morning... For that one glimpse of you.
When you get to the college, I wait for the afternoon...
You don't even get to see me everytime!
Do you see me?
Let's just say I manage to... Even if I have to push a few people around...
That's it, then.
What?
If you love someone and get to see him... It's Christmas indeed.
And there's nothing like him seeing you without you finding out!
Roshni!
What's with the screaming?
You'll have to hear it to believe it!
Yeah?
Mehek's coming!
Okay, get me some water...
Close...
Mum would kill me if Munna told anyone I had a phone.
I could've gotten you another.
You only live once.
I meant another phone.
Adam!
Remember when you got these?
I cried a lot, but you didn't give me those bangles.
I asked who they're for.
You never told me. Just... Got another.
But you never gave these to anyone.
You always bought two gifts every Christmas. You'd give one to me, and one to this cupboard.
I can see right through you now.
No longer my old, kiddish self.
Why don't you put it plainly, Guria? Why do you want to waste so many words?
This cupboard's opened again after two years for her, right?
These bangles... They're for Mehek, right?
Guria! Adam! Mehek's back!
-Munna!
Let's see... A change in the traffic laws...
Fines increased!
Overspeeding... Doubled from 750 to 1,500!
Blimey, that's unfair...
Ma'am!
Come in!
Meh --
Mehek's on her way! She's coming back!
There goes his siren...
Munna! Get a cloth and clean his mouth. It's gonna get dirty the moment his siren stops.
Your Dad's sweet little girl is back. This place is hers now.
She's inferior to me in her relationship to him, her age and status.
But Dad thinks so highly of her!
That's why I grow restless...
As if your cough wasn't enough, now I'll have to toss around all night like a snake, haunted by the authority he's gonna give her!
My dear Zulaikha...
-Eh?
The Minister of State for Railways said a few days back that the trains would arrive on time. Looking at how Mehek's train got here on time, and how easily our people get swayed, we may be looking at our next Prime Minister!
Shut up! Out of my sight! Bloody politician...
Everything fine?
Thank you.
Ask the driver to get the car out.
No need for that!
Why?
She's coming here!
She told you herself?
I could hear that she was on a carriage when she called. I think her train got here early!
Okay...
Thank God.
Okay, go...
You have been kind, O Lord.
Did the bars budge, or did they just wear down your poor little saw?
You never told me what brought you here,
But looking at your obstinacy,
I dare to imagine that that brought you down this rabbit hole.
Keep at it, mate...
Hello! How are you? How was the journey?
-Hello. Help me with these?
-Hello!
Great.
-I'll go tell them inside!
Here...
Uhh... What's your name again...?
Guddi.
Yeah. Come here.
Hold him.
Come with me.
C'mon, quickly!
Hello, Grandpa!
-Hello. Welcome back!
How are you?
-Never been better.
Hello, Aunt.
Hello...
And who would that be?
G -- Grandpa... Remember --?
Yeah. We can talk later. Come in.
How've you been?
Come, Guddi.
Hello.
-Hello.
-Come.
You're late.
Just 15 minutes. But -- You don't even have a clock here!
Silence fills the empty cell...
This bloke never says a word...
The most I can hear is my breath...
I count them to pass the time...
That's how I know...
What?
You'll know when it's your time...
What do you mean?
Go and play, little innocent one...
You won't have to work at it...
When it's your time, you'll realise...
Go...
Oh, shut your trap!
Come, have some...
You'll need more than just tenacity to break free.
Here.
Bless you, my dear.
Why don't you bless her?
Good... Sit.
Get us our lunch. My little girl's back home after two years!
Mehek...
One look at you has made all the waiting worth it.
Grandpa...
I've waited for this day too...
Bless you.
Mehek...
You haven't told us about her.
Who is she?
She worked at Mehek's hostel.
She's the maid?
Why is she sitting on the sofa?
Get up!
Only equals can sit like equals!
I've never considered her a maid.
She's like a sister.
As if we needed any more servants! Why'd you have to bring one from overseas?
She's been... Most unfortunate, Aunt... She needs help.
How?
Take her upstairs. Get some rest before lunch.
Okay, Grandpa.
I wonder what she's done that is so unspeakable!
Come, Guddi. Let me show you your place.
Where's she staying?
The room next to mine.
There are many rooms for servants behind the mansion.
I'm used to taking her help. It'd be nice if she were close by.
Don't even think about it!
You know we let things be as Mehek wants. Willy nilly.
Go. Take her upstairs. Get some rest.
Okay. Come, Guddi...
I wonder why she had to bring her along!
Mehek told me that she's a helpless orphan.
She's real fortunate... For a helpless orphan. I mean... Look at how easily she got a visa!
Please don't mind anything Aunt said... Forgive her.
Hold him properly, will you? What's his fault?
I beg you, forgive her.
I'll do my best to make sure you don't have any trouble.
Where's my room?
Here.
Indeed, the Lord has been very kind...
The thing is... Someone took a liking to Guddi.
Someone from the UK.
He took her with him after their marriage.
But, as fate would have it, her happiness was short-lived...
He lost his life in an accident three months later,
Leaving Guddi alone in a foreign land.
The poor girl...
Freshen up and come downstairs.
60 days. We agreed. It's 58 now.
So we did.
Don't worry. I remember.
I don't lie.
Oh really?
You're telling me! You said you'd save me from disgrace! I've seen just how well... Blimey...
You brought me here as your partner in crime, to give your lie some credibility...! And you're telling me! I don't lie, byt!
I've sinned a thousand times, but not once by lying. Always bold, always audacious. It doesn't lessen my sin, but it does my guilt.
You better tell your Aunt to mind her venomous tongue, for I can breathe fire! I've charred many Goliaths to ash!
Calm down. I'll talk to her.
Aye. You better.
She had no one.
So my girl brought her along.
I'm proud of her.
That's very kind of her. The Lord would be pleased.
-Indeed.
A bit weak if you ask me...
What?
Her story...
I can't make head or tail of it... But I do see the stinking carcass of this cock and bull story. Don't you?
Keep your questions to yourself.
This is my place.
Everything will be as I want it. I hope you don't forget that.
I'm forgiving your first transgression. You better not do it again.
Step aside!
What happened?
My youthful self has never listened to anyone else...
Oh, to live for 58 days, longing to see my old self in the mirror, who couldn't live for but 58 minutes without maquillage...
Oh, to feel the fury, the anger, but be too helpless to even break the wretched mirror!
Lunch has been served.
I said, lunch has been served.
Yeah, I heard it the first time you said it.
Come downstairs.
C'mon, my shawl... The apple of my Dad and brother's eyes... I'm sure you've been yearning to rest on my head! Looks like it's your day!
Iesu... Yeah, I haven't forgotten you!
Munna!
Yeah, Adam?
How are you?
Great!
Something you wanted to ask?
-No.
Hey!
Yeah?
How's everyone?
Great.
Okay, go...
And, Munna...
How's Mehek?
Looks great. Doesn't seem to be.
What do you mean? Did she say something?
She didn't say anything. But I heard it.
What?
She used to laugh at every other word...
-And now?
She doesn't smile... Doesn't even join in when everyone's laughing!
That it?
-Yeah. Go.
It pains me so much to hear about Guddi... So kind of you to bring her along.
Her baby's lovely, isn't it?
Yeah. Very.
What did her husband do?
Sorry?
What is it?
Didn't she tell you?
No...
He's crying...
For God's sake, shut up...
Iesu...
It used to be your cough...
Now, that girl has brought another way to give me sleepless nights!
I'll go see...
The poor kid...
What's up with the noise?
Take her back inside.
He was crying inside.
I thought he'd stop if he got some fresh air.
Well you better not take your thoughts out for some fresh air again.
Roshni's Dad isn't well. The noise bothers him.
Go!
Okay...
Tell me...
Yeah?
Did Dad send your fees on time?
Of course.
Yet it appears you had to sell your decency and good form for this degree!
What do you mean?
I don't get it.
Your Uncle's unwell.
He loves you more than his daughters.
But you never bothered to see him. Check on him.
I --
I'll go see him now...
Hello, Uncle...
Hello.
I hope you're well.
I don't know...
I just know I'm... Still around...
May the Lord give you health.
-Amen.
I'll be back.
You won't forget, will you?
Of course not.
Cau dy geg!
What is it?
Well, what d'you think? He needs his Mam! That's you, numbskull!
Here!
-Keep your voice down!
My boy...
I've tried 70 different ways... It sure ain't love he's craving!
He needs milk!
I got you...
Munna...
Take care of him!
Munna! I hope he hasn't heard us...
Wait... Munna!
Dyw dyw dyw... Put a sock in it!
Munna! Wait!
Munna!
Munna! Stop!
Munna! Open the door!
For God's sake, open the door!
Munna! Please open this door...
Okay... I'm giving your touchscreen mobile to someone else.
What'd you hear?
Nothing... Just the baby crying...
Don't lie...
I -- I can't...
Why'd you run away if you didn't hear anything?
I thought you'd ask me what I was doing if you caught me...
You've heard it, haven't you?
Munna... Please, for God's sake, forget everything.
If you didn't, you may slip in your innocence at the wrong time... I'd be disgraced in everyone's eyes...
Please...
Mehek...
You're my master, but if I had to have a sister... It'd be someone like you...
I just love your smile... I don't want anything to wipe it off your face... Ever...
And... My touchscreen mobile?
I haven't unpacked my things. You'll get it in the morning.
Hup horsey...
My boy...
See this.
Here.
Look here...
Daddy!
Daddy...
It's you!
Thank you for the address.
Don't mention it. I'll call her, okay?
Okay.
Mehek! Someone for you at the door.
For me? Are you sure?
Yeah. This way.
-Thanks.
What's your problem?
Y -- You...
Wha -- Me?
No... I meant...
Who told you I have a problem?
No one needs to tell me. Your cheap monkey tricks scream 'GODAWFUL PROBLEM' in capital letters!
Kill me if you will, but don't call yourself godawful.
What?
How dare you call me godawful?
Just -- How dare you?
-God forbid... I'd die before I say that!
God forbid... I'd die before I say that!
You said I have a godawful problem...
And my problem... Is you...
So, as in, indirectly...
Please shut up! I mean -- Shut up!
It ain't no monkey tricks! I'm just telling you my problem.
I was the bookish type. I used to be tranquil, calm, and relaxed...
Until I saw you...
Now, I've started failing...
I'm restless...
Craving...
Looking at you...
I realise it's you I crave...
As I look into your eyes, I find the same old tranquility.
I've got this beautiful problem...
Shut up...
Just shut up!
-I hold you in the highest regard.
And... I love you.
No...
Don't say anything just yet...
I'll be in the foyer tomorrow.
I'll be waiting outside.
Draw the curtain in slow motion, look down, and smile...
I'll take it as a yes and shake a leg like there's no tomorrow.
Shanzay!
You b --
Where are you running? Wait!
-Hey! It wasn't me!
Wait! Lemme tell you!
Mehek!
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪