I've been waiting for ages!
I got up the moment I got word...
Had to stop when Mum asked me to...
There's something you must know...
-I'm all ears. Go on.
Munna...
Where's Grandpa?
In his room... Smiling to himself...
Okay... And Aunt?
In her room staring emptily at the ceiling. I asked her if she'd like to have breakfast but she didn't say a word.
Okay. Go and wait outside Grandpa's room... And come here and tell me the moment he steps out. Okay?
Okay.
Mehek...
I'm waiting.
What is it?
What should've happened long ago.
But better late than never...
What?
I want a divorce...
Good Lord...
What happened?
'Divorce'... They say the sound of it makes the heavens tremble...
That's why I exclaimed...
What do you think?
Shouldn't I be doing this?
I wouldn't dare call right what the Lord detests the most.
But... It's your life...
Your decision...
You can say that I'm wrong...
I give you the right...
Shayan's wrong.
In fact... It's a massive understatement...
He's depraved. Vile...
But you've made a mistake too...
Aye.
I know.
I couldn't see through his lies...
I lost my heart to him without a thought...
I've made a big mistake...
To love is not to err, Mehek, and I won't say you're wrong for loving him...
You should've looked him in the eye and asked him why he chose to betray you.
Strange, yes, but I've got this feeling that he's got his reasons... Something else...
It'd be most unfortunate if he chose to betray someone like you.
If you ask me, Adam...
The loyal don't give in to any kind of 'reasons'...
They'd rather die...
Than betray...
Get my divorce papers ready.
Think again.
Wait a day...
I've thought it over a hundred times...
I've come to the same conclusion every time.
I want a divorce.
Okay. Just one condition.
-I accept everything.
I'll go there myself.
Ask him why.
Okay...
But get the papers ready.
I'll get going...
Could you do me another favour?
I could give you my life.
You couldn't --
Give my son -- Your name -- Could you?
Aliya...
What is it?
Hear that drum? It's from inside!
Yeah...
Good Lord...
Don't worry.
It's a celebration!
A celebration... That's when it gets ready to strike...
-What?
Grief...
I'll get going... Got to get some papers ready...
I don't think you've got the time to have tea now, yes?
Yeah... Well... No...
I'm so sorry...
No.
You don't need to be.
Have it your way.
Congratulations, Adam!
Didn't see you were here...
But -- Mr Malik...
What's the news?
I'm alive again!
One word of good news is all it took to scare every pain away.
Malik Jr's better!
Great...
Great indeed, Mr Malik... Congratulations!
Our prayers have been heard.
-Of course...
Munna! Get some flowers! M'boy's back! I want a grand welcome!
Everything's ready. Shall we?
Looks like that's Dad's car.
-Come.
How are you?
-Great!
Okay, that's enough, stop it!
In the Lord's name...
Why'd you tell them to stop? Don't you like it?
-Oh, I love it!
I just wanted to hear the happiness I see in your eyes.
Why'd you hide it? Why didn't you tell us you're feeling better?
You know me inside out.
I don't like to keep things half-done.
I thought I'd give you a lasting good news when I'm back to full health!
I hope you're happy.
Very.
Very happy to see you... So happy my eyes...
Are brimming with happiness...
Adam!
Good to see you like this again, Mr Malik.
I don't remember thanking another man in my life.
But Adam's the only one who's been there for me.
I thank you from the bottom of my heart.
You're embarrassing me...
I don't mean to...
I want you to be proud.
Right now, I'd just need your blessings...
Come. Everyone's waiting for you.
I'll be back in a while... Something came up.
Take care. Congratulations.
-See you. Thank you so much!
Why've you stopped it? Let's get back to it!
-Yeah, c'mon!
What are you looking at?
-Nothing...
Not you, at least...
Just looking at your shawl...
Gotta say, it's powerful...
Pleases the Lord when on your head...
And when you lower your gaze...
And your voice... And soften your tone...
Every Tom, Dick, and Harry would testify to your purity.
Oh...
I wish I knew this before...
But it's too late for me...
I wish I could cover myself up like you...
What are you saying?
-Oh, I wouldn't dare...
I won't even dare wish and think...
Bless you two... Adam and you...
Please, Mr Khan...
Eyes used to staring and commanding don't deserve to be lowered like that!
Or is it that you've conceded defeat before the battle's even begun?
You know I haven't.
-Okay...
I didn't know you lowered your gaze when you've won.
First time I heard that.
I'm lowering my eyes...
So your rebellious eyes...
And my fury...
Doesn't defeat my restraint!
Because I value your life more than my victory.
You couldn't -- Give my son -- Your name -- Could you?
I don't think you've got the time to have tea now, yes?
Hey, Adam! Adam!
Where are you off to?
Home?
Doesn't look like it.
What do you mean?
-You left your place way behind.
Thanks.
Dad... I just prayed for one miracle all this time...
That you get better...
Bless you, my girl...
Honestly...
I never believed it before...
But when you don't get what you wish for...
And you're drowning in helplessness...
Sometimes...
Grasping at the straws does indeed help...
Every time I saw a falling star...
I prayed for your health.
Thank you. All of you.
Where's Zulaikha? Why isn't she here to celebrate?
She's too surprised...
Too happy...
Like too much grief...
Too much happiness can be... Crippling...
I'll see her in a while.
I'll get Roshni...
-No.
I'll see her in a while too.
Mehek!
Why are you standing there?
-Good to see you back.
Good to see you too.
What is it?
Nothing?
What happened to those bright eyes?
Why do I see worry in there instead?
It's nothing like that...
It better be nothing like that.
If there's something - or someone - bothering you... Just let me know.
Malik Jr's back from sick leave...
Sickness dares not change him one bit...
Care to knock?
No!
I don't care about anything...
Except plucking every thorn in Mr Khan's side!
Try me. I'm right here.
How dare you?
I'll show you!
What happened?
Feel weak yet?
I'll divorce your sister!
How?
Gonna scream it in your dying voice? Write it down with a bloodied hand?
I'll do the same with Masooma!
Get it?
Now get out!
Yeah, I'm leaving for the courthouse.
Hmm...
Divorce, yeah...
I need the papers for a divorce...
Yeah, it's urgent.
Yeah, I'm coming.
For Mehek?
Yeah.
What about you?
I just want some peace...
How'd you get it?
By seeing everyone happy.
What about your happiness?
-I just told you...
I'd be happy to see everyone happy.
-No, Adam...
The one who's spent his life making everyone happy...
Deserves happiness more than the rest of them.
Pray for me, then...
Pray that the Lord does what's best for me.
Pray for me, will you?
Guddi?
What?
I want to see her.
Why?
You don't know how much it hurts to hear a 'why' from a son who never said anything but 'yes'.
I'll tell Munna to introduce you to her.
-And yes...
Never forget that my son is more than just a caring heart and a shoulder to cry on.
I won't let anyone's tears curse the man that he is.
Take care.
Behold...
What light from yonder window breaks...
It is the east...
And Guddi is the sun.
And so I rise to welcome the day...
Why are you doing this?
Get used to it.
You've got to listen to my compliments all your life.
Just give me some time...
Your ears, your hands...
Have been so lonely...
I'll get you some earrings and bangles tomorrow.
Lovely kid, by the way.
Go.
I'll be coming in a sec.
I'll get going...
-Gotta say...
Your husband is -- was -- so unfortunate...
In his place...
I would've stood up against the Reaper...
Had it come to take me away from you.
I'd never have left you...
Step aside.
Too coy...
Sometimes, it feels like it wouldn't suit anyone else...
Just give me the order and I'll divorce her and take the kids away.
I'd gladly --
No.
Not just yet...
My daughter's life is at stake.
Go.
There!
Bless you, Asher Khan.
-Thank you for giving me your time, Reverend.
I had a feeling you're going to need me last night...
Who knows, I might've called you in a while myself...
I'm in awe of your powers.
So, what is it that worries you?
First time I'm --
Afraid...
Because --
The one who never dared to look me in the eye...
Is now poised to pounce on me like a lion!
He doesn't fear anything now... Says my daughter will be widowed... Or divorced...
He says it like he means it...
God forgive him!
Don't worry, Asher Khan... I'm with you. Or is it that you no longer believe I can do anything?
I need your help, Reverend.
I got my little girl married off to him because you said so. Only you can help me.
Don't worry. Everything will be fine... I'll be back in a week...
What if it's too late? What if he --
God forgive you...
You have turned to disbelief in every way, Asher Khan.
It's a long way down.
No, Reverend...
I'm relieved to hear it...
Thank you...
Can't believe you got that little girl married off! How cruel!
It'd be cruel if a saint did it...
Cruelty is but a habit for some of us...
The only thing I can't believe is it's his own daughter...
You've got daughters too!
Don't you dare say another word!
You better mind your tongue.
I can bludgeon you with the silverware I just brought you if I wanted!
What a shame it'd be if they heard your powers couldn't even save you from your own wife!
I'm sorry... Just got a bit angry because you mentioned my girl...
Maybe next time, you could try drowning your anger in a glass of water, chanting your deceptive spells, and gulping it down!
Keep your voice down... What if one of my disciples heard it?
How dare you shut me up?
Just pray you never face someone who can see right through you! It'll be your end!
For God's sake... Keep your voice down!
I'm doing all of this for you!
So you can live comfortably...
Were you out of options that you chose this deceptive trickery in the guise of a saint?
What could I do?
I remember how hard I worked...
As a labourer...
As a driver...
Served people with loyalty...
Served people who'd give me what I deserved like they were doing a favour!
And...
That's when I decided...
To take my share..
Of their riches...
Fear. That's the only thing that you can deal in.
Make them fear...
Make them feel helpless... Don't let them make head or tail of it...
Tell the mighty their downfall awaits them...
Tell the wealthy...
They're about to be broke...
Have your men as their servants...
So you know everything...
Add 'Reverend' to your name...
Look the part...
Move out... And live a good life...
But aye...
Keep praying for me...
I fear that one day I'd be facing someone who can see right through me... It'll be the end of me!
His Highness is here.
Tell him I'll be coming in a second...
Get my lunch ready... I'll be back...
Another coward's here for my help...
I'll be back...
Shahmir!
Munna!
Go.
Munna! Water!
Aye, Mr Malik!
Mum?
Mum? What happened?
What is it?
-No idea. Heard something break inside...
What happened, Dad? Heard something break...
It's nothing...
The glass slipped from Munna's hand...
Fell and broke...
That's all.
Don't worry, Mehek...
Go.
Okay.
I -- I'll get another...
-No!
Just. Go.
Whatever happens, do not come near my room.
Yeah?
I need a few things. Right now.
Order me.
Sure. On my way.
Munna!
Here!
Yeah?
I'm so worried... I want to see Shahmir... Hold him again...
Please bring him here.
-Just a sec.
Here...
The best coal I could find...
And the strongest rope...
I expected no less.
I wouldn't dare turn you down.
What'd you do with it?
Tie things?
Of course.
I'm gonna tie something too...
And...
What'd you do with coal?
Light a fire?
-Aye...
That's what I'm gonna do too...
But why?
Don't worry...
I'm not gonna burn your sister...
Go back to the estate and call me...
I'll tell you what's next...
Okay.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe