What's the matter?
Untie me and I'll untie you.
Naw, mate... I can't do it...
I can't even untie myself...
Wait... Lemme help you first...
D'you know why we've kept you with them?
I tried to run away...
-Nah, ain't that...
You broke out before... Came back too...
I've chained the good Samaritan in you who would've helped them break free, whether you like it or not.
To the devil with them... I just saw the gun in his hand... Thought it's like the movies... A knight here to save his princess...
It's not like I really saw you as villains! Remember that actor bloke?
He told me that everyone comes here to play the knights... They only become villains if they're forced to...
I thought I'd help the knight...
I've told you the truth...
Please untie me... I've got this awful itch in my head...
Well, guess what, without the villains...
The knights can do little besides play with the kids or get the groceries...
Speaking of which...
The knights are as heroic as their villains evil!
But in the legend of Ruby... There's just this great villain who's got the puny knight chained and helpless!
Madame!
C'mon, now...
Move back...
Back...
Quick!
-How?
Untie me! Quick!
You're sending her to school?
Yeah...
She's got an exam today...
Look at yourself...
She's about to get married...
Instead of getting the girl ready for her marriage... You're sending her off to school!
It's your responsibility too, just in case!
Thank goodness...
You don't normally think this way, but...
Thank goodness you said she's just a girl.
Shut up and get me breakfast.
No one's going anywhere.
Get her dressed properly.
Hello?
You're so fake!
-I'm as real as it gets in love.
You lost your mind?
When you asked me to hold your hand...
My eyes were fixed on you.
I lost my mind the moment I saw your beauty...
You might even find it lying 'round there...
Don't prolong this scene with another monologue.
Now, listen to this... The thorn on our side is the reason we get to see each other.
Don't let her know her new worth.
Give her husband what'll cure him... Not what'll kill him! He'll cure her himself!
And... Get back to work... Don't mourn losing your mind. I can give you a piece of mine if you want.
Got it.
Untie me!
Hey!
Where are you off to?
Shut up!
-Untie me and --
There's no better time to run away! For God's sake, untie me!
Please... Untie us...
You off your head? Because I'm not... Not most of the time, at least...
You want me to set you free so you can get away with your girl while Madame Ruby eats me alive?
Or d'you want me to come with you?
For the love of God, just do me a favour and help me? Please?
Favours will be rewarded on the Day of Judgement. I don't care about anything that won't help me now.
-Please... You're a woman too!
That's precisely why, genius! I'll go tell her I had the chance, but didn't run away!
She'll appreciate it... And reward me! Ta ta!
-Untie me! Hey!
You can't do that! I helped you because you said you'll help me! Hey! Wait!
Anyone there?
Aliya?
Anyone around here?
-Mum... What happened?
What is it?
-Aliya...
I just saw her in my dream...
-Who?
Roshni!
There's this lake... She's drowning...
And they're all watching her beg for help...
They're laughing at it... Enjoying it...
-Mum...
My girl...
Madame...
Madame Ruby?
Madame R --
God forgive me...
I made such a big mistake... A grave mistake...
Please don't punish me like this...
-You've made a mistake...
A mistake...
That we're all being punished for...
Grandpa...
Had a heart attack...
Change of plans.
Now I've got the money... And Madame Ruby's jewellery! I'm open do do any favours I can!
So, what would you have me do?
-Just untie me...
And guess what...
I got your gun too!
Untie my hands... Yeah...
C'mon!
Where d'you think you're going? I'll fix you!
Get off her!
Quick!
-C'mon!
Stop them! Guards!
Guards! Where are you?
Guards!
What the --
No!
Jesus...
Get up! Get up, you morons!
Outside!
Here.
Come!
What th --
No! Hold your fire!
You let them get away! Useless, incompetent morons!
Double time!
Faster!
Just a sec!
Other side! Get in!
♪ Some say I'm Guddi... ♪
(Humming 'Some say I'm a sweetie')
First time I've taken a U-turn...
I don't normally change my mind, Dr Guddi!
I'd die if I heard that again...
-Please don't talk about dying...
Don't get on my bad side, okay?
-But you are on the bad side...
Ehh? What?
You're on the good side and the bad side... I don't see anyone else!
Go, now...
-Huh?
Don't let Madame suspect there isn't even her shadow on your heart...
Ah, yes... Okay... I'll get going.
Dr Guddi!
Shayan!
The Reverend will be here today.
You're getting married on the day he picks.
Congratulations to you.
Congratulations to you too.
Be done with it now, okay?
We're twice as close now...
You're also gonna be my son-in-law.
Tauqir!
I got you these suits.
Pick your favourite.
Show him, Tauqir.
Try the other one.
Ah!
They're all yours. Keep the ones you like.
I like this one.
Show him the rest.
Gotta say, you're clever...
You had your car ready!
You planned for everything, didn't you? Anyway... Who's she to you?
Ah, yes...
And... I nicked this phone on the way...
Just switched it on...
Wanted to see what kind of a man you are...
Looks like it's locked...
Someone's calling...
Hello?
-Thank God! Hello? Adam?
Thank God! Hello? Adam?
First time I've prayed since my GCSEs!
But I'm glad now... I thought the Lord wouldn't hear me after everything I've done... I guess they're right after all... Wish sincerely and He gives...
What'd you ask for?
-Your phone switching on, and your voice reaching my ears.
You know me inside out, you know I know you inside out.
Why don't you just say it?
When you start caring for someone, he ought to know you need something.
What d'you want?
-Just told you. I wanted to hear your voice.
I know my heart inside out.
It's gonna want to see you. And I know the trick...
I'm gonna get back to praying that you come back!
We're at the bus station. We part ways here. Take care.
-Thank you.
I've called out to you fifty times in the last thirty minutes.
But you don't say a word...
Not even 'hmm' me...
Zulaikha...
Guria...
Mehek...
-What happened?
Not a word from Adam all night... No idea where he is...
I said I got to clean the room... If Mum saw me crying, she'll ask why...
She'd be distressed if she found out...
His phone's switched on!
Why don't you take it?
Hello?
Where are you?
On my way.
On your way where?
Home.
Got anything?
Yeah.
What?
I'm coming back with my promise.
What? She's with you?
Yeah. Right here.
Could I talk to her?
Here.
It's Mehek.
H -- Hello?
You alright?
Don't know...
I just know I'm coming back...
I'm very scared... Mum will kill me...
No one will say anything... Just... Get back here quick...
Before we're all disgraced before everyone.
We're on our way.
Give Adam the phone.
-Okay.
Yeah?
I don't think we can ever pay back this favour...
But I pray all your dreams become your reality...
May He guard the honour of your family and your descendants...
May He give you everything you wish for...
However distant it may seem...
You know that can't happen...
Uhh...
I mean...
Once I've brought Roshni back...
I've got to take someone to her destination.
Please be ready. I am.
Take care.
Something you must see, Mehek!
I got to go home... Got something I must --
-Just a minute!
How d'you like these?
-Lovely... I'll have a look later... I gotta go. Bye!
Good Lord... So unfortunate...
She missed her chance to rejoice!
Have some water?
You didn't tell me how you got there.
Don't worry. It's between us.
Ah!
I thought I'd grab your hand and stop you... But remembered I gotta ask for it...
It'd hurt me if you didn't let me...
So I thought I'd rather not grieve my heart when I can take a good look instead...
Talked to Madame?
-Tried my best.
Tried until I thought trying would hurt my ego.
That's when I came out... Don't worry... She'd call me any moment...
There!
Where are you?
Right here...
I'm sorry...
I've lost my mind ever since Roshni eloped... I can't think of anything...
Come here quick... I need you.
Okay.
What'd she say?
She says she...
'Needs' me!
Holy Mary... Bless you... Are you actually happy, or am I just seeing things?
You won't believe it!
-What?
Adam fulfilled his promise! He's found Roshni!
He's on his way.
I'm needed elsewhere...
Shh!
He's just dozed off! Don't disturb him!
Guess what! They've found Roshni!
-Great!
Good Lord...
-I'll go check...
Help us, O Lord...
He's helped us.
-What do you mean?
The shroud of honour you'd woven all your life...
Has been saved...
What happened?
We've found Roshni!
Really?
You've been kind, my Lord...
Very kind indeed...
Thank You...
What happened?
Nothing.
I was washing the glass when it slipped...
But why are you crying?
Just my luck!
-What happened?
One of the glasses had to break by my hand!
The set won't be complete now...
I hate to see incomplete things...
Even if it's 5/6 of the way.
Move aside...
I gotta clean this?
By the Lord... I talked to Adam myself. Talked to Roshni too.
She's fine, isn't she? Where was she?
I was so happy I couldn't even think about asking...
I just ran to you the moment I heard it.
Aunt...
What does Dr Rana say?
Congratulations, Aunt...
The Lord saved us...
Swear you mean it...
I swear.
By?
By my love for Grandpa.
Call her... I want to talk to her.
-Right away...
Hello?
-Yeah, Adam?
Adam...
Where are you?
-On my way.
Where's Roshni?
-With me.
Could I talk to her?
Who is it?
-Your Mum.
Here. They're all so worried...
Roshni...
My dear...
How are you?
For the love of God... Say something... Please...
For your Mum's sake... Please, say something...
Anything...
Why'd you have to give us this fright?
I'm sorry, Mum... I shouldn't have done it...
Just... Come back...
We're all waiting...
Reverend...
Your Holiness...
Hope you're fine.
-The Lord's blessed me...
And you, Asher Khan?
-Just whiling the days waiting for you.
Hope you had a great journey... Come in.
-Yeah, thank the Lord...
We've all been waiting...
Good news, great news, and awful news that may kill you. But don't die just yet - you've got to kill. What do I start with?
Good news... And great news...
Been ages since I've been happy...
Good news first... You're gonna be fine soon.
I pray...
Great news... Adam's found Roshni. He's on his way.
Thank You, O God...
Thank You so much!
-Aww, please don't cry!
Save your tears for the bad news... 'Sec.
Now pay attention.
They didn't just intend to kill you... They'd half done it! Were it not for me seeing Dr Rana throw an empty vial and confirming my suspicions...
I won't forgive this betrayal...
I won't spare them!
Be my guest. But you got to get back on your feet first. Here.
Just a few more days... Keep stoking the flames within...
Munna!
What are you doing here?
Dr Rana asked me to give him his pills.
Done?
-Yes.
Go.
Call Munna.
-Okay.
Why d'you want to drown our happiness and that of our children in your tears?
Don't mothers don't weep at their daughters' happiness?
So... Are you happy?
No.
First time you've said 'no' to me.
It was always about me...
But now...
It's about my daughter...
She's just a girl!
As if you'd brought her as your dowry! She's my daughter too.
Cover your grief in happiness, if you must!
Because I won't value anyone's happiness...
Or life... More than my happiness.
Tell her and Shayan to get ready.
The Reverend's here to fix a date for the wedding.
Quickly.
Masooma!
Yeah?
That'll be enough...
Your days of joy, fun, and games end here...
Roshni's very worried...
I talked to Adam...
He swore by God before her...
That no one will say anything...
So... I beg you...
Please don't say anything to her.
We've got to threaten her before she dares to do it again.
Shut up!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe