I know what you're thinking...
Hmm...
Mehek's suffering pains me.
She didn't deserve this... Any of this...
It pains me too...
But her fault...
Did you just say it's her fault she fell in love?
No.
But forgetting everyone else's love in your love... That's a different story...
I won't say it's her fault now though...
She's suffered long enough...
It'd be too cruel to bring it up every now and then.
But don't worry.
I'll be right by her.
Thank you.
Home.
Nos da...
I'll wait until you go in...
The lunchbox?
Adam...
-Yeah?
This is hardly new...
Like those who came before...
We love to wound ourselves in love.
Na, Mr Adam...
Love is the elixir that can dress all wounds.
Hello?
You still up?
Just trying to sleep.
Alright?
Do I need a reason to call you?
C'mon, now, mate... What is it?
Hello?
H -- ?
I salute your greatness.
You've been kind.
Helped me...
But most of all... I salute the Venus in you.
You don't need to thank me. The Lord God wanted you back on your feet. I just happened to be His agent...
Few people are kind of late...
Why don't you want to be one of them?
Be proud...
Look yourself in the mirror and clap for yourself.
No, thanks... I'm happy that you're fine now.
Oh, that lovely face deserves so much more...
Ever take a good look at yourself?
Eyes as enchanting as yours aren't found outside magazine covers...
And tresses that could ensnare the mightiest of kings...
I swear...
The pill's barely tried...
I'm back on my feet thanks to your beauty...
Please -- Don't say that... It feels so awkward...
Please... Leave... It'll be trouble if anyone saw you.
How well d'you know yourself?
You're a bit of what's troubling me right now.
Anyway, who'd come here?
My treacherous wife?
Who killed my repentance with her deceit?
I'll make her pay for it...
I'll give her a taste of Hell...
Right here...
She'd be flailing to catch her thoughts...
But it'd be too late...
By the time she's got a grip on it!
And the doctor...
Who makes money listening to broken hearts...
That Romeo's heart shall beat its last tonight...
He won't wake up to see the light of day.
For God's sake... Can we talk about it tomorrow? Please... Leave...
Put them on...
I'll take a good look at them for a minute... And leave.
It feels so awkward... Go!
Okay then...
I'll wait here.
There.
There. Go.
I got to sort it out today...
My love cannot take it any longer...
Come in.
Still up?
I dozed off for a while...
My mind was up all night though.
-What were you thinking?
Decided something...
What?
I want a divorce.
I want to break free.
Think again.
I've thought a hundred times.
I'm telling Adam...
To send him the divorce papers...
He'd be starving...
Want me to get something?
I want him here in three days.
Get it?
-Sir.
Go.
Aren't we ready yet?
For?
You forgot it...
What?
It's your daughter's wedding reception...
Never thought I'd see no preparations...
Never thought you'd be thundering the next morning!
Giving you my daughter doesn't weaken me.
You don't see it, do you?
Fathers lose their authority to their sons-in-law.
That's how it is...
She's a widow if he dies.
And not much different if she's divorced.
You're weak... Yeah, you are now...
You?
You're fine?
Back on your feet?
Am I dreamin -- ?
Reality check!
Yeah...
Now, tell me...
Do you remember your place?
Before I married your sister, your biggest dream used to be getting that one slice of bread for dinner...
The day you could get yourself some tea...
Was a feast for you...
May I know why -- You're reminding me?
-The same fate awaits you with open arms.
We're visiting our estate.
Come. Last time you're riding a car.
Quick!
Adam!
What is it?
Why didn't you take my call?
Put it on silent at night...
Why'd you call me?
Everything alright?
Mehek wants to see you... She's crying all day and sobbing all night... Doesn't say a word!
Come.
-Wait.
Go, Munna.
Got to go, Mum... Something came up...
Not more important than me, yes?
Go. I'm coming.
Yeah?
What was that last night?
I couldn't sleep all night!
I tried to ask you...
But shock and disappointment held me back.
What's your game?
It's no game, Mum...
I'll tell you everything.
Just think...
What if I kicked you and your sister out of my place?
How'd it feel?
What?
Awful...
I'd --
I'd die...
Would you do as I say?
Of course... Because -- Why not?
Run in front of the car until we get there...
Don't slow down, okay?
I need to get back before your sister gets up.
What?
Go.
Get to it. C'mon.
We haven't got all day!
C'mon!
Faster!
Run for your life!
Don't stop!
Yeah!
Just like that!
Get up! Quick! Back to it!
You in there?
Hello?
Now where'd he go?
You lied to us...
I know...
I shouldn't have lied... It's sinful...
But sometimes... Just to help someone out...
What could I do?
I just tried to lend a hand. Stand by her.
You deceived all of us...
And got engaged to a married woman!
Not before I deceived myself...
Tricked myself into believing this illusion...
Yeah?
He's back on his feet!
And I'm disgraced in my own eyes...
I saved my body...
But not my heart...
What?
I don't know.
I don't want to know.
Don't call me again...
I need time to get a grip on myself.
I don't blame you...
But that doesn't mean...
I can say you're right... Just because you're my son...
I won't stop you from helping Mehek...
But... You and Guddi... Together at night...
What d'you have to say about that?
-Just the truth, Mum.
I swear I won't hide anything.
I won't.
Wa --
Water...
Feelin' the heat, eh?
Here...
Water... My throat's drying up! Get me some water!
H -- Here... Wh -- What are you doing? Blimey! Get away!
What are you doing?
I've come this far on this thorny road barefoot. It is time you tasted the blood on my feet!
What do you mean?
My helplessness!
Want water?
Eh?
Here. Drink all you want! Here! Want some more?
Shut up and get back to it!
C'mon!
Faster!
Everyone's got their carefully-guarded painful secrets...
Guddi...
So helpless?
Please, Mum...
I was helpless before her helplessness...
Or is it that you've grown to like her?
I've grown to respect her...
Respect her feelings, maybe...
Started respecting her... Yeah...
May I come in, Mehek?
Yeah.
Shahmir's not sleeping, is he?
No. He's up.
May I?
Sure. Here.
In the Lord's name. Careful.
Shahmir! How are you?
Know what, I've missed you so much!
In a few years... I'll be older than this... And I'll take you to school...
No one will bother you there... By the way, you should try the wraps someday...
I'll give you a ride on my shoulders in the break! How d'you like that?
And... Don't... Miss... Your Dad, okay?
It never makes any difference... I missed my Dad a lot too... It didn't bring him back...
What happened? Was it something I said?
I was just talking to Shahmir...
No.
You don't know it, but you said in your innocence a truth I could not...
I don't get it...
Missing someone...
Doesn't really matter to them...
And it sure doesn't bring them back...
I've decided something...
But I can't let Grandpa know...
May I ask you?
But I'm just a kid... What'd I tell you?
Everyone shuts me up... Says I'm too young...
Please, Munna...
O -- Okay, Mehek... Go on...
I've decided to leave his father...
Am I doing the right thing?
What do I say?
Whatever's on your mind...
Whatever feels right...
Just... Say it...
What can you leave someone who was never with you?
I knew...
You'd help me out...
Thank you.
Thank you...
You're crying?
D'you think I should be laughing?
Yeah?
Your happiness is all I've ever prayed for...
Wipe those tears and tell me why.
I heard everything you told Mum...
It breaks your heart completely, doesn't it?
Hearts don't beak completely or in bits, Guria...
They break...
Or they don't...
Saqib!
You're back? Come here!
Check out this new drama on the telly...
You got to watch this with me! C'mon!
Saqib!
I've been making this for an hour... Don't leave before you've had it, okay? C'mon, sit!
I'll be going to work from tomorrow...
But don't worry, I'll leave your breakfast in a hot pot.
This tea's steaming right now, by the way... You don't want to have it any later than right now!
Quick!
Where's Rahim?
On his way...
-Rahim!
Where are you? Come here already!
Enough of your smarts.
Time to pay back every penny you've made off my father's kindness...
It's a weight you cannot carry anymore.
It's a weight...
I won't let you carry anymore...
For it may break your backs!
Now bugger off! All of you! I want you here at 6.
Looks like the Lord's happy I've changed...
Looks like my prayers were just waiting for me to put this bitterness behind me to be answered.
But this time... I didn't even have to finish... Didn't even have to say 'Amen'...
To be heard...
Amen!
Congratulations.
Won't you ask what I was praying for?
I'm just happy that you're happy.
It's what I care about the most.
And if I said I'd be glad to tell you?
Well, then... Tell me why... In the Lord's name...
Oh...
Don't make it difficult for me...
There's just one reason...
But telling you, standing right here... I could make up 99 more...
Yeah?
I opened the door, thinking...
It's too empty... To quiet... Too lonely...
I prayed...
That you show up 'round the corner...
And...
I didn't even say 'grace this scene' when you showed up.
Encore, my Lord!
Amen!
May the Lord do whatever's best for you.
Hey, Adam!
-Hey.
And here's a gentle reminder that I should've said 'Amen'!
Where's Mehek?
Waiting for you. She's asked me so many times and I've told her every time you're on your way... Just came here to check...
Okay. Tell her I'm here.
-Okay.
Would you like some tea?
No, thank you.
You know I'd like some tea right now too...
Okay... Two cuppas, please!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe