God is the greatest...
Munshi Nizam!
This gift is perhaps the only thing that's longed to see you as much as me.
Get the kids here...
O Lord...
My nephew...
Greet him... Take your blessings.
Reverend...
-Bless you... Take a seat.
Hey! What d'you think you're doing?
You'd sit next to the Reverend?
Sit on the floor, or stand where you are...
Sorry...
It's okay if he doesn't know...
Whoever we turn to and look at for a moment thinks he's fortunate and safe...
Asher Khan has been one of my most devoted followers...
My eyes bless him all the time...
I've been very fortunate indeed...
Bless her...
May you live long...
Please, sit...
Your daugher's grown up so fast...
Asher Khan's daughter and her happiness is about to become the key to your fortune.
I hope that - like everyone else - it matters to you.
Take care of Asher Khan's daughter.
Orders, sir?
I'll have lunch before I leave...
-Please...
Stay here a while... Honour us with your presence.
I've got a few things to do... Sorry...
I got to go...
Tomorrow and the day after would be a great time.
Pick either one.
Thank you so much, Reverend.
Go back to your Mum...
Bless you.
May the Lord give you good fortune...
Thanks.
And?
And he told me he was going to get the Reverend...
For our marriage...
I was delighted to hear him talk about getting married...
But there was this constant fear...
That he won't come back...
There was this voice in my heart...
That something's off...
Turns out something was off after all...
He never came back...
I'm so worried, Adam... I don't want to go back...
Don't worry. I talked to them. No one's gonna say anything. And if they did... You know I'm right here.
I don't want to live...
You're out of your mind? What are you doing?
Don't be silly, Roshni...
What's wrong with you?
I don't want to go home...
Don't ever say that again...
What if you --
Fear God...
And promise me you won't do it again.
Promise me!
What if something happened to you?
They're all waiting for you...
I've gone through so much just to bring you back...
Please... Don't even think about it...
Here we are. Home...
Shall we?
Look...
Please...
Believe me... Everyone's waiting for you... We've all been so troubled...
I just can't...
I'd used up every last bit of courage to step out...
How can I go back?
-I'm right here with you...
No one's gonna say anything, no one's gonna do anything.
It's not about that... What if Mum just asked about her fault...? What she'd not done for me?
What if Dad - too ill to say anything - just gave me a look, asking me about how I'd disgraced him...
I've got nothing to tell them... Nothing to tell anyone...
Not even myself... I don't want to go in...
I would ask you why you didn't think of any of this when you stepped out... But I know love better.
I don't think the question suits me...
I know love a lot better than you...
Love rewards itself through trials... Even if your beloved does not...
Your love tried you. You faced it. You triumphed.
But love lost before your lover.
They're all so worried, Roshni...
They're all so worried, Roshni... Mehek...
They're all so worried, Roshni... Mehek, Grandpa...
They're all so worried, Roshni... Mehek, Grandpa... Mum...
C'mon.
No...
I don't feel like...
You gotta come with me...
Please... No...
C'mon.
Here.
It's okay...
Roshni!
How are you? I hope you're okay...
I'm not...
W -- What happened?
I'm s -- scared -- so scared...
What are you scared of?
We left fear far behind...
You've looked defeat in the eye...
But never think it got the better of you.
M -- Mum... Where's Mum?
Inside. Waiting for you. Come.
What'd I tell her?
I've disgraced her before the world.
No one got a word!
Aunt picked a row with the groom's family...
Kicked them out...
Don't worry...
If the wound's not too deep...
It's not like I missed!
It struck right where it hurts!
And I'm ready to strike again...
Before it dares start healing!
Come in, dear...
They'll be delighted to see you...
No one's gonna say anything...
Come.
Curse me...
His sweet talk blinded me to my family's honour...
No...
Roshni...
God's making you think this way...
Because He doesn't want you to forget it...
No one's gonna say a word...
No one.
Oooh...
Someone give this crybaby an Oscar!
Looking at her innocent tears...
No one would believe how eager she was to run away!
Come.
C'mon in...
-Come...
If looks could kill!
So... Enchanting...
My blood was boiling...
Like, literally!
Felt like cursing... Insulting...
But one nonchalant look had that warmth...
I wonder how it'd feel if you looked like you cared...
But I'm only making an exception for you...
Aunt's gonna burn in the flames of Hell... By my hand... I gotta make sure of it...
I swear...
I'll char her black as this night...
Calm down, Zulaikha...
She's on her way...
No idea how she's been... How she'll be...
Let's pray she's fine... Everything's gonna be alright...
Mum...
My dear...
My only hope...
I've cried so much waiting for you... Come here...
Mum...
I --
Don't worry...
I won't say anything...
I won't ask anything...
Not even how you could forget our honour so easily...
Or how you could forget everything I've taught you and leave its bloody corpse just out the back door...
Don't worry...
I won't say a word...
I've promised Mehek...
I'm sorry, Mum... So sorry...
No...
I'm sorry...
I've failed as a mother...
No, Mum...
My upbringing...
You're back...
Thank you...
Thank you so much...
Mum...
What are you doing?
You're such a good son...
So upright...
No words can ever thank you enough for what you've done...
I'll thank you the way you want me to...
-It's nothing.
The Lord God alone decides...
Who to honour and who to disgrace...
He wanted to save your honour, and I just happened to be His agent... That's all I am - His agent...
He could just as well have sent someone else.
But I beg you...
Honour lost once...
Isn't always won back...
Please... Honour it and don't say anything to Roshni...
I promise you...
Order me... You've done me a great favour...
-It's nothing, really --
Come here... Here...
Rest your head on my lap...
Let me stroke you... Caress you... I'm sure all your sorrows will turn to dust...
Come here...
-Mum...
I'm sorry...
You don't know what you've saved...
I can't do anything today...
But I'll be where I can one day...
And...
I'll make sure you get everything you ever need.
No matter what it takes... You won't even have to ask for it...
Thank you so much...
Adam...
For Christ's sake, please don't insult my sincerity with this...
Sometimes, I wonder...
What I've done to earn your help whenever I need it...
What it is I couldn't do...
What?
Nothing, really...
Mehek...
You're happy, aren't you?
Happy?
What is happiness?
What does it mean to be happy?
I've forgotten everything...
But yeah...
I will say...
I'm relieved...
And that means so much more...
Thank you so much...
May God grant you everything you wish for...
Mehek...
Grandpa wants to see you...
Go. I'm coming...
Okay.
See you...
May you always be happy, Adam...
Mehek...
We...
We're going to see Shayan tomorrow...
Tomorrow?
Yeah.
But...
What do I tell them?
No idea...
All I know is I'm taking you where you belong.
Okay.
-Be ready.
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
In the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful...
C'mon...
Easy...
By Grist, ain't we up to something!
Let's try again, shall we?
Again?
Okay...
If you say so...
Whoa!
Wonderful!
Gotta say that's splendid!
Plan B's all set to go just when Plan A started failing!
Okay, that's enough... Tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
Mum...
I'm sorry, Mum... I made a big mistake...
I'm so sorry...
Mum...
You're not angry with me, are you?
Swear by me?
Can't believe you're saying that, Adam!
You haven't blinked an eye, waiting for her to see your love...
Are you seriously going to hand her over to someone else?
He's not just anyone else...
He's her husband...
Her little son deserves to see him...
Deserves to be with him...
Are you off your head?
Yeah, I'm off my head...
If taking her to her husband... And taking her son to his father means I've lost it, then I'm glad I have.
I don't care about anything else...
Not one bit...
For the love of God...
Anyone got food...
Water for me?
Hey! Where are you going?
For God's sake...
How'd you come in?
The door was open... I thought someone could...
Please, leave... I'm sorry...
Wait.
In the Lord's name...
-Go...
Here.
So much?
Pray for me, will you?
I --
I'm having a tough time...
I knew when I saw it...
I don't get it.
No one gives anyone so much unless he's having a tough time.
Those who are happy barely give a few quids...
Those who are grieving or fear ill fortune...
Give far more...
I've just one thing to say.
-Yeah?
Bow and beg before Him.
Beg before Him and He won't disappoint.
I've got so many more to pray for.
May you find happiness.
O Lord...
You help whoever begs before You with humility, tears, and sincerity...
You know the pain and the anguish in his heart...
You could give me Mehek...
Couldn't You?
But my love won't let me conquer her... My love isn't so weak as to be blind to hers...
So I only want the courage, my Lord...
I just want courage...
And I pray that You...
Give Mehek her happiness...
I promise You, my Lord...
If You gave Mehek her happiness, I'll try my best to find mine in hers...
Please give Mehek the peace and happiness she deserves, my Lord...
Amen.
Wait.
Yeah, Guddi?
G -- Guddi!
It was for Roshni!
Aye. Was for her. Ain't no more.
I thought it's mine.
Anyway, go tell Adam to see me in the backyard. Right now.
Why?
Who are you to ask me anyway? Me Tad?
-'Course not...
But -- What do I tell him if he asked why?
Tell him the world's about to end.
God forbid...
-Oh, please... Can it...
It ain't the end of your tiny world. Okay?
Go! Double time! That way.
Adam...
Mehek told you I've been crying for ages, didn't she?
You weren't taking my call!
Why didn't you come home?
Well, Guria -- I --
Come.
I --
I'm fine...
Just -- Come...
-Some friends are coming over... I need to see them... It's important... I'll be back once I'm done.
Some friends are coming over... I need to see them... It's important... I'll be back once I'm done.
Promise.
Get back quickly.
I'm fine...
Masooma...
Uncle got this gown for you... From the city! What d'you say?
Lovely!
-Innit?
The veil's lovely too.
-I'm wearing red too!
Twinning with you!
Like it?
-Love it!
Where is he?
No idea. I'm sure Adam knows though.
I didn't ask you! Just talkin' to myself.
I heard it though...
Oh, you did? You better lock that tongue inside your mouth and shut your gob!
Get going!
What is it?
Munna said --
The world's about to end...
-God forbid -- but that's what he said.
Is it true? What Mehek said...
That you've found him? You-know-who?
Yeah.
You ain't lying, are you?
I don't lie.
Well, unfortunately...
That's the problem with your type.
You don't normally lie...
But you think it's a virtue...
To lie for someone's happiness.
Don't do anything for her happiness... It isn't meant for you.
It's always about profit and loss for you, innit? Everything, every feeling...
Not really...
But avoiding losses can be a great profit too!
I've lived a life of avoiding losses, Adam... So I know it well...
Someone's coming...
It's you!
Aye, had to ask Munna to -- I'll get going --
-If you're done...
Yeah?
I want to ask something too...
Go on.
Why can't all men be like you?
Why d'you want to curse everyone?
It pains to be me...
Every feeling weighs a ton...
On my heart...
Every beat hurts... But you gotta go on...
For all that you've done for me...
I'll pray for you...
Whoever sees you will know you've earned someone's blessings.
Thank you.
It's getting late. Go.
'Earned someone's blessings'...
Psst!
Come here.
Ie, here.
What are you afraid of?
God forbid -- I hope I haven't scared you!
C'mon, don't let me debase myself so much!
So many times, I've asked the mirror... So many times, I've heard just praises...
I never even thought that...
So... What d'you want?
Look...
Newly-broken hearts - like Roshni's - long for a shoulder to cry on.
And there's no shortage of shoulders looking to give refuge to broken hearts.
So... Be careful, okay?
Thanks for droppin' by!
Goodbye!
Ie... If ever there's anyone...!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe