Don't worry...
I'm not gonna burn your sister...
Go back to the estate and call me...
I'll tell you what's next...
Okay.
Mr Malik wants to see Aunt.
What's the hurry? I ain't done yet...
Go...
I'll send her in a sec...
Ie...
You played your move...
My turn now...
I'm punishing you for tormenting me...
That's what you think, innit?
No.
I'm punishing you for what you've been up to with Dr Rana!
Come.
Over here.
I want to take a good look at you... Back to full health...
A father's a lord...
Your wish is my command.
I wanted to say something...
Yes?
Go on...
If someone you trust...
And count among your dearest friends...
Pulls you into an embrace only to stab you in the back again and again...
Without you ever finding out...
What's the most tragic part of it?
It's all very tragic.
But perhaps never finding out that your enemy masquerades as your dearest friend is the most tragic.
And to find out...
Is the Lord's favour, yes?
Hmm...
Who are you talking about?
Promise me you won't stop me from punishing this enemy...
And that you'd thank the Lord without taking it to heart...
For the truth bows and waits to be heard in your court...
I promise.
My dear Zulaikha... Let the powerless worry...
I've started poisoning Malik Jr as you wanted...
Death will come to him like a fever... Just a slight cough... Before a sudden and painful death.
For a moment, I thought the codger got his ticket...
I know just what can put him to sleep... Awaiting orders.
No... Not just yet...
My husband goes first.
It's nearly this man's time anyway...
And then?
We'll seize the day...
And live our life... Our way... Together...
No, Dad.
You promised me you'll let me sort it out my way.
You promised me you won't take it to heart.
Okay.
Masooma...
Masooma...?
What happened dear? Why are you crying? Tell me, I'm so worried!
Dad...
No one wants to play with me...
We thought we'd play hide and seek...
But everyone chose to hide from me... For real...
And -- When I called Mishil...
She said her Mum had told them not to play with me because I've grown up...
When I asked if she's coming over, she said, 'Never'...
Dad...
My dear...
-I haven't grown up, have I?
Wait.
You don't need to earwig...
When you can just ask...
I'd gladly tell you everything I'm going to do.
I'm going to my lawyer...
Sort out some matters about inheritance...
Sort out my marriage... File for divorce.
Sort things out with Dr Rana by killing him...
And finally sort out my issues with my wife... Punish her for what she's done...
Before marrying my English rose... You.
In your dreams.
What?
-Our marriage.
Our marriage...
Thank you for saying we're but one...
But I wonder why you refuse...
I love someone else.
Don't worry. I'll sort him out too.
Hello?
-Ie, where are you?
Going to see Shayan.
-Get back here.
What happened?
-Malik Jr's gonna kill Dr Rana.
Ask him to hide somewhere... Leave this place...
-What?
For the love of God, could you just cut the questions? Dr Rana's in danger. You don't have time.
But why?
Okay.
Munna!
Yeah?
-Get me the keys!
No idea. I don't know where they keep it!
-Find it! You got to! Someone's life is at risk!
Try there.
No luck?
Where could it be?
Come...
My dear Zulaikha... Let the powerless worry...
I've started poisoning Malik Jr as you wanted...
Death will come to him like a fever... Just a slight cough... Before a sudden and painful death.
Close the door.
What happened?
-Where d'you keep the keys?
No idea. What happened?
-Find it. I want it before this moment!
What happened? We're so worried...
Your Tad asked Qutbuddin to get some rope and coal. Your Mam's locked in and I smell ashes!
-What?
Hush!
Grandpa won't let us open the door if he found out.
-Mum...
But we haven't got the keys.
-Well then, we gotta find them! Double time!
Check here. I'll look downstairs.
-Aye.
Mum!
Mum? You alright?
Say something!
Mum!
You haven't got time to waste, Doc... I'm here to help you, so if you can't let me in, could you just come out here for a second?
What if I don't?
Your misfortune...
If I did?
-You'll be saved.
Found it?
-No.
What happened?
Malik Jr's locked his wife in the room and I smell ashes...
He slapped her before me...
And we can't find the keys to this lock...
I've got some spares... Try those.
Here.
Try this one.
God help us all...
Lemme try!
Mum!
-Mum?
-Mum's gone to the loo!
Got out this way...
Where's she?
-Somewhere that's safe...
Why'd she leave her phone?
First time you've asked me to see you.
Everything's not alright, innit?
You're two steps ahead of your thoughts.
-And you read fortunes without reading palms...
Leave this place.
I don't know whether I should be laughing... Or shocked...
Nothing, as long as you leave this place.
Why?
Your life.
What's the worst that could happen?
He's gonna kill you.
Who?
He?
He's up there...
What do you know what He's got planned?
I've got my reasons to believe so.
Goodbye.
Talking about death and wishing me God be with ye...
I'm praying I don't have to pray for you.
Take care.
I won't run away so easily!
I'm gonna look it in the eye!
Have it your way...
Mum will be back. Don't worry...
Aliya...
Get up. Have some water... Here.
Mum... When'd we see her?
Mum... When'd she come back?
She'll be back...
Don't worry... Easy...
I've got the courage, Mr Khan...
I can face whatever's thrown at me.
All I lack...
Is the courage to see you worried...
I beg you, Mr Khan...
Please... Don't worry yourself...
Shayan spews venom with every word...
Every syllable kills me...
His eyes mock me... Saying...
That I've been cruel...
To my own daughter...
I've saved her, Khawar...
She's got a right to everything that's mine...
I've prayed a lot...
That He give me a son...
He gave me everything I never wished for...
But never gave me what I always wished for...
A son...
This land is like my mother...
I can't even think of giving it to anyone...
I can't give away my mother...
But I couldn't turn the Reverend down either...
You've got your way out where you live.
I don't get it, Reverend...?
Your nephew...
Your family can retain everything it owns.
I'm sorry for saying this, but...
For someone as upright as you, the land you own is like your mother...
Don't let Shayan go back without getting him married.
But -- Reverend... He leaves in two days...
And Masooma's too young!
The trouble that awaits you...
Is too great for you...
Your daughter's age... Or averting your destruction... It is up to you...
Which is why I say again - do not let him go back without getting him married.
As you say, Reverend...
You did the right thing, Mr Khan...
I'll always stand by you.
Hello?
Yeah...
Yeah, I'd need backup... Two or three men...
Okay.
I'll call you as soon as I'm in the city.
Thank you, sir. Bye.
Who's here so late?
You're here so late?
Yeah.
Believe your eyes.
Step aside...
I thought I'd dress up like this when I - God forbid - got married... But thank goodness that never happened... Why does it feel like I'm looking death in the eye today?
You know, don't you?
-Who?
You know why.
No.
I know you know everything.
Roshni...
I've got my reasons for saying no.
Just speak your heart out.
Mum jumped from the window, risking her life to save herself from the fire...
You're the only one here who doesn't have any questions...
You haven't got time, Roshni...
Can't waste it looking for answers...
Start praying that your Mam's fine before you blink again.
She's made a run for her life.
For the love of God... Just tell me what you know...
The purest thing God ever made is the respect kids have for their parents.
My respect for that purity keeps me quiet.
So please... Don't ask why and start praying.
Yes, Doc?
Two cups, clean as crystal...
Some milk, and teabags...
A kettle of hot water and one and a half teaspoons of sugar...
Put it up there to welcome our guest.
It's someone very special.
I'd like to serve him nothing but the finest tea.
Go.
Why didn't you tell me before?
I love you so much.
Don't you love Mehek?
She gave you her life... And her family's honour...
You've got me in a fix...
I can't say you're wrong even though I know you are...
Because my misfortune is just as guilty as you.
No. This isn't your fault.
Saving your marr --
Protecting your happiness... It's my duty...
You've been through so much...
You suffered so much...
But didn't even let out a sigh...
Brothers don't need strength to carry the weight of their sisters' troubles.
They just need a heart that beats.
Shayan...
For the love of the Lord... For the sake of your sister's honour... Promise me you'll reward Mehek's devoted love and long wait by giving her the happiness she deserves.
Orders, Doc?
Is Mr Malik here?
-No.
But Mrs Malik was here.
What'd you say?
Everything you'd told me.
Tell me properly. I want to be sure you didn't forget something.
I told her that the Doctor said I should tell her he doesn't want to meet, see, or have anything to do with you.
What'd she say?
She was quiet...
Eyes dripping...
I saw one drop fall...
But I shut the door...
But I shut the door before a second could fall.
Good.
Go.
You're done for the day.
Don't weep for the living!
Just thank God she made a run for her life!
Tell her, will you?
Hello?
Aye, I'm in the city.
Okay.
I sent you the address. Get there ASAP.
Thank you.
What now?
The flames of rebellion shall rise...
I'm with you.
I know.
Get off, Qutbuddin...
I don't think you should be coming with me.
Okay.
If it isn't the esteemed Mr Malik! Come in!
On his feet! I see you don't need a wheelchair anymore?
Glad to see you.
Please, take a seat...
Touched to see your delight...
Hmm?
One of Shayan's friends is here to see him.
His friend?
Where's Khawar?
He said he'll be back tomorrow.
What's his name?
Adam.
Who are you?
A guest.
Want to see Dad?
Mr Khan?
Yeah.
You're Shayan's sister?
He's not my brother anymore.
What do you mean?
We've gotten married... How can he be my brother now?
Anything else?
He said he's a friend from University. Here from London.
Mentioned a few other friends too... Class-fellows, roommates...
Sohail, Mehek, and Khadim...
Don't let Shayan find out.
Where's Adam?
I asked you something!
In the lounge.
I never made tea for anyone...
You're the first to have the honour...
And I swear...
I'm so glad to be serving you.
Your humble servant is delighted.
What are you doing here?
-Mehek sent you?
-Yeah.
(Don't mention her before him, okay?) Lovely surprise, mate! It's Christmas!
'Evening.
-Good evening.
You're his Uncle?
Yeah.
He loved to talk about you.
Did he?
-Gotta say, you're rather famous 'round here! I just asked where you live... But they wanted to drop me here themselves!
Gotta say, you're rather famous 'round here! I just asked where you live... But they wanted to drop me here themselves!
I heard odes to your glory all the way.
Please, take a seat. I'll get you some tea.
Shayan... Come with me...
No, thanks, Mr Khan...
I'd love to show my guest some kindness.
I won't hear a no from such an honoured guest!
Shayan?
Take a seat.
-Thank you.
We've had our tea...
Looking each other in the eye...
Saying not a word, hearing not a word...
I'm still thinking of where to start...
Start wherever you want... I'm sure it'll end up making sense. Please, begin in the Lord's name.
Third time I'm thanking you...
Thank you for treating me... Getting me back on my feet...
Oh...
I couldn't help it...
I thought it's pronounced 'It was my duty'.
-No.
No.
I know and mean exactly what I'm saying.
I've sinned a thousand times...
But lying is not one of them.
Thank you for the fourth time...
The most priceless of trust is that between husband and wife...
Cursed are those...
Who leave this world, unaware that their wives...
Chose to two-time shamelessly right under their noses...
Why'd you stop at wives?
I've seen a few cheating women...
But countless more cheating men...
Only because...
I'm talking about my wife...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe