Adam!
Want me to get breakfast?
Come here...
I've made you cry buckets for some of these, haven't I?
No way... It's nothing like that...
I was just a kid...
Of course...
You wanted to keep this shawl, remember?
I'd turned you down.
You cried all night...
I cried a bit when I saw you too...
But I could never give my sister what I'd got for Mehek...
And... These bangles...
You wanted them the moment you'd seen them...
But I couldn't give them to you even though I wanted to...
Never had the courage...
Why don't you keep them, Guria?
And this...
All of this... I'm sorry...
No way, mate... They're Mehek's!
Mehek's not in a position to keep them, Guria...
What are you saying?
She wants something else...
What?
I've found what she wants...
I've just got to give it to her.
See you...
Take care...
What's up?
-What a delightful day!
I don't get it?
Forgotten happiness entirely, have you? Lemme explain it...
It's a great fiend they all waste their whole lives seeking...
But only few ever get a lasting taste of it...
They'd kill and be killed for it... And it's what makes everyone forget about poor old grief...
Although grief is far more devoted... Always by your side...
Happiness can be a tad high-headed... You don't get it so easily.
And seeing you end your wait for Godot makes me so happy...
What'd you tell Grandpa?
I said one of my old friends is getting married, and I got to be there...
I'll be back in two days and I'm taking Guddi with me.
I thought he'd refuse...
But he nodded the moment I said I'll be with Adam.
I pray it's the last lie you ever tell anyone!
Mehek!
We'll see Shahmir again, right?
Can't say.
Like... Sometime?
Here we go again...
Can't say.
May I play with him?
Sure.
Is Mehek ready?
She's been ready for ages...
Just looking for her exit.
Okay, I'll be waiting in the car...
-Wait.
For God's sake, Guddi...
Don't say anything today.
I'm not sure I can take it.
My breaths sound like noise I need to shut out...
Been crying, of late?
No.
Ie.
Those eyes ain't red from a vigil.
I can see everything...
I can see how you pressured your mind, your heart...
And how your eyes narrowed...
Before they rained for hours.
I don't like to see it.
It almost pains me...
We gotta go...
Not us...
Just you...
Give him here...
I'll get her things in the car...
Hey...
May I hold him one last time?
Sure.
Shahmir...
Don't worry, okay?
Don't cry... Take care...
You knew it, Munna?
No...
Easy...
Easy there...
I'm here to thank you.
I've murdered my conscience.
Well, guess what, I've nothing to do with it...
And...
Nothing to do with you either, really...
And - as wicked as it sounds -
And - as wicked as it sounds - nothing to do with your sister either.
I'm just doing my duty as a good and loyal man...
So why waste your thanks?
I don't need it.
Keep it to yourself. Use it in the line of duty...
No.
You deserve it.
Thank you for pleasing Mr Khan like nothing else.
I could give you my heart if I could live with it.
Unfortunately, you'd have to make do with a thank you...
You seen Mum, Uncle Khawar?
-Aye, many times.
Please don't joke about it... Just -- Look at this... My gown's so loose!
Bless you.
She's so happy...
Looking forward to her wedding this evening!
I think it looks just fine...
I think it looks just fine... Shayan?
What d'you say?
-Yeah...
Too loose here... And too long!
Yeah? She's asking you.
Grandpa...
Take care...
Side-seat's mine!
I swear I ain't sayin' that to enjoy the ride or mock you...
What it is is sitting at the back makes me feel like there's only room for two...
I've worked so hard to make room for myself...
Ready?
Yeah.
Mr Khan...
Not a single guest...
What's with this... Boring wedding?
I've called a few witnesses...
What if Shayan...
God forbid... Refused?
The only way I can save myself from disgrace --
-Of course. I know what to do.
Take these pills for five days, and you'll be fine, okay?
Come back after five days...
Okay.
Just do as I say and you'll be fine.
Get the pills from out there.
Should I send the next one, Doc?
No... Not now...
In a moment...
Doctor's orders, I guess?
What's wrong with me?
I used to be a doctor...
How'd I get this affliction of the heart?
Shayan...
Come in.
There's...
Something I wanted to ask...
Mr Khan's been asking me to get you a gift...
My mind's stopped working...
I don't know what I should get you...
I thought...
I'd ask you...
What you'd want...
Could you curse me with all your heart?
With bitter spite?
Could you ask the Lord to curse me...
With death?
Life's too much for me to take...
I'm slipping...
If He listened to my prayers for death...
I wouldn't be here talking to you...
How long before we get there?
At this speed, four and a half hours. If we don't stop anywhere.
I've packed some things for you in the bag.
Topped up the petrol.
We won't have to stop anywhere...
Good Heavens... What was that?
I think the tyre burst...
Alas...
What happened?
Over there...
Yeah?
Guess where you'll end up fifteen minutes down that road?
My place...
Your Mum lives there?
Ie...
Want to see her?
Good day, Doc.
Good day...
Aye...
Where's everyone?
Who?
Everyone.
Grandpa's sleeping... Want me to wake him up?
-No...
And the others?
Roshni and Aliya are in the room with their Mum. Guddi and Mehek are on the way...
Where've they gone?
-Karachi.
But --
When?
And why?
I mean... When are they coming back?
They're going to a wedding... They'll be back in a few days.
Should I go tell Madame?
-No...
Get me a glass of water.
-Right away...
Would've been glad if you could tell me... Ease my waiting...
I can't rest now...
Got a few restless days ahead of me...
-Here.
Here...
Actually, never mind...
Ie...
Right about here...
Want us to come with you?
Just you.
Wait here, Mehek...
I want to see my Mam... Find some peace in her embrace...
Mum... Wanted to ask something...
Sure... Go on...
Could we get my doll married to Ayesha's today too?
Bai fi yw e (It's me), Mam! Guddi!
Can it be?
Mam!
I hope no one saw you... Come!
Here!
Mam...
-Get in!
Why'd you have to come here?
-I'm here, Mam...
Okay, but why?
Do I need reasons to come home, now, Mam?
There's four complaints against you in the pentref!
They ain't gonna wait one moment before calling the plods!
Your Tad and I haven't slept in peace one night...
But seeing your Tad sleep peacefully three days ago...
I knew something was off...
Peace announces grief's visit here...
You callin' me grief, Mam?
Okay, mun, sori...
But why'd you come here?
I just strolled right in... Can't help it when I miss you...
Can't think of the time or the place...
I don't ask myself why I'm missing you...
Your Tad's health is so unpredictable...
He's fine sometimes...
And sick at others...
The doctor's asked him to stay away from stress and worry...
How's Tad?
He's been better for the last three days...
How's Chutki? Happy?
Yeah. Very...
And you, Mam?
I'll tell you everything on the phone... Don't wait 'round here. Go!
Won't you give me a kiss, Mam?
There. Quickly, now... Go...
I ain't even seen you yet!
I've missed you so much...
I swear I cry for hours before going to sleep...
I may drown but never stop missing you...
That's what you get...
For everything you've done...
I never did it for meself...
But for me own...
As if we asked you to smirch our names!
What could I do?
Remember when Chutki was kicked out of school for not paying her fees?
When Dad fell so ill...
But we couldn't even get him his pills?
I remember everything, Mam... Even what you do not...
Begging the neighbours for tea and sugar...
I never did any of it for me...
I never wanted anything, Mam...
I just did it for you... All of you...
So it is...
But we don't have time to talk.
Go... Quickly...
Mam...
C'mon, now...
Get going! Before someone saw you!
Ie... You wouldn't happen to have some money, would you? I need to get your Tad's pills...
Dad...
Get out of here... Just as you stepped out of the house...
Besmirching our names with your filthy footsteps!
I've come here to say sorry, Dad...
'Sorry'...
Did you listen to us?
Our honour fell at your feet and begged you as you stepped out...
Did you listen?
I couldn't think of anything...
My ill fortune held my hand and led me every step of the way...
Just... Do me a favour and get out of my room.
And do your best to make sure my eyes don't ever see your face again.
Get out!
-Dad...
Out!
Here.
Have some.
Don't cry again, okay?
Ever...
Why are you crying?
You're missing that stinker again, aren't you?
No.
Dad pulled me up and said he'd never want to see me again...
He won't even let me see his face again...
Easy there...
Not good. Come here...
Everything's gonna be alright... Go... I'm coming in a moment...
Hello?
Took you 125 calls to say hello!
I know...
I ought to say sorry...
Any half-decent man ought to say sorry as soon as he knows he's wrong.
But what about a man whose thoughts, intellect, reason, and sensibility have all called a strike?
What do you mean?
No idea...
No idea what's wrong with me...
Anyway...
Why'd you call me?
My husband's getting better...
Getting ready to get the better of us!
Order me...
Stop his breaths right now.
He doesn't deserve one more...
Come in.
I don't need it.
But I do.
I'm giving you a piece of my heart...
The scent of these flowers will ease me.
Never thought those who hurt others could feel pain.
Your mother's death pains me...
That's why I'm fulfilling my promise to her.
Okay... Enough with the dolls getting married...
Gimme my doll back, Mum... I gotta dress her up...
Girl...
Your Dad thinks you're too old for this.
It's your wedding today!
Mind if I say something, Mehek?
No...
These tears don't suit your eyes as you approach your destination...
They should be glowing instead.
I'm divided, Adam...
Waiting for him didn't let me think of anything...
But now that I know my wait's ending...
It feels like my ageing Grandpa's holding me back...
If he found out about this... Any of this...
I fear his heart may succumb to dishonour...
Come in...
The groom looks ready!
It's time for the nuptials...
The guests and the Reverend are waiting for you.
Many congratulations to you...
And...
And... Many more to you.
Come.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe