We need to talk. Just the two of us.
His blood pressure's very low. He's running a temperature of over 104.
Yet you're insisting you'd rather not go to the hospital... You do realise his life's in danger, don't you?
I don't need to take him to the hospital...
When their best doctor's here.
As you say.
Munshi Nizam!
Sir?
Get the doctor whatever he asks for.
And...
He's staying here tonight. Make sure he's comfortable.
As you say, sir.
Okay?
You'll be fine.
Be a man!
Dyw, look at him... Like the Devil himself!
His sickness holds him captive...
I've heard everything about you from Qutbuddin!
And I know just what ails you! Well, almost...
Hello? Guddi?
-Ie...
Could you tell me what this shot's for? I sent you a pic.
Just a second...
Hello?
Blimey, Guddi... That's a slow poison... Kills slowly and without a trace... What are you up to?
I'll get back to you.
Dr Rana and your wife are giving you these shots of death...
So sorry...
But I meant to disturb you. It's time for your medicine.
My heart is heavy...
Everything tastes so... Bitter... Venomous...
I can't take any more...
Please... Do me a favour...
Pray tell. Your wish is my command!
Just throw the pills somewhere...
And tell my wife I've taken them.
Okay.
I can do that.
Let me rub your feet. I'm sure you're tired.
-Thank you, I don't really need --
Thank you, I don't really need --
-Oh, please... Allow me...
Oh, please... Allow me...
You haven't had anything.
Yeah. I'm not hungry.
Munna left something in the fridge for you.
-Go to bed...
Now, don't answer if you get a call from her number. Her Mam calls you to check.
Please, Saqib... Talk to me!
The stage is set for Aunt's downfall...
The time to act, Guddi, is now!
Can't you hear the clocks ticking?
I've been waiting for two days. Where were you?
Shush your lips and open your ears wide!
So wide that everything you hear goes straight in!
Roshni's Mam has betrothed her.
She's getting married one of these days.
What?
Before you start getting any ideas, lemme tell you that a contract man's itching to earn something for his kids.
What do you want me to do?
Pay attention, mush...
Psst!
What is it?
Come.
Quickly!
Patience - and trust in Guddi - always pays off! Told you!
What is it?
Here.
Talk to him.
Hello?
Roshni... It's Saqib...
Saqib!
I've waited so long to hear your voice...
Shed so many tears it hurts to close my eyes...
We don't have much time... Just listen to me...
So just do as Guddi says. I'm in touch with her...
And...
I love you so much I could never even imagine leaving you...
Bye.
You want him, don't you?
Alright, then... Act 1 - Acquiescence! Just do as your Mam says!
Convince her you've surrendered before her honour!
Make the road ahead easy for us!
Okay.
As you say.
Shh!
What?
Tomorrow?
Hardly surprising, now, isn't it?
Isn't that what we always wanted? To get them married off at the earliest.
They wanted some time... They'll tell us in the evening tomorrow. Sit...
It's for the best. The earlier they got married, the easier it will be for Roshni to get a visa.
How will we prepare in one day?
The Lord has given us everything. Even time bows before money.
I'm sure we can do it. Go and get gowns for Roshni and Mehek.
I'll take care of everything else.
As you say, Dad.
What colour do you want his suit to be?
Ehh?
What colour would you like Adam to wear? Adam, you know, the man you like?
If you ask me, the man should pick what he likes... Whether you like him or not! What d'ya say, Roshni?
Let him pick what he likes... Or ask the one who likes him...
Hey...
Why are you wasting a hundred gee on his suit? He's just a groom for hire... Just rent one!
Return it with the man! How's that?
He's better now...
What are you doing here?
Just...
Checking on you...
Thought I'd massage your head... It hurts, right?
Who asked you to do anything?
-No one? I just thought --
Go... What if someone saw you here?
So what?
Just go!
Don't just barge in like that!
Go!
So you're the one!
Do you see anyone else around here?
Of course... I can see the restlessness seizing your right hand...
And helplessness, or perhaps heedlessness (Or is it meanness?) clutching the little finger on your other hand...
And, of course, the burning flame that brought you here, the love in your eyes... That makes four of you!
By the way, I note you haven't got any notes. I don't like it one bit.
I would have them in my hands if they were a couple thousand... But I've got a hundred.
Blimey, you have the gift of the gab... Just like me! Neat!
But... How do you know Aunt gave me the money?
Oh, well...
You know this doctor close by? Let's just say he's very close.
Your mother-in-law called to tell him.
I don't know about the walls, but I have ears.
Not gonna lie to you, they can go to any lengths to hear what they want! How's that?
Thank you.
Just follow the plan.
Bye!
And...
This isn't the price for my help...
You're celebrating your love with some charity!
Adam!
First time I've seen a groom too busy with his horses to dress up nicely!
Groom?
Good Lord, what do you mean?
You're getting engaged this evening and all my friends are coming over to celebrate!
I'm just getting engaged, Guria... Not married...
Don't call me a groom just yet...
-Why not? You're a groom to-be!
And I can't tell you how happy I am for you!
I'll be over the moon the day you got married!
Here... Mehek will be walking under the shade of this lovely cloth as they seat her with you!
You'll look so lovely together!
Aren't you happy?
Hmm?
When did I say that?
It's just --
I'll talk to you when I'm back...
I'll be waiting!
Hey!
Yeah?
Where are you coming from?
-Had to get my phone topped up. Something you need?
I called you so many times! You didn't even bother to answer!
Had to get some fresh air to top my energy up too. Got a problem?
Get all of this inside, Imam Deen.
Good Lord!
Blimey...
You've barely got the news that your brother's getting engaged, and you're putting up this show like it's his wedding!
Of course. He's my only brother. And a real prince at that!
Were it up to me, I'd make the entire city cut a rug!
Where are you off to, Adam?
-Adam!
-Here...
What happened?
Blimey, I haven't seen a groom so coy...!
Leagues ahead his bride!
It's nothing like that, just...
I got a few things to do...
-Hey! Wait a minute!
I got to go, Guria. I'll be back.
No. You gotta stay here with us.
-I told you, Guria... It's important...
I told you, Guria... It's important...
-We aren't singing or playing before you sit with us.
We aren't singing or playing before you sit with us.
-Aye.
Why are you bothering my son like that?
No one's bothering him! We're just celebrating with him!
He ought to sit here!
-But... I gotta go...
-Yeah, right here!
-Now we're talkin'!
-Okay...
As you like it!
But you're doing what I ask you to after an hour.
And... Get your brother a nice suit, okay?
-Of course.
-Yay!
Of course.
-Woo hoo!
Mehek...
(Guddi!)
Guddi!
(Here!)
Here!
Mum'll be back.
Grandpa?
Everything alright?
What are you doing?
You're happy with it, aren't you?
Don't worry.
Everything's going to be alright.
I hope indeed...
Bless you, my girl.
God bless you.
Go get some rest... You'll need it.
Do not disgrace me...
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
Mum...
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
Mum...
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ My resolve faded as an aching wound took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ You were distant though so near ♪
♪ You're distant yet so dear ♪
♪ You etched your name on my heart, right here ♪
♪ You forgot me, yet you're dear... ♪
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
What's up? Why's he crying so much?
-He's got a fever. A real bad one.
What?
What happened? Shahmir...
And you're telling m --
Took you long enough to find out!
He was sleeping for a few hours. Got up and started crying just now. I found out when I touched him.
Here.
Where are you going? Let me dress your hair!
Forget it.
-Stop her, will you? Where's she off to?
Stop her, will you? Where's she off to?
-Just a minute...
Ehh?
Munna!
-Yeah?
Ask the driver to get the car out. Right now!
Everything fine?
Shahmir's got a bad fever! Quickly, now! Get going!
-Okay.
Where are you off to?
Uhh...
He's got a bad fever.
But why are you leaving when the guests are almost here?
I'm taking him to the doctor.
Why?
Where's his mother? Why can't she take him?
The car's waiting for... you...
There she is! I'm sure she can take him herself.
Just... Had to get my shawl... Here.
Guddi!
Guddi?
Come in.
You called me?
Go and get Guddi. I've been calling her for ages!
-She's gone!
But when? And where?
She's gone to the hospital with the k -- h -- her kid...
Okay, go...
What kind of trial is this that holds uncertainty at every turn, every step?
My son... My life... Is unwell... And I can't even take him to the hospital...
This is no trial... It's damnation! It's a curse! An unending nightmare...
Hello?
Did you have to leave for the hospital right now?
Aye, as if I'd invited this fever that's ailing him!
What if it took you too long and I got married here?
It won't. Don't worry. It's just five minutes to the hospital. That makes fifteen minutes until he gets his shot and half an hour until I get back.
Just... Keep the stylists busy... Ask them to start over again. Just keep them busy, okay?
Please come back quick...
Step on the gas!
Go and give this to the servants.
My son outshines every royal in the world today.
That's how charming you look.
Bless you.
Guria, bring him downstairs. Come.
Adam...
-Hmm?
Mind if I ask something?
-Of course not.
How does it feel to see your one cherished dream become a reality?
What do I tell you?
Just how you feel.
It feels like this room is teeming with happiness...
Every one of them looking me in the eye, smiling...
Laughing... At me... Mocking...
It's all just... Happiness that'd bring you to tears...
One blink and they'd roll down...
Blimey...
Bless you...
Tears of happiness!
Yeah, right...
Come.
-Yeah...
Just give me a minute.
Hello?
I've called you so many times! What are you doing?
I'm not getting a pedicure at a parlour, get it?
I'm getting your son treated, so you better watch what you're saying.
How's he?
The doctor says it's nothing serious.
He's given him a shot. I'm coming back.
Good Lord... It must've hurt him so much...
Of course. Not like it's gonna tickle him, yes?
I'm on my way. Don't call me again.
I'm here.
What's up with her?
No idea. It's been an hour and she's still in the loo!
I'm tired of waiting.
-Me too.
How much longer do you need?
I'm coming...
What about the other functions?
We can't go anywhere because of her!
-Yeah...
Hello?
Where are you?
On my way. Halfway home.
They'll be here for me in ten minutes!
And guess what, he's already there, waiting for you. Having killed his act of two-timing, he's standing close to the back gate, carrying its coffin!
Just be done with it already, Mehek... I'm on my way!
We gotta get back before these folks! I've got the jewellery with me.
They're blocking the entire road!
Just peep or something! Quickly!
Yeah... Good...
Quickly!
Faster!
Wonder what she's doing in there!
Where's Roshni?
She's been in the loo for half an hour!
We've got other clients too, just in case!
Roshni!
What are you doing in there? They're almost here.
Well --
-They haven't even done your makeup properly!
She hasn't even got her cloak on! What are you even doing here?
And what were you doing in there?
I've barely been in there five minutes!
Hurry up!
Get her ready quickly!
-Okay.
Close the door.
Blimey, this bride sure knows how to deck up!
-Mehek!
Mehek!
Adam's family just came in! I swear he looks like royalty!
I'm sure you won't even blink if you saw him!
Get ready quick, we've got to take you downstairs!
Could you go out for a minute, Salma?
My boy...
M'boy...
He's fine!
The doctor says the shot will kill the fever in no time. He'll be just like he was!
C'mon, now, get ready quick!
Adam's here, wearing a coat of lies over his truth!
C'mon!
Hello?
Hello.
You used to praying?
No.
-Why?
I prayed for something a few years back... Shed a few tears too... But my prayers were never heard... I don't really believe in praying now...
Well, then, rewind the clock and start praying. I'm about to snatch the bait from the lion's maw! Be ready. Bye.
God help us all...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe