♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ My resolve faded as an aching wound took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ You were distant though so near ♪
♪ You're distant yet so dear ♪
♪ You etched your name on my heart, right here ♪
♪ You forgot me, yet you're dear... ♪
♪ Seeing the raindrops, old memories ignite ♪
♪ These raindrops slowly set my heart alight... ♪
♪ O Mender of every broken heart, ♪
♪ When will You see mine fall apart? ♪
♪ Turn back and take a look ♪
♪ At who you forsook... ♪
♪ My love torments me; ♪
♪ My heart asks Thee ♪
♪ 'If I was destined to break', ♪
♪ 'Why did You create me'? ♪
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe
♪ My heart was set on a dream ♪
♪ That's falling apart at the seam ♪
♪ Sleepless, troubled nights I bear, ♪
♪ To express it, my words do not dare; ♪
♪ My heart beats within me, I swear, ♪
♪ But it's lost somewhere... ♪
♪ Yea, I've lost my heart to her ♪
♪ For the first time, as it were; ♪
♪ This affliction is all mine; ♪
♪ Don't say a word to her... ♪
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪