Open this door!
Anyone!
For the love of God... Please...
Anyone there...
Please... Open this door...
I'm dying in here...
OPEN THE DOOR!
Please...
Sure, Mr Gardezi... She'll be there by 8.
Okay.
Go and ask Sheena to get ready.
Please... Open this door...
Please...
Please, Madame... Open the door... She's been crying her guts out.
Not as much as you did when your brother-in-law sold you. Did I open the door for you?
No.
Let her starve for a day.
Hunger will make her see some sense.
Ma'am.
Yes?
Water.
Water... Everywhere... This sinking feeling...
I meant... Do you want water?
No...
You really should. You've been crying buckets, drying your heart out, giving it a hard time.
No.
I know how you feel...
You're brave... Back at the pentref, Bano eloped with Miskin, the barber... It wasn't even an hour before her Mam and Tad...
Let's just say they chose death over disgrace.
Thank the Lord you still stand strong.
Sorry if it's something I said...
Please, drink some, okay? I'll leave it here.
You're sitting here!
Yeah? Your oul' fella's place, is it?
-No...
I couldn't care less if it were, okay?
They're here.
Everyone?
-Yeah.
And Grandpa?
-Of course.
Just barely didn't make it...
-What?
Nothing... I hope Grandpa's right as rain now!
Yeah.
-Okay.
Now get out of my sights!
Tears, grief, heart attacks, honour... You bilkers disappoint me! Couldn't even claim one of 'em!
Thank goodness you're here...
Alright... Stop here...
You sure you can walk?
I'll try.
-Come.
Hello?
-Where are you?
How are you? How's Grandpa?
I'm as fine as Grandpa.
He's better.
So am I.
He's back.
Thank the Lord...
Got word yet?
Aye... But just a word...
But don't worry, I'll be in Karachi by the morning. Find out everything I can.
Tell me you'll find her...
If we could find Shayan, I'm sure we can find her too...
I promise you, Mehek...
I'll do everything I can to bring her back.
And... As soon as we're back...
I'll drop you at Shayan's.
Take care. I'll get back soon...
Yeah? Everything alright?
Why are you doing all of this? Any of this?
Why? Well...
I'm doing this because... Mehek...
Because I...
I...
I really...
Yeah?
I really care for you... I know how you feel... We've grown up together...
You've grown up... I'm still stuck somewhere back there I guess...
I don't get it.
Who'd know it better than me that you don't get it?
Let's just say the Lord's enlisted me for this.
Don't worry. I'll bring Roshni back.
I'll get back. Bye. And please... Don't worry.
Bye...
Don't even think of going out... Wait here.
An unpleasant death awaits you outside.
But I care for you... You could say I'm a friend...
I want to save your life.
Tell me...
They've done something to my Saqib, haven't they?
They haven't -- God forbid -- Killed him, have they?
Your Saqib? He was never yours, girl! He sold his 'love' and your honour to Madame Ruby for two million.
They're very dangerous. Resist and they'll kill you.
If you don't believe me... Look at this...
And now, we turn to a gruesome incident from Karachi. Two young girls were found dead at Clifton Beach this morning.
Sources identify them as Suraiyya and Ruqaiyya. They'd come to Karachi from a hamlet in the Punjab in search of a job
Madame Ruby bought them too.
Very upright, both of them.
It's just a matter of a few months... Just do as Madame Ruby says...
Win her trust, and when you get the chance... Run away!
Why are you so restless, Mr Gardezi?
I've sent her... She'll be there any moment.
On her way right now, of course!
But you disappoint me... Just one thing I asked for... And you...
You've told them? Great. Thank you!
Bye.
Done.
I've scared her so proper I could see it in her eyes!
You can put her pictures up now.
What's up with the telly?
Call the cable guy. It's time for my favourite drama.
Just a sec...
Guddi!
Take my hand.
C'mon!
Now let go.
Boundaries.
Shamim!
Get me some cold water!
Have something.
And what are you doing?
Please, have something.
I don't feel like it.
I beg you...
Stop my tears...
Save my life...
My fate... My children's future... Is in your hands.
♪ Some say I'm Guddi... ♪
(Humming 'Some say I'm a sweetie')
Ahh...
How do you feel now? After you stopped taking that dreadful pill?
Aye...
My chest feels... Relieved... Feels like I can still... Breathe...
Just do as I say and you'll be just like your old self over there!
The enchanting man with deep eyes...
As charming as always! Spiffing, innit?
Why are you helping me?
-No.
Guddi doesn't help anyone. She always helps herself when she wants to, and she wants when...
How say we leave that for another day?
When you're standing before me like in that picture? Okay?
-Aye...
Hey... Any word on Roshni?
Our knight marches forth. Surely, he won't disappoint!
By the way, don't let anyone know you're better now, okay?
-Sure.
See you in the morning. Nighty night!
Good night...
-(Humming 'Some say I'm a sweetie')
(Humming 'Some say I'm a sweetie')
Gotta say, you make such a lovely Mam...
Because you're such a lovely granddaughter already, you ought to rush down to be the lovely niece!
Your Aunt's grieving because her daughter turned out to be... You know...
I mean... Because her daughter's run away... So she's down there, alive, but not quite...
She won't eat. Won't drink water.
She'd rather weep at her lost honour and drown in her tears.
Guess why she isn't going into her room? She's worried what she'll tell her husband. Like, seriously?
Look after Shahmir. I'll be back...
Hey!
-Yeah?
I need a hundred bags tomorrow.
Uhh...
Grandpa's not really well... Give me a couple of days... You'll get the money...
Don't get on my wick. I want my money.
-But how...?
Just... Give me two days... Grandpa's not well... I'll give you the money once he's better...
My blood's boiling.
I've got little sisters... An ageing Mam... And an ailing Tad. They need the money, and they need it tomorrow.
But if I can't get it by then... Who cares if I scream my guts out with your truth? How's that?
Are you out of your mind?
Okay...
Here...
Sell these tomorrow... Keep everything you get...
How dare you?
I'm asking for my pay.
I'm not your servant or a blimmin' blackmailer! I need my money, and I need it tomorrow.
You'll get it.
Roshni!
Get up, Roshni!
'Morning, Mum...
-Morning. Go have breakfast.
Get up, Roshni!
Not now, Mum... Gimme two minutes...
What good is it? Your sister's gone downstairs too... Get up and have breakfast; you're getting late!
Get up, Roshni!
Saqib...
Saqib!
Shayan!
Get up!
Good Lord... Wake up, mate!
Shayan!
-Mhm...
Get up! I'm getting late...
Shayan?
-Hmm?
I've been screaming for ages! Get up already!
-Mhm...
Okay... You asked for it!
Get up! Now!
Okay! Hey! Stop!
-Shayan!
I have to go to University! Got an assignment to submit!
-Be done with the water already!
Get up!
-Okay...
Shayan...
I've got a maths exam...
Could you help me with this question?
What's up, Mr Romeo?
You say no day is complete until you've seen me...
I was looking out the window all the way today...
I didn't see you.
Roshni...
I've given you an anaesthetic... Let me know if it hurts.
-Sure...
Who is it?
-'Sec...
Yeah?
Where's Dr Rana?
He's busy right now...
-Tell him it's Guddi.
I told you he's busy.
-I told you to tell him it's me!
Okay... Doc...
It's a certain Guddi... Wants to talk to you...
-Yeah, give it here...
Yeah, just a sec... Here.
Hello?
I need to see you. Right now.
-Right now?
I'll be there in an hour.
It's 15 minutes to the mansion. Get here before the 16th, or I ain't callin' you or lookin' your way again.
I'm stitching up this patient, Guddi... I just need...
Hello?
Guddi? Hello?
Here...
-Sir...
What are you doing?
-Nothing you can't finish, I'm sure?
Doctor!
Doc!
Doctor's orders, I guess?
Hey...
Do it only if you know how... Don't try something... You know...
Don't worry, sir... It'll hurt a bit, but only for a moment...
Ow!
What?
Madame Ruby?
You know her?
Mr Nusrat said you're such an upright man...
Why?
What makes you... Doubt it?
You want to journey into the abyss... Yet you're so afraid of the scars...
What does she do?
-Ehh?
Don't you know her? Who are you kidding? Why are you here if you don't know her?
Please don't ask anything... Just think someone's life is at stake and tell me what you know...
Few are famous for being upright... Very few...
Let's just say Ruby's the other sort.
I need to pay her a visit.
Why are you here?
-Please don't ask any questions... Just tell me what you know.
I swear to God you'll be rewarded for it. Someone's in trouble.
One of my friends... A businessman... He's quite close to this Ruby...
I'll talk to him... Fix an appointment for you...
-Please.
When?
-Right now. Call him right now. Tell him it's now or never.
Okay... I'll see what I can do...
Just three seconds away from being too late!
I could've done anything to stop those three seconds from passing! Clipped their wings if I had to!
Gonna ask me why I've called you?
Lemme take a good look... Before I... Start asking...
You can ask while you look, and look while you ask...
-Aye... Normally, yeah...
But you're so special...
Anyway... Here goes...
Why'd you call me here?
I've never had a dream in my sleep... Not for a moment... But only when awake...
Before last night. Guess who I saw in my dream?
I pray you say my name! I'll give everyone sweets!
Well, then...
What are you waiting for?
Your wish is my command.
Your guest... Is ours...
Don't worry... We'll give him a warm welcome.
Did she have anything?
Of course. She's so scared to see the murder videos she's doing everything I say! I've got her wrapped around my little finger!
Get Roshni ready...
Make sure she looks extra lovely.
But don't go overboard with the makeup.
Too much makeup would be so... Insulting to her youthful charms...
Blimey... Every word you say is so poetic...
Oh, please... Put a sock in it... Go.
Just a minute... I'll check with the doctor and...
-Is he here yet?
Yeah, he's inside... Please, wait here.
Doc...
Hmm?
The patients have been waiting for an hour!
Let them...
I haven't got the time...
Too busy thinking of someone...
Okay, Doc... Doctor's orders, I guess?
Guddi...
Oh, how these tearful eyes must've driven your lover mad...
Gotta say, you're one lovely maid...
Munna... Here...
I'm sure you're tired...
No... I just love his little eyes, cute little hands and feet... I want to be with him all day... Play with him all the time...
Okay...
Go. I need to talk to Mehek.
Lemme play for a moment?
-What?
D'you think he's a blimmin' bat or ball? Ask him to leave, Mehek... We need to talk.
Give him to me and go...
Easy there...
Your money's in your drawer.
My love, you take my questions away! Neat! Thank you!
M'boy...
Looks like he's here...
I'll go see...
Who d'you want to see, sir?
The name's Adam. I'm here to see Madame Ruby.
We need to search you, sir.
Adam, is that you?
Yes.
Khan...
We don't search our guests.
Ma'am...
Let him in.
Come. Here.
Thanks.
I've had enough of tittle-tattle...
-Bienvenue!
You hear me? If I don't get the money tomorrow, I'll crumble his false sense of honour like a tissue paper and throw it in the bin!
Don't you dare threaten me with the cops. Rosy doesn't fear them.
You know your place... Don't try to trick me!
Aye... I want the money tomorrow.
Mind if I ask something?
No.
You had a lover like Adam...
Who lives in wait of the day he'd get to die for you... But you had to marry that rat Shayan!
Keep your voice down! I'll be doomed if someone heard that!
-You're doomed, except you don't see it.
When a husband deserts his wife and baby, she's doomed, so to speak.
Come in. Make yourself at home. Please...
Take a seat.
My apologies...
I've apologised... Won't you say thank you?
Well, thanks...
Wow, you're so simple... You didn't even ask why I asked for a thanks.
I know why...
You stopped the guards before they could search me...
Oh...
Looks like you're smart after all...
Mr Waqas Hassan is rather self-concerned...
He isn't usually so concerned about someone else...
Before you came in, he told me I'll be having an important guest... Asked me to take care of you...
Naturally, I agreed...
Gave him my word, so to speak.
And you got to stand by your word.
Willy
Willy-nilly.
Not cricket. You didn't tell me...
You don't get admirers like Adam just like that.
How'd you miss him?
It's nothing...
We grew up together... I guess that's why...
Adam's a good man...
Naw, if he were just that, he'd be in the BASW or something...
But he only helps you.
Because he's much more...
He's a devoted lover...
Please...
Keep swiping...
Just stop at the one you like...
How'd you like some sandalwood syrup?
God, I love it so much...
The aroma, the flavour...
What a lovely feeling... Orgasmic...
Whoa...
Gotta say, you're quite the connoisseur!
Get her here...
Please, have a sip...
I don't think it's working!
-Shut up...
I mean it...
Some tea for you... Please, have some.
Don't want it. Get out.
As you say...
(Like I care!)
I've been dying for this moment!
I've been living for this moment!
Come in.
Don't be shy...
Greet him.
Good day, sir...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe