A child... A daughter is the dearest of all...
A hundred pearls cannot come close to a single tear falling from your child's eyes.
She's in tears before you two got married!
So...
What is it?
I braved every sorrow, hoping that my daughter would be repaid in happiness for everything I suffered.
You extinguished that hope.
Let me take a look...
I don't like this eye makeup... Please start it over again...
For the love of God... We've done it over three times! We've got other weddings to go to, you know.
Please do it over. I don't like it one bit.
Hey! Why aren't you ready yet?
Just -- Just fifteen more minutes, Mum... They haven't done my eyes very well... They'll start over.
I wish your ads could give a better idea about your work!
Hey!
Shut up and 'Hey' your Mum like that! Quickly, now, get to it!
There's something I wanted to tell you...
-Yeah?
They're here for Roshni... Adam's here too.
Is that it?
I've welcomed them myself.
I know...
What is it then?
Mehek's in there, crying.
Why?
She's getting married to the man of her dreams... What's her problem?
She says her Mam would've held her hand and taken her downstairs if she were with us.
Why aren't you talking to me?
Mum?
Yeah?
I'm gonna need twenty minutes or so... Why don't you go take Mehek downstairs?
It'll delight her... And Grandpa.
What's the big deal? I'll take you both downstairs together.
It wouldn't really be the same...
But... As you wish...
Okay.
I'll escort her downstairs. Get ready quick.
Yeah.
-Get to it!
Come, Guddi...
Yeah, the eyes...
Actually, forget it. I can do the rest myself. Go. I don't think you can do it.
Go!
Aren't you getting late for somewhere or something?
Blimey...
Let her have it her way...
My heart wants to tell you everything I've gone through...
But my mind makes every betrayal come to life before me, and shoots my heart dead with it!
Why did you agree, then?
Uncle's might... My helplessness... Neither would budge one bit.
So you want me to give his might and your helplessness free rein to kill my daughter's happiness?
I don't fear his threats.
My sister loves her kids so much...
He said her husband would divorce her and take the kids with him if I didn't give in.
If only you had an ounce of that love for my daughter!
What do you say? What should I do?
Wait here.
I'll be back.
Why aren't you answering my phone?
I'll go get my bag...
♪ My heart was set on a dream ♪
♪ That's falling apart at the seam ♪
Roshni! You ready?
Yeah.
Hello?
Ie.
I'll be at the gate with Roshni in about eight minutes. Where are you?
Close by. In the back alley.
I'll go have a look. Check if anyone's around. I'll watch out for you. Just be ready to move on my signal. And hide this bag behind you, okay?
-Okay.
Here.
Leave this place.
They'll catch me again.
You say you're fearless, but hesitate so much.
No time to waver. You'll lose everything if you don't do anything. So... Which way is it?
And what if I got there but didn't get what I'm doing all of this for?
Stand firm against Asher Khan's tyranny.
I'll clear the way for you downstairs.
Get out by the back gate.
I should take a look...
What if it's someone else?
Dad?
Love, care, affection...
I couldn't give you anything, my dear...
But now that I see you leaving... It feels like you're taking my world with you...
There'd be nothing left of it the moment your steps took you out of this place... It'll all be so... Empty...
Why are you saying that, Dad?
Please... Forgive me for everything...
God bless you, love.
He better not throw a spanner in the works!
Munna...
Take him downstairs. The guests are here. It isn't proper... C'mon, now...
Gettin' all dewy-eyed, are we?
Wait here. I'll be back.
Fine now?
Shahmir's seriously ill...
On your feet, Roshni! Double time! Shut the door!
Close it already!
Quickly!
All clear! Come!
Hey! Where are you off to? Back gate, remember?
Come.
Guard!
He's gone. Come.
You're clear.
What happened?
I'm not doing something wrong... Am I?
Of course you are. Very wrong, in fact. Stopping for the most ill-timed questions!
Get going, mun! Double time!
Guard!
Get me these medicines.
Yes, ma'am.
Quickly! Get back quick, okay?
Go!
Psst!
I've sent the guards away. Your way's clear for half an hour.
Whatever happens, just... Don't be afraid. Take up arms against tyranny and you'll find that fate stands with you like a mother.
Quickly, now!
Thank you, Aunt... Thank you so much...
I may be on the side of the unfaithful... But I'm not one of them!
Come in.
I hope you like the room.
-Of course, thanks.
Just call 313 if you need anything.
Go and change. I'll get something for us.
Roshni!
Roshni! Where are you?
Everyone's ready!
Roshni?
Now where'd she go?
What's for dinner?
I'll tell you in a sec. Thank you.
Where's your wedding gown?
Threw it away with the same unease, agony, and grief I'd put it on with.
Get me a new one, okay?
I give you my life!
We leave in an hour and a half. As you like it.
Want to have something?
No.
Where were you?
Putting him to sleep. He's not well, you know...
Let's go get Roshni.
Mum! Mum! Roshni isn't in her room!
What?
Must've gone for a stroll... Go see the guests. I'll get her.
Roshni!
Roshni?
Roshni...
Roshni!
Roshni...?
Roshni...!
Roshni!
Wait.
Where?
Aliya said you called us to get Roshni.
I'll call you when she's ready.
Go.
You'll get petrol for 50 Rupees, I tell you!
Aye, the day you become the Prime Minister!
You havin' a Turkish?
No, we're just waiting for the day.
-Celebrating in advance, you know?
Qutb!
-Grandpa?
Come here.
It's getting late. The Reverend's waiting. Go and get Roshni.
Sure... By the way... They're filling nominations for the local election next week... You made me a promise...
And I will honour it, but go get Roshni first!
Grandpa!
Get going already!
What a twit!
Zulaikha!
Zulaikha...?
Zulaikha...
Good Lord...
Your teary eyes, your worried face, your heart growing restless by the moment... That's all it'd take to kill me...
Please wipe your tears. Stop worrying, and get a hold on yourself!
How?
Just... How?
My daughter ran away, desecrating my honour with her filthy footsteps!
It's her wedding... They're all down there...
And their questions wait out the door, mocking... Look at them jeer at me, knowing I have no answer...
How do I get a grip on myself?
Zulaikha...
Don't worry, even if things go out of hand...
Would you rather wait for a quiet death...
Or try your best to get out?
So... Which way is it? A quiet death in inaction or giving your best shot to survive?
For the love of God... Help me... Save me from this disgrace...
I will.
You have my word.
But there's something you must do...
Order me. I can give you my life.
In that case...
Wipe these tears...
I can't see them.
There.
Now, listen to me and do as I say...
Two tickets to Karachi, please.
What happened?
No idea...
Why do I see this fear in your eyes?
Your eyes should be glowing to see your destination...
Don't insult your destination by looking at it with such fear and sorrow...
C'mon.
It's all an illusion...
A trick I'm playing on myself...
But Lord... What a lovely illusion...
They say illusions are lovely until you find out it's a trick...
I know everything about it...
But this illusion refuses to lose its appeal for me...
Sorry...
You're fine, aren't you?
Got word of Shayan?
Not yet...
But I'm working on it... Hope to hear something soon...
And how are you, little one? Lookin' lush, not gonna lie! Congratulations!
-Thank you.
Bless you, bless you all! Especially our two stars here! Would you look at them!
Don't let it go to your head, okay?
I ain't callin' you stars because you're looking as lovely and bright as the stars.
You're the stars of this show, right? Puttin' up your best act? And, dyw, this groom for hire here's a real gem!
Ward the evil eye off them, will you? I'll be back!
Rana...
Do you think it'll be anything close to as easy as it sounds?
My confidence won't let doubt creep in.
Someone's gotta be disgraced today...
Just... Do as I say and I assure you... It won't be you.
We can wait here, Saqib.
Not here.
Over there. Come.
Here.
Want to have something?
Bye.
See you...
Hey!
Why are you out here in the dark?
We're just... You know...
It's getting late. Why don't you wait in there?
Except if you're... Hiding something?
H --
H -- How do you know?
I have enough experience reading that silence.
In your case, I read worry... And a fair bit of fear...
What is it?
I can help.
Well...
Zulaikha...
Who told you?
Grandpa...
How does he know?
He planned it!
What are you saying?
Grandpa says I can stand for the local elections this --
Roshni's eloped!
Roshni...?
Run away...
I couldn't even govern my house...
How'll I run this country?
The end of my political career...
The end of my political career before it even began...?
What'll they think?
Take up arms against tyranny and you'll find that fate stands with you like a mother.
Where to?
Where's the detective chief inspector?
He'll be here in three hours.
Three hours?
-Yes.
I'll wait here.
Please call the bride. It's time for the nuptials.
-I'm getting late too.
She'll be here in a moment... I sent for her...
Qutbuddin will be here with her any moment...
Girls these days...
Girls these days... You know...
Girls these days... You know... Take forever...
Girls these days... You know... Take forever... What with friends and all...
Take a good look, m'girl. Few kids get to see their Paw as a groom...
Excuse me, siùir!
-God forgive you!
How easily you 'siùir'red your wife!
What are you saying?
Whose kid? Whose wife? And what marriage --?
My marriage to you! Our daughter! You lying cheat!
Oh, shut up! Stop accusing my son!
Happy now? Always wanted to ruin my life, didn't ya?
Snatched your son back from me so that you could give him to someone else?
What are you saying?
Only the truth...
He didn't send a penny home for three months, and my poor little daughter's been starving...
And he's here getting married!
He's the most upright man around here!
Another word and...!
What do you think you're doing?
I don't know her, and I sure as anything don't know her daughter!
Why should we believe you?
I swear by my daughter's life...
He's my husband!
And -- If you didn't believe me... I'll burn myself to death right here!
And you! You better come back right away, or the cops will be lookin' for you!
Twenty years running a clinic here...
All I've earned here is respect.
I vouched for you...
And you thank me by betraying my trust!
Get out! Right now!
Out!
You have no right to do any of this, Doctor.
Just let chaos reign...
Your honour depends on it!
Zulaikha asked me to do this. I swear!
Out!
Get out!
-But -- Doc!
Just listen to me!
-Why'd she lie?
-I don't know, but she was!
-But we mean it for real! Out!
Please -- Listen to us!
-Get going! We don't want to hear anything! We won't take any of that nonsense! Out!
Never thought you'd be so shameless! Out of my sights! Out!
-I swear she's lying!
I better not see you coming this way again!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe