I don't know what to say.
You don't need to.
Just... Be happy...
I'll get going...
Adam...
Wouldn't you like some tea?
In the evening...
Sure.
Alright.
Take care.
That's dresses and sweets for everyone...
One for Aunt... And one for Mr Noor...
And this one for my daughter-in-law.
I'm gonna give Mehek 20,000.
Guria!
We leave after the prayer.
The Lord will bless us for what's to come.
Of course. I've taken care of everything. I've even got something for the servants.
They're very well-off... I hope they're happy with it.
My son's getting what he always wished for!
The kind of son who'd rather stay hungry than bother anyone else...
His heart's as white and soft as a cotton ball...
Well, his patience has been rewarded...
The dream that he always had will now be his reality.
Hello, Mum.
-Hello.
-Hey.
I've kept things for charity. Keep it on the terrace after he's blessed it. It'll ward the evil eye off him if the birds had it.
I'll go get it.
You didn't have to do all of this, Mum.
Please don't be so happy...
I mean...
We don't need to be so... Extravagant...
What are you saying?
It's the happiest day in the life of my only son!
Were it up to me, I'd provide for every being in every corner of the city.
Not so fast!
Over here.
-Eh?
C'mon.
Done?
Thanks to You, O Lord, I live to see this day.
The Reverend's here after ages.
Come with me...
He'd bless you.
I think I'll pass.
I said you're coming, so you better come!
No, doctor... Please spare me... For the love of God...
Don't give me another shot... It only makes me worse!
This shot's going to relieve you forever, sir.
I don't think you'd need any more than... Five, maybe?
Then, you can kiss all your troubles, pains, and misery goodbye, farewell, adieu... Forever.
I don't want another shot!
No way, Zulaikha!
-Stop being childish!
Zulaikha! Tell him I don't want another shot! I don't! Not ANOTHER!
There, now... That's all it was...
Doctor!
I knew there was something dodgy going on here... And in Aunt's mind!
Let go...
That's all...
Doc --
Ehh...
Give him some water.
I'll take my leave.
Come in.
How are you?
Fine...
You wanted to see me?
Yes... Someone's coming here with a proposal for my girl today...
I want you to prepare for a welcome so warm they know we accept before we even say a word.
Who's the proposal for?
Mehek.
Who is it?
Adam's mother is coming.
Mind if I ask you something?
Not at all?
How do you know they're coming if they haven't already proposed?
Just do as I said.
Okay.
Take care.
-Take care.
At last...
I swear, I tried to stop myself from paying a visit in your thoughts...
But, I guess...
It didn't work...
Something's come up.
Yes?
You mentioned a match for Roshni two months ago... The charming boy from the family on easy street, remember?
I said she's gonna study further.
Yeah. What is it?
Tell them we accept their proposal...
As long as they can come here today!
Today?
Right now.
My honour is at stake...
And yours...
I'll do something.
Wait!
Over here.
I hear Adam's family is coming here to propose your marriage?
No idea.
Really? Way to run the show, then.
What do you mean?
The man with you that night... Was it, by any chance... Adam?
The night you besmirched my pure and sinless daughter's name.
The Lord knows every truth.
Funnily, some liars know it too.
I'm sure time will clear everything up... And when it does, the weight of your lies will stay your tongue. And these questions shall be silenced.
You know, I sometimes wonder...
How your son would feel when he grows up and his friends constantly remind him his Mam's past...
What've I done that'd embarrass Shahmir?
Oooh... Big words...
Lemme give you an example...
Let's say he's in Year 11, and he gets into a row with a friend...
He has the strength to fight back and the finest four-letter-words to mouth, but don't you think it'd burst his bubble of courage, strength, and ego if someone asked him about his Tad?
Then again, I know how clever you are... You'll come up with something!
So... How clever am I?
Got a Mam for hire. Got Adam for hire. I'm sure it ain't that hard for you to get him a Tad for hire.
You're artful, I give you that!
I've got my cloak, Mum...
I don't need to put it on before Aliya.
It's not a cloak...
It's a request...
An imploration...
A prayer... A mother's prayer to her daughter...
What are you saying, Mum?
I can't bear the sin of making you beg me...
Your mother's dignity and honour are in your hands.
Please... Guard them well...
What do you want me to do?
Someone's coming with a proposal for you in the evening.
They're very good people. Please, accept it.
But how?
And why?
I just can't...
No...
You leave me with no choice but to end my life!
May I try Saqib's number... Just once?
Okay.
I pray he answers it.
Now, don't answer if you get a call from her number. Her Mam calls you to check.
Your turn, Saqib... What are you waiting for?
What happened?
He rejected my call.
Mum...
Mum... I can't watch you cry...
Then ask your sister to say yes and wipe my tears!
My mouth can't utter it...
You can take it as my silent acceptance...
My girl...
Dad...
Yes?
Is everything ready?
Yes. I've also done what you asked me to do two days back.
What?
Someone's got a proposal for Roshni. It's a very good family. I like them. They're coming to see you this evening.
Good. Very good indeed.
I'll make ready, then.
Thank you, O Lord...
Don't take anything Guddi says seriously.
She says anything...
You're my son.
You're me.
I won't let anything happen to you.
You're innocent.
An angel...
The Lord won't let your prayers go unanswered.
Plead with Him in His court with your little hands...
Tell Him the moments weigh on your mother like eons.
Tell Him she's tired... Broken...
Pray to Him...
Ask Him to help me find your Dad...
My prayers don't seem to work...
As if they're cursed to never reach Him...
Pray for me, will you?
You're my boy...
You're me...
What's he doing with you?
Well...
His mother's -- In the kitchen -- To get something...
Something's not right...
Uh...
What?
If you ask me, it looks far more like you're Guddi's maid than the other way around!
Anyway... There's something you need to know.
The Lord has blessed my Roshni with a wonderful match. They'll be here in the evening.
Tell your dearest Adam he better not show up before they're gone!
But -- Aunt --
-That will be all.
You better not say you don't even talk to him...
Because I'm not falling for this one... Not now...
Such undying love...
Seldom lets you fall out of touch...
I hope we're clear.
I'm thinking of fielding you in the election...
What do you say?
Think about it, okay? Go.
Yes, Munshi? Did you talk to Hatim?
Hey...
He's gone.
He was old, you know...
He fought Asher Khan's tyranny and his loneliness until his last breath...
He survived the last year and a half thanks to you...
His loneliness took over him the moment you came here...
And his solitude took his life...
Mr Khan!
What is it?
The prisoner's dead.
How?
No idea.
Where the devil were you?
Come. We need to get rid of the body.
Come.
Please, come in.
Here.
Good evening.
-Good evening.
Good evening, Mr Malik. How are you?
-Good evening. Please, sit.
Thank you.
'Evening.
-'Evening.
They're the ones I told Mrs Zulaikha about.
Bless you. Pleasure to meet you.
Dead?
Yes, Mr Khan.
What do we do with the body?
The priest would make sure the entire town hears it... We need to do something else...
I'll pray for his soul.
Munshi...
-Sir?
We'll bury him around here.
Get the gravedigger.
Yes, sir.
So glad to see you... You may not know it but your grandfather and I are friends from college.
Wow... That's wonderful...
-Indeed...
I'll bring Roshni here.
-Sure.
And how are you doing, Mr Malik?
-Fine, with His blessings.
-I hope you're taking your pills on time.
-Of course.
Bless her.
She's lovely. Come.
She's just the type I wanted for my son.
I know just what you're gonna say next!
Pray tell?
You're gonna say, 'We accept her'.
Of course. We're just waiting for Mr Malik's reply.
You're leaving for England in 15 days. When are you coming back?
A year from now? Two at the most.
A year?
Isn't it too long?
I'm eagerly waiting to get him married off. They can get married next week if it's fine with you.
I want him to take her to England with her.
That's great.
I'll ask for a day's time. I'll tell you tomorrow.
It's for the best.
-Okay.
-Alright.
I'm going...
To bury him...
Make sure he's comfortable, okay?
He's lived a hard life...
Lower him gently...
Consider these the first thing I gave my love...
Take care of them... Treat them with respect befitting royalty.
O God, the Creator and Redeemer...
Tell the gravedigger to keep his trap shut... Any way you see fit!
Okay?
Shall we lower him?
Yeah. Go.
In your hands, Oh Lord,
We humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;
Deliver them now from every evil
And bid them eternal rest.
Forever and ever. Amen.
Okay, that's enough...
What happened, sir?
Ma'am! They're here! They're here, sir!
Keep it there.
Hello.
-Hello.
How are you?
Hello.
-Hello. How are you?
-Bless you. Come.
Please, have some.
Thank you so much.
Excuse me for speaking so freely... But we've come here with a lot of hope...
I'm here to ask for your daughter Mehek's hand in matrimony for my son, Adam.
Don't worry...
I'll care for Mehek like my own daughter... If not more!
We've got many hopes... Please don't turn us down.
There'd be very few men in the world like Adam.
My Mehek would be very fortunate to have someone like him.
So you accept?
Of course. I'm chuffed.
I was thinking if you've asked Mehek...
I know my girl... She knows what I decide will be best for her.
I don't think I'll ever find a better family for her than you.
Roshni's fiancé doesn't live in Pakistan.
They're insisting because of, or should I say, forced by the fact that he won't be back for a couple of years - his job won't allow it - that they be married as soon as possible...
They don't have time. They'd rather have them married off in two weeks.
If you wouldn't mind...
Of course not.
But I do...
Yes?
Mr Malik... Before he passed away, Dad had me promise...
That I'd get my sister married off before I get married... And she's just started her bachelor's...
So I thought if we could get some time...
I'd rather... Mehek and I can get engaged when Roshni gets married... It'd give us some time...
I can understand.
Your father was a close friend of mine.
I know.
It's my duty to honour his promise.
Thank you.
Too bad the lights had to go out at this delightful moment!
I told you not to vote for that bloke! But you didn't listen to me.
Go and turn the generator on.
-I'll go have a look.
I'll go have a look.
-No, Qutbuddin will take care of it.
No, Qutbuddin will take care of it.
-No problem.
-Yeah, go.
No problem.
He's your son.
A son-in-law's just like a son.
-Of course.
-Munna!
Munna!
Yeah, Adam?
Why isn't the generator on yet?
It's out of petrol! Just a minute!
Hurry up!
Would you look who we have here! Adam! Oh wait, you don't know him, do you? Let me tell you...
I'm sure you know who he is though. Your wife-to-be's son!
Lower your voice before someone hears you!
Aww, not so fast, bytt!
You haven't even met your almost-stepson yet!
Shahmir... Adam. The man for hire.
For hire... Don't you get it?
Let me put you wise.
Like cars, tents, and labour for hire, your Mam's got herself a husband for hire... Your Tad for hire!
He's her man for hire!
That's right.
I'm a man for hire.
But I'm here to help someone out. Lend a hand.
I've been hired for this job by my Lord, and I'm doing this to earn His reward.
As if what you're doing is worth rewarding!
Can't believe you think He'd reward you for getting engaged to a married woman!
Look at yourself... And look at her, hiding her face in her nods!
You seriously think you're earning His favour?
Gentle reminder, your shoulder devil's having a hard time keeping up with your long list of sins!
Gotta say, though...
In darkness and light... You look lush!
Mind if I take a good look?
Aye?
That isn't the sweet smell of happiness... It's gunpowder!
I'm just waiting for it to get to Aunt's room... Engulf this entire place...
Before I light the fuse!
For now, though... Gotta write more scenes for our heroic villain, Saqib!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe