It's been 40 days since your mother passed away.
I never had the time between the grief and the tears...
But?
But I had your mother promise me before she passed away...
Promise what?
We betrothed you to Masooma.
She's your fiancée now.
Your orphaned childhood... Our love for you... Everything we ever did to make sure you never felt neglected... Didn't you think of anything before refusing?
I remember everything.
But Masooma's my sister. She's 15 years younger than me! Didn't you think of that?
It makes no difference.
Khadija's much younger than me... About 15 years.
Besides, I'm not asking you to get married right away.
Just... Accept it.
Get married a couple of years later, when Masooma comes of age.
I beg you, Uncle.
I've held Masooma most dear... But as a sister! I mean... I've been her brother from her youngest days!
That's unfair... You're doing injustice to me, to her, to our bond... Just look at her age!
She's my sister. My sister!
She was, yes.
She's your fiancée now.
Your mother made a promise.
Let her grow up. Let her study. I thought we were past the dark ages when we'd get girls her age married off!
I'm not the one for her... God forgive that I ever think of it!
Besides, I've gotten ma --
-Not a word!
Not one more word!
Don't make me send you to your lonely Mum!
I'm descended from Badshah Khan... And Masooma from Asher Khan.
There's no one else who even comes close, let alone equal us.
You're the only man in the family.
I'm sparing your life in exchange for your acceptance!
I'm never coming back here again!
Mehek!
Open the door!
Jesus... Why've you locked it? Guards!
-Where are you, Mehek!?
Break it open!
-Mehek!
Hello?
Hello? Shayan?
Shay --
The name's Asher Khan. They call me the fortunate one.
Those who take up arms against me aren't so fortunate.
Lock him up!
What?
I said lock him up!
Sir!
Yes?
This Mir Adam?
-Aye.
Thank you.
Not so fast!
Good Lord... 102...
I'll call the doctor.
-No... No need... I'll take the pill. I'll be fine.
Why'd you have to get all wet?
Mum told me you never liked playing in the rain. When'd it grow on you?
Just yesterday?
Blimey... I'll get you some yahni.
Sir...
-Yeah?
Where does Malik Nureddin live?
Take a right here, then a left, then right again, and you'll be on a road straight to his manor.
Thank you.
-Take care.
You're coming with us!
Step on the gas!
No, Saqib, I can't...
No!
Good Lord, Saqib... I haven't got the courage!
Hmm... In other words you don't love me.
No way I'm vaulting the wall!
I mean just -- How?
Just like the other girls.
One of your friend's coming to meet one of mine... Come with her.
No way, Saqib.
I'm sorry.
C'mon, the van's here.
I'm coming in a second. Bag a seat for me!
-Okay.
I'm going, Saqib.
By your life and my love, if you didn't come...
I'm gonna slit my wrist. No chance I'm making it out of this alive.
You're mad?
I've got the knife on my wrist!
Jesus... Throw it away!
On three...
One...
The knife's right on my vein...
Two...
Just a little more pressure and I'll be gone, thanks to you...
For God's sake, Saqib... Don't even think about it!
Just say yes... Or my breaths will die out by the time you take your next gasp!
I'm about to say three...
Yeah... I'll be there.
Hey! Untie me you dunderheads!
Shut up!
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ My resolve faded as an aching wound took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ You were distant though so near ♪
♪ You're distant yet so dear ♪
♪ You etched your name on my heart, right here ♪
♪ You forgot me, yet you're dear... ♪
♪ My falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
Water...
Anyone here? I need water...
Water... My throat's drying up! Get me some water!
H -- Here... Wh -- What are you doing? Blimey! Get away!
What are you doing?
I'm giving you a taste of it for trampling my life under your feet. I want you to feel how you barged into my life, encroached on my heart, my mind, and my life!
I've come this far on this thorny road barefoot. It is time you tasted the blood on my feet!
What do you mean?
My helplessness
That you forced my body and my soul into,
Wagering my kids' share, my jewellery... And losing it all! I still remember how you had the audacity to barge back in without a shred of remorse...
I still remember my helplessness... For my marriage, my family's honour, and my children... I couldn't say a word!
You bringing a new woman home every night...
Oh, Mr Malik...
One look at you...
Drove me crazy...
You've given me so many sleepless nights!
It's your love, Mr Malik...
-Innit?
Mr Malik's love indeed...
What is going on?
Who's she?
The Empress...
She's gonna be my Empress tonight...
Didn't her beauty tell you?
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Ever thought about your daughters?
You gonna lecture me?
Lemme teach you some manners!
Come! I'll show you!
Having to live with this knot in my heart after your betrayal...
Mum... I'm scared...
Why'd Dad beat you?
Feel the helplessness yet?
FEEL IT YET?
What happened, Zulaikha?
She's gone raving mad --
Nothing! This man dropped the glass!
I'll let you go if you don't say a word.
Or I'll strangle you with that tongue of yours!
Are we clear?
Eh?
Where are we going?
Not far.
But where?
Paradise.
A paradise for lease.
I'm very worried. Please tell me clearly.
-Hey! Who's worried about going to Paradise? By the way, the lease is for your safety.
You telling me or want me to go back?
Okay... It's an internet café. That's what the board says, at least.
Closed down a year ago. Now it's a place for lovers to meet, to make fond memories to look back upon.
For 500 bucks an hour. Ain't that wonderful?
No. I'm not going to that sort of a place.
It's safe! Bet your head it's the safest lovers' point in the city!
Put on some lipstick before you get there. I'll give it to you. It'll be the icing on the cake!
No way!
Bring him here.
Aye...
They did...
Okay.
The day after tomorrow, it is.
And so my claws managed to seize your hooves...
You should've known...
Then again, I'm glad you got to see it firsthand...
Lock him in!
Where was he off to?
I know the place...
But why?
You'll know it in two days, Mr Khan.
Good morning, ma'am.
'Morning.
Did Dad have breakfast?
Yeah. Two hours ago. Then left for Hasilpore. He said the Tribal Council's meeting there. Adam was a bit under the weather so he took Qutbuddin with him.
Okay... Tell Rukhsana I want some tea.
She went home.
Who let her?
No one. She didn't ask you as you were sleeping. Left in tears. The folks at the village caught her husband stealing and beat him real bad.
It's 9.30 already...
Hey...
-Yeah?
Go and tell her - what's her name - the girl who came here with Mehek - to get me some tea.
-Okay.
Who's there?
Munna!
What's your problem?
Madame's calling you.
Well, then, what's her problem?
She wants to have tea. Rukhsana's gone home, so she asked me to tell you to prepare the dinner.
Why, she paralysed or something?
-Blimey, what are you saying?
You heard me.
She'll be really angry.
Oh really? Try me. Her anger's no more than a puny insect before mine! One shout and I can stomp the life out of it! Get it?
Please...
-Oh, put a sock in it!
Or I'm gonna twist your arm and smite you proper! Can you see your cheeks going red, then blue? Now go. Get going before I feel like doing it!
Told her?
Of course...
Okay.
Here.
What's up?
Just... Let me go...
Why are you running away from me?
-I'm running away from everyone.
But from this guy?
Okay, sit.
-This is wrong.
I don't like this place.
Munna!
Yes?
I asked for tea an hour ago. How much time does she need?
W -- Well...
I asked you something!
I'll get you in a moment.
Why?
I told you to ask her.
I did.
What'd she say?
More than I could hear.
What do you mean?
Guddi said she's not getting up.
Did you tell her I called her?
-Yes.
Girl, are you lookin' for trouble!
Guddi!
Munna came to rouse you. Told you I sent for you.
Get up! Right now!
What are you looking at?
Lower your gaze.
Lower your gaze or --
You better mind your eyes, tongue, and hands. I won't think twice before gouging your eyes out, cutting that foul tongue, or breaking those insolent arms. Are we clear?
Get off me!
I'll cut you down to size! Who do you think you are? You ruddy maid! Get off!
Think twice before looking at me that way, opening that mouth, or raising your hand! You won't get away so easily next time. You better remember it, because I will.
What's wrong with you? What were you thinking?
Are you touched in the head, Guddi?
Jesus... What've you done?
Destroyed everything...
Were you out of your mind? You've ruined everything!
So you think it's wrong... What you feel about me, that is...
Funny because I've always heard that you never care about right or wrong in love.
But it seems you haven't started going down the road of love... Even if you've charted your course!
Get a move on! Or you'll never get where you want.
You've got your own ways of 'measuring' love.
You forgot that a girl cares just as much about her family's honour as her love.
Okay... Have it your way...
But just stay here five minutes?
No... The van would be there any minute...
More like half an hour. Just be with me for five minutes. For me?
Munna!
Yes, ma'am?
Go and ask the guard to load his gun and be ready! I need him!
Go!
-Ma'am...
I'm getting late... I should get going.
Just a minute... I've got something for you. Don't you want to see it?
I'll put them on when I get back.
I've come here to put them on you myself.
I thought I'd look into your eyes when putting them on you. Get this Heavenly feeling...
As I tuck your lovely tresses behind your ears, making your heart and mine skip a beat...
And, blinded by the goddess of love wearing these earrings, I'd quietly shut my eyes.
You're comin' with us!
-Come out!
-Take him!
Saqib! N -- No! He didn't --
-Come!
I didn't...
-I'll tell you!
Aren't you ashamed of yourselves? Your family, what'd they think?
-No! We didn't -- We're not! No! Saqib!
Load your guns!
Ready?
Aim for her head.
Feel free to fill her with lead if she dares move, speak, or think!
Munna! Pick up her bags.
No -- Aunt... No... Please...
Thought you could get away with it, eh?
Come! Get out!
-Forgive her, Aunt!
Munna! Take her kid. Get a carriage. Come!
-No... Please, Aunt...
For the love of God, Aunt... Please forgive her!
-I'll show you!
Please, Aunt! She was really tired!
-Come!
No! She doesn't think when she's -- No, Aunt!
-Get lost!
Please, Aunt... She's helpless -- And -- Think of the kid... What's his fault?
The helpless listen more than they speak!
Please forgive her, Aunt! I beg you!
Uncle...
Quickly, Uncle...
Let me finish my tea.
Madame's gonna kill me! Have two cups once you're back.
Your house on fire or something?
-More or less. It's searing everyone!
Come.
-Come.
Sit down!
On the floor. Bloody Princess Charmings.
Please let us go. We haven't done anything.
Oh, please. If you ask me, you've done worse than murder.
For you've murdered your family's honour.
Look at yourself, smirching your family's name and saying you haven't done anything!
Not another word, okay?
We're gonna do as the inspector says.
Please... No...
No...
Here.
To the station.
You didn't get to your destination... But it appears you got the chance to nick a pair of shoes from there.
You soured the celebration in a moment...
Forget about me... Why didn't you think of your restlessness, the sleepless nights spent helplessly tossing around in this cell?
Just... Why'd you get caught?
They say nothing equals your own happiness,
Except that of your children.
You're not my son...
Nor are you me...
But, for a moment, it felt like I had broken out...
As if I was, at long last, free.
But you got caught...
Alas...
Caught...
Have you seen my sister, Uncle?
-No.
Yes, sir. I'll take care of it... Yes?
Good evening, sir.
-Good evening.
We've called the parents of everyone... Except her, who won't say a word!
And the lad's one daft baddie too!
She's always itching to give your type a proper beating. It won't be pretty if you angered her. Begging for mercy won't work with her. You've been warned.
So... Lemme ask you again...
What's your Dad's name?
What's his name?
Malik Ahmed.
Where do you live?
Mir Adam.
My boy...
This number is switched off.
Don't worry, Mehek. You know it's four hours before the train gets there. I'll do the chores and dash in half an hour. Please don't cry.
Promise?
-Promise.
M'boy...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe