I'll get going then...
You haven't had anything all day. Should I get you something?
-Thanks...
But I don't need it...
-Don't you care too much about needs?
Why not?
-Oh I won't dare...
I won't dare say a word about needing anything...
I'm here because I've learnt to respect needs...
I'd like to say sorry...
To you... To myself...
I'm so sorry I always misunderstood...
-No, Adam...
I swear...
You've earned a place in my heart.
The times may've done what they've done to my mind...
But my heart is crystal clear...
I'd hate to be the reason you're grieved or embarrassed.
I pray to get a chance...
To give you the happiness you deserve.
You're back! And Shahmir!
How're you, boyo? Guess what? I'd prayed that you come back quickly so I can play with you again!
You'd prayed?
Yeah.
Upstairs?
That's my story.
I didn't tell you my story to earn a place in your heart...
You asked... I answered...
Stories don't earn a place in our hearts, Guddi.
Surely not in a heart like mine.
But I will say this...
You have my respects.
Just respect?
Not a place in your heart?
Respect from the bottom of my heart...
-Well then, how say you respect what my heart wants?
Haven't felt like cooking something in ages.
Please, have it...
I'd be delighted.
Send it with Munna.
Nah...
This is too easy...
Too unfair...
For everything I've suffered!
I'll make you suffer...
I won't say much... Nor ask you to stop crying...
Nor give you anything close to a false hope...
Cry all you want...
Over your misfortune... For your kid... Cry buckets!
But for God's sake, don't shed a tear for that blimmin' two-timer!
Betrayal craves tears.
It thrives on tears.
Get it?
Zafar!
You're -- Here -- Sir? How -- ?
Servants are paid to answer...
Questioning doesn't suit their poor selves...
Yet you asked two...
That's all the questions you'll ever ask in your life.
Before you dare ask another...
Remember that I don't need to ask anyone before kicking you out.
Forgive me, sir...
I wouldn't have said any of this if I hadn't already...
You know just as well that my hands know how to - and would love to - do the talking.
Get my car out.
Sir.
Come in.
Sit...
Not here to sit.
-Why?
Make yourself at home.
Oh...
I get it...
Coming into your daughter's room at this hour on her wedding night...
The embarrassment holds your feet...
You said something to her.
Aye...
She said she's scared.
I said it's okay. I'm right here.
But she's just a little girl...
What does she know about marriage...
Or her husband protecting her?
All she knows...
Is her Mum's lap...
And her Dad's chest...
So, I said...
'Go'...
You having a laugh?
-No.
I pity you.
I promise you, Mr Khan...
This is only the beginning...
You weren't there for me in my grief...
But I'll be right by your side in yours...
I'm honestly knackered. If you could just?
Take her to her room.
Get up. C'mon.
Come.
Mehek...
Me --
Shahmir's been crying for ages... I've heard him for five minutes! I thought you'd be calming him... But you look distressed yourself...
Mehek?
Why?
Hmm...
He's just a kid... How can he tell you?
Probably hungry... Or having a headache... Or just couldn't sleep?
Give him here and go...
Okay.
Shahmir!
Easy there, mate...
Here.
Mind if I asked something?
No.
Sure?
Not now...
I won't mind any bit of hope or comfort...
But if anyone were to pray for me... I'd shut him up.
What are you saying?
Nothing...
You wanted to ask something...
What is it?
Well... I've never seen my Dad...
Mum said the Lord God called him for something important...
And when she was gone, everyone else said she'd gone to see Dad...
I believed it back then...
But I could only believe it for so long before I realised I'm orphaned...
Don't say that, Munna...
No -- I'm not grieving or something...
I just wanted to ask...
If it's the same with Shahmir... Has he never seen his Dad too?
Never had a ride on his Dad's shoulders? Like all the other kids...
Or felt a tear of happiness fall on him as his Dad picked him up for the first time?
Or touched his Dad's face with his little hands?
Was it something I said?
No.
Not at all.
Everything you said was... Touching... Pure...
But it's never happened...
Shahmir's Dad never even picked him up?
But why?
Let's just say...
His Dad's with your parents now... For me, at least...
Munna! Don't go to bed just yet. Dinner's almost ready. You're coming with me to Adam's.
Couldn't he get anything for himself?
No questions.
Just do as I say.
You were crying?
N -- No?
Okay.
Sit.
Come here...
Little lies less than the eyes...
So... What happened?
Your eyes are doing their favourite thing.
Telling the truth.
Nothing, really... Don't say anything...
Do I look that dangerous?
That's what they all think, innit?
That Guddi doesn't know empathy... Kindness... Love?
Innit?
May I speak freely?
-Please.
That 'innit' says everything. That's how everyone thinks...
There was a time when I could sense pain a hundred miles away...
And whenever I did, I'd run towards it...
I didn't care who was suffering...
But only... How much I could ease him...
Until... It started weighing on my chest...
And gradually...
Suffocating me...
As I breathed my last...
I looked all around...
But there was no one to ease my pain...
Much less make me forget it.
And...
That's when Guddi got angry!
In her fury, she grabbed her empathy by the throat...
And throttled it until it begged to be forgiven...
Did you forgive it?
As for kindness... And love... Let's just say...
They died the same day...
God forgive --
-Don't.
Just pray...
That he never live a moment without thinking of me...
Just like I never stop thinking of him...
Who?
You know...
Our very own...
Iesu... Who is it this late? Could you go check?
Hello?
Hylo!
What is it?
Don't pretend like my 'hello' was nothing!
I mean -- Go on...
Don't turn in yet... Dinner's almost ready.
I won't claim you'd be delighted to taste it...
Just that I was delighted to cook!
Well, then...
I'll be delighted to try it!
Okay.
'Evening...
Why'd you lie to me?
-What?
You said they'd be back in two days!
I told you what they told me... What's my fault if they came back early?
Where's Guddi?
Why?
Don't bug me with another question and tell me... Where is she?
By the kitchen...
Hey...
Why's your phone off?
You didn't even tell me you're going!
Didn't think what I'd think...
Didn't think how restless I'd be if I didn't hear your voice... Or see you...
You're angry?
Was it something I did?
Munna... Tell him to get out of my way...
-Sir?
Didn't say a word!
Didn't even greet me back...
Ie, right...
You got a point.
Not greeting someone back's sinful. I'd rather stay away from it.
So, have a good night... But just one good night. Bye.
Munna... Show him all the way out, will you?
C'mon, sir... I'll show you all the way out...
Love the aroma.
-Made with love!
Just a sec... I'll let Grandpa know where we're going...
-Not so fast!
You lost it?
Why?
Don't you think we should ask him before leaving?
I'm older than you. Don't you think you should be doing as I say?
Of course.
-Innit? Then get a move on!
C'mon!
Loathe yourself yet?
So weak you couldn't even face yourself...
I'm not weak!
I ought to loathe you...
As your conscience, I ought to loathe you!
And I do!
You.
You. Are.
You. Are. Weak!
You think only Asher Khan's got the right to take lives.
You forgot about the Lord...
I didn't! It's Him I fear!
So you, already married to a woman, got married to that girl because you feared Him!
Why didn't your soul tremble at the thought?
Don't even think of tricking me. I'm as old as you...
-Okay, I'm weak!
I'm weak before my sister's tears... Not weak to face death!
I'm weak before her kids' fate!
I'm weak...
Oh, I get it now... You're worried about their fate...
What about the fate you've condemned Mehek to?
Hey!
Double time!
Quickly, Munna! Give it to me!
Come in.
You?
Why?
Why can't I come knocking here myself?
That's not what I meant... Not at all...
Oh? I wonder what that 'you' meant then... Mind telling me?
It's late, Guddi -- I told you -- Just send Munna...
So -- I was just -- Surprised to see you...
That's all...
Want me to leave?
You're my guest.
I wouldn't dare say that.
But I would say... They're all here... My family...
What'd they think if they saw you?
Thinking... That's the problem!
Here. Walk right behind us.
C'mon.
C'mon already!
-What? Where?
Quickly!
-Guddi!
Where are you ta --
You'll find out!
-Where are we going?
No one around here.
Get your thoughts in bed. It's too late.
What's with the smile?
Everytime you'd say something, I'd be furious...
But now...
I feel like smiling...
But if you don't like it...
I might as well not.
To like...
And your smile...
Grist, they sound one and the same. Synonymous, as they'd say in school.
May I?
Yeah?
I feel like smiling again. May I?
What are you waiting for? I'd be delighted.
'Synonymous'!
Aye...
Orders?
Oops...
I almost forgot you're here! What was I saying?
Sorry I didn't hear you?
Go.
How'd you come back?
You couldn't drop me, could you?
-Hmm?
Drop me home?
Anytime.
Quickly. It's a bit urgent!
-Go! Give it here!
Here.
Thank you.
Wasted my life...
And...
Ruined it...
I'd laugh when one of my toys broke...
I'd laugh when Mum and Dad beat me...
I always felt like smiling when someone tried to break my young heart...
Never cried for a moment...
Always covered my eyes and faked it at funerals...
Always got by without shedding a tear...
I've seen many eyes cry... Made them, too...
But it's the first time I've seen my own moisten...
Just pray it doesn't go on like this...
Because the more the tears...
The more the bloodshed...
I hope I'm not forcing myself on you.
-Of course not...
Just... Haven't seen you this way before...
Everything you say...
Every word is redolent with pain...
I fear forcing myself...
Life's forced itself on me for too long... Almost always...
This is the first thing I'm doing because I want to. For you.
A bitter childhood, Guddi...
Makes one's inner child cower behind his heart...
And, dare I say, your inner child is so... Innocent...
May the Lord bless it with a long life.
Feeling cold?
Yeah... But not because I want you to play my knight and give me your coat!
Oh, I don't have to be a knight to do that...
Just... Human.
What about you?
I'll build a fire.
Oh, just don't...
Why d'you want to go just yet?
The young Mr Malik can be a very nice man!
And these flowers...
Just... Lovely...
So lovely...
Okay now?
You forgot something.
Yeah?
I made something specially for you, but you haven't even tried it!
Ah, yes...
I'm sorry... I just -- Got too -- Busy talking... Forgot it...
Shall we?
After you.
Mind if I make a wish?
No?
I'm sure you would...
But I wouldn't be able to sleep if I didn't.
Go on.
Mind if I feed you your first?
Guddi...
I don't mind it, but...
You know...
Okay.
In the Lord's name...
Have something.
Here.
Lovely.
Everything.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe