Mehek!
So my curiosity finally broke your silence...
So you've loved, too...
A prisoner of love...
Behind bars...
May the Lord...
May the Lord free you...
Free you...
Mehek...
Mehek!
I'm starving.
Weren't you back then?
A little...
I've never had anything without some diet cola.
Where'd you get diet cola this late?
Don't know. Don't care. I just know I have to have my diet cola. Right now.
Because I grow peckish by the moment. That makes me angry. Raises my blood pressure. A shout or two may kill me, and I'm in no mood to die tonight.
So if you want the night to be peaceful and quiet, you better get me some.
There, now...
Take care of him.
O Lord, You are great!
It only took You moments to set him free...
May he have no trouble on his way.
Go.
Careful...
Hey!
Come here!
Aren't you coming?
Just go!
The journey ahead of you is long...
Mine ends somewhere around here...
Go...
Well, then...
Take care!
Take care.
I think there's someone there.
Where?
-Over there.
No one here. You're hearing things!
I want this money in the bank on time.
-Okay.
Munna!
Go. Bye.
Where are you going?
To the shop.
-Right now?
But the shops close at 9.
I know, Adam... But Mehek's asked me to get her a det cola. She had me swear I won't tell anyone!
What's a det cola?
Sugar-free.
Diet, ah yes...
Where'd you get one at this hour?
Go, I'll get it.
Here.
Keep the money.
She'll be waiting!
They'll be worried if I took the car out.
It's just a kilometre away... Ish...
Time for a walk in the moonlight, I guess?
Mehek!
What's that?
Well, what does it look like? Used to be bars...
Stood firm for a long time...
But gave way now.
Where's Shayan?
Shayan?
Where's he? He -- Ah, yes...
He's out.
Out?
Out there waiting for you.
Go and catch him if you can!
I'll take care of you later, you bleedin' codger!
-Catch him if you can!
Mr Khan! Shayan's run away!
-Mr Khan!
Don't get caught...
Just get away...
In the car, double time!
-C'mon, Khan!
I'm getting dizzy, you know!
Keep your voice down!
I'll go see... Munna would be on his way back...
-Oh, please!
Check any car or bike that comes here.
He must not escape!
Where to?
Back from the University. You know...
-Eh?
Let them go.
-Go.
Stop the car!
Stop!
Yeah?
-Yes sir...
Where are you coming from?
-From a wedding... Just family in here...
Let us see...
-You can't just!
I'm sure you have mothers and sisters... These are my daughters and daughters-in-law... Please don't remove their veils.
Let them pass!
Go.
-Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Hey, Asim...
-Hello there, Adam... How come you're here so late and... Without your car?
Yeah, I...
Give me...
A carton of diet cola.
I knew you close your shop at 11.
I prayed that your shop's open when I get here.
Just my luck!
-Yeah, I close at 11... Just got a little late with things...
It's about to rain, Asim...
But not here. It's windy. The clouds will be far away before they rain.
Asim! I told you it's gonna rain!
You're yawning, Aliya... Making me sleepy too... I got a test tomorrow.
Go, get some sleep.
-I'm not sleepy.
You don't know it but you are. Go get some rest.
I --
-Yeah. Go...
What are you doing here? You're out of your mind!
Of course. My love for you drove me mad the moment I saw you.
What are you doing here?
Justice.
What kind of justice?
-Doing justice to your memory.
For God's sake, get out. They're gonna kill me!
God forbid! I pray our love be immortal...
Just... Go.
Go!
What's that on your hand?
-What? It's nothing, really...
Go!
Go before someone sees you! Careful!
Mind your step!
♪ Seeing the raindrops, old memories ignite ♪
Munna!
♪ These raindrops slowly set my heart alight... ♪
Munna told me you wanted some diet cola.
Thank you.
Good night...
I mean... It's nothing...
Blimey, you're all wet! Come in.
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
Mr Khan... I'm sorry...
I've got kids... An ageing Mum and an ill Dad...
I fell asleep... I didn't notice... Mr Khan...
You didn't just fall asleep...
The Reaper's knocks put you to sleep.
Mr Khan... Please...
The dogs can have their treat...
Bless, O Father, Thy gifts to our use and us to Thy service; for Christ's sake.
Amen.
I felt like I should thank you for this, but my huge favour to you kept staring at me. Kept hushing me.
So, no sorries, no thank yous!
Hungry friends, or hungry enemies...
What's the difference?
I would've done it for anyone. Without ever expecting a word of thanks.
That's what I don't get about you straight and simple types... Why do you bother yourself hoping for some future reward from God?
I mean, I believe in His reward, but where do you get the courage, man? Your husband ran away 5 days after your wedding, and - forget cursing him - you don't even say one bad word about him!
Because I am the more guilty.
He never forced himself, except when expressing his love.
I took the road from love to passion myself.
I pressed him to get married.
Fantastic...
You just destroyed the image I had of you...
What do you mean?
Modest looks, care for everyone, care for mankind... It just took a moment for everything to sound so suspicious!
I mean, look at how much Grandpa trusts you. Look at the great man he is. Now look at who you are.
If anyone asked him to give another name to trust and faith, I'm sure he wouldn't think before saying 'Mehek'!
And, Iesu, look at his Mehek! Pressuring a lad to get married, all in secret, now living a lie. Chuffing lovely!
I did what I thought was best. For me and my love.
Do you think my love would blind me so much that I'd let him go without giving him reason to come back?
I can't say about blinding you... But I can see that you didn't give him reason enough to come back.
He broke the shackles in his feet the moment he stepped out, before trampling your faith under them and disappearing forever!
He hasn't disappeared... He just hasn't come back.
I'm sure he has his reasons...
I'll ask him when I see him.
Blimey, such unshakeable faith!
You forced him into marrying you so he wouldn't run away, and now you're denying that he ran away! D'you suppose he's gone off to China to get some toys for your kid?
I had my reasons...
What?
I had a friend...
Shanzay...
No way I'm going to sleep before I've heard this one.
Here.
I've got a chance to be kind after so long... Poverty and drudgery have me occupied round the clock...
How far is Mir Adam?
About 4 hours from here.
But your Uncle controls everything in the area. There's a police checkpoint ahead. He may catch you there.
So I'll tell the police he had me locked up!
Don't be stupid. The law kneels before men like your Uncle.
You want to get there or not?
How much?
-120 for the tea.
Okay.
Her heart's weak. I think she's in shock.
She's safe now, but any worry or shock may be dangerous.
Fakhr... Shayan's dearest friend.
And Shanzay, mine...
We used to see each other together.
That's when they took a liking to each other.
Shanzay didn't think much... She lost her heart to Fakhr.
She just saw the beginning of a happy life... She never thought about the end.
And he left for Pakistan, saying he'd be back in 15 days.
Apparently, he's been doing as the Romans do!
I'm sorry, I have this habit of joking... Can't disappoint my old habit!
Anyway, go on.
15 days became 1 month, and soon, 2.
Shanzay got ill.
Not a word. Not a trace. Not a hope.
Her lively face became barren.
Full Juliet. Complete with the sadness!
Innit?
Yeah.
It was her love...
She came to my room one day...
Shanzay!
-Mehek!
What happened?
-Mehek...
Easy there...
Mehek...
My life, my dreams... Everything's finished!
God forbid! What are you saying? What happened?
Fakhr got married in Pakistan.
I'm sure you're mistaken.
I'm sure he's joking!
-I'm not mistaken!
He called and told me himself. Sent me this picture! He said I'm no one to him!
That's Fakhr! I'm ruined now, Mehek!
Shanzay!
That's when I got insecure about my love.
You ought to be.
Orders, Mr Khan?
Any progress?
He's left a trail and we're on it.
Rest assured, sir. You'll have him by the morning.
Bless me!
Adam...
You were smiling.
Yeah.
I saw you.
Where?
Here. Smiling, of course.
Oh...
Don't ask me why.
Oh I wouldn't dare. I know it already. I know everything!
Pray tell me?
I'm sure you saw Mehek a while back. You're smiling because you're thinking of her.
No I'm not.
-Yes you are.
I told you.
-I told you.
Guria... Go to sleep.
Shayan's Mum fell ill a while later.
Or at least... That's what he told me.
He'd graduated by then.
It almost killed me when he talked about going back.
Mehek...
You're my world.
I can't live without you.
Leaving you pains me a lot.
I swear by you, I'll be back soon.
If you can't believe me... Come with me. We'll go together.
Come back together too.
That's what Fakhr said...
He wrapped his false promises to Shanzay in sweet words too.
You're doing the same, aren't you?
The fear of losing him blinded my unfortunate self...
To Grandpa's trust... My family... Their love... Everything...
So what do you want?
Marry me.
I will.
I never saw him after he was gone.
His number was off... Offline on Facebook... His old place was empty.
Ever thought about suicide?
I did.
Almost ended my life twice.
What stopped you?
The first time, I found out about the child growing inside me.
The second, when my grief forced my courage to its knees...
Yeah?
I heard the call to pray on my phone. Just like now.
I felt a fear of God...
Then heard the call again. Carefully, this time.
I felt my courage get back on its feet by the time it ended.
This is as far as we go.
There's a sewer over there, and across from it there's a police station.
I wish I could do more for you.
I haven't got anything for you.
Take care. May the Lord protect you.
And yeah, don't do something silly.
Bye.
-Bye.
So you forgot your family's trust in you for the puny fear of your lover never coming back?
Never thought what'd happen if he never came back?
You outta your mind, eh, girl? You outta your blimmin' mind?
Two days after the marriage, I was just as surprised as you.
Only you're laughing, and I was crying.
Just... Just tell me what you were thinking when you got married.
You don't think.
The heart sends the brain off on vacation the moment it falls for someone.
The heart thought about its fear and made me do it.
At least someone thought about something!
Anyway... Go to sleep. It's morning already.
Everyone gets up early here.
-I'll get up when I want.
Do me a favour, will you? Blockade all ways to me.
Help me with this, bro... I don't get anything! 7th grade maths is really hard!
Come, Masooma... The car's waiting for you. Your Mum's got to go to the market after dropping you at your tutor's.
Just a minute, Dad. Let me ask Shayan just one question.
I told you not to call him bro.
Just say Mr Khan.
Okay, Dad.
Shayan... I thought I'd see you before I leave. You've got a flight today. You must be late.
Of course, Aunt.
Bless you. Come.
Bye.
-Bye, Dad.
Uncle...
What was that about 'bro'?
She used to be like your sister.
What do you mean?
It's been 40 days since your mother passed away.
I never had the time between the grief and the tears...
But?
But I had your mother promise me before she passed away...
Promise what?
We betrothed you to Masooma.
She's your fiancée now.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe