Don't wipe those tears.
After what she's done, it's best that you let it all out.
A father's tears prove that he hasn't lost his honour after his daughter...
I cried a lot too... All night... Know why?
I thought of you. A father who'd want nothing but to search the world for his daughter, but can't even stand on his own two feet...
I wish I could do something for you...
Lemme rub your feet...
-No...
Please don't stop me... Let me do whatever I can... I can't just sit back and relax...
Hey, Aunt... Meet Roshni.
Hello... Bless you. Bless you two.
You have a way with words, Saqib... But got to say... No words could ever capture her brilliance!
No words can describe your English rose...
-Come in.
-Come, my dear...
God bless you. Come in.
Ever trusted someone without reason?
But look where you ended up...
What's this got to do with trust?
Oh, everything...
What do you mean?
Just a fever. A puny fever. That's all it took to get you in this state.
A bit fishy, don't you think?
I could never think of anything but getting better...
I swear you've been brought to this state... And I swear you will be fine...
You're kidding.
I feel for you. You've got a special place in my heart. Just... Don't ask why.
Don't tell anyone what I said if you want to get well soon!
Guddi!
-Ie, what?
Your son's crying.
-Noted. Go.
You're only taking the pills I give you.
O Lord...
Save me from this trial, or at least remind me of the sin you're punishing me for, so I can know what I've done to deserve this...
Hey, Rida...
Hey...
Why are you crying? There, now...
Bless her. Ain't she lovely?
Wait here, I'll get something for you.
I'll get going...
Where?
Get the Reverend here, and some friends, you know? Witnesses, remember?
I'd rather we get married today.
Yeah. I'll make ready. I'll leave you to yourselves, then.
If a two-timer asked me to tell him what true love means, I'll tell him about you. Nothing else could come close.
In the age of digital love, what you've done for me happens only in dreams...
I'll get going, then...
Got to make ready to make this dream a reality.
Please don't leave...
Why?
Aren't you eager to become Roshni Saqib?
Eager? I'm dying to see the moment.
I'll open my eyes to all the happiness in the world after I've said 'I do'.
But... I don't know why... When you talk about going... I feel like stopping you...
Don't go anywhere... My fear as I took the first step out of the house was nothing before this fear...
Do you see how worried I am?
It's okay.
Sorrows don't like it when you start heading towards happiness... They'd rather engulf you... Stop you in your tracks...
But only those who take these heavy steps make it through this trial.
I'll get going.
I'll be back.
Any word?
Qutbuddin got to the man he lived with... Put the screws on him.
I don't think he could get anything.
But yeah, Saqib's got family in Karachi.
Grandpa will die if she didn't...
Please, Adam... Do something...
Mehek...
Your sobs destroy my spirit...
Don't worry.
Strength, Mehek... I'm heading for Karachi.
Yeah?
May I ask something?
Why not?
Have you really found Shayan?
Yeah.
How's he?
No idea.
But I know where he is.
I can get him first if you want.
No...
Grandpa's life matters the most to me right now.
Do what you must... Get Roshni back.
May the Lord will thus...
Guess what? They've found Daddy...
Just pray he comes back soon.
Come here...
This number cannot accept calls at the moment. Please --
Just in from the back gate... A few steps in... I'll be waiting!
I've been asking Roshni's friends...
Trying to find out where she is without giving much away...
Let's hope I find something...
Psst!
Why d'you men always conflate smiles with consent?
No -- I -- Just --
Ie, you just what?
70% of the women here have to struggle to suppress their smiles at the best of times because 100% of the men read consent into them!
I'm sorry... I'm so sorry...
Hmm... If you're so sorry... It's okay...
Thank you.
Take my hand.
Uh?
C'mon!
Now let go.
Boundaries.
Learn to respect them and you will earn your forgiveness.
Would you like some water?
-W -- Water?
Ah, yes...
Please, come in. I'll get you some...
I'd like it... Cold...
Sure.
After you!
How you doin', mate?
Fine. You?
-Just...
Fit as a fiddle...
Which, for someone my age, means...
Putting up well enough!
But when the bones start hurting...
Sometimes, we just...
Gotta say that we're gettin' old...
Where are you off to?
I'm looking for someone.
Who?
Someone's honour.
Who got away, not aware how dear she is.
Whose honour are you talking about? I don't get it.
Just... High society things...
Seen her anywhere?
Well...
I dunno...
Know what...
I think it's gonna rain...
I gotta go prepare my lunch...
Why are you getting worried?
Had anything?
Call him, will you?
This number is switched off.
But why?
Cor blimey...
It's not like he's left you forever...
God forbid!
Sir!
Aye?
Well...
I can see it in your eyes.
I can see you're hiding something.
Please, sir...
For the love of God...
For the sake of an honourable family... I beg you...
Tell me whatever it is that you know.
It -- It's time -- f -- for my prayers... I'll talk to you in a sec...
Dreadful...
But there's just one silver lining that shines brighter than everything.
No one outside the family has the foggiest.
My men are looking for them in Karachi.
I will not say 'Don't worry'... Empty words can only do so much...
But trust me, I'll find her.
I'll be back... Mr Malik missed his pills yesterday. I don't want it happening again.
Gone a bridge too far, haven't you?
-Ehh?
I don't get it...
We passed the door to Mr Malik's room and you didn't even notice... Not your fault, though... No one ever got his eyes off me after I was all grown-up! You just missed a door... They've all missed so much more... Want me to take you there?
Blimey, that's two marvels in one...
A charming personality topped by a lovely voice, etching the melodies of heaven with every gilded syllable...
Mind if I say thank you?
Of course not.
-Thank you so much...
I can see my dream in your eyes, by the way...
Whoa... Really?
Yeah... That one sinful dream... Always wanted to become a doctor...
What stopped you?
Let's just say I couldn't come to terms with the fees...
How say we fix that?
How?
I can call you Dr Guddi if that's what you like.
Lovely...
So...
-Yeah?
Would you mind if I take over and give Mr Malik his pills every day?
That's all?
Of course.
Fine by me... With all my heart...
-Great. Come with me.
Great. Come with me.
-After you.
Put it down!
-I won't!
Give me my phone!
-Delete it right now!
Delete his number!
-You better watch yourself!
Delete his number and don't you dare call or text him again! I'll kill you!
Holy Mary... Her Majesty at her coldest and wildest!
Weren't you ashamed of yourself when you gave the estate agent your number in broad daylight?
You stole his number, didn't you? From this 'ere dog?
God forgive you... You blimmin' hag! He blocked Rosy... Stopped taking my calls... Mind sharing your secret spell?
Oh, I know you inside out... You live on his money, eh? He topped it up for you... How much has he squandered on you by now?
Oh, please...
I need the money, Rosy... He's ready to give me some... I've got to pay my brother's fees... Please don't do anything...
Oh, can it!
And you! Bet you heard everything, yes?
Who d'you think's right? C'mon, tell us.
I'm sure it's the agent!
-Pretty sure it's Aslam.
What...
What was that?
Did you miss it, kiddiewink?
He threw us a flower...
You only do that when you want to keep company with someone... Or part company at a funeral...
W -- Wh -- What is this place?
Madame Ruby's drum.
Don't worry though. I was worried too... But two years here and I dread the thought of leaving!
I ain't goin' back to bein' boracic...
That number's never gonna take your call!
What d'you mean?
Two million, was it? Your husband to-be just made himself a fortune...
This number is switched off.
I swear by God, sir...
Everything I've told you is true.
Please... For the sake of someone's honour...
Her grandfather couldn't take it... He had a heart attack...
Sir... I'm worried... Her family's worried... Please, help us if you know anything... Tell us what you know...
Anything...
In truth, I couldn't really believe them...
But... I feared God...
And helped them a bit...
Looking at you...
I can see the truth etched on your face...
It's all...
Crystal clear...
What do you know?
Of course, I know your address.
Besides, everyone in Defence knows you.
I'll just ask a cabbie to take me to Madame Ruby's.
I don't need a house number or street.
Yeah, she's with me...
What are you doing out here?
It's not safe. Go. I'll get you some tea...
Madame Ruby?
Still out cold...
Her lover's sold her... She's down with regret... She won't be getting up before she's done regretting...
Good evening, Saqib.
-'Evening.
How's Nadia?
The same as always... The same as eight years ago... Yet, another day passes and you ask again...
You may leave now. I'm here. Here's your salary.
Thank you so much.
Dinner's in the fridge. Please, have something.
Thank you.
Good night.
Hey...
You've been on this bed, counting the days...
Not one night have I slept peacefully...
Ever since he destroyed our lives... Our world...
Eight years... Eight long years...
That's how long it took your brother to avenge you.
But Karma caught up with that man today... He tried to sully someone's honour...
And now he stands to answer for it!
I sold the geezer's girl to a whorehouse.
Our report for the last year, sir.
682 students study in 14 schools in these districts.
Our organisation's been trying to start two new schools every year. That's why we've been working --
And who would that be? Your son?
Sir?
No. He's my brother, Saqib.
Why d'you always have him around... Surely not at this age? Just... Let the lad play...
Siddiq!
Show the young lad around our lawn. Get him some juice, okay?
Come.
-Go.
And get some sherbet for us too.
I'm sure you wouldn't mind some...?
So, Mr Malik... How much would you donate to our schools?
Ten grand...
Ten grand... Twenty...
Ten grand... Twenty... Fifty...
Ten grand... Twenty... Fifty... A hundred...
Ten grand... Twenty... Fifty... A hundred... Two, or if you will...
Ten grand... Twenty... Fifty... A hundred... Two, or if you will, five...
It depends entirely on how much you can...
That'll be enough, Mr Malik!
I'll take my leave.
Where are you off to?
Get off me, Mr Malik!
You're -- You're getting it all wrong! Get off me! Geroff --
One more step and I'll jump!
I ain't seeing this act for the first time.
The last time someone said that, I said, 'Be my guest'.
Scared the pants off her...
What a shame...
I swear I'll kill myself!
Big words... Ain't gonna believe it until I see it... Go on...
Nadia...
Wasn't it fair? What I did?
Nadia?
Did I do something wrong?
I just avenged you...
Roshni...
R -- Roshni...
Roshni!
Roshni...?
Roshni...
Roshni...!
My girl... Where are you?
Sir?
I'd like a cuppa.
-'Sec!
Hello?
Our knight's willing to put everything on the line for his princess, but this time around, she's not even his! Never was, never will be!
Why'd you call me?
Thought I'd congratulate you. The man who'd jump in to save so much as a dead leaf falling from the tree etched with his love's name...
Pure love, blind love, selfless love... There's a thousand ways to love, but yours is the thousand-and-fifty-first - pig-headed love!
You could sacrifice your life for her, but the most she'd ever say is 'Thank you'.
There are no ways to love...
It's the way of those willing to live and die for the oath.
But you won't get it.
What would you know love?
You only know hatred... It's what defines you, it's the only thing you ever feel... And perhaps the only thing you believe in.
Ain't so easy for you to get it...
I feel like cracking up... Doubling up in stitches until I'm all in tears... But my eyes fall on the kid... Her kid...
I so wish a laugh could knock your slumbering morality up.
No, Adam...
Don't say that...
I'd mind it if anyone else said that...
But... Hearing it from you... Pains me...
What if I don't want to be loved back?
It's sinful to ask for anything in return when you find happiness in theirs...
It'd be so insulting to our hearts...
First time in years someone's bitter words have pained me...
Like it's someone who actually cares...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe