How d'you feel?
Where's Adam?
Ma'am?
The man with me.
He said he had something to do. You're fine now. You're on glucose until the evening. Then, you can go home.
Could I use your phone? Got to call someone...
-Okay.
Thank you.
Malik Jr!
Where's he?
Enough, Mehek...
Enough...
Adam won't 'yes' you this time. Where's Malik Jr?
You bloody dog!
-Dad!
-Adam! No!
You vile, rotten, disgraceful animal!
-I'll get Grandpa...
-Dad!
-Adam!
I'll get Grandpa...
-Dad!
-Adam!
I'll kill you!
Mr Adam!
-Adam!
-Leave him!
-It's okay, Mr Adam!
We'll take it from here. He's a murderer. He'll be punished by the law. Arrest him!
Thought you could get away so easily?
I knew something was off when you asked me to get off the car. I followed you...
I want to thank you with a hug, Doctor... You've been kind.
Most welcome, Mr Malik... You are most welcome...
I recorded you murdering Dr Rana on my phone...
And gave it to the police.
May you rot behind the bars for the rest of your life...
Take him away!
We're done here!
Adam...
Grandpa's not good... Can't breathe... Hurry up!
-Grandpa...
Grandpa...
-Grandpa!
Requiescat...
No...
-...In pace...
Grandpa!
-Grandpa...
No...
-No! Grandpa...
Grandpa! No!
But -- Grandpa...
Huh?
Grandpa...
Grandpa!
No...
Grandpa...
I'll arrange the funeral...
I've told you everything, Mam...
I'm tired of running away...
I can't go on any more...
Don't know what else fate has in store for me...
But it sure ain't happiness...
-No, love...
A daughter struggling day and night...
To make ends meet...
Gives her mother sleepless nights...
I kept you away from myself...
To save your Tad from disgrace...
But, in truth...
What'd we have to lose?
Mam...
I'm tired of this...
My hands and legs grow weary... My heart rusts...
Na, Mam... All I want right now...
Is to lay my head in your lap...
Nothing else...
It's okay...
Your crimes aren't too great...
Swindling the moneylender to save your dying Tad...
Any loving daughter would've done the same...
That's where it started, innit?
I wish...
I so wish...
I hadn't thrown you out... But I feared the cops...
I wish I'd saved you from this long and thorny journey...
Everything you did ever since...
Was to help us get by...
Make ends meet...
I wish I weren't scared of the cops...
But...
When a man...
Threatens...
A poor, ageing mother...
Because of her young daughter...
It is... Frightening, to say the least...
I was wrong...
I lost to my fear...
Just -- Forget everything and -- Come back...
Your home...
Your Mam's lap...
Await you...
Come back...
The funeral's done... I've got something to do... Take care of everything here, okay? See you...
-Adam! Wait!
Yeah?
E -- Everyone's asking about Guddi... Mehek's so worried too...
Tell her she's fine.
Don't worry.
Okay...
Don't touch me...
Go...
Uh...
It's you, innit?
Ydw. Me.
I'm sorry I was so rude the other day.
I've got grandchildren your age, girl...
Aye...
They do that too, sometimes...
Kids these days...
Could you help me, sir?
I want to go home to my Mam...
But...
I haven't got any money...
I promise you I'll pay you back...
You need...
Hmm...
Money... Well...
Where's the patient?
-Just left.
But where?
I don't know. I was in the other room. She was gone when I came back.
In her state -- How could y --
Where'd you have to go in this condition, Guddi?
Guddi!
Hello?
Yeah, Munna... Is she home? Guddi.
No...?
Where are you, mate?
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ Love faded as tears took over ♪
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
♪ The redolence faded as sobs of love took over ♪
Hem!
♪ Yea, took over... ♪
Who're you looking for today?
Always looking for someone.
Guts haggard... Sweating... Worried...
Yet as innocent as always...
Go!
This humble porter prays...
That you find yourself...
And your long wait END AT LAST...!
Hey!
The number three's here! C'mon!
Everyone here!
Leaving?
Ie.
Leaving me?
Ie...
Why?
No idea...
Well, then...
Why don't you think again, mate?
Why?
Just spoke my heart out...
Stop lying...
I don't know how to lie...
I swear... I mean it...
Why d'you want me to stay?
Well... There's two reasons...
I want to hear them right now.
For one...
I'd have to go all the way with a proposal, mate...
And?
And...
I can't live without you...
I swear.
By the Lord...
I can't...
Okay.
I'm staying here...
But what do I tell Mam? I said I'm coming.
Well...
Call her...
Tell her you're coming... In two days?
Yeah.
Two days.
-Yeah.
♪ I'm a falling star ♪
♪ Fallen so far ♪
♪ By the Lord, I claim ♪
♪ I'll never be the same... ♪
♪ My heart was set on a dream ♪
♪ That's falling apart at the seam ♪
♪ Sleepless, troubled nights I bear, ♪
♪ To express it, my words do not dare; ♪
♪ My heart beats within me, I swear, ♪
♪ But it's lost somewhere... ♪
♪ Yea, I've lost my heart to her ♪
♪ For the first time, as it were; ♪
♪ This affliction is all mine; ♪
♪ Don't say a word to her... ♪
Good day...
Good day to you too... You'll get your money in a couple of days...
It's okay. Just wanted to tell you I don't want to continue my claim. Guddi's like my sister... She can come here anytime.
Thank you so much.
It's nothing. Take care.
Take care...
Who is it? Dyw, I'm comin'!
Can't wait a second...
Mam...
Guddi...
Guddi!
I've missed you so much...
It's okay, Mam... I'm here now... I'm not going anywhere...
Come...
What happened to your strength,
Your pride,
Your conceit...
Your ego?
Ehh?
I asked something...
You don't know...
But I do...
Their stiff corpses rot in a morgue...
How'd you like a cuppa, Mr Khan?
Come in... In the Lord's name...
How are you?
Hello.
-Come.
-Sit.
Please, take a seat...
-After you.
I can't believe you're here.
How couldn't we?
I don't know how I could be of service to someone your stature...
We're just here to ask for your daughter's hand in marriage...
Uhh...
Got to take this call...
Excuse me...
Just shy as always!
What are you doing here?
Just couldn't resist...
That...
Magnetic look...
Whoa...
Never thought a man so serious could be so romantic.
Get used to it.
There's a lot more in store for Mrs Adam!
What've we here?
Well -- I --
Call --
Calm down, Aliya... Mum will be back... Easy...
She'll be back soon.
We've found Zulaikha.
Where's Mum?
Karachi...
At a refuge...
Refuge?
Yeah.
Good Lord... I'm knackered...
My legs are aching so bad...
Guddi... Make sure we've got everything we need, okay?
I'll have a look too... Dyw... I'm positively knackered...
I gotta take this one!
-Forget it for a change! You're always on your phone! Just -- Listen to me... Guddi!
Yeah?
Ie?
Ain't that what I always say?
Order me.
All your life.
Won't you ask me why I've called you?
-You don't ask why when your prayers get heard. You just say 'Amen'.
I'll tell you then...
I was trying my wedding suit on... Everyone said it's lovely so I thought I'd give you the good news...
Your voice is all the good news I need.
Guddi!
Did you talk to the Reverend about your marriage?
-I'm coming, Mam...
Gotta hang up now...
Okay...
Nope. You do it.
-No, you. I won't.
Don't even start. You can't beat me at my own game.
Okay, bye...
Ie, Mam?
Talk to the Reverend... You can have a chat later!
-That's all?
Grist, Mam...
-Mam...
Are you prepared, as you follow the path of Marriage, to love and honour each other for as long as you both shall live?
Of course.
With all my heart!
Here. Sign this.
Deo gratias...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe