I've been trying for so long...
-She must be on her way...
Why bother walking?
-Strange...
You took so long, Afreen...
Where to, darling?
-I have no interest in music...
Good Lord, look at her!
-Youse alls don't know me.
I love him so much!
I'll make your life so miserable
That you'll beg to get to resign!
A few months back...
What a wonderful place...
Those who get to work here are so fortunate...
O Lord, please help me, too...
Just get me a job here...
Even if it doesn't pay me as much...
Please, O Lord, hear my prayer...
Miss Afreen?
That'd be me.
The boss' room is over there.
Please.
-Thank you so much.
May I come in, sir?
-Yes.
Please, take a seat.
Thank you.
I got your CV.
So it's you that that song is about...
'Afreen, Afreen'! [Beautiful]
'I have no words to praise my beloved'...
Well, sir... I have no interest in music...
Strange...
You're into media studies but have no interest in music?
Well, sir -- I've specialised in media management.
And that's exactly what I'm interested in.
Good.
But you'd do well to understand
That real life
Is very different
From what you've studied.
The realities of the job are, so to speak, quite the opposite.
So...
Yes...
What brings you to me?
Let me see...
Azan Ali Khan's embroiled in another 'Me Too' scandal!
A renowned actress states that Azan Ali Khan promised to cast her in his video, and sexually harassed her in the name of an audition!
Viewers may be aware that this is the second time the singer's been accused of something like this.
A matter had come up last year as well, but this time, actress and model Alizeh has decided to go to court.
She says she's got all the witnesses and evidence.
Once again, Azan Ali Khan's silence makes things tough for him.
We couldn't get in t--
Would you look at that!
Everyone wants to make the news
No matter how low he has to fall for it.
He hasn't sung one decent song in five years.
But girls are head over heels for him!
Are you his fan too?
No, sir.
I don't know him,
And, after hearing this news, I don't even want to.
You don't know Azan Khan?
He's the girls' favourite star!
No, sir.
Strange...
Did you see my writing samples that I'd mailed you, sir?
No.
I've seen what I had to.
Sir? I didn't quite get it...
Don't worry.
You want this job? You'll get it. In fact, you could say you've already got it.
Seriously?
I'm honest.
One look at you was enough.
But you haven't even had a look at my certificates, sir...
None of that has any value here...
Now, tell me,
What can you do to get this position?
Believe me, sir, I'll do my best.
You don't know -- My mother's toiled hard to educate us and get us here.
I want to achieve my goals. All of them.
And give her everything
She would only have dreamt of.
Alright, hold on...
I am confident you'll do all of that.
What else can you do?
Sir?
What else -- sir?
Oh, come on...
I'm offering you the job of a personal secretary.
It'll do you good.
You'll be earning more than you can ever imagine.
Now, it's up to you.
You have to prove that I've done the right thing.
Sir... I'm very dedicated.
You won't have any complaints.
But I'm only interested in media management.
You can do that, too.
But first, come...
As my secretary, you'll have to be very close to me...
You need to work on your looks, though.
Be more open.
You've got such a lovely personality, Afreen. Why do you want to keep it under the wraps?
And yes,
Whatever happens between a boss and his secretary
Stays between them.
If you accept the deal...
Shall we?
You vile lowlife!
You'd do well to remember this slap before leching after another woman!
Good evening, sir.
Is there a bus station nearby?
You won't get a bus at this hour, but you can get a rickshaw from over there.
Alright, thanks.
Good evening.
-Evening.
Can you take me to North Asmabad?
-Sure. It'll be 400 Rupees.
I've only got 200.
-Sorry, ma'am...
Well, then...
How about 300, ma'am?
No, thanks. I haven't got 300.
Where to, darling?
I can give you a ride. Why bother walking?
How's that for an answer?
Bleedin' leches! Begone or I'll kill you for real!
Slippering him broke my slipper...
Uncouth cads.
You don't know! Mahira Beyg will soon be Mahira Azan!
Why are you changing your name?
Dumbo! My name will obviously be Mahira Azan once I'm married to Azan Khan.
You? Married to Azan Ali Khan?
Every girl's dream, yes,
But I'm marrying him!
How do you know? Besides...
All the actresses are head over heels for him.
Haven't you heard about that scandal?
The model Alizeh sued him right after their breakup!
All lies! Please don't believe any of that guff!
Youse alls don't know me.
Bet you I'll click a picture with him on the stage today!
Hey, boys and girls! Are you ready for the sensational rockstar, Azan Ali Khan?
Oh my God! Azan!
You took so long, Afreen...
And... I've been trying to call Mahira for so long! It's 9 and she hasn't come back yet!
Don't worry, Mum. Sit.
Here.
Bless you, dear...
Find out about Mahira. I'm really worried.
It's very late.
She's not a kid, Mum. She must be on her way...
Alright...
How'd your interview go?
Any success?
Don't worry, my dear...
Finding a good job takes time...
By the way...
Why is your sandal broken?
It's --
It's -- Nothing really, Mum...
How many times have I asked you to take a bus or rickshaw?
I don't have so much money, Mum.
Just enough to walk...
Don't worry about me.
How many times have I asked you to take care of your health?
I'll take care of everything else.
♪Your eyes look teary♪
♪Is it me you're missing?♪
♪Forget all moments past...♪
♪Forget all the pain of parting...♪
♪I swear by my love, my love,♪
♪You'll spend every moment smiling...♪
♪Don't shed a tear...♪
♪My sweeting...♪
It's Mahira! Mum! Look!
-Where?
Hey! Where --
-Not at the door, Mum. Here!
Heavens, look at her!
Look at her dance with all the makeup!
She took 2,000 from me for 'extra classes' today!
Good Lord, her lies!
I'm working hard to earn,
And she's squandering it all!
How'd she go there?
And how come you don't know anything?
No -- I really don't.
I would've gone there if I knew!
I love him so much!
As if I would've let either of you go!
Just -- Who is he?
Don't you know Azan Ali Khan?
Mahira and I are his biggest fans!
Whatever is it he's got?
Do you know he's Pakistan's most famous singer?
His film came out recently! All its songs were hits! And I remembered every one of them!
Be done with your plaudits already.
From what I've heard, he hasn't come up with a single hit for long.
He only makes the news because of the scandals!
Whatever. But the girls still love him!
I even watched a video where a girl fainted when she got to meet him!
Alright, just listen to one song of his. I bet he'll grow on you, too!
Not interested, thank you!
Where's this concert? Where's Mahira gone?
I think Port Grand.
But how will you go?
Your sandals are broken.
I'll change.
Mum...
Would you happen to have some money?
Let me see...
I've only got 500.
It'll do.
Don't worry.
I'm bringing Mahira back!
Look at her! How lovely...
Azan! What are you doing, mate?
My performances aren't complete without it and you know it.
Enough of that.
The sponsors are clear - no messing up this performance. So, please, go back.
My dear man, I'm doing your sponsors a favour!
-The show's barely started!
You know me.
No melody comes out until this goes in.
You, too, know we're in big trouble if we mess this show up!
How's this -
You want the show to go well?
I can make this night so rocking
That it'll go down in history!
I can't take any risks.
The crowd's restless. Go back.
-Oh?
Let's do it this way -
You take the stage.
Satisfy yourself and your sponsors.
I'm out. Bye.
Azan!
I'll do -- something...
Okay.
One, two, three, four, five! Five minutes. I'll be back.
That's the bleedin' limit.
Yes!
Be done with it!
I'm going to get Mahira.
May I come too? I want to click a selfie with Azan! Please?
Shut up and stay at home. Satisfy yourself on that tablet. I'm not going there for fun.
I'll twist her ear before everyone so she knows she can't get away with lying to you!
Take care, my dear...
Doesn't Mahira look so lovely!
Stop it already!
I love you!
Oh my God! Azan!
What?
I love you!
-What?
Can I please come on the stage?
Hold on...
So she wants to come on the stage! What good will this show be...
If I turned a lady so comely down?
What good will my music be?
What good will all your love be?
Let me bring her up here.
Oh my God...
I'm a huge fan of yours! Please -- Please marry me!
Oh... So she wants to marry me!
So, what's your name?
Mahira.
Well, Miss Mahira, I'll believe it
Only if you sung your wish out!
Sure!
♪Your eyes look teary♪
♪Is it me you're missing?♪
♪I swear by my love, my love,♪
♪You'll spend every moment smiling...♪
♪Don't shed a tear...♪
Mum! Look here!
The imbecile!
Look at her make her Dad proud!
I'll break her legs, the shameless lass!
But Mum...
What's wrong with it?
It's Azan Ali Khan.
I can't believe it!
She's so close to him!
She's driven you mad too!
Shamelessly backing your sister!
Good Lord!
Who knows what you'll do after I'm dead!
Kill me, O Lord!
Mum!
Don't say that!
What are you saying?
Leave me.
The shameless lass...
The two of you've disgraced me!
♪Don't shed a tear...♪
♪My sweeting...♪
Shut it down, will you?
♪I'm sure♪
♪We'll meet♪
♪Someday♪
♪Never again♪
♪To be parted♪
♪Just believe it, will you?♪
♪The distances♪
♪That separate us♪
♪Will not last but a few moments...♪
♪Don't shed a tear...♪
Excuse me!
I need to go in!
-So do all of them. Got a pass?
No --
-Please go back. No pass, no entry.
I really need to go in! I need to get my sister!
Call her outside.
My phone's died, I can't call her. I need to take her home!
I'll be out of this job if I let you in, ma'am.
Okay, when will the show be over?
By the morning.
Jeez...
I'm very worried. I rea --
-Sorry, ma'am. Please don't jump the queue. Go back.
Looking at the crowd, it looks like the blimming gold rush!
It's time, now, Miss Mahira,
You should go back to your friends.
Well, yeah...
Actually -- No.
I love you so much! Please marry me!
This is so sweet!
Isn't it too early? We just met.
But, I say, keep dreaming.
You may just get your wish!
Keep dreaming, but for now, it's time you go back to your friends.
But -- Just a little longer?
-No.
Please. Careful.
Be careful! Don't hurt yourself! Okay.
♪Don't shed a tear...♪
♪My sweeting...♪
Where are you from? Show me your card.
I'm press!
Which agency are you from?
Forget it. I need to go in.
No card, no entry.
I've left my card in my car.
So please let me in.
Sorry ma'am. You'll have to show your card to get in.
I'm Azan Ali Khan's guest.
I'll complain to him if you misbehaved with me.
And you'll be ousted if he found out!
Think again. I'm going in.
I was just doing my duty, ma'am.
You could've told me earlier! You're the boss' guest, which makes you my guest too!
You may go in.
Did you see that? Just as I said!
-What?
As they say,
When you yearn for something with all your heart, the entire privy purse conspires in helping you achieve it!
Universe, not privy purse!
Aye, that...
Honey, you're so lit!
-Ain't I?
♪Every moment♪
♪I long to be♪
♪With you...♪
♪Nothing♪
♪Holds my heart's fancy♪
♪Except you...♪
♪I see you in my dreams♪
♪And tell you every time♪
♪It will not last but a few moments...♪
♪Don't shed a tear...♪
♪My sweeting...♪
Which song would you choose to play?
Thank you all for coming here, but there'll be no interviews today.
Azan's not really well.
It'll only take five minutes. We have to talk.
Please, it won't be possible.
I've heard Azan's been sued again?
The people would want to hear his side.
Ask me. I'm Azan's spokesperson.
Alright, tell me why he isn't saying anything about the charges against him? It's the social media age, after all!
No tweets, no videos... What do we take this to mean?
Is it that these charges are - at least partly - true?
We don't consider every tweet worthy of a reply.
If those speaking against Azan are so truthful...
They can go to court.
Azan's here!
How much more will you milk your old songs? Why don't you release a new album?
Well, as they say, old is gold...
Your songs may be old, but what do you say about the fresh accusations against you?
It seems, ma'am, you're more interested in the accusations than my songs and me!
In that case, what are you doing here?
Go to them.
We did. She's suing you. Why don't you say anything?
Is your silence a confession?
Who do I tell the truth?
You?
Her?
Or this media who'd try me?
The court would try you, because Alizeh's sued you.
Why is it always you?
Why don't you respect women?
There's a new case every other day!
-You know very well, ma'am...
I've performed across the world -- the neighbouring countries -- You think I'd leave all the girls in the world
And hit on her,
And do whatever else she says?
Can you believe it? Just think -- Just -- Why?
Because you would've done something.
There's nothing. I haven't done anything.
If you want the truth, I'm telling you -
As long as you're chums, you're chums,
And the moment you're not, you're an enemy. But I'm happy...
The court's hearing it.
I'm done with the interview.
Thank you so much for coming.
I hope you've gotten all your answers, so please --
-Just one thing!
Have you been depressed lately over your mother's death?
I heard your mother died of something other than ill health...
Do you know about it? Or are you lying even about your mother's death to save your career and fame?
How dare you talk about my mother, eh?
How dare you talk about my mother?
-Camera over here! Record Azan!
You'll pay for misbehaving with and assaulting the press!
-You'll pay for what you said!
How dare you talk about my Mum?
-You'll pay for it!
I'll kill you right here! I'm Azan Ali Khan!
I won't spare you!
I'll make you pay for misbehaving with the press.
-Leave him, Azan!
Do you hear me? I'm Azan Ali Khan!
-Record it!
Azan!
This is the last one.
No more.
And this better not affect your performance.
The sponsors are panicking because of the press.
Please, get ready quickly.
I'll never go back on my word.
And forget you?
Impossible.
I love you, Mum.
Where could she be...
What are you -- Why are you staring at me -- like you'd eat me alive? Let go!
Ouch!
What was that?
You said, 'Let go'.
I just did.
Don't you have common sense?
What?
You broke my bottle, and instead of saying sorry, you're arguing with me!
I'm sorry.
It was an accident.
By the way, you don't need to yell like that.
Of all the nerve!
Why are you shouting? We were both wrong.
Besides, it's not like you were looking where you were going!
-Hey!
What kind of attitude is that?
Do you even know
Who I am?
I don't and I have no interest!
By the way, you don't know who you're talking to!
I'm no random Mary, Jane or Susie!
Hey, ma'am!
You barged into my place, broke my bottle,
And instead of saying sorry, you're acting up!
I get it now!
You are one of those girls
Who want to meet me, cling to me, and when they don't get to,
They show their ugly true faces.
Call the press. Start campaigns against me. I know that.
Shut up!
What?
I said shut up!
Are you even thinking or blabbering just about anything?
I have no such vices!
I'm just here for my sister who's mad about Azan Ali Khan,
Who's leading the youth astray!
I'm surprised though, that there's folks like you here!
Me?
I'm leading the youth astray?
You idiot! I'm talking about Azan Ali Khan.
The bottle you broke was mine,
But it seems you're high, ma'am.
I
I am Azan Ali Khan.
How shameless!
-Stop it, Mum...
Leave it be.
-Stop it!
She's crossed every limit! I'll break her legs!
Sorry, Mum -- Why are you so angry?
Why shouldn't she? Did you have to lie?
I'll get some sense into her!
-Mum!
Stop it.
-Oh, please!
She's got no idea! My hands grow tired of weaving,
And you'd squander my money on this vileness!
Azan Khan had a concert in Karachi after ages, Mum...
How could I miss it?
-I'll get this Azan Ali Khan out of you!
Arguing back to her mother! The shameless lass!
-Sit down, Mum...
Your blood pressure will shoot up. Why sicken yourself? Alisha, get some water.
-Just let me die!
I'd rather die than see her accursed face!
Do you have any idea at all? One sister walks 20 miles, but she!
She's wasting my hard-earned money on her decadence!
If only I knew that going to the concert would get me in the soup!
Look at her! As lippy as shameless!
Shut up, Mahira!
-Good Lord, what is happening!
Who's cursed us?
-Mum...
Mum, have some water.
Out of my sights!
Have some water.
Don't worry, Mum.
I've told her.
She won't do it again.
Please... Calm down.
Alright, Mum, I'll serve dinner.
I'm not having anything.
I'm full of this wigging!
Good Lord, her insolence!
And you always back her, don't you?
Tell me,
Is he really so lovely, handsome, and good?
Yes, very handsome. In fact, these pictures don't show a thing!
So, why didn't you click a selfie with him?
I couldn't, not in that rush! Besides, my phone had died.
Either way, I wouldn't have taken this dirt cheap phone out before him.
So, did he talk to you?
Obviously, he talked to me. I even performed on the stage with him.
I wish I'd been there!
I would've clicked a selfie with him!
I'll take you along next time!
Really?
-Yes.
You're so good. You can do everything.
I want to be just like you.
Your hairstyle, makeup -- Everything!
My dear, I'll make you look far prettier than me!
Really? You're so good!
Well, spoiler! No one looks pretty on an empty stomach!
And you... You'd rather starve than give up.
As if there's anything left.
I've brought dinner. Here.
Oh, you're just great...
Why don't you be great too?
Look around. Be responsible. Focus on your studies.
I've studied enough. Just get me married.
What's this madness, Juliet?
Whatever have you studied?
What good will any of it be?
What'd I do with this complicated law or that one?
The only law I understand is, 'Get me married quick'.
You haven't grown up one bit, Mahira. Your mental age is younger than Alisha's!
Hey --
-Well, that makes me your elder sister!
Oh, really!
I mean --
She's so little...
-Oh?
Must you be so adamant?
Present day
Here. Have it.
Why are you doing this?
What've I done? Let me go!
Finish it quick!
Do you have any idea who you're talking to?
You don't know who I work with. They'll make you pay!
It's you, isn't it?
Another video of Azan Ali Khan has been leaked,
Which complicates matters for him.
Was she going to be his next victim?
Translation: J. Mir © TV One