♪I'm lonely♪
♪Without you♪
♪No one can take your place...♪
♪My sweetheart...♪
♪Mould me...♪
Translation: J. Mir © TV One
♪Mould me in your likeness♪
♪Just the way you are...♪
♪My sweetheart...♪
♪My life...♪
Quickly!
What happened?
-Omar Khan's informed the police!
They're coming!
(Present day)
Untie her! Quick!
Hurry up!
(Present day)
Double time!
Come! Quickly!
-There!
Omar Khan's found out. He won't spare you.
Nor will the police.
For the love of God, let me go! I won't tell anyone!
-Hurry up!
Or I'll fill you with lead right here. Get up!
Here.
-Quickly!
Get a move on!
In there!
Come.
A few months ago
So you want to be my new manager...
What's your name?
Afreen Beyg.
Hmm...
Sounds familiar.
Anyway...
Which of my songs is your favourite?
None.
You!
What kind of scene are you here to create now?
Please -- put -- something on...
You're getting uncomfortable...
Know what...
My female fans die to see me this way.
But...
You're so middle-class. I know!
But actually, you're a drama queen. A man who, just yesterday, was a bad role model corrupting the youth and was just a very bad man...
I'm just surprised to know you want to be his manager today!
I think you changed your mind. You want to go about 'corrupting' people with me, innit?
It's nothing like that, Mr Az --
-I don't want another word from you, Miss Afreen Beyg; you've already said enough!
I've heard a lot about me in the news.
I saw the news.
I think this is the moment I should capture and go live.
Innit?
Let the fans know who's droppin' by!
Just a minute.
Okay.
We're going live now.
Aren't you excited? I think you are!
Okay, we're live! Hello, hip-hoppers and rock 'n rollers!
This is Azan Ali Khan, and I'm here to tell you who's in the house.
My new manager. Surprised to see her? I was, too!
Like, I was the worst man in the world for her. The most vile, the most insolent...
But tell me...
Should I have her as my manager?
Please, start voting now and tell me.
Let's see what they're saying... Actually, you got zero votes!
Baby...
My fans
Reject you.
You are
You are rejected!
Yes!
-What are you doing!?
What was that?
Please deduct it from my salary.
-You're fired.
You may leave. Get out.
Actually... You can't fire me.
You're still here? Jeez, what are you?
Arguing with me at my place, in my room! Please, get out!
Your father, Omar Khan, has appointed me.
No one else can fire me.
Don't you dare
Call that man my father again!
Okay...
You'll go if Omar Khan asks you, eh? C'mon.
Have it your way.
What the devil is going on, Meryem?
She can't be my manager!
Why?
Why not?
What's up with you?
How can you even --
The woman responsible for such a huge mess!
You want to make her my manager!
Fair enough.
Just for once.
Meryem.
Once.
Take a good look at her.
Look at her.
Does she look one bit like the manager of an artist, of Azan Ali Khan, the rockstar?
Why, what's wrong?
There's a problem with how you think!
Her simplicity is your problem,
Because the managers before her had left no quarter to destroy you!
Meryem...
Honestly?
Like -- seriously?
So it's come to this!
She'd be my manager!
I have no issues with her, Meryem. It's nothing personal.
I don't wish her bad.
Why don't you get it -- She just can't be my manager!
And my fans have rejected her in a moment! So, the chapter's closed!
I have already decided!
You or your fans are nothing before my decision!
Afreen will be your manager. Understood?
-Splendid...
Splendid indeed, sir...
You've got a problem with her simplicity, eh?
Wasn't your Mum like that?
Don't drag Mum into this!
Not a word about her!
-Your Mum was my wife!
I don't want to talk about anything. I've told you my decision!
This adamance will get you nothing. Everything's been decided.
Understood?
I'm really sorry, sir...
I don't want your family to have a row over me.
I'll find another job.
I think I should leave.
No -- Afreen -- Please don't say that.
He -- He's down the road to his own ruin -- Only you can stop him, so please...
Don't go.
I'm really sorry, sir.
Thank you.
You're back already?
What happened?
How was your first day at work?
Fine...
Doesn't seem like it. What happened?
No, it's nothing. It was good.
May you always be happy.
Know what, I turned down an order for the first time!
I'm going to put this sewing machine away.
Your sisters are going crazy. I mean -- Just look at the young lass!
She got a form from a coaching centre.
-Forget that, Mum!
What's my marital home like? It's up to my standards, right?
I'm sure Azan must be asking a lot about me!
Don't give it too much importance!
Tell him he can meet me anytime.
Jeez, be done with it already. It was her first day at work.
She must be tired. Get her some tea.
Omar, must Azan's manager be a woman?
Seeing her brought back some memories.
I had a teacher like her at school...
Miss Parveen.
She was about her age and dressed up like her.
We'd spot her and say loudly, 'It's the dame'!
You were saying something, Mr Omar?
Meryem...
I'm doing what's best for Azan.
And...
I'm sure you would've seen that Afreen looked very confident.
She lives a simple life in this materialistic world. She's got her principles straight.
Unlike his previous managers, she won't let Azan screw anything up.
You know Azan only too well.
He's drunk every other moment, and mired in a new scandal every other day.
I'm sure he won't make a mess
When someone like Afreen is with him. What do you think?
I think Mr Omar's thought a lot before hiring her.
And we should trust his choice.
But she's left...
I'd take this as your acceptance.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
You made the right decision.
And...
Don't fear or worry about Azan.
If he's ever a bother,
Feel free to come to me,
Or Meryem.
That won't be necessary, sir.
I've faced many challenges in my life. I'll handle it.
Imran...
Thank you, sir.
Don't call me 'sir'. I'm not one bit the sir-type!
You're still here?
I thought there's something called 'self-respect'.
But it seems you've got none.
Doesn't it hurt you?
It does.
But only if it's sincere and sensible.
I won't even touch you,
Because I remember Mum's upbringing,
But I'll make your life so miserable, I promise,
That you'll beg Omar Khan to get to resign!
I'm telling you, I don't like you one bit.
I don't like you one bit either.
At least I know how to dress.
I dress up decently.
No ripped jeans or hideous hairdos!
I don't know why people love you so much.
Seriously?
Wow...
An unenlightened woman
Lecturing me on fashion!
I mean -- Jeez, that's the last straw!
What's your qualification?
I'm a graduate.
I've done my master's.
Who's the more unenlightened now?
That ego will have to wait.
You've got a meeting with a sponsor.
Right.
I'm going.
But don't take it
It's because of you.
I'm going because I want to. Are we clear?
Whatever.
Jeez, what a stupid office!
Where do we go?
Azan...
Take off your glasses and see...
Shut up and wait for me. I'll be back after the meeting.
Okay?
Where's the room?
How are you, Mr Rana?
-Fine.
But... You?
-She's my maid.
I mean...
My new manager.
Oh...
I like your style. Our generation's forgotten that there's true beauty in simplicity.
Thank you.
It's her.
So it's you!
The girl from the viral video?
You're with Azan?
Yes, that's me.
The video had been edited
To hurt Azan's image.
You know what it is with social media only too well...
The media folks just need an excuse... Anyway, nice to see you.
Alright, let's talk business, then, Azan.
You know your position very well, Mr Azan. We can't fund you.
Your controversies are more famous than your songs!
-You can't be serious!
You've been working with Azan for so long. Been on international tours too. All superhits!
That's history. There's nothing in the present even close to success.
Can I say something?
-Please shut up!
Yes?
-I'd like to ask you, sir...
There's so many singers in Pakistan. Many foreign singers famous through YouTube as well.
Why do you want to do this show with Azan?
Shut up!
Do you know anything? I've been with them for years!
Out!
Azan's got a following, but it's dwindling, thanks to his recent songs...
It'll be ages before he loses his following.
In any case, Azan's signing the contract only if you give him a 10% raise.
Otherwise, you've always got the option of a new singer...
-Are you mad?
What are you doing? Why do you want to ruin my career? Why are you in my life at all? Get out!
I'm sorry...
But it won't be possible.
Okay, sir. No problem. Thank you for your time.
But --
Why do you want to ruin my life?
Why did you come here?
Please stop him, sir...
Wait, Azan...
Listen to me for once...
10%'s nothing. And we're for nothing below it.
We're meeting other sponsors too. They may have better offers.
But...
Oh...
Perhaps something I don't know. Go on.
Alright.
Thank you. We'll get going.
Please, sit. Where are you going? I agree.
I accept your terms.
I agree. Tell me when you're signing the contract.
-Alright, then. Pleased to be working with you again.
Please prepare the contract. We'll sign it after our legal team's gone through it.
Congratulations, Mr Azan. You've got a wonderful manager.
What is this? I don't understand...
We're meeting other sponsors? Why didn't you tell me?
You aren't as smart as you look...
-Get to the point.
The point, Mr Azan, is there's no other sponsor. No other meeting.
Nor does anyone want to work with you.
That bluff in there was something I had to do.
I get it...
Very well...
But don't think you've won.
You haven't.
-I know. You've won.
Whatever! Remember,
I absolutely loathe you!
Hello?
Would you follow me in here, too?
It's my job to be with you.
This isn't a business meeting, madam, I'm here for leisure. I can't take you inside.
I've got some respect. And by the way, you must be angry...
Here's some money,
Go and
Have something.
Find something.
I'm your manager, not your maid. Thank you so much.
Your loss!
Guard! Take care of the lady.
Make sure she doesn't walk in.
Eyes on her.
It's been so long...
He didn't even bother to ask!
Hello, Mum!
-Where are you, Afreen?
I've been trying to call you for so long, but didn't have any balance!
You didn't call to tell me anything!
Don't worry, Mum. I'll be a bit late.
But why?
I'm with Mr Azan and he's dropped dead inside the club!
Then, just come back home. Call and tell him.
Do you know how long I've been trying? He just isn't answering!
Did you have anything at all?
I'll talk when I'm back.
Bye.
Don't touch me.
Don't touch me...
I can take care of myself.
Alright, I'll get going.
Wait, Afreen.
Your job isn't done yet.
You've got to come home.
But...
Not with me.
Take an auto, taxi... Whatever... Okay?
You wouldn't have the money.
How much would you need?
100? That enough?
Keep your money. I'll do on my own.
As you wish!
But...
Do come.
I'll be waiting.
Azan... I'll take my leave.
Just one wish...
To live in your shade...
Just me... Forever...
Sipping the nectar...
Dripping from your lips...
Every morning...
Azan...
It's wonderful... Say it again, will you?
Sipping the nectar...
Dripping from your lips...
Every morning...
Your love has bewitched me...
I'm nought without you...
For you...
You are my world...
Thank goodness. You're asleep...
A --
Azan... Please lie down straight.
Azan! I'm leaving. Please lie down straight.
Where are you going at this hour? Rest in the guest room. It's almost morning.
No, I'll go...
-Leave when it's day. Go.
Okay.
No sense to help her Mum!
This Mahira's sitting here scrubbing her hands!
At least cut the onions for the omelette!
What's up with these lowly chores every moment, Mum?
I just got this manicure and pedicure!
You make my blood pressure shoot up!
Good morning, Mum.
-Bless you, my dear.
You're coming now? I thought you're sleeping.
But...
Do they want everything done in a day?
Oh my God! Is Azan with you?
He can't see me like this! You should've told!
Blimey, Mahira. Isn't it enough that I'm here?
I'll get you your breakfast. Have it and get some rest.
Leave it be. I'll d --
-But you've just come back! And you!
Get ready for college!
The dratted college again! When will I get rid of it and when will I get married to Azan?
Mum...
How many times have I told you not to worry?
I'm just worried about you. Take care of yourself.
But I get very worried.
Any other job would be far better...
I can get back to weaving...
I've got a lot of work.
I mean...
Nothing above health...
You'll get sick.
Easy, Mum.
Besides... Nobody else would offer me the salary Mr Omar did.
Please don't worry.
And I know there's a bit of an issue about the time...
But I'm sure you'll adjust in time.
So will you be out all night?
No, Mum...
I mean -- well, yes -- who cares about days and nights in this job?
He's such a big star... He has his own time.
Don't worry. Everything will be alright.
I'm just worried for your health.
I can take care of myself, Mum.
I'm just worried about you. Take care.
Alright... As you see fit...
So, tell me, what's Azan Ali Khan like in real life?
He's quite the egomaniac.
I haven't seen one like him.
No idea what he thinks of himself! And look at the height of madness!
Always admiring himself in the mirror! Always waltzing about the house wearing shades!
Guess his favourite pastime? Pulling my leg!
The two of you would have quite the slanging match! Must be fun!
By the way...
You have no idea how much your Granny insulted me for not having a son.
But I'm so glad to see you...
You're dearer than 10 sons to me.
Hey... Don't get too emotional. I'll go change. We'll have breakfast together. Okay?
What's with this cough, Mum?
-I'm fine.
I'll get you water.
Floor it!
Present day
Roadblock ahead, boss! What do we do?
Stop it!
Take the road.
I'll meet you at the old hideout.
Alright, sir.
-Please let me go...
I won't tell anyone. I swear!
-Quiet!
Gag her!
She's proper lippy! Quick!