♪I'm lonely♪
♪Without you♪
♪No one can take your place...♪
♪My sweetheart...♪
♪Mould me...♪
Translation: J. Mir © TV One
♪Mould me in your likeness♪
♪Just the way you are...♪
♪My sweetheart...♪
♪My life...♪
Present day
Have some water.
You haven't had anything since yesterday.
You might die.
And
We're supposed to keep you alive.
I won't!
Get out of my sights!
Another video of Azan Ali Khan has been leaked,
Which complicates matters for him.
Was she going to be his next victim?
Azan Ali Khan doesn't quite seem to be in his senses,
And it seems she's scolding him over something he did!
It's worth a thought what Azan Ali Khan was doing backstage with her right in the middle of a show.
Where was his security detail?
He must have invited her himself!
This video has complicated matters for him.
Was she going to be his next victim?
Azan Ali Khan doesn't quite seem to be in his senses,
And it seems she's scolding him over something he did!
It's worth a thought what Azan Ali Khan was doing...
What rubbish!
What's going on?
I won't spare her!
How many will you shut up?
You're into the fire before you're even out of the frying pan!
You are your own enemy, Azan, you'll destroy yourself!
Whatever.
It's none of your business, Mr Omar Khan.
Oh,
Oh, really?
'None of my business'...
Then,
How say you pay back the millions owed by your flop music company yourself?
This lifestyle,
This luxury, your bills,
I'm sure you can afford it all, right?
You can't.
You know that.
So,
That makes it
My business.
Your life, like your music,
Is a big flop.
One flop album
Doesn't do anything to my music or my stardom!
It's just gotten into you. You're always looking for an excuse to do me down.
It's just your excuse!
It isn't about one album.
Just name one half-decent song you've done in the last three years.
Just one!
Nobody wants to work with you;
The least you could do is maintain a good image with the public!
But no,
One model complains against you, another sues you!
What...
What's going on?
Why don't you ask him?
Please, ask him.
He's disgraced the family already.
Omar Khan has failed to teach his son anything!
What happened?
Meryem, please tell him I'll fix everything with Ejaz.
-I've fired Ejaz.
What?
Would you look at that, Meryem!
What the devil is going on?
Who told you to?
I hired him, and I fired him.
He's 60% of the reason you're ruined!
He was good for nothing! No strategy, no PR!
No one controls my life like this!
Azan Ali Khan,
It'd suit you
When you're in any control of your life in the first place. Are we clear?
Please tell him
To stay away from my life.
Please, think over it again.
Why be so stern?
Your love got him here.
I hope you know that.
Why shouldn't I love him?
He's my only nephew.
I say, be patient.
By the way, didn't you have a meeting today?
Look at what you've gotten into.
I'll tell him.
Meryem, please tell him I want Ejaz back, willy-nilly.
That's all.
Ejaz?
Come.
Here.
Ejaz's latest exploit.
He couldn't even stop this from making the news! Whatever can he do?
Anyway,
I'll get his new manager. I'll handle everything myself.
Heavens...
What kind of a girl is she?
She must've been sent by a sworn enemy... And --
Look at how she's talking!
No, Meryem...
She didn't even know me.
There's no girl who doesn't know you.
How'd she come to your concert?
I'm positive, Meryem.
Absolutely positive.
She didn't know me.
Mum!
Your cough won't get better if you miss your pills!
Come with me.
I'm fine...
No you aren't. Sit with me.
If you missed another pill, I'll never talk to you again.
Good evening!
-Good evening.
I must say, you look so delighted!
How was your day?
Splendid.
Splendid-est!
The salon whose Facebook page I commented on first sent me a free gift voucher.
I can go to them thrice a month for free makeup!
Please take me along too!
-How many times have I said I would?
But first, let me go.
Oh?
But how?
Simple. I liked and shared every post, and they sent me the voucher.
Good Lord, whatever will she do?
Jeez, Mum...
Get ready. I can hear wedding bells. Azan Ali Khan's coming!
Are you touched in the head?
As if that bon viveur lacks anything! At least have decent dreams.
What do you know? Just stay tuned...
I can barely tolerate you as his fan,
And you're talking about marriage? I might just have a heart attack!
He's a spoilt lowlife!
Even if he were the last man in the world, we'd rather you stay single than marry him!
What are you saying? What happened?
Mahira, focus on your studies.
Educated people are in demand.
Besides, only if you become something can we marry you off to a good man.
Why are you scaring me like that?
You haven't seen how he only had eyes for me...
He's never called anyone onstage before.
Everybody was saying to me, 'How lucky'!
As in, he accepts the proposal, so to speak!
I just want to meet him one more time.
Hello?
Yes, it's me.
Of course, I'm available.
Yes, I've seen the Khan Garments office.
Send me the address, I'll be there at 4.
Thank you.
Who was it?
Khan Garments.
They're offering a job.
They need a manager.
Wow! Best of luck!
Thank you so much!
Thank you, O Lord...
Alright, Mum, I need to be there at 4. I'll change and leave.
Afreen! Please, take a seat.
Thank you, sir.
I must say, sir,
Your office looks great.
Thank you.
So do you know why
I've called you here?
Yes, sir.
I know it very well.
Mum had a passion for weaving.
Has -- even now.
She's taught me everything. And I love it too.
Really?
How did she manage everything?
Actually,
She was really adept at it.
She's a real expert. She could get any kind of clothes ready for Eid or weddings.
And she's taught me everything.
Clothes?
Yes, sir.
I love stitching and weaving. Know it all.
I can do anything, really.
Alright, tell me,
Would you be able to manage my son?
Why not?
By the way, what does your son like to wear?
Whatzit that's in vogue today...
Ripped jeans,
Colourful shirts, and so on...
Honestly, if you ask me...
I don't quite get this fashion.
Fair enough.
I mean,
Ripped and torn clothes used to be a sign of poverty...
But now it's in vogue...
Touché. Gotta agree with that.
Don't worry, sir. I won't let your son dress up like that.
But, Afreen...
What's up with this fixation with dressing?
W -- Why, sir?
Isn't it a job related to garments?
Not at all.
So --?
You've been called here
To manage my son.
You must've heard of him -
Azan Ali Khan, the rockstar.
Hey, ma'am!
You barged into my place, broke my bottle...
You are one of those girls
Who want to meet me, cling to me, and when they don't get to,
They show their ugly true faces.
Impossible!
Why?
I think there's been a confusion, sir.
Isn't this Khan Garments?
I was offered the job of a manager.
Thank goodness that's clear now.
So, tell me,
What do you say about this?
I'd thought of something else, sir.
I'm not interested in it. I can't do it.
Don't worry about your pay.
I'll double whatever you ask for.
Really sorry, sir.
But I can't do it.
I have no interest
Or experience.
Just try and consider it.
You'll develop an interest for it.
What good is this drudgery?
But managing a celebrity... It's different. It's a job with its benefits.
Stardom, travelling...
Everything is a part of your pay.
I highly appreciate that,
But my goals in life are a bit different.
Here.
It's you, isn't it?
Isn't it a pleasant surprise
The the father of the man you gave an earful
And insulted before the world
Is offering you a job?
You were right in your place.
I wish I could all of what you did.
Azan's my son...
But out of control...
But sir,
It's not my job to correct your spoilt son.
Please don't force me.
Why not?
Just -- Why?
The lengths we go to for our sons...
I'm just asking for your help,
Because ever since I saw you,
I've got a feeling -
No idea why - that you can correct my son.
I've met him before, sir.
I'd decided I'd never see him again.
He's an uncouth tetchy egomaniac!
I don't even want to see his face.
Aye, but there's a reason for it -- Everything has a reason!
The one he loved the most...
He lost her... His Mum...
She passed away three years ago.
Ever since then...
He's been... So cross with life...
That he --
Drowned himself in alcohol.
And then...
He never cared or bothered about anyone.
I'm his stepfather, and...
He never thought of me as his own.
Otherwise, perhaps today...
I might not have been begging you...
No, sir...
That won't be necessary.
I can't run away from my responsibility.
His Mum always wanted to see him happy, and...
I regret that I
Couldn't fulfil this tiny wish of hers.
Afreen,
I don't know why, but
I'm insisting because, ever since I saw you, I got some hope...
I mean --
Let's be practical.
I'm not having you sign a lifelong bond.
I'm offering you twice your salary.
What's it to you? You can leave anytime.
But, it's also possible
That you may be able to achieve some of your goals
With this salary.
My hands grow tired of weaving...
O Lord!
What kind of trial is this?
This salary would change the lives of Mahira, Alisha, and Mum...
But how would I put up with him?
What are you thinking?
O --
O -- Okay.
Thank you very much.
I'm sorry, I --
Got a bit too excited. I'm really sorry...
But you've given me my life's greatest happiness.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of you. Feel free to talk to me about any problem.
And... You may start... Today.
Thank you.
May we both succeed in our endeavours.
Amen.
I think I should leave. I'll join from tomorrow.
Sure.
-Thank you, sir.
Good evening, Mum!
-Good evening! May you live long!
Leave it be!
-Hey!
What happened?
All this weaving business ends today!
At least tell me why.
Start preparing for your wedding, Mahira.
You aren't kidding, are you?
But -- At least tell me what happened?
-And you get ready for your coaching.
Care to tell me what's going on?
Have you hit the jackpot?
More like she's seen sense, Mum!
Get up, I'll tell you!
I got the job! I'm so happy!
-Easy there!
Thank you, O Lord...
All thanks to your prayers!
I've brought your favourite sweets. Here!
Bless you. Have some with me.
I'll go to a good salon for my makeover!
You're taking me along, right?
-Of course!
I'll get you styled for Azan's next concert!
You're the best!
Afreen's got the job, but the two of you have started dreaming!
So what, Mum? Let them wish...
We've lived our lives, throttling our wishes...
Just let them...
Bless you.
You've gotten very intelligent!
Where's your office?
And what are you doing?
What do I say... I'd gone to a garment factory as a manager.
But who knew that I'd be managing a celebrity.
But -- What's that?
Oh my God! Mum! She'll be with celebrities now!
Who are you managing?
Azan Ali Khan.
What?
You can't be serious!
No, I'm serious.
Oh my God!
I can see it happening!
The entire universe is conspiring to unite me and Azan!
This is the latest one!
I can't believe it!
So we can meet Azan Ali Khan anytime?
-Obviously!
What's up with you? Touched in the head?
No one can stop her now.
Aye, no one can stop me now.
Start preparing for my wedding, Mum!
There, now! Trust the robbers to arrive on time.
These two are out of their minds!
Go and freshen up. I'm cooking something you love!
-Ok.
Leave it be, Mum! Just start preparing for my wedding.
I'll give you a nice whacking and get this wedding mania out of you! Imbecile!
So, have you given her the job, sir?
-Of course.
She turned it down, but I convinced her.
But...
Thank you for helping me. I really appreciate that.
You'll get your payment tomorrow.
Please don't embarrass me, sir. Happy to be of help.
Oh, you don't know how important this was for me.
Thanks to you.
-You're welcome.
A Miss Afreen Beyg's here to meet you, sir.
Bring her here.
-Okay, sir.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning. Please, take a seat.
Your coffee, sir.
She's our caretaker.
Feel free to ask her if you need anything.
Welcome, Madam. Would you like tea or coffee?
No, thank you.
Let's get straight to business, then.
The situation is right before you.
In fact, it won't be incorrect to say
That you have created this situation.
The first order of business is to put an end to this negative publicity.
Especially from social media.
You're right, sir. But for this, Azan would have to understand and do what I say.
You have my full support.
Do what you must.
As for Azan...
I'm here if he becomes a bother.
That over there is Azan's room.
You can get to work right away.
Good luck.
Okay. Thank you, sir.
♪Don't shed a tear...♪
Ouch!
Don't you have common sense?
You broke my bottle, and instead of saying sorry, you're arguing with me!
Sir?
I'd like some coffee.
Sir... Mr Azan's sleeping.
Didn't you tell him about his meeting today?
You're a star's manager, Afreen.
Do you expect him to get up with the world?
But, sir --
-But nothing.
This is precisely what you're here to fix. Go and wake him up.
Okay.
A --
Azan...
Please get up, Azan...
I love you, Meryem...
He's dreaming about some Meryem...
First, get me my juice.
Please.
Juice. Okay...
Excuse me.
Yes, Ma'am?
Where's the kitchen?
Over there. Do you want anything?
No, thank you.
-Most welcome!
Quickly with the juice, now. Mr Azan's waiting.
Are you talking to me?
Obviously. Quickly, now. He's waiting.
I've seen you before.
I haven't got time for this. Please, give me the juice.
Who are you?
I'm Mr Azan's new manager.
Give me the juice already!
Omar...
What kind of girl have you hired as a manager?
Everything alright? What happened?
She barged into the kitchen when I was preparing the juice and started ordering me around like I'm a maid!
But... Why?
I'm sorry, sir. I thought she's also a maid.
No -- What's so funny about this?
I'm sorry, Meryem. It's my fault.
I should've told her.
Afreen, she's Meryem. Azan's aunt.
His only aunt. In fact, it wouldn't be wrong to say that she's more his mother.
I'm really sorry. First thing in the morning...
A blimming row. That's the blimming limit.
So you're Meryem?
Any doubts?
Let me tell you, Afreen...
Azan loves her so much. In fact, if there's anyone he ever listens to, it's Meryem.
Three years ago,
When Azan's mother passed away,
Meryem left everything and came here
To look after Azan.
Meryem and Azan cannot live without each other.
Please forgive me. I had no idea.
I'm the only one he's given the right to get him juice in the morning.
Nobody else.
Good morning.
I was waiting for you.
Oh -- Sorry...
I think we're missing the coordination.
Well...
Let me introduce you to Imran.
Imran is Meryem's son.
Know what, Afreen, Imran supports me in my business a lot.
Not gonna lie to you, he's my right hand man.
Azan and Imran are poles apart.
He's very careless, and he's very dedicated.
Here's your laptop.
Thank you.
I've made a folder with everything you need to know about Azan.
-Thank you so much.
Come, I'll brief you on the hearing this week.
Sure.
What's this?
You're still asleep!
Get up, quick.
Good morning.
My juice...
Meryem...
Thank you.
For?
For being here.
Sweetening me up first thing in the morning, eh?
You think I'm just sweetening you up?
You know my mornings aren't complete
Without your sweet face to greet me.
I'm not at peace until I've seen you, my dear.
I know.
That's why...
All of that aside, get ready quick.
I've got you a personal secretary.
Who's he?
-She!
What do you mean?
A woman?
Yes.
How's she?
What kind of question is that?
Look at yourself.
Jealous already.
How would you bear her with me all day?
No way...
Just -- Get her out.
Just meet her for once.
Alright, seriously.
What kind of joke is it? How could a woman be my manager?
I don't see why not!
But you know me so well!
I've got two cases against me already. I can't put up with her now!
Turn it to your advantage. Let everyone know that Azan Ali Khan's manager is a woman.
It'll rebuild their trust in you.
It'll improve your image.
Everyone will think
That you honour women. Innit?
And if she questioned my honour, it'd be safe to say this Azan Ali Khan's image will be dead.
You know just as well as me that I don't come back from a concert. I'm brought back.
How would a woman do that?
Don't worry.
Your Dad has hired her after a lot of thought.
How many times have I told you
To not call that man my Dad!
Why must you do that, Meryem?