I'm lonely
Without you
No one can take your place...
My sweetheart...
Mould me...
My sweetheart... Translation: J. Mir © TV One
Mould me... Translation: J. Mir © TV One
Mould me...
Mould me in your likeness
Just the way you are...
My sweetheart...
My life...
Here!
Come!
(Present day)
Quick!
Police! Help!
Help!
Police!
Jesus, what now...
What do I do...?
Where am I?
Vanished into thin air!
She's proper clever!
Who knows where Nasir is!
The cops got him maybe?
We're gonna need more men...
Abdul!
Send a few more men!
She's proper clever!
Quick!
Nasir -- No idea where he is.
Find him! And send your men right now!
Hurry up!
A few months ago
Get up, superstar!
You're the only superstar I see, Meryem.
Juice?
Ah, yes.
Right here, Your Lordship.
Thank you.
I've travelled the world, had juice at the best hotels. But I swear, I'm yet to taste something better than yours.
Well, I guess someone knows his sweet-talk.
By the way, how's your new manager?
She's intelligent...
But super-duper boring.
You won't believe what she did yesterday.
She stood outside the club, waiting for me. I'd given her some money for dinner, and I thou --
Oh my God...
How could you do that, Azan?
Is this what your Mum and I've taught you?
Remember - a man who cannot respect women is no man.
She's got self-respect, for sure.
Why don't you take her in?
Just look at what she wears!
You know my social circle, my friends...
I'm a star, I've got an image... How could I take that country girl with me?
-Oh?
This country girl's been looking after you all night.
I came here to check.
She put you on the bed. Covered you in this blanket.
What else do you want?
Listen...
I like her very much.
What do you want, Meryem?
You're playing matchmaker, aren't you?
I think that's what you're up to!
You always do what you think is the best...
Anyway...
It's time for breakfast. I'll be waiting for you.
This poem's so lovely.
One of your old songs?
When did you write this?
Me?
I don't remember writing that...
Just read it... You can use it somewhere.
In a song or something?
Put it to some use! Make something good out of it!
Yeah, just give me ten minutes, I'll be there.
Yeah, ten minutes.
-I'm so late...
Out of the frying pan into the tea!
I'm really sorry, sir...
No... It's okay.
I'll clean it, sir...
-It's okay.
I'm really impressed, by the way. I never thought you'd be able to put up with Azan for more than a day.
I'm really sorry, sir...
You're doing a great job.
Azan's calling you. Something about his papers... Help him, will you?
Sure, ma'am.
If I spilled tea on him, I'm sure the old geezer would've had me wash his shirt five times.
Not to speak of his fury if the stain didn't go!
But, blimey, looking at how he let Afreen go... Something seems off!
I want...
Nope. Not quite feelin' it.
All I want
Is to live...
Is to live in your shade...
What's written here? Can't read a thing...
'Live in your shade for --'
'Live --'
'In your shade --'
-'Forever'.
How do you know about my song?
You stole my song!
Innit?
Oh God...
Why didn't I think of this before?
Oh? Hit the enlightenment now?
Well, Madam... You can steal my words, but who's gonna work on the composition?
There can only be one rockstar.
Azan Ali Khan.
No doubt.
By the way... Meryem told me you took good care of me all night.
Honestly speaking, though, I don't remember a thing.
That's why you shouldn't get drunk.
It makes you forget everything. Even feelings.
You've got no idea how I got home last night.
I didn't even have dinner.
-Excuse me!
I offered you money to get something.
I might've considered it if you'd offered me dinner.
I'd offer you dinner?
In your dreams!
How can you forget?
I hate you!
Funny coincidence. I hate you too!
Thank you.
Anyway...
We're meeting a record company today.
In an hour. So, please get ready quick.
Azan Ali Khan hasn't fallen so low as to take orders from you.
I don't want to meet anyone. Go.
Okay.
I just thought... It was a new record company interested in producing a new album with you.
Your company's in debt. This might've helped.
But it's okay if you don't want to go...
I'm not meeting anyone!
Didn't I just tell you? I don't want to meet anyone!
In fact... I'll meet them. Because why not?
But not because you ordered me.
Because I want to. Remember that, okay?
Blimey, I'm changing! Go out, will you? Or would you rather see everything?
Oh, sorry...
C'mon.
Come.
Don't you have any other T-shirt or pants?
Why?
What's the problem with these?
Blimey... So it comes to this!
Someone with a nonexistent fashion sense is gonna tell me what to wear!
Gotta say, you got guts.
Seriously.
No, I just meant you could've changed...
And your hair look so weird...
I'm sorry but it looks like a bomb went off in your face.
What do you mean?
What's wrong with my hair?
No surprise.
Seriously.
Can't blame you. What tastes could I expect from someone who should've been born a couple centuries ago?
And know what, you're dealing with Azan Ali Khan.
You won't find someone who's got a style like me.
But... What else do I have to teach you?
I wonder when ripped jeans became 'fashion'...
What was that?
What'd you say?
I mean -- We're late for the meeting... Let's go?
Actually... Wait. Sit.
Sir?
-Sit.
Wait for me. I'll be back in a moment.
Okay.
-Wait here.
He's messin' with you.
Really?
-Really.
Make a run for it, he'll be leaving! Double time!
Thank you! Thank you so much!
Come in.
Welcome, Mr Azan.
We're excited to be working on this album with you.
Thank you. Please, take a seat.
I'd like to hear something new.
Okay...
Like dew on autumn leaves,
This fragrance through the air cleaves...
A whiff of you - can it be?
Like a shore washed by the sea,
Shooting stars, whoopee!
The light of my life, can you be?
Mr Azan...
Have you got something else?
I mean, something exciting?
Azan, why don't you play what you were humming earlier today?
Oh, please...
I know just what I want to show them.
Azan... Can't you see? They're bored.
Leave this one... It needs more work. Show me something else.
No, sir. That one's really good, sir! I'm not saying much because I'm his manager.
I'm sure you'd love it!
Okay. Let's see if it's any good.
All I want
Is to live in your shade
Forever...
Sipping the nectar
Dripping from your lips
Every morning...
-Wonderful!
-This is it!
This is it!
Lovely lyrics! Fantastic melody! This is the real deal!
Your choice is so good.
Your manager's very smart.
You're lucky.
Please, finish this song.
We'll make it the title song of the album.
And...
This'll give us the title for the album.
We'll discuss more details on the content in the next meeting.
Congratulations again.
Thank you.
-Thank you, sir. Thank you so much.
Come.
This is Azan Ali Khan!
Saw that?
You should thank me.
Oh...
My poor manager...
Thank you for what? It's my song they loved!
For writing this down and reminding you here.
Oh...
I get it... I never knew my manager worked so hard!
Wow!
I shouldn't really expect anything else from you.
You want appreciation, don't you?
Don't worry. You'll get your share soon.
I promise...
I'll appreciate you... My way.
Coming?
Yeah.
So that's your new manager?
Hot, isn't she?
Why's she looking at me like that, mate?
Stop laughing at her. Her bite hurts as much as her bark!
Afreen!
You can't go anywhere.
It's my order.
Yes, sir...
Who was that, Azan?
Just a sec. I'll tell you.
I know. You're dying to dance with me.
You feel bad I'm talking to the ladies.
It's nothing like that.
-Oh?
You're jealous. I can see it on your face.
By the way, who was he?
Oh, him!
He's a bookie.
I've 'invested' in a cricket match. Get it? I like it.
How can you do that, Azan?
Do you have any idea about the money?
You've borrowed so much already!
All I want to do right now is thank you... For getting me the contract.
And, for that, you can dance with me. That's what you want, innit?
Ouch!
Oh!
Blimey! Snake dance?
So lovely! I swear!
I get you the contract, and you do this?
Oh, my poor baby... How couldn't I thank you?
Why do you want to drown your life like that?
You're so talented...
Why do you want to destroy everything?
I'm lonely
Without you
No one can take your place...
My sweetheart...
Mould me...
Mould me in your likeness
Just the way you are...
My sweetheart...
My life...
How was that, Mum?
Nice. Just fantastic!
Really? You like it?
Of course! It's so lovely!
Oh?
It may be lovely, but not more than you.
You're in the mood for jokes?
I'm honest. Work on it. It'll be a hit, I tell you!
Don't believe me?
I don't believe it because you've supported everything I did - right or wrong.
You appreciate every melody I work on.
And you?
Haven't you always said, 'No one can be more beautiful than you, Mum'?
Which is true!
But...
I'm sure you won't say that after your marriage.
You'll forget your Mum.
I swear I'll never go back on my word.
And forget you?
Impossible.
I love you, Mum.
I love you too, my dear. I'll pray for you.
May the Lord give you success.
May you be happy.
Likewise.
You're back?
Good evening.
Why'd you get up?
I was just waiting for you.
What happened to your foot?
It's nothing, really.
You're injured!
A woman stepped on my toe in the bus. That's all.
Couldn't she see?
Wait, I'll get you some ice...
Mum!
What's this?
Sit down!
Present day
Please don't shoot me!
It's a water gun! It ain't killin' nobody!
Wait! Stop! Or I'll shoot! Stop!
You dimwit! Can't you see where you're going?
Who'd get water for us now?
Give me some money! I want your money!
I'm sorry -- I didn't see you coming -- Really --
Such nerve! You can't even walk straight! C'mon, give me the money!
I haven't got any!
I don't care, I want your money!
How can I give you anything? Just let me go! Leave me --
-No! I won't let you go until you've given me your money!
-Stop right there!
Let me go!
Stop!
Where'd she go?
I know you're with her! Give me the money!
Geroff, you crazy woman!
Who's there? Come out with your hands up!
Who are you? A thief!
Mum! Dad!
Saw a woman 'round here?
No.
I can see you're a thief!
Mum! Dad! Hurry up!
Don't worry. He's gone.
Why are you crying? He's gone.
What's your name?
Azan.
You want appreciation, don't you?
Don't worry. You'll get your share soon.
I promise...
I'll appreciate you... My way.
Here. It's cold.
Hello?
-Yeah?
It's cold. You might need this.
How'd your mother fight if we gave up?
My dear...
Just...
Get married while I'm still here...
Mum!
What happened?
I'm sorry...
My Mum's not well.
I haven't seen or talked to her in three days.
Who are you?
What's your name?
I'm...
Afreen...
I don't remember much of it... But some people kidnapped me...
Someone you had a row with?
No.
Aye, but of course...
How could you have a row with anyone?
It's not like you've got millions... Who are they? What do they want from you?
No idea...
All I know is that your son's very nice.
He helped me so much.
He's wise beyond his years.
You fell asleep...
Looked sick and tired. So I didn't wake you up.
But seriously... You should leave.
But...
Please don't mind it... I work hard all day to feed them and myself.
I'm very poor.
I don't want any trouble.
Please try to understand.
Just... Go.
We should call the police and help her, or they'll get her.
No way...
We can't have the police to get involved. Not good.
I'm so sorry, but you should leave.
But I've got nowhere to go... I don't know anyone.
Could you tell me where I am?
Gadap Town.
Gadap Town?
And how far is DHA Karachi?
Two hours by bus.
Bus?
Where could I get the bus?
On the highway.
Could you take me there?
Yeah, I know the way.
Hey!
Wait! Don't get involved in this! Shut up!
You better go on your own. Take that road and turn left.
Just go.
She doesn't know the way, Mum. We should help her.
Would you like it if you lost your way and nobody helped you?
Okay, go.
Leave her at the stop and come back quickly.
You're in for a beating if you're late!
Go. Quick!
Thank you.
-Get going.
Come.
C'mon.
I can't walk anymore... How far is it?
Just five more minutes... We can wait if you like.
-Okay.
Boss...
I've found her.