Gulrez...
Gulrez?
Gulrez!
What is it, Neelam?
I was dreaming...
About?
A wedding...
Whose?
Maheen and Waqar's.
Know what,
She looked so lovely as the bride...
And Waqar... Mind-blowing...
I saw them seated together...
And Fajr clicking pictures like mad!
The Reverend was about to start with the vows when you woke me up.
What happened?
Why are you laughing?
Nano thinks
You can't augur.
♪ I will keep with me the memories of our conversations and of you ♪
♪ Such bounties, O Love, are all one gets from you in benefaction ♪
♪ I will laugh wholeheartedly at this, I will embrace the heart with rapture ♪
♪ I will remember you then... ♪
♪ I will remember you then, and then I will forget you... ♪
♪ And then I will forget you... ♪
I've decided it now...
I'll marry him.
Ask why.
Because you love him.
Nopes.
-Why, then?
Jiya told me that's the only way I can get even.
Marrying him.
Oh, please, look at yourself.
I can see him in your eyes.
My eyes?
Very funny. Don't you see they're so bright and lovely?
I've always known it.
What?
She loves him!
Put a sock in it!
Quit lying. I've seen it for myself.
Remember when Jiya held his hand and took him away?
When she ended the match?
Ended her life, more like.
Shut up!
You broke.
And I broke up.
First time I saw someone green with envy.
What's it like?
Ooh, a lot. But surely not bright and lovely!
Your phone's ringing.
Care to see who it is?
Whoa...
Your Romeo.
Romeo?
Waqar Mashood Ahmed.
Whoa...
Hello?
I hear you're happy.
As in, you said yes?
I've thrown the young'uns a party too.
She means us!
You off your head? Marrying your enemy?
I'm scheming...
I'd so love to kill you with my own bare hands!
Very funny.
Ever thought about Gulrez?
Ever thought about yourself?
What?
The name's Maheen Aurangzeb. I can count the feathers of a bird in the air.
So?
What's it to me?
You can keep counting your feathers while he'd die under the weight of his Foxy.
Oh, can it. You've been caught.
Why don't you admit that you love me?
I swear I don't love you one bit.
Don't take Dado too seriously, by the way.
I was just settling scores.
Would you hear that load of guff!
What is it?
Who?
Fajr.
What's going on, mate?
They're getting us married!
So?
She's been so mad as to say yes!
Tell her I'm not interested at all!
Where are you?
Somewhere. Havin' a ball.
I'll get back to you...
Wait, Fajr...
Aye?
I'm so scared...
Why are you smiling?
He's soooo scared...
Hey!
Here. 50.
50 gee?
Your tip.
Much appreciated.
Enjoy yourself.
You'll get your 20 gee every month.
You'll live a life of luxury.
Much appreciated.
Waqar?
Big trouble, mate.
What?
Dado's getting me married.
To?
Maheen.
What'd she say?
She says yes.
Congratulations.
What?
Congratulations to you, mate.
Why?
I'm not marrying her!
I can't take Gulrez's curses!
D'you know how much he loves her?
How much?
Yeah?
More than you, I guess?
I swear...
He doesn't love her more than you!
You're just worried...
You pity him... That's all...
I feel like I've sinned, Jiya...
I shouldn't have said it to Dado.
Said what?
I lied to her!
I was just teasing Maheen when I said I love her.
You were honest.
You do love her.
I'll crash into a wall.
I was lying!
I even told Maheen I don't love her! Why don't you folks get it?
You'll have to prove it...
How?
How can I prove it to you?
Go and tell Maheen
You love Jiya.
♪ Love's testimony is not to be asked of it ♪
Hello?
You there?
♪ Love's testimony is not to be asked of it ♪
Waqar?
♪ It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes... ♪
I told Neelam...
The twit's brave.
She said she's waiting for the sweets!
I told Wali too.
He congratulated me.
But I know...
He didn't really mean it.
Look what we have here...
Look at her march in like royalty!
Have some shame...
Girls don't behave so brazenly before their marriage!
What if anyone saw you?
What?
You don't want me to tell you...
What's with the anger?
Waqar says he's not interested.
Why are you saying it in English?
He said it in English.
What does he mean?
He doesn't want to marry Maheen.
My...
I say, disown him, Ammi Begum.
Hold your horses, Dastoor Ahmed.
What now?
It's like the twit has the crow before his eyes
But says it's not black!
That's barking mad!
I mean, he's got the crow right in his sights but says it's not black! Like, seriously?
Could you please do us a favour and keep quiet?
And what are you looking at?
What d'you think?
What can I say, Ammi Begum?
If he's not happy... Forget it?
You want to see a proper scene?
I know
He'll say
He'd die without Maheen at the top of his lungs.
You thinking of bewitching him?
My...
Dastoor's company is affecting you...
Take my hand.
Fajr...
Here...
Where's Ali?
Outside.
Stand guard here...
I've got a few spells to cast.
C'mon.
Reminds me of something Dad would say...
It was when I was hiding from him, scared...
He walked past me, holding Ammi Begum's hand...
And said,
'You've got me under your spell'.
Aye.
So you said
You're not marrying Maheen.
You serious about that?
Don't you love her?
Find out where she is!
What's wrong with you, Dado?
I've got the perfect truth serum for you...
Wait and watch...
Everything's gonna be crystal clear...
Who are you calling?
Sit.
C'mon.
You called Maheen here?
Aye.
Fair enough...
She's your truth serum.
She's here!
Geroff me!
Have a last look.
Stand by him.
Good.
So...
Could you
Think one final time
If you're gonna change your mind?
I won't.
Say the Lord's name [auspicious beginning].
In the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
-Now swear by Maheen's head...
Now swear by Maheen's head...
You don't love her.
Go on.
I pray you see me dead if you lie under oath.
Nano...
You've surprised us all.
All of you are here.
We're so delighted.
You're happy, aren't you?
All my kids have a thing for theatrics...
Every one of them.
We're here to mourn a promise unfulfilled...
Please, forgive us...
What are you saying, Aunt Suraiyya?
That twit's not family...
But I've always considered him a brother.
And she's like an old friend.
Remember, Nano,
How I picked her up, the little girl?
She nearly slipped and fell.
I won't let her this time.
She'll get
Whatever she asks for.
Peace be upon you all, how are you?
How are you?
Great, Aunt. You?
You're happy, aren't you?
But...
Where's Gulrez?
He's not home, Nano.
In fact, he just left.
Gone where?
I don't ask him now.
Guess what,
His Foxy starts without any problems now.
Turn the key,
And full steam ahead!
Ask me
Why I brought you here.
I'm trying to venture a guess.
I know
You're gonna ask me to forget that you love her...
No, Waqar.
I want you to forget
That I loved her.
As if 'love' ever changes to 'loved'.
So if you saw me talking to her, would you think I love her?
Of course not.
All that matters to me
Is who hates her.
You're a great man.
No way.
Not greater than you.
You've been very kind. Generous.
Don't get engaged though, Waqar.
Why?
Get married straight away.
Engagements break.
Okay.
If you say so.
But promise me...
I do.
You didn't even let me finish it.
I'll do as you say.
Get married.
I will.
When?
I'm
Gonna ask Neelam to find me a match.
Why don't you look yourself?
Yeah?
Find your dream girl?
Never.
My heart would like to have its way.
I can't do it, Waqar.
I won't let it. Not again.
We'll play cricket together again.
I won't be in Maheen's team.
Instead...
I'll knock 'em for six!
The wedding will be on Sunday.
I thought
We'd get them engaged,
But Mehru said engagements can break.
Congratulations.
Congratulations to everyone.
The wedding's on Sunday.
Good news!
Everyone's gone over to Neelam's.
Say Gulrez's!
I would, but Gulrez isn't home.
Where's he?
Out with Waqar.
He took Waqar with him just a while back.
Where?
No idea.
Blimey...
What happened?
A girl's two lovers should never meet before her marriage!
Is it?
Wow...
You'd wear a suit?
No. You'd wear one.
I'm buying you your wedding suit!
Please...
Don't turn me down.
I won't.
Get the most expensive one.
Everyone thinks I'm a Scrooge.
I want them to know
I'm not a Scrooge.
I'm just... Careful about where I spend.
Have a look.
But remember -
Pick only the most elegant
And the most expensive suit.
What are they up to?
No idea.
Maybe ask Gulrez?
What do I care if you don't?
I don't.
In fact, I'm glad.
They ought to see each other.
So there's no bad blood.
Fair enough.
But aye...
I almost forgot...
Yeah?
You're not getting engaged. You're getting married right away!
I know.
Mum asked me...
I said okay.
Engagements can break...
Jiya!
'Sup, matey?
Jiminy Cricket...
Someone sounds a bit too lively!
Hit the jackpot, eh, matey?
Jackpot?
I know everything.
Sunday... Your handsome Romeo...
Can it... As if I'm any less!
You're gonna be the crown jewel, matey!
Come here?
Saturday. Sleepover. Okay?
For real?
For real.
No excuses.
I swear.
Love you.
Ooh...
Never thought you could say that.
Guess what...
Hmm?
I haven't said that to him yet.
Just... Learning.
Hey...
Yeah?
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Congrats to you too.
Any idea
How much I've helped you?
So?
Say the three words before me? Please?
I'd love to watch it live!
Belt up and bog off!
Lovely. Just -- Lovely!
That's how you thank me!
No one loves me!
Love you.
Keep up with the practice!
Actually -- Hate you, Fajr!
That's when he lost it.
He seized my hand.
I pushed him away and struck him with a vase,
But by then, a car had stopped outside...
He made a run for it, rubbing his face,
But - curse my luck -
Your Dad had seen him...
Going through it all... It was almost like... I lost my mind...
I could never imagine Aurangzeb doing any of it... Not least to me!
I was startled to see your Dad walk in.
It felt like being caught red-handed.
He asked questions
And I said whatever I came up with.
That was the moment
That ruined my life
Forever.
'Bout time your past caught up to you, Aurangzeb.
The flames that charred my family and our lives
Are about to engulf your daughter.
And I will make sure she burns...
♪ She's mine, ♪
♪ Yeah she's mine! ♪
♪ She's mine... ♪
♪ She's mine, ♪
♪ Yeah she's mine! ♪
What d'you think you're doing? Got the manners to - maybe - knock before you enter a girl's room?
Guess what, this is my Dado's room.
Have some shame.
-Shame?
Why?
You're my Aunt's daughter. My cousin.
And now... My wife to-be.
What's with all the shame?
-Stop right there, you villain!
Surely, girl, you mean hero? What's wrong with you?
Speak for yourself... What's wrong with you?
Never forget I can break the hand that dares touch me.
You'll break my hands?
If I didn't get hold of you today...
I'll break them myself.
You're gonna be a goner!
Mum!
No one can hear a word out there.
You sure she'll hear that cowardly squeal?
Did you call me a coward?
I ain't even started yet --
-N -- Nano!
You silly girl...
You'd call out to everyone... But not my name. Just once? Please?
Look at yourself. You look like a bleedin' Paki!
You gonna marry this Paki?
In your dreams!
When the Reverend asks me, I'll say...
'I won't'!
Wait until I get my hands on you, girl!
I'd rather die.
I mean it.
Whoa. Someone got too serious.
Please, go...
Yeah...
Step aside.
My touch will bring you back to life.
You broke my bangles...
I'll get you new ones.
Oh you will?
Because who else will?
Leave it...
D'you love me?
You?
Forget love...
I don't even hate you.
I'll ravish you.
And when I do, you'll have to tell everyone...
I'll claw that face!
Just say you love me. It's a lot easier.
I don't!
I'll let go.
Don't.
I won't.
Enough... That's enough...
I'm knackered...
Rest a while.
Call Waqar, will you? I'd love to see him dance.
Yeah, but...
Where is he?
Seriously, what are you made of?
Where's Waqar?
What'd Gulrez say?
Nothing.
He just took me to the beach and asked me to forget that he ever loved Maheen.
'Loved'? I asked him.
He didn't say anything.
Then he took me shopping.
Said I'd have to wear the sherwani he picked.
Shoes, shirt, sherwani... He got me everything.
And guess what, he said he's proving he's no Scrooge. He just spends wisely.
He got me the most expensive things he could find.
So sweet of him.
Do you know who's putting up the most lively dance upstairs?
Gulrez?
Hey!
I thought he said he couldn't dance!
You gotta see his belly dance! The filly!
Don't you pity him?
A bit.
I do too.
But I feel that love is selfish.
Very selfish.
My love can make me do anything...
Except give my Maheen to Gulrez.
Would you pick fights with me after we're married?
I wouldn't mind that. Just...
Just don't slap me, okay?
I'm not the kind who'd slap...
That was just -- you might've been arrested!
Shut up!
Anyway. Forget the slap.
How can I?
You gave me a scar right here!
Can't we talk about something else?
Ever said sorry?
Twice!
I want you
To keep saying sorry
As long as I live.
Okay.
I'll say sorry as long as I live.
Okay?
Sorry.
What's up?
W -- What? We were just -- You know -- Havin' a chat?
I'm growing old waiting for one of you to say 'I love you'!
Say it, will you,
Waqar?
I really want to hear the three magical words!
There goes your chance.
I'll say it for everyone to hear on the wedding day.
You have my word.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV