Maheen?
Maheen!
Fajr!
Call the doctor! Maheen's not --
What's up, Mum?
Mum...?
Mum...
What?
What happened?
(Maheen...)
(Maheen?)
What'd you nick just now?
You complete blighter!
I was just droppin' by to say hi.
But you were sleeping as if you've got everything.
Come here...
What's the time?
Almost midnight.
You alright?
'Course. That's why I was sleeping so peacefully.
Girls... Blimey...
Tell them
They're getting what they've always wanted,
And they sleep without a care!
It's nothing like that.
The doctor gave me a few meds after the bullet incident.
They're a lot better at doing their job.
But why are you here so late?
Just... Felt like comin'?
Thought I'd sit with you a while... Have a chat...
It'd ease me.
You worried?
Aye.
Why?
I just found out yesterday
That Mum
Was innocent all along.
Whoa...
Dad's shaken.
Ashamed at everything he did.
What good is it?
She died a grieving woman.
Not entirely Dad's fault though.
What happened?
I will... Someday...
For now, I'm... Looking for him...
I swear...
I'll settle all scores.
But you said he died with your Mum in the car crash?
So he did, aye...
But his kids...
Gotta pay...
For the sins of their father...
Not fair, Jiya.
What's their fault?
That blighter's dead.
You can do anything you want and he won't even stir in his grave.
You don't know, but he will...
I know his soul's lurking around here somewhere...
Anyway...
Have a good night's sleep...
I'll be back.
Take care.
Won't you have a cuppa?
No.
I don't need a cuppa to stay awake now.
Bye.
Jiya!
When'd you get in?
Just a while ago?
Sorry I didn't call...
Just... Wanted to see her.
Can't believe you're done so quickly!
The blighter's turned in!
Won't you have anything?
Next time?
I've got old ties to this place...
I'll come knocking like I have a right...
Bye.
Hi partner!
Hi.
Lemme guess. She didn't take your call, so you thought you'd ask Fajr.
No, mate...
Worry not though
The conditions have become completely concordant. Restrictions have been lifted.
You can meet her easily.
Speaking of which, why don't you two ever meet?
Honestly
I find it a sight to behold to see two lovers meet!
See?
Even you think I love her.
I've always known it.
She realised it a tad late.
May I confide in you?
Yes?
But promise me it will stay between us.
It will; you don't need my word for it.
I don't love her.
Ohhh!
I swear
I was just teasing her.
She used to be so proud of herself,
And now
Look how I've shattered her ego!
Put a sock in it.
It's your ego that's been shattered.
Springing off into the sky like that!
I'm not joking, Fajr...
I'm not joking either.
I understand love better than both of you. Combined.
That's why I feel guilty.
Keep up with it.
Keep feeling guilty for the rest of your life.
Fajr, I'm so ashamed of myself and you don't even get it...
I mean -- Her calling me and my turning back doesn't mean we love each other.
Just think -- our quarrel's been resolved.
Do you even know that she refused to wear the engagement ring?
I know.
The silly girl.
What made her act so foolishly and unashamedly?
Trapped me with herself.
Trapped?
Of course.
Everyone's thinking we've got something going on.
I'm almost dying of shame.
How do I even begin to tell you I'd never even imagined I'd marry a country girl!
Who told you to lie like that?
I was lying back then.
But now I'm telling the truth.
100%.
Upon reflection...
I realised I shouldn't have flirted with her.
After all, she's my cousin, mate.
My Aunt's daughter.
But I'm so stupid.
I ended up making a mistake.
Curse your filthy mouth!
There!
I knew you'd all curse me if you ever found out.
But... Could you not say that?
Are you going back?
No.
You're blowing the gaff on yourself and stayin' put here?
I'll go, mate. In a few days.
But
First, I'll apologise to her.
What?
Aye.
Today itself.
Then don't tarry. You've got your chance.
She's still awake.
♪ Love's testimony is not to be asked of it ♪
♪ It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes ♪
♪ Ask all you will what comes out of love ♪
♪ The heart is its maker, and ends up being destroyed by it... ♪
♪ In the tale of love... ♪
♪ In the tale of love ♪
♪ Where do these turns come from... ♪
♪ Where do these turns come from ♪
♪ That those we hold dear to us ♪
♪ Are the ones who break our heart ♪
♪ Are the ones who break our heart... ♪
♪ In the tale of love ♪
♪ Where do these turns come from ♪
♪ That those we hold dear to us ♪
♪ Are the ones who break our heart ♪
♪ Are the ones who break our heart... ♪
Someone's got a knack for catching me red-handed.
I thought you'd turned in.
Go.
Or Wali will get up too.
He sent me.
He said there's no smoke without a fire.
Here.
Were it so easy...
These flames burnt your letters. A different flame's searing the two of us.
Tell me...
Does every lover get his love?
No. Yes?
Hardly new, this...
I didn't get her.
I'll settle for someone else.
Sure?
Sure.
Why'd you collect these ashes, then?
I thought
I'd scatter them in the sea tomorrow.
Should I find you a match?
No.
Find me a second match.
Or it'll sound so weird.
Find a good one.
But...
Not better than her.
Here's your cuppa!
You off your head? It's midnight!
How will I doze off?
That's what I want. Have it and open your eyes.
What d'you mean?
It's just an excuse...
I've got news that will keep you awake.
Here.
Have a sip.
Tell me.
Have a sip first.
So, breaking news.
The Romeo from London is smitten with you.
Aren't you surprised?
You better be.
That ain't all.
I swear it is.
I'm just telling it my way.
Care to explain?
Of course.
He called me a while back.
He said he doesn't love you
And was just flirting.
Then, he asked me
If I thought he could ever fall for a country girl.
Hold your horses and let me finish!
Cool down and think about it carefully.
He's coming here to say sorry.
For?
For when he, with his head in Nano's lap, said he loved you.
Upon reflection, he figured
He didn't.
He was cursing you.
He said refusing the ring was a big mistake.
You earned him a bad name.
He's coming to say sorry for that?
That's what he said.
How could you take that quietly?
I didn't! I cursed his filthy mouth!
Why didn't you curse him with death already?
Not so fast! Not before you know who made him say it!
I swear I wasn't angry.
He felt... Like someone so close...
English roses? He's just teasing you!
I know he's so desi [Asian] as to sacrifice his love for Gulrez!
Ammi Begum must've said something about the family's honour...
He grabbed his chance to play Romeo.
Know what?
His type can be found singing at their beloved's weddings. Exempli gratia...
♪ This lambent, sightly procession ♪
♪ To whom do I present this? ♪
♪ This magnificent -- ♪
Wh -- ?
Slap him the moment you see him!
In fact, it's just fair to rip his face apart!
Hello?
Peace be upon you, Ammi Begum.
Upon you as well.
Where's the lad?
Who?
Waqar.
Slouching about in his room.
I'm not humouring him.
Whoa...
Where'd she go then?
Who?
Maheen!
At this hour?
It's half past midnight!
She left in a fit of rage!
Call and ask her.
D'you seriously think she'd be angry with him?
I called her. Her phone's in her room.
Byrlady...
Where'd she go?
Ask Fajr.
I asked her.
That wretch said, 'You're gonna tell Ammi Begum if I told you'.
They're all in it together!
Munshi Alam!
I think I've got my answer...
I'll get back once I'm through with her.
Who is it?
Wee Maheen.
Where's Dastoor and Mehru?
It's half past midnight! I'm sure they turned in!
Did I ask you the time?
Waqar Ahmed. Where is he?
Someone seems to have forgotten all her manners!
And...
D'you seriously think I'd know where to find a wastrel like that rotter?
Rouse Dastoor.
Ma'am.
Not the day after. I got to leave tomorrow.
I'll get back to you in a sec. Bye.
Heard you called Fajr.
What?
Care to tell me
Everything you told her?
Yeah?
Okay...
You must be embarrassed.
How 'bout
You tell everyone?
I've roused him.
Stay right here.
C'mon! Tell everyone right now!
What is it?
Hold it.
Let 'em sort it out.
Don't say that, Nano...
This is no longer just between us.
So...
Why don't you tell 'em everything?
Say those fiery words
And shatter my ego for Nano to see!
You look like a man, Waqar Ahmed.
Show 'em you are one for real.
I would hate to poke my nose where it doesn't belong,
But care to tell me
What this little domestic at my place is all about?
Aye, hero?
Tell 'em and win their hearts.
Look at her
Shamelessly prattling on and on and on...
Don't you want to tell them?
Okay...
Fair 'nuff...
I'll tell 'em myself...
Remember how you all thought
He's fallen for me?
You were mighty mistaken.
He was just flirting.
Upon reflection... He felt ashamed...
How could he flirt with his Aunt's girl?
That's what you told Fajr, right?
♪ What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance? ♪
Aye...
I hope you were serious about that.
Aye.
Promise me you always will be.
Promise.
♪ Thus, before reaching the destination, I choose to take a detour ♪
♪ For those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart... ♪
You'd do well to remember it, Waqar Ahmed -
When it's about her ego, Maheen Aurangzeb can be far more ruthless than you can ever imagine.
♪ For those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart... ♪
I'll finish you off
Where you won't get an ounce of relief.
I don't care!
Poor Gulrez!
So you said
You don't love Maheen?
Aye.
So you were just taking her for a ride?
Slap some sense into him, will you?
The blighter's lying through his teeth.
'I don't love her'!
Could you check if he's in his room or made a run for it?
He's sleeping.
Those who sleep peacefully after hearing all sorts of insults have no honour.
He's not sleeping.
He's put his honour to sleep.
What d'you mean?
Forget it, Ammi Begum.
You'd mind it if I said something.
You got to say it.
Willy-nilly.
Yeah, say it or she's gonna be furious.
Shut up, Dastoor Ahmed...
So... Tell me...
Why's he putting his honour to sleep?
He loves you a lot.
After falling for Maheen,
He feels your word and the family's honour [Waqar] are at stake.
He's thinking of fixing the match and winning you this one.
That's the blimmin' limit.
You better not talk about limits, Dastoor Ahmed...
Mehrunnisa's right.
The wretch has broken goodness-knows how many hearts in one shot...
Can't believe he can sleep peacefully... With his honour intact.
Stay here, Dastoor Ahmed...
Don't let him
Slip away!
Slip away?
Why'd she say that?
Because he's about to.
Where to?
There's only one place he can go.
He'd leave for a few years...
And come back
When Maheen's had a few kids...
Saying,
'Blimey, are they cute'!
Hmm...
He's putting one over us all!
One what?
Oh wait...
You mean pulling one over us...
Aye.
He's pulling our legs,
And ruthless Ammi Begum
Is set to kick him in the teeth.
Stay on your guard. He may run away for real this time.
Well done!
Very well done!
50 gee...
All for me?
Of course.
But your job's not done yet.
I may need a few more pages...
Don't worry.
I'll write whatever you want.
Umm...
Could you...
Return the photocopy?
Huh?
Photocopy?
Aye...
'He thinks I've fallen for him'...
'The poor prat'!
'If this be love, dear'...
'May you'
'Groan in agony'...
'"Amour"' (Love),
'"Je te déteste"' (I hate you)...
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV