Imagine you're playing against the British Empire.
But I'm not as great a cricketer as he's making it sound like.
Toss the coin.
Gulrez will toss the coin for me.
May I go from our side?
No.
I got this one.
Heads or tails?
Heads.
I can't believe my Mum wrote these letters.
Can you recognise her handwriting?
It's hers alright...
But...
But why did she say she's innocent until her last moment?
I wish she were.
I wish it were all a lie.
I know she lost her memory after the accident.
She remembered my name,
But not my face.
Despite everything, the last words on her mouth were,
'I'm innocent, Jiya'...
'I'm innocent'...
This --
Who's this Aurangzeb?
My friend.
So to speak.
I knew him only
Because your mother was my wife.
They were class-fellows
At University.
He loved your mother.
And your mother
Admitted that she, too,
Had begun to like him at one point.
But then she got married.
I
Met Aurangzeb
On a plane.
We just exchanged pleasantries
On the plane,
But it wasn't long before we became friends.
He started coming at our place.
But I felt
As if Aurangzeb and your mother
Already knew each other.
I was most perplexed.
You could say
I had my suspicions.
To confirm them,
I never stopped him from coming,
Even though
He never invited me over.
In fact, he never told me
Where he lived.
When I got home one day,
I saw him leave in a hurry.
His mouth was dripping blood.
Seeing him run away,
I hid behind the wall.
Wiping the blood, he made a run for it
Like a thief.
When I got in,
Your mother was very upset.
Seeing me,
She lost it.
I was broken,
But somehow, I managed to ask your mother
What he was doing
In my absence,
And how she ended up with a wound on her forehead,
And he on his lip.
Your mother answered everything
Like someone
Caught red-handed.
Looking for any kind of excuse - sensible or not.
But excuses can only shield concupiscence so well...
You're my daughter,
So I want to make it clear
That if a man agrees to anything less than modesty,
He's better off not marrying at all.
None but Aurangzeb
Gave me these letters
After your mother left.
And these
Were written after our marriage.
Wonderful!
Woo hoo!
YAY!
Dado!
Back off...
Five balls, eight runs to win.
Go forth, m'lad.
Give the Royal Army a proper pasting!
Go.
You're hoping for too much.
If you don't make it, I don't want to see your face.
Remember, boss...
Gulrez is the last man in the way to certain victory.
You don't know
I'm the only man
Who's gonna lead us down that way.
Action stations. Go.
Five balls, eight runs! Make it quick!
Gulrez!
What was that?
Didn't you see?
I'm making way.
They're celebrating already!
Hmm...
Go.
Battlestations!
Four balls, four runs! We just need one four! Just one!
O Lord...
Just one more awful ball...
WOO HOO!
Victory!
Well done, partner.
Way to bowl.
We may've found our next star!
Much appreciated!
Your mother answered everything
Like someone
Caught red-handed.
Looking for any kind of excuse - sensible or not.
You're my daughter,
So I want to make it clear
That if a man agrees to anything less than modesty,
He's better off not marrying at all.
Okay.
Send the invoice.
Jiya...
You called me?
Got to say, Papa...
I love you...
I love you too...
I love you so much, Jiya...
How 'bout dinner tomorrow?
Yes, love.
Dinner tomorrow it is.
Love you, my dear...
You're still shy?
Just talk to her!
I will, when the date is fixed.
What are you gonna say?
And how, monsieur le Marié?
You're tongue-tied before her!
You struggle to catch your breath!
It ain't that bad, Aunt.
I ain't as cowardly
As I look.
Okay...
So...
Talk to her.
I will.
There.
I mean it, Aunt.
Once the date is fixed,
You'll see
How I take her on a date.
You gonna hold her hand?
I swear I will!
I'll pull her into a corner.
You'll be awed
At everything I say!
By the Lord...
Hear that, Neelam?
Hear him talk!
D'you think he's even gonna touch her?
Forget it, Aunt...
He'd tremble if his hand
So much as brushed hers!
Scaredy-cat!
Why'd you call me a scaredy-cat?
Because no one plans in love, you twit!
Nor says, 'You'll see'!
You just do it for everyone to see!
You challenging me?
Aye.
For real?
For real.
Do it.
Seize my hand
And I'll go on a date with you. Right now.
Hmm?
Gulrez will toss the coin for me.
Why are you sitting like that?
I'm tired of this world.
Look at your little self, mate.
I may be young --
'But I'm more experienced than the old', innit?
So...
How's it feel to be defeated?
Oh, lovely. Just called my friends in London to tell 'em how Gulrez's started hitting fours.
Flowers. For you.
Hey! Thanks.
This garland looks like a ring of flowers.
I know.
The same as in running rings round someone.
I lost on purpose!
Elementary, innit?
Had to, partner.
Winning doesn't nearly feel that good.
Looking at the faces of those who lose is uniquely painful.
Look at them...
Looks like they all won when I lost...
You're quite skilled at it, you know...
Losing a match you've almost won.
When Nano fixes the date for Maheen and Gulrez's engagement,
You can adorn the grave of your victory here with that garland.
Because there ain't gonna be
A next over.
What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance
I've decided
To marry
Gulrez.
What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance
What is union and separation to one struck by love
What is this illusion you, O Love, create, and then expunge
Quaff the blood out of me...
Quaff the blood out of me and feast on my heart
And feast on my heart...
Get up...
And sit where I'm sitting.
How can that be?
I wouldn't dare
Sit where you sit.
Dad would slap me
In my dreams!
I'm asking you
To sit here.
I can see
Mashood Ahmed from over there.
Okay.
I get it now.
But, Ammi Begum,
You always look at him once
Before saying something important.
Pass the spittoon.
Here.
Who asked you to come here?
Why, you?
You asked me.
'It's time we fixed a date for the engagement'.
It must've slipped out, m'lad.
Go out.
Send Mehrunnisa in.
As you say.
But this is gonna look so insulting...
Thanks to what you say, she's started thinking
That she's suddenly become wise.
Hmm.
Okay, sit.
But quietly.
Listen quietly
Until the date is fixed.
Quietly, okay?
Okay.
Tell me...
What would be a good day?
I won't, Ammi Begum...
I've been waiting for two hours.
You know how long it takes to fix the date?
A little over two hours?
It's been two hours.
No idea,
But it won't be much longer.
The engagement's taking so long.
Imagine how long the wedding will take.
They'd be sitting for months before fixing a date for the wedding.
In principle, we got engaged the moment I agreed.
Wonder what this formality's all about...
Maheen...
Have some shame.
Watch what you say.
Uhh...
Just felt like having a cuppa...
Mhm!
Stay right where you are.
You too.
You better act like you're getting engaged.
I will.
But could someone tell me when?
Or are they gonna keep it to themselves?
In the last
Forty years,
All engagements on Mondays and Tuesdays
Broke. Without exception.
8 out of 10 on Wednesdays
Didn't break...
But...
Those on Thursdays and Fridays
Ended in marriage. All of them.
So...
I say...
Friday it is.
What d'you say?
You said 'Friday it is'.
I wouldn't dare say Saturday or Sunday.
Why don't you say something, Suraiyya Begum?
I got engaged on a Friday too.
Okay...
How 'bout a Saturday or Sunday this time?
Here...
We had
Six engagements on Saturdays.
Four got married.
And on Sundays...
7 of 8 got married...
Sunday...
Sunday it is then.
Aye.
Sunday it is.
Sunday.
I hear engagements on Sundays don't break.
Eight in the family got engaged on Sundays
In the last 40 years.
Just one broke.
Good luck.
I told you, I got to go.
I can't wait six days!
I ain't taking chances! It must be confirmed!
No, Sunday would be too late...
Just here to say...
You've overstayed your welcome.
I say...
Don't come back if you leave this time.
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
You want her to wear
Red on her engagement?
Keep it there.
Show me something else.
Aye...
She likes this one.
Now you're talking.
She'd look like a fairy in this one.
But I don't like it.
I don't want her to look like a fairy.
I want her to look like a bride.
A proper bride.
Covered, protected...
But...
What's wrong with this blue one?
Remember, Ammi Begum,
I wore a blue suit on my engagement.
You said back then, too,
'You look just like a fairy, Suraiyya'...
The higher your fairy flew,
The harder she fell...
We'd rather not have another fairy here, Ammi Begum...
Pick whatever you like.
Just... Not this one.
Tear that, will you?
Why?
It's time for a new picture.
With you holding the gun.
Don't you think you're aiming for Waqar Ahmed's head?
You're talking about aiming!
I just pulled the trigger!
He's gonna die for real.
No, he's not.
Just on the rack.
There's a hundred prerequisites to dying, my dear.
The first... Is torment!
That's what I was thinking.
You won't let him die so easily.
Well, guess what, he ain't going down that easy, Maheen Aurangzeb!
The living ought to know
That those who die on purpose mean business!
How much does he pay you?
For?
Running these campaigns for him, making a gentleman out of him, and shielding the nasty piece of work that he is?
You know how nasty he is?
Let's keep it under the wraps, shall we? Everyone loves him so much.
Who doesn't know him?
You sure don't.
It ain't that bad.
I know him a bit too.
When the London tramp gets tired of his English roses,
He comes to Pakistan for a change of taste!
This time, he wanted to get the big fish.
Such as?
Such as Maheen Aurangzeb!
But his plot failed here.
I made mincemeat of him!
Care to tell me about your plot?
I don't plot.
I decide, my dear.
So...
Getting engaged to Gulrez
Is but your 'decision'?
Ever slept in peace
Since you made this decision?
Is your heart at ease for a moment?
Doesn't it hurt?
Doesn't it awaken you from your sleep
And say, 'You're gonna ruin me in your revenge plot, you imbecile'!
The least your poor heart would ask you
Is if you actually got engaged on Sunday,
What happens on Monday?
There'll be no Sunday after this one, Maheen Aurangzeb.
Days change,
But changed days like to have their way.
If you feel like torturing someone on Monday,
You can't be sure that tramp's gonna be in the city to take it.
What if he went back?
What if
He left on Sunday night?
What if someone's told him...
'Don't come back again'
'If you leave now'?
What d'you say, Ammi Begum?
Fajr...
Call her here.
She ought to take her pick.
I figured I ought to tear it for real after you left.
As I was about to, I thought...
He wasn't like this back then.
All that's left of childhood is the memories...
You ought to hold on to memories...
But why are you here?
Don't let his company spoil you!
You shouldn't be peeping into others' rooms.
D'you know,
Eight people got engaged on Sundays in our family in the last 40 years.
Just one broke.
Because the girl didn't want to marry him.
Please.
No more of your balderdash.
None of what I've said in the last few days
Qualifies as balderdash.
I've seen and heard it myself.
He leaves on Sunday.
He was arguing with his agent.
He wasn't so lucky
As to get a flight
Before Sunday.
He'll be gone forever on Sunday.
Because I've asked him to.
'Don't ever come back if you go'.
He won't be coming back, Maheen.
Ever.
Translation: Aditya Misra Â© GEO TV