I've seen and heard it myself.
He leaves on Sunday.
He was arguing with his agent.
He wasn't so lucky as to get a flight before Sunday.
He'll be gone forever on Sunday.
Because I've asked him to.
'Don't ever come back if you go'.
He won't be coming back, Maheen.
Ever.
Come and pick your engagement gown. They're waiting for you.
And please reject the blue one.
Mum wore it on her engagement.
She doesn't consider it auspicious.
♪ Love's testimony is not to be asked of it ♪
♪ It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes... ♪
♪ Make it on your own, but we don't have to grow up, we can stay forever young... ♪
♪ Living on my sofa, drinking rum and cola underneath the rising sun... ♪
♪ I could give a thousand reasons why ♪
♪ But you're going, and you know that... ♪
I don't like any of these colours...
Please help me, Waqar?
I thought you said you'd pick. But you're just looking at me.
I'm looking at how you're saving all your love for her.
Otherwise, I'm sure this suit's gonna look very good on you. This one.
This one?
Please pack this one.
Let's check out the ties...
I've never bought a tie.
You can help me pick a matching colour.
Yeah, sure.
How about this one?
Yeah, this one's good.
Would you have picked this one in my place?
No. I would've picked that one.
This one?
Okay.
Please pack these...
Bill, please?
It's been paid, sir.
Paid?
I paid the bill.
What am I here for?
Consider it my gift on your engagement.
Oh yeah... For the ties.
Thank you.
Please don't add this one.
Why?
Because I'd picked this one for you.
I don't know how to tie one.
Waqar...
I've learnt so much from you. The least I can do is teach you how to.
Thank you.
No.
Peace be upon you!
And upon you, peace.
So...
M'girl...
Which of these four do you like the most?
Umm...
Hmm?
Mhm!
This one...
I'll pick...
The blue one.
Should I go invite Jiya?
How could you not invite her?
But... Think again before you leave.
There's three other gowns here.
Why don't you folks wear these? Nano?
Here we are...
You gonna sit there? Come out.
No, not today.
Please? I'll make you a nice cuppa.
No, thank you. Not used to having a nice cuppa.
Come out already!
You would've left if I hadn't seen you!
Ever gone shopping with him?
God forgive!
Yeah God forgive me too!
Come.
-Come.
Hi, Chief.
Hi.
Studying hard, I see.
What are you two up to?
Who else?
I can deal with the second.
Where's the third?
There's a third?
Here yet?
Who do you mean? I think I'm mixing the second and the third...
You-Know-Who... Waqar the Winner.
Well, the Jury's changed that name.
He's officially Waqar the Loser now. For losing the match on purpose.
Anyway... Where is he?
Shopping with Gulrez. For the engagement.
What're you up to?
Do you think he's poisoning his ears?
Might as well be.
Guess what he says.
Why do you worry? Let the world say what they want.
He bowled awfully on purpose,
Didn't he?
Yeah.
But why?
He decided to lose to Gulrez as soon as you were out.
Why is he so determined to lose?
Chief...
He never wants to lose...
But he doesn't want to beat you. No idea why...
Why does he give a hoot about me?
Oh, Chief...
Always thinking about those who have nothing to do with you.
He's back from his mission impossible after you practically beat him with your boots!
The very mention of your name wipes the expression clean from his face. Like a fused bulb!
As in, no expression.
Chief...
You said a word too much.
What?
Asking him to get the devil out.
Don't you think it was a bit too harsh?
Yeah... But why are you talking about that?
I didn't beat him with my boots!
So Fajr's lying?
What'd she say?
She said you smacked your boot into his face!
I'm sure you did that in your fury... You don't really think, do you?
The 'get the devil out' part?
Has it hurt him so much?
Yeah...
Maybe...
So he's actually going back?
As if you give two boots -- *hem* -- hoots.
Where's Gulrez?
Trying his new suit.
The twit! Why couldn't he wait until the big day?
I asked him to try it on.
Why?
I wanted to see him wear that suit once.
You say that like you won't be there at the engagement.
The engagement's three days away.
Enough to change the world.
Who knows? I might not even live to see it... Or be here to attend it.
So you're leaving.
I won't be so sure...
I'm not sure I'll live through it.
No, Waqar Ahmed.
You've ruled that option out.
Those who bring others to life don't die in three days.
Would you keep it between ourselves?
I promise. What is it?
I'm leaving.
Without attending the engagement?
I'll be there. My flight leaves the same night. At 2.
I knew you'd leave.
I had to, Neelam...
It's been two months.
I haven't been here this long.
I know you didn't come here to go back.
I also know
Why you're going.
Everyone knows that.
I miss my English roses too much.
Can it.
There's no one.
Why d'you want to paint yourself as a loafer, a gadabout?
You're just spawning hatred for you in our hearts...
And especially... In her heart... She, who lives in yours...
No idea what you're talking about... And no idea what's taking him so long!
You know what I'm talking about.
I know what you're gonna do.
Know what, Waqar,
One moment
Has made me feel like I've wronged you.
I admit I'd fallen for Maheen, Neelam...
But my love
Could never be as powerful as Gulrez's.
So...
Don't think I'm pitying anyone...
I'm giving him what's rightfully his.
And I promise you
I won't be coming back this time.
You're leaving?
Yeah.
And this suit?
You wanted to see me in it.
Bless you. You look fantastic.
All eyes will be fixed on you.
See you.
I'm getting engaged on Sunday.
To Gulrez.
I did the right thing... Right?
You'd know that.
No, mate. I'm asking you.
Tell me.
Do you love Gulrez,
Or are you just showing someone?
You seriously think I'd wager my life to show someone?
Why are you getting engaged? You got engaged as kids.
Engagements of kids aren't really engagements.
Then why are you asking me if you're doing the right thing?
Because someone gave me a tip...
If you think you don't know yourself well enough, ask your best friend.
She always knows.
You don't love Gulrez.
Yet!
You never will.
Why?
Because you love someone else.
I don't love anyone!
You folks are just -- Thinking things!
You folks?
So... Who else told you that?
Aye?
Fajr.
I'm sure she'd know
Who you love?
I hate him! That's all you should know!
Waqar Ahmed!
I swear...
I hate the sound of his name!
And you'll see...
I'll prove it on Sunday...
Maheen Aurangzeb's heart is an open book...
Everyone can read it
On her face!
Don't forget to come, okay?
Hey...
Did you just say...
Maheen Aurangzeb?
As always, as always!
Aurangzeb was my Dad.
Aye...
How'd he die?
Car crash...
Please don't ask me anything else...
Hello, Jiya!
Hey, Dad!
I'll pick you up at 8.
I want to ask something...
Yes?
About that car crash...
Was
Aurangzeb with Mum in the car?
Please tell me, Dad...
For my sake?
Yes.
And he died on the spot?
Aye.
Could I have his picture?
His picture?
Why?
I said
I want his picture.
I don't care if you get late... Get here at 9 or 10...
But get me his picture.
Please, Dad? Please?
Please...?
Not so fast, partner!
What's with the roughness of late?
What's on your mind?
What's the news?
Nothing much... Just... There's this engagement thingy...
Good.
It'll be over by Sunday.
Ever thought
Why happier moments end so quickly?
Why's there no Sunday after Sunday?
Very funny.
Aye, very funny.
You're calling the moon a 100-Watt bulb.
It's the entire blimmin' moon, Waqar!
Where'd you learn this stuff?
Sacrifice teaches me.
As do lies
That your type tell solemnly.
Truth can be a real ghost.
It comes back to haunt you.
Get it?
She was here for you.
Who?
Maheen.
Saying sorry I guess?
-No.
She said you'd lead Gulrez astray.
But...
You've got to see him.
Why?
You need to figure out why there's no Sunday after Sunday.
I know.
Monday follows Sunday. It's for the best.
Know why happiness is so short-lived?
Because one man's happiness is another man's sorrow. God doesn't want such happiness to last long.
Okay...
Care to tell me whose sorrow this happiness could be?
Maybe the girl who's overjoyed about it...
Or maybe...
You, who's too afraid to face the truth.
'Bout time you faced it.
Or you'll have to live a lie for the rest of your life.
♪ What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance? ♪
Thank you, love.
By the way...
Why d'you want his picture?
I want to see how ugly his type can look.
Forget it.
Just... Forget it...
Dad...
Never thought you'd be the type who'd mistake remembering for forgetting.
Show me his pic.
I need to see the blighter... Remember him one last time before forgetting him...
♪ O Beloved! ♪
♪ O ♪
You may rehearse if you'd like.
Rehearse for what?
Getting ringed.
Why?
You won't be able to put it on so suddenly.
Suddenly?
Perhaps
You may get bad news at that moment?
It may be good news for you too.
That zestful dance of his
To the beats of the drum
Is all but an act.
All his tears have altered course
From his eyes to his heart.
You're under coercion; he's persevering.
By the time it's time for you to wear the ring,
It'd be time for him to leave your life forever.
You'll be left watching
As he
Leaves.
Does Nano know?
No.
And --
Aunt Mehru?
I told you - besides me, it's just Ali who knows.
So why don't you tell Nano?
Why should I?
Everyone wants him to leave.
Everyone thinks
That if he leaves, he will, as always, bounce back.
But I swear to God,
Only I know
That he won't be coming back.
It's 11 p.m. right now.
You always ask for time to decide.
But this time,
You've only got a few minutes
Before Maheen Aurangzeb
Will be left cursing the hands of the clock.
♪ O ♪
♪ O Beloved! ♪
♪ Pull away the veil on your face, O Beloved, ♪
♪ Let the curtains fall, O Beloved! ♪
♪ O Beloved! ♪
♪ O ♪
♪ Show me the beauty of your spring once, ♪
♪ Show me the beauty of your spring once... ♪
By the time it's time for you to wear the ring,
It'd be time for him to leave your life forever.
By Jove, Matey!
You look like trouble!
Lovely!
Show me.
♪ O Beloved! ♪
♪ O ♪
♪ This life is dull without you... ♪
♪ Love's testimony is not to be asked of it ♪
♪ It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes ♪
♪ Ask all you will what comes out of love ♪
♪ The heart is its creator, and ends up being destroyed by it... ♪
♪ In the tale of love where do these turns come from... ♪
♪ In the tale of love where do these turns come from ♪
♪ That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart ♪
♪ That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart... ♪
Are you touched in the head?
Somebody might come to suspect I'm leaving.
There's no room for suspicion now.
Because I've told her you're leaving.
So --
As if telling her makes things any different!
And if it did?
Codswallop!
Like you, I don't know what you'd do.
But take it as a bit of parting advice
If she stops you from leaving,
Don't ever leave.
Or you'll be leaving her in quite the mare's nest!
♪ I will keep with me the memories of our conversations and of you ♪
Take it as a bit of parting advice
♪ Such bounties, O Love, are all one gets from you in benefaction ♪
If she stops you from leaving,
Don't ever leave.
♪ Such bounties, O Love, are all one gets from you in benefaction ♪
♪ I will laugh wholeheartedly at this, I will embrace the heart with rapture ♪
♪ I will remember you then... ♪
Enough with it already!
Will anybody call the girl or are we going to dance all the way until sunrise?
Come on.
It's time to meet your love.
Just as the Lord God willed!
Everyone's waiting, c'mon!
Hey --
Whose picture is it in your feet?
This is Dad's picture...
How come it's here on the floor?
You might've dropped it accidentally.
I've never seen this picture of Dad's before...
You've seen it now!
Come!
Everyone's waiting.
Aunt's standing outside. Come.
You look so sweet!
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV