Don't let go...
I'd die...
♪ Love's testimony is not to be asked of it ♪
♪ It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes ♪
♪ Ask all you will what comes out of love ♪
♪ The heart is its creator, and ends up being destroyed by it... ♪
♪ In the tale of love... ♪
♪ In the tale of love where do these turns come from... ♪
♪ In the tale of love where do these turns come from ♪
♪ That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart... ♪
This is not the one
I take right now, you twit.
Would you rather
Kill me by giving me the wrong pills now that I've signed the will?
There, now...
Enough.
I was just kidding...
I know
That you love me so much.
But, my dear,
Mum and Dad have to go someday...
And it's better this way.
Just pray
That no parent
Ever live to witness the death of a child,
Or the poor souls
Would have to die twice.
There, now!
The little twit's crying!
Don't worry.
I'm fine.
I was just
Missing Mashood Ahmed a bit.
I thought
I'd fool around with you.
But it is wrong to remember him, too, Dastoor Ahmed,
For that London tramp comes to mind, too.
Just like that.
Listen...
Yes?
Ever felt
That I find some excuse or the other to remember him?
Tell me honestly.
Or
Do I just feel so
Because that twerp is here?
Hasn't he left yet?
No.
He'd leave in a couple of days.
Oh?
How do you know?
Have you met him? Ties of blood got the better of you?
No, Ammi Begum, I haven't met him.
I got word.
He's staying at the farmhouse.
Munshi Alam's looking after him.
It kills me to hear.
Would you look at what Munshi Alam's turned out to be?
As if he'd have the guts to say a word!
Alright, tell me,
Is that farmhouse his,
As per the will?
Aye.
What's it to us, then? He may stay there or leave...
And you...
Give me the pill.
The yellow one.
'Yellow' is an English word, Ammi Begum.
I know.
Let's just say
The sick are excused for speaking it.
Now,
I even say things like
'Blood pressure' and 'temperature'.
Seeing Maheen smile today, I knew he was coming.
Call him inside.
Come in.
He's here to see you.
Who?
Who could it be
But the one
Whose coming makes the cacti in Nano's lawn blossom,
And brings a smile to your face?
Waqar?
♪ What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance ♪
♪ What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance? ♪
♪ What is union and separation to one struck by love ♪
♪ What is this illusion you, O Love, create, and then expunge ♪
♪ Quaff the blood out of me... ♪
Howdy, partner?
♪ Ask all you will what comes out of love ♪
♪ The heart is its creator, and ends up being destroyed by it... ♪
I saw the cacti eight days ago.
They were blossoming.
This time, they're so colourful!
Oh, the pinks, the blues, the yellows!
And you're here today?
Come.
Sit.
Where'd you jet off to this time?
Surely, you weren't in London!
France.
And that noisy old dame was looking for you in London!
Who?
My Nano, of course.
Your Dado.
You're officially un clochard parisien (a Paris tramp) now, Waqar Ahmed!
What'd happened to Gulrez?
Blood cancer.
By the time we found out,
The night had almost fallen.
Night -- ?
You moron!
The sun had almost set.
Would you like some tea?
Neelam...
What's up with you?
Whatever he may be like, whatever he's done...
He may be bad for others, but he cleared the way for Gulrez.
But nobody listened to his side of the story.
We'll ask him now that he's come -
'Why'd you leave, mate'?
I'm afraid of him.
I'm more afraid of Maheen.
Why are you here?
I mean, why now,
After eight long years?
Maheen, I didn't know...
That Gulrez's left us.
Gulrez left us.
Where do you come in?
He'd started auguring in his last days.
He'd say,
'He'd come one day'
'With tears in his eyes',
'Regret on his face',
'And the proof of his innocence in his hands'.
Where's your proof?
Wait, Maheen.
I'll talk once I'm over Gulrez's grief.
Did you visit his grave?
Aye.
Just today, in fact.
It's been four years since he died.
For four years,
The sorrow of his death has been coursing in our veins.
For four years, we've been waiting for the next death.
And you say, 'Wait, Maheen',
'I'll talk once I'm over Gulrez's grief'?
Is your grief so little, Waqar Ahmed?
You'd be delighted to hear the next thing I say.
For four years, I've been waiting for you, too.
So, where's that twit, Wali?
Ask him to beat him with his boots and throw him out!
Wali says that he hasn't wronged us.
He'd cleared the way for our sake.
Wali's got a point.
That wretch has just wronged me.
He's got a point.
Brought your proof?
Aye.
I've got your diary
In which you'd poured your heart out.
I read it that day.
I've read it over and over so many times in eight years that I know it by heart.
I mumble its words in my loneliness...
I thought you only said you were my enemy, Maheen,
But you were actually my enemy all along.
So, I was delighted to hear that you got married to Gulrez.
That's why I lay in France for eight years.
I thought I'd pay a visit
When you'd look at me and say,
'Hey! That's Waqar Ahmed'!
'My cousin...'
'My Uncle's son'.
But I made just one mistake.
What?
I couldn't stand my ground against you, Maheen.
It occurred to me that I defeat you,
But my victory
Would mean poor Gulrez's defeat.
So, I cleared the way for him.
No, Waqar Ahmed.
You left me defeated.
I'd suffered a bitter defeat.
I'd fallen face-first before everyone.
I stopped breathing...
My heart stopped beating...
My head bowed...
And everyone felt such pity that they teared up.
And all along, you, with a diary by your side, thought,
That you've ensured my victory as you left.
Come with me.
You say you read my diary,
And took it with you to France.
So, which diary could this be?
Who could've written this one?
And if this is my diary,
Who could've written that one?
But I've got the diary with me.
I've got the diary with me, Waqar Ahmed.
And if I'd lost this diary,
If you'd taken this diary with you to France,
I would've followed you to France.
I would've grabbed your collar
Right in the middle of a Paris street,
Given you a proper scolding,
And spat in your face.
I've got the diary in my car.
I'll go get it.
He's brought a diary, Nano.
Just like Maheen's.
What's there in it?
One'd know if one's read it...
Then, go and see what's written in it.
You tell everything like a news bulletin.
You skip what's really going on.
He's leaving, Nano...
Another news?
He hasn't got the diary with him.
He would've given it to Maheen. Go.
Find out what's written in that diary
And why that twit took something like that from him.
Dastoor!
Dastoor! Come here. My heart grows restless...
Dastoor Ahmed...
What's written in this diary?
How did he get this?
They look the same!
The handwriting looks the same, too.
What do you mean?
Someone's written in a diary like mine
In a handwriting like mine,
But he's written what he wanted -
There's dark
Where there was day,
There's a heart poured out
Where there was nothing to say;
There's verve
Where there was vexation,
And there's woe
Where there was delectation.
What about where you'd written Waqar?
He's written whatever he wanted to...
It was a worse enemy than Waqar
Who'd stabbed me in the back.
I've been betrayed, Munshi Alam.
Think again.
Have you been betrayed,
Or those at Kaneez Mahal?
There's a diary just like Maheen's.
The handwriting's the same, too.
But the words are not Maheen's.
So,
You read the diary that day, too!
The one you show about as proof.
Just read that diary.
You, too, would feel that Maheen doesn't love me.
It was you
Who didn't love her, Waqar Ahmed.
It was just whim,
And you can never love
When love's a whim.
If you read that diary, Munshi Alam, you, too, would think that Maheen's written it herself.
I'd heard
That, in love, one can
Read their faces,
And look into their hearts
Through
Their eyes,
And believe them,
Have faith.
I'd never heard
That one could read their diary
And take it along as 'proof'!
Where'd you go?
To Maheen's.
With
The 'proof' of your innocence,
Or, rather,
To show, after eight long years
And fifteen days,
How Maheen had been at fault?
Up there on the writing table is Maheen's diary.
I think
She forgot to keep it in the drawer.
Don't go anywhere, Waqar...
For my sake...
So,
You want to get out of her life somehow, innit?
Then, just marry me.
When you've decided to sacrifice yourself,
Why not give me your pelt?
Good evening, sir.
Good evening.
Is Mlle Jiya home?
She's at her father's place.
Father's?
Aye, M. Mir Mehtab.
Alright.
I don't have his address.
But it's important that I meet him
Right now.
Just a moment. I'll give you his address.
Oui?
Monsieur,
A M. Waqar's here to meet you.
Waqar...?
Oui...
Send him in.
Bonsoir.
I'm seeing you for the first time, but I know you.
I know you, too.
Come.
She's awake, isn't she?
No problem
If she isn't, either.
Come in.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV