This last will and testament is hereby recorded as decreed
Copies of the will
Shall be sent to each heritor today
To be signed by them.
Should they have any opposition
They shall have fifteen days to express the same.
Else, this bequest will be assumed to have been accepted as just and fair.
Yes.
That's right.
Ammi Begum
Madam, please sign here.
Look.
Munshi Alam has arrived too.
Madam, we require your thumb impression here.
Love's testimony is not to be asked for
It pulls out tears and throws them from the eyes
What good is grieving and writhing in your name?
Sir?
My car's not starting.
Car?
The banger's a Foxy.
Yes
It's a Foxy.
But you're saying it's a car.
Is it not a car to you?
Come on, bro.
A Foxy's a Foxy.
Not a car.
Come, mate.
Hey!
This is Gulrez's Foxy.
How come it's alone out here?
Hey!
Where's your husband?
Probably had a domestic.
Even then, the pride of the family is not to be abandoned on the streets like this.
Splendid.
This Foxy is parked right in the middle of the road,
And Gulrez is nowhere to be seen.
Oh God!
What am I witnessing here?
Such immodesty, Maheen!
Arthritis.
Arthritis?
Pain in the knee joints.
Unable to move any further, she'd have said to Gulrez Bhai,
'End of the line, mate'!
Take out the rope.
I swear, Wali
She worked just fine when I left.
Ran smoothly as if waltzing.
When I
Stopped at the traffic signal,
I thought I heard something.
She worked fine again
But
Barely moved another hundred yards.
Mind if I say something?
It is time.
Time for what?
I mean, be done with it.
Look at her age and resilience.
Tell me honestly,
What else do you expect from her?
Put it plainly
What are you trying to say?
-Sell it.
Sell the Foxy?
Alright, don't sell it.
Let it be this way:
Park it on the porch
Adorn it with a garland
And shower rose petals on it.
But please do one thing
Purchase a new car to drive to office.
Accursed be the new car.
Just to show people like you,
I cannot sell the one I've loved for fifteen years.
No.
Never.
Stop the car.
Stop the car, please.
Where did it vanish?
You mean the Foxy?
Of course, Wali.
What else could I mean?
Where did you park it?
Right here.
No.
You're forgetting something.
You're so worried you're unable to remember correctly; think harder.
Think harder about what?
I left her right here
One hundred percent.
At this very spot --
Look!
Tire marks!
Has this happened before?
How --
You left her and she drove off?
Fantastic, Wali.
How can she drive off on her own?
She couldn't walk one inch from this spot.
That means it's been stolen.
Have you, ever in your life,
Heard or read that someone's Foxy got stolen?
Thieves are getting innovative these days.
Who knows?
One might've taken a liking to it!
How much would it fetch?
What do you mean, 'fetch'?
The thief, after all
Surely does not intend to use it as a rooster coop.
Look, Wali
You don't understand my feelings.
Everybody understands your feelings.
Neelam says
One just needs to witness your relationship with your Foxy
To understand how you would treat your wife.
To the police station.
Haul on the bo'lin!
The bo'lin haul!
The bloody ship's is a-rollin'!
That's it!
Alright.
What now?
That which happens in kidnapping cases.
You'll collect a ransom from him?
Why not?
Put a sock in it!
Chap's a miser.
He'll weep out of sorrow
But won't give a penny.
In that case
This Foxy stays here for the next hundred years.
Hello?
Yes, we're headed to the police station.
What happened?
Thieving rascal.
He's going to die by Gulrez's hand.
'Thieving rascal'? What are you talking about?
Gulrez's Foxy has been stolen.
Oh God!
Say something more than just 'Oh God'.
Thank you, O God!
Just pray that it's found.
May God will that it never be found.
I'm disconnecting for now.
You were talking to Neelam?
Yes.
Why did she say, 'Oh God'?
She was worried.
Exclaimed, 'Oh God' on hearing about it.
Deep down, she loves Foxy too.
Yes...
Peace be upon you, Munshi Uncle!
Peace be upon you!
Munshi Uncle, catch the keys.
Peace be upon you, Auntie!
And upon you, peace.
And it's not 'Auntie;' say 'aintín'.
She'll be scornful about it if she hears it.
Where is she?
She's praying.
Right,
Mr Gulrez!
What colour is your car?
Maroon.
Maroon...
Model?
1966.
1966...
Mind if I say something?
Please.
Don't file a complaint for theft.
Why?
Such an old car isn't getting stolen.
Then what might have happened to her?
Leave it be.
Tell me, did it work?
Work?
What?
You don't need to ask.
It works so well
With the attitude of a viscountess!
Just sometimes --
Sometimes --?
If it ever stopped working
I'd take it to the workshop using Wali's car.
And the address of the workshop?
It sure hasn't gone to the workshop on its own...
You can never know, my good sir...
If only we knew what surprise awaits...
Don't worry, though.
You're at the right place.
I'd never thought of it.
That I'd have to come here
Because of her.
Stop, Maheen.
My first benediction in orison is for you.
And a prayer that you pay a visit precedes it.
Gulrez's Foxy has been stolen.
It kills me to hear that!
Poor Gulrez.
Poor thief.
What will he do with it?
If the right compensation isn't received,
Set it ablaze by the shore!
What do you mean?
The thief
Is none but me.
Don't do it, the poor lad will die.
I'll return it before he dies!
But however did you manage to steal the Foxy?
It's not as if it's a matchbox.
Just think, Nano, as if
The Foxy is inside a matchbox!
But
You have to make a promise to me.
What promise?
You haven't the foggiest about the Foxy.
I mean
Neither do you know about the theft
Nor about the thief.
Hold up.
Alright, let me get up from this sacred spot.
You have to make a promise too.
What promise?
You
Will only inflict as much torment as the poor man can bear.
Then you don't know, Nano.
He's not beggarly.
The only poverty that afflicts him is related to pluck!
And his breed of destitutes get a strike
Where there's not the slightest relief.
Step aside.
Blabbering on and on and --
Alright.
I'll strike him where he'll have the slightest of relief.
Listen!
Tell me
Where have you kept the banger?
In a matchbox!
Oh Gulrez...!
Tell me about the tyres.
What do you mean?
Tell me the age.
When did you purchase them?
Around -- four months ago?
Wow...
Then the tyres can lead one to consider it...
Consider what?
You'll not understand it, Mr Gulrez.
Tell me - did you have a tape deck in it?
Why not?
Plus, I change it every year.
That's it, then!
What's it?
Case closed.
Rest assured, gentlemen!
Leave it to us.
It'll be found when we're done with our rest, won't it?
How many hours do you sleep?
Oh sir...
Who'll be able to sleep now?
No, Mr Gulrez...
Having a nice and peaceful sleep is important.
Hey girl!
You won't have anything before you leave?
If I have something here, will I just stare at people eating at Neelam's birthday party?
No, young lady.
Something else is going on...
What could it be?
The redness on your cheeks suggests...
You've been leeching someone's blood.
Suspicion
Suspicion is the pair of scissors that cuts the threads of affection.
It has already snipped, my dear...
It'll be clear within a few hours who's been struck.
Let me know when it's clear to you!
Bye!
Listen!
Tell Mum that Dastoor Ahmed will be late.
He'll take me and Mum along with him.
Only you!
Why?
Nano's coming with us!
Fajr!
She's stolen
Gulrez's Foxy.
You've found out?
She told me about her latest exploit herself!
She had me promise not to tell anyone!
Oh?
She had me promise too.
But I've reneged on it.
I'm honestly worried, Ammi Begum.
Why are you worried?
She may create a scene over it.
Leave it be.
I used to fight such battles with your father.
Dad used to say,
'This girl never fails to ruffle Siraj Ahmed'.
And see,
At the age of 60 years,
He departed after 120 years of life.
In his last moments,
He seized my hand and said,
'I used to cower before you for nothing, Kaneez Begum'.
If you say, should I ask?
Don't you dare!
Don't even say a word.
Let me handle the talking.
She'll be going to the birthday party with me in the evening.
I'll ask her on the way.
Ask her when the car is moving slowly.
Or stopped at a traffic signal.
Why?
Just --
Dad used to say, 'Drive neither in excessive sorrow nor in ebullience'.
She's here.
Disconnect the phone.
And don't say
That I mentioned the theft.
Who were you talking to?
To Ammi Begum.
You told her?
Of course not; there was no mention of the Foxy.
She was just asking me what I'd wear for the birthday celebration.
And what will you wear?
I'm thinking
Of a pink sari...
That's great!
You're really decking up for Neelam's birthday.
Keep the black one as well.
Why?
Who knows if there'll be cause for celebration at all!
Why not?
He's got such a puny heart, Mum.
Who knows, it may just go boom at the mention of the ransom!
How much will you demand?
Just about a 100-150 grand or so.
What?
Are you in your senses?
If you ask for a hundred grand, he won't give you.
He'll give you his head.
By God!
What a spectacle will that be!
For the first time, a man will give his head for a Foxy!
Then I'll write in my diary,
'I've not seen such a one as you, Gulrez Akhtar',
'You're not dead; you're a martyr'.
Go.
Careful!
Need any help?
Please, enjoy the party.
Have you no shame, Wali Ahmed?
Keep on serving her with such sobreity
And you might just end up dancing to her tunes forever!
You know well enough, Aunt Mehru.
If I am able to dance to her tunes,
I'd be greatly honoured.
Oh?
So that's what you desire!
At my friend's mehendi [wedding ritual]
She was in the mood for a presto
I couldn't even keep up with the rhythm.
You're so indecorous!
Stay tuned for more!
Hey!
Congratulations to you
You've got a terpsichorean for a husband!
Congratulate her, Aunt!
It's not necessary for everything to go with the rhythm!
You haven't asked, Nano
Why I've brought petals along with the bouquet.
I know.
Yes, that's why you're our friend.
You're so intelligent.
Why the petals, Dado?
This buffon has a feeling that he'd die of sorrow on hearing about the Foxy.
And she'll shower these petals on his body.
Oh my God!
This will ruin the birthday celebrations!
Leave it be!
Tell me Maheen,
If you're married off to someone like him --
Life will come to a standstill like this, Nano!
Good evening ladies and gentlemen!
Why are you speaking English?
Because Ammi Begum isn't around!
Peace be upon you, Dastoor Uncle!
And upon you, peace!
Thank you!
Welcome.
Cutting the cake will have to wait four hours.
Why, Uncle?
A bit of a problem.
By the way, where's Ammi Begum?
Yes?
What do you want from Ammi Begum?
Happy Birthday!
Thank you!
Before you arrived, Ammi Begum
He was speaking English!
Defiantly, I will today.
Hold your tongue, Dastoor Ahmed.
You getting thwacked at this age isn't going to look nice.
I've brought news
I will break it after four hours.
Speak right now.
Right now, I will narrate it in English.
Alright
Break the news after four hours.
Come.
Where's Gulrez?
The colleen's in mourning.
Mourning?
His Foxy's been stolen.
What kind of fool has stolen it?
Don't say it so loud.
He'll start wailing.
Anyways, where is he?
Perhaps it's not been stolen.
It's been stolen.
It could've been abducted.
Abducted?
Just tell me
If you have to pay 25 gee as compensation,
Can you make this sacrifice for your Foxy?
Who's collecting it?
I'm just asking -- so to speak.
I can do anything for my Foxy.
But --
25 gee is a bit too much.
Your love is not true.
It's nothing like that.
I just don't have the dough --
Fibster!
Aunt Suraiyya
Look at that.
Say it before they do, please?
That Gulrez is Maheen's.
What?
Gulrez is Maheen's.
Please say it.
Alright.
Maheen is Gulrez's.
The weather ain't bad.
Come on.
See you soon!
How long are you here?
No idea.
Well, I'll see you soon then!
Alright.
Let's meet again soon then. Bye.
Bye!
Munshi Alam!
You look so old!
Not a penny less than 25 gee.
Where's the car?
The Foxy - not the car.
And we don't know where it is.
But we can look for it for you.
Alright.
Deal.
Place 25 gee on Fajr's palm.
I will give it when the Foxy is found.
First, the buck; then we work.
Don't you trust me?
Not at all.
Have this sweet, quickly.
What's the occasion?
Not trusting him!
We'll have one too, then.
Yes, please.
Have one.
And you too.
Alright, tell me in English.
Tell you what?
What's the news?
Oh --
Say it quickly.
Waqar Ahmed is coming.
Wa --
Waq --
Waqar Ahmed!
I'd die of happiness, Dastoor Ahmed!
That's why
That's why I had said
That I'd say it in English.
Indeed!
Waqar...
Hello?
Jiya.
You there yet?
I'm on the way.
I'm home.
Will you call tonight?
Yes, maybe...
Maybe?
Why?
I think I'll talk to you tomorrow.
Okay?
Okay.
Bye.
25.
Wali! You scared me!
Had the sweet?
I did!
Congratulations!
For what?
The Foxy's yours from now on!
What?
Wali!
What will I do with the Foxy?
Ask Neelam about it
Or Mum.
They've sealed the deal together.
They've purchased it?
100%!
Suraiyya!
Mum!
Come with me.
What happened?
Come.
Tell me, what is it?
Tell me what is it!
Sit down.
Why did you purchase the Foxy?
Foxy?
Neelam just fed me a sweet.
And Wali says it's about the purchase of the Foxy!
If you'd all come to know that we'd stolen the Foxy
Then --
We could've --
Just returned it quietly.
But please.
Don't make a mistake by purchasing it.
It's a lurgy!
Mum!
Wali told her we've purchased the Foxy!
The sweet has triggered her anger!
I'm in for it...
Tell me honestly
What's the matter with the Foxy?
Why is Mum tittering like that?
And what was this sweet I've just eaten for?
If I tell you the truth --
Something might just explode.
It will if you don't, too.
Oh?
A deal about you and the Foxy's owner has been sealed.
What?
Calm down.
You're flaring up.
25 gee right here.
Now hand us our cut.
Here's your 25,000!
We don't want a penny of it!
And don't eat this sweet.
It's bitter.
Your Foxy is parked on our porch.
Come and collect it.
Munshi Alam!
Who was this girl?
That
Was Maheen.
She's not changed one bit.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV