I mean it, Nano.
I saw her with my own eyes.
Maheen was behind the white-bearded man.
For a moment, I felt
Like my world had been upended.
Until... She approached me.
Maheen?
Of course.
Maheen.
She said,
'The painter remembers his painting, Gulrez',
'But not the other way around'.
'The painting but looks for an art gallery'
'That would adorn its ornamented wall with her beauty'.
So
You
Are here to tell me
That you
Aren't gonna marry Maheen?
Don't mistake me for one of your English roses,
Who'd fall for the hollow words of a London tramp!
If I talk nicely to you,
Just know it's my love for Uncle Mashood!
As for you, I loathe you so much
I'd spit in your face any day!
But you!
You dare say you want to marry Maheen Aurangzeb?
D'you think Your Highness is at a departmental store?
D'you think you can pull out your riches and buy everything under the sun?
Have some shame!
You're friends with God-knows-how-many girls!
And now, you've got your eyes on me!
Your Royal Highness would do well to remember
I won't think twice before chopping those filthy hands off!
Stop it, Maheen!
Don't stop me, Aunt.
It's best for him
If he packed his bags and jetted off to London before this instant!
You can't stay here!
So get going!
And aye,
If you dared say so much as my name,
I'd ruin you!
♪ Love's testimony is not to be asked of it ♪
♪ It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes ♪
♪ Ask all you will what comes out of love ♪
♪ The heart is its creator, and ends up being destroyed by it... ♪
Don't mistake me for one of your English roses,
Who'd fall for the hollow words of a London tramp!
You're friends with God-knows-how-many girls!
And now, you've got your eyes on me!
Your Royal Highness would do well to remember...
If you dared say so much as my name,
I'd ruin you!
Now you see what a force to reckon with girls can be, Waqar Ahmed...
Dado's right...
It isn't proper to marry
A friend.
♪ What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance? ♪
♪ What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance ♪
♪ What is union and separation to one struck by love ♪
♪ What is this illusion you, O Love, create, and then expunge ♪
♪ Quaff the blood out of me... ♪
♪ Quaff the blood out of me and feast on my heart ♪
♪ And feast on my heart... ♪
He got hurt?
How?
She threw
Whatever she could get her hands on.
He's a proper man too.
He didn't move an inch.
What'd he think?
That's what you wanted, innit?
Go...
Check on him...
Gulrez...
Not every dream mirrors your fate.
Sometimes, your fate
Is the opposite of your dreams.
So...
Would you care more about the dream... Or your fate?
Hello?
It's Suraiyya, Mehrunnisa.
Aye?
Was Maheen there?
No.
A storm is more like it.
What happened?
She thundered down on Waqar Ahmed.
Threw whatever she could see at him!
What?
Don't even ask about it.
She left him a wreck.
I saw his lip bleed.
Good Lord...
Why didn't you stop her?
We could.
Except she wouldn't.
Honestly?
She's been very cruel.
He'd done nothing to earn Maheen's punishment.
Why don't you ask Ammi Begum?
I feel like asking her for real this time.
If he wants to marry Maheen,
I don't see how it's wrong to think about it or express his wish.
What can I do, Mehrunnisa?
I'm very worried myself.
I thought
There'd be a minor row before everything's over.
But Maheen!
Mind if I said something?
I'm sorry but...
You're just as guilty.
Mind if I said something, too, Mehrunnisa?
Granted
It was most unfortunate,
I know just as well as everyone else
That there's no one like Waqar Ahmed in the family.
But when it's about promises...
Your honour depends on keeping it.
Ammi Begum ain't gonna take the world's million insults
For this one silly love story.
I'd never want
To sacrifice Gulrez Akhtar
For the sake of one Waqar Ahmed's wish.
Who told you to do any of this?
We talked about breaking his face.
So you'd actually do it?
I do
What I say!
What'd he think?
Oh!
You're worried about what he thinks!
I told him
To pack his bags and get going!
From?
Nano's place, of course!
You calling the shots there now?
Well, then, lemme be clear...
I ain't setting foot there
As long as that man's around!
You broke his face or all ties with him?
Who's he to me?
Whoa.
So now, you're not on talking terms.
No going over in life and death...
You ended everything, didn't you?
I haven't got time for hollow ties.
So you'd rather gibbet a man
For desiring to marry you?
I don't know about anyone else, but he deserves every bit of it!
Very cruel.
If he dared say another word,
You're all gonna see this ain't even close to the worst of me!
And what are you doing here?
Learning the art of disguise!
Who's in disguise?
Who isn't?
I'm amusing myself with the spectacle.
I mean, Jesus Christ, each actor is better than the next!
Blimey, Neelam...
I didn't know what an earthquake was until I saw her.
She upturned everything before you could blink!
I swear,
If she had a gun,
She would've shot Waqar Ahmed dead!
That's rude.
Waqar's family. Her Uncle's son.
It's okay between cousins!
He didn't go to her with the proposal.
He just talked to Ammi Begum.
The least he had was that right.
What next?
Everyone's gonna curse her. Pull her up.
Although, to be quite frank, it is a bit unbelievable. She's very decent.
She does have a thing for pranks, but... Nothing like this...
As if I'm lying!
I'm just a bit surprised
That she wreaked this havoc and Waqar stood there quietly...
By the Lord,
He didn't move an inch.
She'd have to apologise for that.
She ain't all that decent!
You can have it in writing, Gulrez Akhtar,
She'd beg forgiveness.
What are you looking at?
Just thinking.
About?
Thinking about what kind of man
Would stand firm in his place as an earthquake wreaks havoc all around
Without moving an inch...
Go see where he's going!
If one look could tell...
Go after him!
He took his car and left.
He left?
Who?
Waqar.
Big deal.
I'm very worried, Ammi Begum.
Don't worry.
He can drive.
You haven't seen the fury on his face, Mum!
It's only fair!
That puny pixie
Almost swallowed him whole!
What if he went straight to her?
The phone...
Quickly! Here!
Call her...
Hello?
It's Ammi Begum.
Yes, Ammi Begum?
Bolt the doors and shut the windows!
He's coming!
Who?
The man with the broken face!
Okay!
Hi, Aunt!
How are you, Jiya?
Dreadful.
She's such a cheat I feel like I'd kill her!
Kill her!
Where's she?
Upstairs. Be careful.
She's in a temper.
Why?
Something... Happened.
Nothing much. Waqar, you know...
He proposed to her.
And?
She disposed of him.
Umm...
I'll go see her.
Why'd you have to tell her?
I know who to tell what and when!
Bolt the door. He's coming.
Who?
-Waqar.
Won't you let him in?
I hear he left in a fury.
Don't bolt the door.
Ask Khushi Mohammad to put anything that can break away!
Khushi Mohammad!
Too late...
Waqar...
Forgive her, m'boy.
I'm here to say sorry.
I hurt her for no reason.
She's hurt you real bad...
It's nothing.
She just got even for the old slap.
So...
Where's she?
Upstairs. In her room.
Don't do anything...
It's okay, Aunt.
Back off.
Back. Off!
I
I said
I said BACK
I said BACK OFF!
Don't you dare come upstairs.
Please, Mum...
Tell him
He's not welcome when I'm around!
And you! You better hear this...
Your theatrics won't work here!
Go back where you came from!
What are you doing, Maheen?
Nothing this blighter doesn't deserve!
And aye,
I've decided for real this time...
Won't you ask me
What it's about?
I thought you were so excited about it.
What d'you mean?
I've decided
To marry
Gulrez.
I did the right thing, didn't I?
You gave him the boot.
I didn't really want to.
Don't be apologetic, mate.
Those who break hearts
Ought to live with heartbreak.
Whose heart did he break?
Those who make friends are connatural heartbreakers.
They make careless promises,
Swear hollow vows...
But when they come to,
They go back on them both.
Just pray he leaves.
Why are you so afraid of his being here?
I don't think I can face him.
Is that regret I hear?
It's nothing like that.
He's guilty...
But I don't know
What he's guilty of.
Isn't it enough he said, 'I'm gonna marry Maheen' before everyone?
Aye, but it isn't exactly wrong, is it, Jiya?
It's okay between cousins...
Sometimes, you begin to like someone...
I mean, he didn't tell me.
He told Nano.
Nano's order would've been enough to stop him.
With so many people to refuse...
Me giving him the boot...
Doesn't seem fair...
But you did... And for real...
He slapped me...
But I gave him the boot...
Everyone's gonna doubt you if you regret what you did!
Doubt me?
We can all doubt you're not all right upstairs.
Mind if I turned in?
No.
I'll call you at night.
And aye...
If you can't sleep,
Write your diary.
Pour your heart out.
It'll give you some peace.
She went to bed.
Take care of her, Aunt.
Take care, love.
Bye.
-Bye.
Let's go, shall we?
Where?
Over to Neelam's.
Why?
Tell her she's agreed.
Ask her again
If she means it.
She announced it out loud.
No room for questions now.
She named Gulrez too.
You wanted her to nod quietly.
But - God bless her - she said his name out loud!
But I wonder what this delay's about.
You call them every other moment.
Here's an idea. I'll call her.
Nano would be delighted!
Wait, Fajr.
Let her wake up.
I'll ask her.
She'd change her decision when she gets up.
Don't waste this chance.
Now that she's said it,
Just break the news to everyone!
Actually...
No need...
Just tell Ammi Begum.
She'll take care of the rest.
You're overstepping your limits, Fajr!
Hey!
My sister's agreed to marry him.
So many people got their wish.
We can finally fulfil our promises.
Our honour's intact.
Can't I be just a bit delighted?
Ohhhh...
I get it...
What?
I get it.
As always, you want to tell Nano yourself.
Lemme call her.
Just a sec.
What happened?
I hope you didn't say anything!
She's just a silly girl.
She's got a mind of her own.
Takes two and two together to get twenty.
Hope you didn't slap her or something.
She's ready.
Ready?
She said yes?
Aye.
At the slight inconvenience of getting a few broken teeth, it's done.
She still said yes?
You all plot here, don't you?
Especially you, Dado...
Life's a bleedin' chessboard to you, isn't it?
Pawn to F7,
Queen takes Rook...
Checkmate.
You just don't want to be on the wrong end of it.
But there's greater grandmasters than you 'round here.
Such as this London tramp.
A loafer, aye. A wastrel, too, aye. But one...
Who's mastered the art of the checkmate with his English roses...
What'd she say?
I'm sure you'd get the news... But tell me...
How d'you intend to tan your hide?
Before I do that,
I'm gonna skin her alive! Claw her eyes out and cut that tongue of hers!
Why?
Why'd you claw her eyes out and cut her tongue
For speaking her heart out?
You seem to have got old blood with love.
I expected no better from you.
I knew the spark that rages within you would burn us all down.
Grab a pew, Dastoor Ahmed...
Enjoy
The heat...
You know Uncle Dastoor enjoying the heat ain't gonna cool you down, Dado!
KNOW YOUR LIMITS!
Hear those who limit the desires of hearts
Cry out, 'Know your limits'!
The times have changed, Dado.
No longer will the Nanos and Dados chain hearts...
Love brings them all to their knees.
Well...
You don't know me, Waqar Ahmed...
I know you inside out, Dado.
You play politics in love.
What are you saying?
-Just a second, Uncle Dastoor...
I ain't even started yet.
Consumed in the intoxication of power,
This so-called lady of 65...
This 75-year-old cow, I say...
Thinks the palaces of love are but sandcastles!
I dare her to take up arms.
She'll be dust in no time.
She'll be dust in no time. Poof!
Aye...
The phone...
Do it nice and proper.
Clean it everyday. I don't want this getting dirty.
And the dust over there! Goodness!
Hello?
Give your Mum the phone.
Mum!
What is it?
Nano...
Aye, Ammi Begum?
Maheen said yes?
Aye.
Where were you?
Right by her.
And Waqar?
With us.
And you looked on quietly?
What could I do?
Slap properly!
Slap who?
The twit who broke everything here to punish that blighter!
Know what,
I wouldn't tire of kissing his face,
Yet even he barked like mad at me today!
He said,
'Consumed in the intoxication of power',
'This 75-year-old cow'
'Thinks the palaces of love are but sandcastles'!
'I dare her to take up arms'!
'She'll be dust in no time'.
'She'll be dust in no time. Poof'!
Why'd he say that?
Because your sweet little girl said yes!
Where's he?
He left when I slapped him.
Good Heavens...
You pitying him?
You would too.
He's been humiliated here too.
Maheen said before him...
That she's ready to marry Gulrez.
There's just one way out.
Kill me one of these days.
Which father in the world
Can leave
His daughter alone in the wild world
And live in peace?
You've got to decide...
Would you rather kill me,
Or listen
To my side of the story someday.
I'm leaving this job, Mademoiselle.
I can't make a girl's father wait outside her door like that.
Don't leave her.
She's
Changed, of late...
She left herself
Without asking me to leave.
If you're done cleaning your Foxy, come inside?
Your cuppa's ready.
Could I have it here?
I'll thank you.
♪ In the tale of love where do these turns come from ♪
♪ That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart ♪
♪ That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart... ♪
I've decided
To marry
Gulrez.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV