C'mon, now, you illywhacker... Put it on her.
Give him your hand already, my girl.
Where's Waqar?
He just left.
Where?
Back where he'd come from.
His flight leaves at 2 a.m.
Hello?
You're leaving?
Maheen?
I asked if you're leaving.
Got engaged?
Stop the car!
Stop the car.
Don't go anywhere, Waqar...
For my sake...
Don't leave me in here...
I want to tell you something...
Especially you, Nano...
I think... I want to tell you, Nano...
But I want everyone else to know...
When you get us engaged as kids...
We're too young...
Too young to know what it means...
What we eat, when we sleep - You decide everything.
We eat even when we're not hungry.
Doze off even when we're not sleepy...
We're so stupid we skive off school for fun...
We realise later that school's more important.
We pray that our teachers get hurt,
Or the city rises up in an insurrection,
Without a care for the living or the dead... We just want the school to close down!
But these wishes, these curses...
They don't really mean anything.
We know what death is.
We know death
As a moment of sorrow and mourning.
But we don't know
What it means to die...
Our life's without any logic.
Fighting for no reason,
Making peace for no reason...
I've heard
I was 10
When you got me engaged to Gulrez.
I'm sure you told me...
I must've been delighted and agreed.
But...
Did any of you ever think
Why I was so happy I agreed?
Who knows, I might just be thinking
That engagements and weddings are more excuses to skive off school!
I'm sure you're all wondering
Why I had to accept it
Just to refuse on the day of the engagement.
In truth...
I've been fighting myself
Until the moment I put on the ring and refused...
I wanted to sacrifice myself for your happiness.
But I lost as the clock struck 12.
My heart, which used to celebrate another day off
10 years ago,
Started beating for someone.
I'm sorry, Neelam...
But it isn't Gulrez.
So it's you...
Maheen's old man... You blighter!
You charred three lives in the searing flames of your desires,
Only to die and escape everything! How convenient!
What'd you think?
Your sins would die with you?
That the record of your sins would be buried with you?
No, Aurangzeb! No...
No...
Your generations
Have to pay for it
Until every score
Has been settled!
HEAR ME IF YOU CAN!
Don't...
Don't cower in your grave thinking
That everyone will forget the seeds you've sown now that you're dust.
Sins are debts, Aurangzeb! DEBTS!
Sins are debts, Aurangzeb.
And the debts of the father
Are to be laid
Upon the children.
AURANGZEB!
Dastoor Ahmed! Go and tell him if he's upstairs
That Ammi Begum ain't going away so quickly!
He better not set foot here until I'm dead!
GO!
I knew in the morning what was going to happen tonight...
Do you know how?
I had to go somewhere in the afternoon.
My Foxy refused to start...
I was like, 'Jesus Christ, mate'...
'You're gonna kill me today'.
For many years now,
That's how
She's told me to stop.
That's her signal.
That's how I know
That it's not the day.
I knew by the afternoon.
But I thought the day would change by midnight, when I'd get engaged...
Hoped, perhaps, that so would my fate...
But Nano...
She's always in a hurry.
She didn't even wait until midnight.
Comforting won't make this sorrow vanish into thin air.
It isn't a cure either
That'd work like a spell on your pat.
If you ask me,
I'm honoured.
I mean,
Just think of it this way...
She's confident
That I can take it.
Go and comfort the one
Who's suffering in someone else's sorrow.
He needs it more than me.
He didn't come here, Ammi Begum.
How will he?
Who could he look in the eye?
Please sit, Ammi Begum.
Cool down and think over it.
I'm a blimmin' fireball right now and you want me to cool down?
Get it through to him!
He better leave the country! Or the city at the very least!
I better not see him while I'm alive!
Jeez...
'Jeez'?
What do you mean?
You're pushing yourself, Ammi Begum.
He's here after ages.
Remember your prayers?
All wasted as far as I care, Dastoor Ahmed.
Now, I pray that I hear the rotter's landed in London.
That's what I think...
He would've landed by tomorrow.
I'm sure he'd think about the family's honour... And your order.
He isn't going, Dastoor Ahmed...
Maheen's silence was enough to stop him.
And now the twit's called out to him.
Come.
Remember this place? From your Mum and Dad's last days?
Oh, I almost miss the Saturday nights, the Sunday mornings! So lively...
Not to mention the cricket matches in the lawn. In the floodlights!
Ammi Begum used to bowl too!
Your Mum and Dad stayed in this room when they were here.
I'm sure it's a bit dusty... It's only cleaned once a year.
And the spiderwebs! But don't worry...
I'll have it cleaned.
That's okay, Munshi Alam... But what next?
Dado would be furious.
That's why I brought you here.
I've saved your life, so to speak.
What do you mean?
She'd kill me if she saw me?
I wouldn't rule that out.
You don't know how much she loves me.
I did... Until yesterday evening.
No idea now.
And the food... What about the food? I don't think anyone would deliver anything here.
Don't worry while I'm here.
Just think about how long you're staying here.
What do you mean?
It's best for you that you leave.
Leave?
Why?
It ain't easy to take up arms against Ammi Begum.
Wait in the lounge outside while I clean the room.
Munshi Alam...
Mind if I ask something?
It wasn't right, was it?
Yeah...
She's been Gulrez's fiancée for years.
We never thought she wouldn't marry him.
And we had absolutely no idea she'd refuse right on the day of the engagement!
I'm sorry...
Sorry?
You're sorry about something?
Aye.
You don't love Maheen?
Don't you love Maheen?
I do.
Why are you sorry, then?
Wait in the lawn.
Okay.
You want to read my diary?
No. Why would I? I thought it'd wake you up.
Is Mum up?
Scared?
I'm scared because she's worried.
Did you talk to him?
Who?
The one you asked to not go anywhere.
Did he leave?
Do you think he'd leave for any English rose in the world?
Nano would fill him with lead.
What about you?
I don't think she'd even consider me worth aiming a gun at...
Fall at her feet when you see her.
She'd move back, call Uncle Dastoor and say,
'Tell her I don't want to see her face, Dastoor Ahmed'!
'She better die... And if she can't, let her know that Kaneez Begum's dead for her'!
What are my options?
In that case...
Seize her hand and say...
'I'm gonna die for real, Nano'!
As if she'd give two hoots.
No. She won't let you die. Focus on finding out about the one you want to live for.
Impossible!
What do you mean? Just call him!
I'd call that loafer?
Aye, fair enough... I'm sure youse twos will be oh-so-shy now...
You said God-knows-what about him, and now you're saying you want to marry him?
By the Lord, I never said that!
Well, maybe you didn't, but we heard it!
I just asked him to stay here.
Does it look good? Leaving the country over a trifle?
That's what everyone's furious about. You think the engagement was a trifle.
Call him, pinhead! Ask him how well he can cheat death!
It's all your fault!
I nearly put the ring on!
If you put the ring on, I wouldn't have let you take it off.
And that's the only good thing about the scene last night - you not wearing the ring.
I'm sure you broke many hearts. But if you'd taken it off after wearing it, it might've killed someone.
I've been thinking all night...
What would've they gone through?
The one I stopped...
And the one I let go of?
Just see him once.
I'm sure you'd be a bit ashamed, but try not to look like it.
Many would've comforted him, but he won't find peace until he's met you.
And... Don't be afraid even if someone pointed a gun at your head.
Don't give in to anyone's tears.
You don't have or ask for mercy in love.
And don't come to the table for breakfast while Mum's around.
Why?
Because there's knives, forks, and china plates.
Hey...
When do I see him?
Who?
Gulrez.
Try to see him today.
What do I tell him?
Do I have to tell you? You're one weird girl.
Just say... 'If that's what was destined for us'...
Destined?
I'm sure he's heard the old
'Matches are made in Heaven'.
Ah, lovely excuse...
There's no better excuse than destiny when you're helpless.
I just wish he understands...
May he not curse me.
Then just go and beg, 'Please don't curse me, Gulrez'!
By the way...
You don't need to chant any incantations or say anything to curse.
If you see him tormented, crying, just think he's cursing.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV