Who could it be?
Maheen, of course.
So soon?
Maheen?
I look lovely, don't I?
What about the birthday?
Still celebrating...
Maybe done by now.
Blimey... Here!
I'm starving!
Wait, Maheen.
What happened there?
Why are you back?
What could I do?
He was there.
Waqar?
Aye.
What's your problem with him?
That's what I'm thinking.
What's my problem?
I don't know, but there is something...
The sight of him...
Gives me the creeps!
I hid the moment I saw him. And the moment Jiya saw him...
I came back sharpish.
Mmm!
Lovely!
Whoa...
What?
There's Gulrez.
He fears her.
Then there's her.
She fears Waqar.
She's lying.
She doesn't fear anyone.
♪ Happy birthday to you! ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Jiya! ♪
That wastes my shopping.
How?
I wouldn't be caught dead there. Not with you around!
Waqar!
I'm okay, thanks.
There's no party without you!
I'll send everyone back.
I'm giving you 30 minutes. If you don't come, I'm sending your Maheen back.
Pity her, Gulrez.
If she's back on the road, don't think she won't stop again.
You're just a bit jealous, aren't you?
Curse the one who'd be jealous of your love for your Foxy.
Just say what you want to, Wali Ahmed.
You're just furious at your own car
To see the Foxy go full steam ahead!
I'm furious at you.
You know how far we've gone?
I thought
You loved long drives?
Not in a donkey cart!
Someone's jealous!
Quickly...
If this bugger stops again, it'll be your loss!
Loss?
My foot.
Care to ask what's your loss?
Alright.
Go on.
Neelam's going to her place.
Whose?
Tell him.
I'm going to Maheen's.
I want to sort everything out.
Why'd you stop the car?
Why'd you talk to her?
Because you never will!
My fault.
I'll suffer for it.
No.
Not at all.
I won't take any help
In my battles.
I went to talk to her yesterday.
If I couldn't, it doesn't mean I wouldn't.
I will.
One day.
I give you two days.
Last and final.
If you couldn't, you will let me handle it my way.
Two days?
Want some more?
How much?
What are you saying, mate?
It's quite a lot, frankly.
It's 10! Where are you folks?
She's still sleeping.
She's growing old...
No. Just angry.
She likes to sleep her anger off.
No idea why we depend on such a good-for-nothing to live our lives.
Can it. She's our Chief.
We'd decided to do as the Chief says.
To get angry or sleep it off...
It's her choice!
So no cricket today?
We're playing.
Just one player less. It happens.
Okay.
I'll call Gulrez.
Isn't she coming?
No.
She's sleeping.
Blimey...
Look at the time.
Let her.
We're playing without her.
What's a good game without her?
The London tramp's gonna knock us for six!
D'you know
He's been practicing since daybreak, the blighter!
Practicing?
Call Gulrez...
I'll do something to rouse that twit.
I thought I told you we're playing today.
What are you doing with the newspaper?
Heavens...
Put that down, Munshi Alam!
And -- Get to the ground.
As you say.
15 minutes. Skim through the headlines.
Read the rest after we've lost.
Okay.
Bless you.
You're okaying as if you're sure we've lost this.
It's Ali, Gulrez!
Hello?
Hello.
How are you, matey?
Fine...
Why'd you run off last night?
You didn't even tell me!
Had to. He got there!
He wasn't coming.
I got him to come.
I thought you'd make peace.
We've made peace.
He said sorry.
Hey!
You secret squirrels!
Didn't even tell me!
I just did.
It was just yesterday.
Feel good?
What?
Making peace, making friends...
Friends?
Put a sock in it!
He's not worth it!
Think again, matey...
You don't really know, do you?
I don't even want to discuss him.
I think you just want to discuss him.
Did you call me to say that load of guff?
I swear not...
You didn't accept Gulrez's proposal yet...
So I thought you've got something going on...
Not until after Doomsday!
Get it?
Keep up with that arrogance and someone else will get her hands on him!
The twit...
The handsome twit...
The lovely twit...
The mellifluous twit...
Why don't you get your hands on him? He even listens to your earfuls!
You mean it?
I said it.
I meant it.
He's all yours, for all I care.
Lemme know if you get your hands on him. We'll celebrate together!
Maheen!
It's Nano!
I'll get back to you. Nano's calling...
Bye!
Bye.
C'mon!
Gulrez!
Aye, Gulrez!
Ugh!
Ow!
Close!
Gulrez! Maheen!
-Good show!
Go for a four!
Can't you say 'six'?
Ever seen him hit one?
Besides,
He's bowling!
Who?
Which namby-pamby sissy's got the guts?
C'mon.
Show me what you've got!
That's one wicket down!
No, Nano.
Not this time.
Close, aye...
Lovely, Dado...
What's this?
What?
You turned away the moment the ball touched the wicket!
Couldn't help it...
Couldn't see it.
Never thought our umpire's gonna be so biased.
What was that?
Why'd I be biased against you?
If I were, I could just ask Maheen, you know.
Okay.
Okay...
Just a minute, Nano!
Who swings up towards the air to hit a four?
I thought a six would delight you.
A four will do just as well...
If you can actually hit one!
Suraiyya...
Would you look at that?
They're seeing each other at last!
Okay.
Alright.
I'll hit a four.
You'll see, Skip.
Out!
-Yeah!
Woo hoo!
Wicket?
Aye.
Wicket.
Aye...
That was a ball for a six. But you told me to go for a four.
You couldn't hit anything but a six on it!
Aye.
Thank you.
But don't worry, Cap'n.
The bowling's easy.
Aye, I know.
Easier than yours!
C'mon already!
Don't be furious at him!
Well played, mate.
That's one wicket down... Blimey...
Wali... Take it easy, okay?
No hurries, okay?
Maheen!
Wali!
You better save our honour!
Hey...
Good...
Run!
Good!
YEAH!
YEEHAW!
Whew!
Four!
Yeah!
Good!
-Lovely!
Good show!
Wait.
For you.
Not now!
Take it, m'boy...
Or she'll hit another four.
So...
Who is it?
It's...
Jiya.
It's Jiya, love...
The poor girl must be dying to hear from you.
I don't want to talk to her!
Alright...
Back to the game...
Let her score another four...
C'mon...
WOO HOO!
Now's your chance! She's out too!
What?
She -- Out?
Aye.
Perfect chance indeed...
We lost the match... More or less...
You're worried about the match?
So...?
Talk to her!
Blimey...
She takes the match more seriously than me...
She'd clobber me head with her bat if I talked to her now.
What's the score?
You'd be left scratching your head.
Gee...
She's out for a duck too?
She was pulling me up like she's won the blimmin' World Cup!
Don't worry. I'll talk to her...
You're still here?
Come!
Double time!
Look...
32 runs ain't really a doddle.
Don't lose hope just yet.
I won't.
Once Ali's out...
It'll only leave him...
I can take care of the rest on my own.
You ought to be the one to bowl Waqar out.
Why?
Don't you want to get even? He bowled you out!
Don't you want to get even? He bowled you out too!
Aye, but...
I can't settle any scores...
Less talk, more bowling!
That London tramp deserves to be bowled out by your hand!
Get even.
Take the blighter's wicket!
Battlestations!
You can do it, Gulrez!
Alright, alright... C'mon...
Here.
C'mon, Gulrez!
Throw a short pitch!
Yay!
WOO HOO!
Lovely!
YEAH!
WOO HOO!
YEE HAW!
But you asked for a short pitch!
I was cheating...
Wanted to trick him.
I'd told Gulrez to bowl a yorker when I say short pitch!
Wow, someone's getting very clever!
Alright, next!
C'mon!
Okay...
Alright...
Here!
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon! Double time!
Good show, Gulrez!
He's got a point.
Are you gonna plan for seven hours to save seven runs?
Just send a good bowler.
Save your victory.
Or... Consider the match lost.
(Let 'em...)
What was that?
I'm bowling this time.
Whoa...
Can you guarantee
You won't let them score seven runs?
I can try.
I can't guarantee that.
Well, then, stay outside the pitch!
C'mon!
C'mon, Waqar!
-Seven runs!
Just seven runs! Just seven!
Aye, seven runs!
Next.
C'mon.
Keep at it for the next five balls and we've got this!
I told you not to come here.
I'm not here to see you.
I got some gifts
For your birthday.
I'm here to give you these.
Take them and I'll leave.
My birthday's long gone.
I don't need any gifts now.
Please, leave.
Please, love...
Just take these...
And throw them in the trash if you want...
Just... Don't kick me out like that...
No way.
You'll regret it one day
Like I regret today.
You
You wait
You wait and
You wait and watch,
You wait and watch, Mir
You wait and watch, Mir Mehtab
You wait and watch, Mir Mehtab Ahmed...
I won't regret it one bit.
I'll settle the scores with everyone who's guilty.
I settled a few scores too.
That's what I regret today.
Because settling scores
Only suits God.
Not me, not you, not anyone.
Shugufta!
Take these gifts
And throw them in the trash!
Now, if you'll excuse me...
Move it!
C'mon, c'mon!
Yes!
Someone seems too scared...!
Way to go, Maheen! He fears you!
Why are you here?
Just get in the car for a minute.
No way, Jiya, they're all in the lawn! You want to create a scene?
You getting in or do I need to go in?
-Hey!
Just... Abducting you!
C'mon!
Move it already!
What's the meaning of this?
It's only fair!
So...
We won the match!
We didn't?
We didn't.
Someone go call him.
Who knows where he's gone!
Bet they're all thinking I've run off with you.
We were playing for 10 blasted gee and just one ball away from victory! My honour was at stake!
I can see that, but...
Who are you playing?
Maheen.
Told you we had a match today.
You two make quite a match...!
We do?
Aunt, Ali, Fajr and all the rest are playing!
But it's really between the two of you, no?
All I need to know, folks,
Is where he left for in such a hurry.
Surely, he doesn't know any sorcery or some such thing
That he'd cast a spell and vanish into thin air.
I mean, just a minute later,
Munshi Alam went after him...
But the knockoff wizard wasn't around anywhere!
Bet he's scared of Maheen.
Did you see Maheen's bowling?
It'd take an Alec James Stewart to face her!
Brendon McCullum, more like.
Aye,
How'd I forget him?
I always heard of him as a player...
Until...
That knockoff wizard showed up on the pitch
And vanished!
Oh, he didn't vanish.
He'd just run back to the dressing room.
But what about him?
Where could he have gone?
Gorblimey
For having this most queer thought...
But how long
Is the blasted flight to London?
Seven hours.
He got to the airport
In two hours
And got on the plane...
What d'you mean?
I mean
He'd call you in about ten hours
And say, 'Something came up. Had to dash to London'.
Why don't you say something?
What're you gawpin' at?
No idea, Nano...
I respect him a lot.
Don't speak English!
It's okay...
He's forgiven for this one mistake...
But still...
He spelt doom for your victory as he left.
Just say something in your anger!
May I?
Aye, go on.
Technically, we've won the match.
You can read the ICC's rules if you want.
Innit, Wali?
There, now...
Where's Bakhshi?
What can he tell you?
That ne'er-do-well doesn't know a thing about cricket.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Don't you like it?
What?
Like what?
Snatching you away.
No way, mate.
Just... It was quite the match.
Now I'm pretty sure they're thinking there's something going on between us.
Isn't there?
Ehh?
There's nothing between us?
Jiya...
You're joking, right?
You're not serious, are you?
I'm very serious, Waqar.
Uncle Bakhshi!
Aye?
-Here...
Come here.
Ma'am.
What'd you say to Waqar Ahmed?
Waqar Ahmed?
You know, the one you whispered something to?
What'd you tell him?
Ah, him.
Mlle Jiya rang up the intercom
And said she's outside.
She asked me to tell Waqar
That if he didn't come out in two minutes,
She's coming in
To drag him along for everyone to see.
♪ Love's testimony is not to be asked of it... ♪
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV