In that case, I admit that I love you.
I can't pay the bill; I left my wallet at home.
Don't worry.
I'll pay the bill.
Muck!
He hasn't lost the match.
The blighter's lost his heart.
Hey.
Do I look like I'm lying?
I swear, I'm trying to forget his disappearance
And think about his running away.
Remember how he darted?
Just...
Like Runaway Groom, you get it?
Anyway.
That's one quandary sorted out.
Quandary?
As in?
He's found someone too.
He's not like that.
Then what's he like?
Blow me pink!
So you'd tell Kaneez Begum who's like what!
Do you see my hair?
Aye.
The greys reflect experience.
I knew it when the lad ran
Where he was headed.
He won't go there.
I can give it in writing.
It's not as if these blacks reflect inexperience.
Have some shame, you're talking to Ammi Begum.
Please don't intervene; we're having a Gang meeting.
Aye.
Stay out of it.
We're all equals in the Gang.
And you, Chief?
What do you think?
I also knew when the lad ran
Where he was headed.
What did she say as she left?
The same as you.
No, my dear.
I meant something else entirely.
Anyway.
The meeting is adjourned.
I like one thing about you.
You're a boy, yet you don't believe in part-time affairs.
By George!
You're from London, aren't you?
I used to live in London,
But I'm back now.
So,
Didn't you have affairs there?
To be frank, there sure was this itch in the beginning.
Then, it was almost as if someone had whispered to me,
'Love the one you talk love to'.
'Don't besmirch the name of love with your "affairs".'
And I never use this term 'love affair'.
I think
Affairs can never be love
And love can never be an affair.
Sit down.
Jiya...
What's the time? I think I'm getting late.
Are you a girl?
Girls in Pakistan talk like this.
'It's getting late',
'Dad will be back',
'Please let me go'.
I like your sense of humour.
Maheen will never understand.
What?
That you don't despise her.
Come on, mate.
I don't despise her; she despises me.
I could've hit a six on the first ball.
But I just kept on batting through her balls.
I just want her to win, but
I don't want her to despise me.
She doesn't despise you, Waqar.
She loves you.
Shut up, mate.
If she starts loving me, Gulrez's curses will kill me.
It just can't be.
If she's forgiven one murder, she'd kill me right away.
And you?
If you're forgiven one murder, who would you kill?
Don't even think about it.
I can't even kill an ant.
You just did.
I said something trivial and you crushed this ant under its weight...
Blimey...
Anyway, tell me...
If you're convinced that Maheen doesn't love you,
Who would you love?
What's this guff?
Tell me.
Would you love someone?
Of course, mate.
I'm just waiting, Jiya.
And you know what,
I get a feeling that love is in the air...
Who is it?
I just got this feeling...
Not the name.
I think
She's headed for me.
I think you don't believe it.
I believe it.
Alright then.
No more conversations about Maheen.
And I can give it in writing, it can never be Maheen.
I mean she's Gulrez's.
Maheen!
Listen to me.
I'm not having an affair with Jiya.
Why are you telling me?
Thought you ought to know.
Listen...
I don't give a hoot what you do or don't do.
But aye, I'd like to tell you one thing -
If you make a place for yourself in a girl's heart, learn to stay there.
You don't learn this so easily in London,
But girl's hearts are not leaseholds
That you can leave at your leisure.
Sometimes, I'm afraid of you, Gulrez.
Why?
Dad said,
'When he turns 24, get him married'.
Why are you smiling?
Because I'm 25.
And you'll be 26 this December.
And 27 the next December.
So d'you want me to just keep counting years?
Tell me.
What can I do?
Talk to Maheen today itself
Or look for another girl.
Why --
Why is Wali here reading a book?
What's it to you if he's reading here?
Everything's according to a plan, right?
Wali doesn't usually read here.
You scallywag!
Why are you dragging me in?
That's quite the mouthful.
Now he's going to start too.
But please let me finish it by saying one thing.
I haven't got a second option.
Okay.
But what if
She's got one?
Big deal, bud!
We'll attend her wedding.
Dancing, singing, feasting all the way!
What else d'you want?
And you won't get married.
Blooming Mark Antony!
I'll convince her.
Tomorrow, if not today; if not tomorrow --
-Never. If not tomorrow, never.
Not a moment after tomorrow.
Convince her
Or give me a second option.
See?
I didn't utter a word.
Maheen...
I'm not having an affair with Jiya.
Mlle Jiya rang up the intercom
And said she's outside.
She asked me to tell Waqar
That if he didn't come out in two minutes,
She's coming in...
Read them?
Aye.
There's countless more.
Tell me, what do I do?
It's simple.
Just tell him to talk to Maheen.
And get married to her.
It's no joke.
I agree
But what's happening is a complete farce.
We're surrounded by threats.
You're his sister.
You claim to know him well.
But the truth is
I know him far better than you.
We laugh at his love for his Foxy.
Deep down, we don't laugh.
We're ashamed
That our commitment to love isn't as pure.
He'd die for Maheen,
And you create this illusion of another girl to keep him alive
Trying to change his heart.
But he knows only too well
That you can only love one.
And her name is Maheen Aurangzeb.
None but her.
Love is an affliction...
This vaurien often seeks a place
Where it is de trop.
I have always learnt something new from him.
Sometimes,
Loving like him,
And sometimes, beaming in pain like him,
And sometimes...
Weeping like him,
Without the trace of a tear in the eyes...
I'm afraid of him, Neelam.
People like him
Always get love,
But rarely, if ever,
The one they love.
How can it be anger over the match?
Dado had said that Maheen's team won.
So?
What's she angry about?
Your little escapade with Jiya
Probably that.
I think she's angry because you left the match and ran away.
But Fajr has another point of view.
Scares you, doesn't it?
Aye.
Why did you have to ruffle her then?
What with just two balls left?
You could've just played 'em... Gone for the sixes!
Before going for her.
Anyways what's done's been done.
Tell her --
We can play again today.
Forget the chance of her playing cricket with you.
Maheen Aurangzeb doesn't play cricket with deserters.
I'm sorry but that's her line.
Alright.
As if I'm too interested!
Watch what you say.
Who knows, someone might just tell her.
Who will tell her? Who's here except you?
Why, I would, of course.
I can't keep a secret for more than two days.
Get up.
Get up,
Get out.
I said get up!
Big mistake!
Asking the Chief's right hand man to get out?
Meh!
Sir 'Chief's right hand'!
Sissy's wimpish skivvy.
Bog off!
You're taking me lightly.
Wait.
Now you're talking.
Wh --
What'd Fajr say?
Why's she angry?
Nothing, really.
She was just guessing.
But you know what?
Maheen says,
Between the two of us, Fajr's the less intelligent!
Oh.
Go, now!
♪ Ain't nobody ♪
♪ Loves me better ♪
♪ Makes me happy ♪
♪ Makes me feel this way ♪
♪ Ain't nobody ♪
♪ Loves me better ♪
Hi!
What brings you here?
The same as you.
Oh really. I come here everyday.
What am I seeing today?
My thoughts brought you here?
You think of those who have become distant.
I see you around here every now and then.
C'mon.
Good morning!
Good morning.
Where's Mum?
She left for Nano's.
But today's Sunday!
It's not about Sunday.
It's because she took Waqar along.
Your Jiya.
So Nano's thought
About both of them.
What?
She said, 'The girl's nice and beautiful'.
'Why not get the couple married'?
What happened?
What could happen?
I was thinking --
Jiya's so nice...
And Waqar's a proper London tramp.
It doesn't quite fit.
Whether it fits or not, they love each other!
They don't; I know.
Jiya's not interested in him.
She's just -- his friend.
How long does it take for a friend to become a wife?
It takes just one attempt.
Attempt?
Just one 'I love you', Sherlock!
What else do you call it?
Oh.
Let them get married.
As if I give a hoot.
I know it very well.
Honestly, Jiya and Waqar look wonderful together.
That's good.
That's two weddings this season.
It's gonna be so fun!
Who's the other one?
You, of course.
Shut up!
Why? Won't you get married?
And if so, why don't you tell everyone?
Why are you standing here like that?
What?
'Standing here like this'?
You blabbering blighter!
Pull my leg all you want.
You're just proving your friendship with her.
Sorry mate.
You took it seriously.
Not me; she's serious, you twit.
About who?
You?
Jiya, please. Don't start.
This isn't a time for jokes.
I'm not joking.
She's engaged to Gulrez. He'd die for her!
That witch is after me like crazy!
You say it like you don't deserve it!
Do you even know what happened?
I do.
You slapped her.
And she told the world about it!
No idea about the world.
But I'm her closest friend. I know everything.
Jiya... I thought you were sensible.
'Thought'?
I mean, if you knew everything,
Why didn't you tell her how wrong she was?
Easy, mate. Kids make mistakes.
Kids?
As if she was an infant four years ago!
It's been four years but she remembers it as if it was just yesterday!
What are you looking at?
Mind if I ask you something?
Not at all.
Do you feel bad that she still remembers the slap,
Or that she ignores you?
Excuse me, who is she?
What do I care if she ignores me?
Dado's emboldened her, or...
Or?
Or another slap would bring her back to her senses.
Really?
Lemme vent it out in words, mate...
Loser!
She may be a bit on the impish side...
A bit on the rowdy side, too...
Our Maheen's on the rowdy side too...
Plus, she's Maheen's friend...
She looks good.
I think...
She'd do.
Do what?
There, now...
She'd do for Waqar like you did for Mehrunnisa.
Oh...
So that's what it's about.
What do you think?
Whatever you think.
I didn't ask you.
I'm asking Suraiyya and Mehrunnisa.
I say she'd do.
And guess who's here!
Come here.
Hiya, Dado.
Good morning to you, too.
Tea?
You'll get anything you want, m'lad.
In fact...
You'd even get
Whoever you want.
Why are we talking about that?
We're just talking about her...
You've been seeing her, meeting her, my dear...
Just...
Tell me
If you've had the talk.
What talk?
Oh, nothing, just the gewgaws of marriage...
Whose marriage?
Splendid.
My lad's learnt acting in London.
Dado...
Oh, please...
Let me talk.
Give me her address.
You'd better. Or I'll ask Maheen.
Ask her what?
Please, Dado, tell me something.
She's talking about Jiya.
Dastoor Ahmed!
Alright...
Now that it's in the open,
Give me her address and number.
Let me talk to her
Before her parents.
What'll you talk about?
Is that coyness
Or you trying to fool everyone?
Dado, by the L --
-Don't swear.
I like her.
I've even looked at your stars.
Seen the omens, too.
It's a match made in Heaven.
Are you even hearing what you say?
When did I say I want to marry Jiya?
So are you just gadding about with her?
You think Karachi's anything like London, you twit?
It is how it is.
When a girl would be caught enjoying herself with someone,
The elders would get her married to him.
In short,
You've been caught.
'Caught'? If she's my friend -- and she grabbed my hand -- you'd say I've been 'caught gadding about'?
No!
I'm not the type!
So?
No way I'm marrying Jiya.
Who, then?
Anyone but Jiya.
Hold on to the railing.
Keep your eyes closed. Don't peek.
I'm not.
Step up onto the railing.
Why was Nano rubbing her hands?
I didn't ask.
Ali just said she started rubbing her hands when it was all over.
Her face was drained of all colour.
Splendid...
Turn up the volume.
No.
Let me think.
If he says he won't marry Jiya...
What's the problem?
He must be after some English rose.
He'd marry her.
Aye. That's why Ammi Begum's troubled.
Hey!
What's wrong with that?
He can bring his English rose if he wants.
It's all about the heart, Fajr.
It's all about Ammi Begum's honour, Maheen.
Ammi Begum's as good as dead if he brought his English rose.
How come?
Wouldn't she die if she heard English all day?
She'd much rather kill someone!
Honestly, though,
If he wasn't interested in Jiya,
Why was he dating her?
Hey! She's his friend.
Oh, please.
Boys and girls are never just friends.
Oh?
Never knew you were so conservative.
Let me tell you.
Those who tell the truth are conservative.
Boys are always ready to prowl in 'friendship'.
The moment her guard's down, she goes down.
Call Jiya.
Why?
Ask her
What she'd do if Waqar proposed to her.
She'd accept it, of course.
Let's just ask her.
Give me the phone.
The number you've dialled is busy...
It's busy.
Bet she's talking to him.
We were on the plane together. Had a chat, became friends.
And?
We know about your friendship.
Go on.
Go on about what?
Haven't fallen in love yet, eh?
No!
But of course...
He must've told you he's in touch with the ladies of London.
He isn't in touch with anyone.
He's your ordinary boy-next-door.
He just says that to tease you.
Look...
You better tell me the truth.
I'm very happy.
Otherwise...
Please, be happy.
He's very good.
If he is...
Marry him.
I swear, you look so good with him.
What are you saying?
I'm playing matchmaker.
But he never --
I mean...
It never felt that...
The blighter's like the East India Company.
Who could see they were here to plunder everything?
I just caught him red-handed.
I could see he's got his eyes on you.
So,
Who have you got with you?
My Dad.
Give me his number.
I need to see him tomorrow.
No, Ammi Begum. It's nothing like that.
Did you ask him?
Tell me about yourself.
What do you think?
Ask him first.
If he agrees,
So will I.
Then, let me tell you.
I accept it on his behalf.
Give me your Dad's number.
You can't believe it, can you?
Not at all.
I'm coming with the ring tomorrow.
I'll put it on you myself!
You would?
Have some shame, dear. Back in our day, Mums and Grannies used to do these things.
I'll give you his number.
Promise me...
You'll bring him.
You may put the ring on me,
But do so before him.
Alright.
I promise you. I'll put the ring on you before him.
So,
Tell me what you say.
I'll send you the number.
Dastoor Ahmed!
Mehrunnisa! Where are you?
Over here!
I've got news.
What happened, Ammi Begum?
Everything alright?
Not just alright!
Take a seat.
You may just trip and fall if you heard it.
She said yes.
Who?
Why don't you ask me?
Yes, Ammi Begum?
Who?
Jiya.
What did she say yes to?
The proposal about her and Waqar's marriage!
As if theirs is any match!
What's that guff?
He was swearing
That he isn't interested in Jiya.
He won't marry Jiya.
Is he having second thoughts?
He won't, Ammi Begum.
He was stressing it so much.
I understood him.
Over there.
He's coming.
Ask him yourself.
See whether he stands firm or agrees to marry Jiya.
Wait a minute, my sweetie.
Come here.
Let me give you the news too.
Aye?
Talked to Jiya?
I mean...
Didn't she call you?
She did.
She's been calling for the last 15 minutes.
So, m'lad, just talk to her, will you?
Must be something important.
Nobody tries continuously for 15 minutes for nothing.
When did she grow so much on you?
She's such a close friend of Maheen's.
That makes her
Just like Maheen to me.
Good night.
Not so fast, you twit.
Spouting English and running away, eh?
We're going to her place tomorrow.
And...
Here's her Dad's number.
I've asked for her hand in marriage.
I'll talk to her Dad tomorrow and formalise it.
If he accepts the proposal,
I'll put the ring on her myself!
Before you.
You may do it yourself if you want.
I won't mind it one bit.
What in the world is your problem?
What do you think I am?
A blimming circus-monkey who'd dance to your tunes?
Do you think I'd start loving Jiya because you ordered me to?
That I'd marry her if you put a ring on her?
As if hearts beat
Or love by your will!
When I said I won't marry Jiya, I mean I won't!
Are we clear?
Ammi Begum!
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV