Done, done, done!
I'd say you
Head for Dado's; we'll get ready and come.
Okay.
See you.
Bye.
May I go?
Why not? Go.
Listen!
Up there
On the writing table
Is Maheen's diary.
I think
She forgot to keep it in the drawer.
Please,
Don't read it.
Who knows what it may conceal!
Come on, mate.
I don't read others' diaries.
Well,
May nobody read the diary of one
Who's accused of loving someone else.
And don't even touch
Your enemy's diary!
Otherwise, friendship with her will be impossible.
Alright,
Bye.
Have to dash!
It's a love marriage,
Innit?
What does it look like?
It's 100% a love marriage.
Someone must've told you.
No?
Not at all.
Nobody told me.
How do you know, then?
It's etched
On the girl's face.
If you ask her to close her eyes,
She opens them repeatedly.
Why?
She doesn't quite believe it, I think,
And she tries to see it again
To believe it.
Even if you tell her a good joke,
She says, 'Hmm... What was that'?
And she's chuffed to have someone
Who'd get her decked up quickly!
And she starts laughing
Like you are every now and then.
You're almost ready.
In just a moment, now, you...
Here, Nano.
The bride's jewellery.
Come here, let me kiss your forehead.
May you live long.
On the writing table
Is Maheen's diary.
I think
She forgot to keep it in the drawer.
Please,
Don't read it.
Who knows what it may conceal!
Well,
May nobody read the diary of one
Who's accused of loving someone else.
And don't even touch
Your enemy's diary!
Is it that Gulrez loves me,
Or that he worships me?
I start to question myself
If I'd ever be able to take such love.
Please, Gulrez,
Keep on loving me.
In time, I'll learn to take it.
Neelam told me today
That you'd purchased a bindiya [ornament] for me.
I smiled coyly to myself for long.
What are you made of, Gulrez,
Remembering every single detail like you do?
That muppet, that Londoner tramp,
He's landed in Karachi.
Looking at him, I'm reminded of his slap.
There is but one thing my heart longs for,
And that is the day when I'd get even with him.
In the tale of love where do these turns come from
That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart
Why are you smiling?
These looks could kill
Anybody unfortunate enough to meet your gaze!
You look so sweet!
My gaze would only meet his today.
It'll be like an offering unto him.
Dastoor!
Come here.
Yes, Ammi Begum?
The Reverend is going over the top of the dishes, gorbing everything he can.
Call the nincompoop,
Ask him to come here with the procession.
Alright.
Listen,
-Yes?
Just say what I've told you, and not a word beyond it. Go, now.
Alright, Ammi Begum.
There, now!
Would you look at this wee lassie!
The filly's showing up now!
Go!
Why are you quiet?
You're quiet.
That's why.
I don't know why, Ali,
But my heart grows restless.
Doesn't it?
What do you mean?
My heart grows restless too.
Would you like some water?
Yes.
I'll get some.
Splendid!
Just as the Lord has willed!
Come on.
Don't tarry too much.
As if I have to deck up like a bride, mate!
Just give me 15 minutes,
And I'll be ready.
Let's see...
Make it quick.
It'll take a while, Uncle,
He's dressing up like the groom.
He'll make haste only if you ask him to,
The Reverend over here is going over the top of the dishes, gorbing everything he can.
Sir,
Where's the loo?
This way.
What's there this way, Uncle?
I'm not saying it to you, mate!
Go, Reverend, the loo's this way.
Waqar!
This phone is switched off.
Waqar, please answer me.
Your phone's switched off too!
Waqar, everyone's waiting over there!
Waqar!
Waqar?
Dear Maheen,
It has been a pleasure
That this chapter of our love began,
And we fell in love;
Such love that you agreed to marry me.
Splendid.
Does one wager oneself in one's quest for revenge?
I could've taken two slaps from you had you just said it;
Why did you have to play this elaborate game just to avenge one slap?
Do you have any idea how many people here love you?
There are many besides Gulrez who adore you with all their lives.
Take Ammi Begum, for instance,
She'd kick her sense of justice away when it'd come to you.
Aunt Suraiyya,
Your mother,
Do you have any idea how many woes she's gone through?
And your sister Fajr,
She always kept guessing you'd fallen for me!
You silly girl,
At least you could've thought of Gulrez, if none of them.
He kept writhing in love like an animal to be sacrificed,
And kept on doing what you wanted him to.
Honestly,
Is he in on this one?
He doesn't seem the type, though.
He's very simple.
He endures sorrow,
But never gives one any.
I thought for long before I threw away the sherwani about what it was --
What were you up to?
At first, it occurred to me
That I should let the vaudeville commence,
But then thought
That if, amidst this vaudeville, we got espoused, your face would be smirched by my name.
Gulrez has done me so many favours
That I find it improper that he should get to wear what I shall take off.
I'm leaving.
I won't be coming back.
And listen,
Never before had I wished that you should taste defeat by my hand,
But my heart says that I should leave you bitterly defeated today,
And show you, Maheen, that to triumph in the name of love,
One has to yield.
I depart a victor,
And I say this as I leave,
'Bless you'
'With this closing checkmate'.
What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance
After eight long years, I'm hearing
The rathe shuffling of your footsteps...
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
Just like this, you used to come eagerly, hying --
As if you'd trample everyone under your feet...
In the tale of love where do these turns come from
That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart
Inheritance --
If word got out
That he may get a share --
Perhaps he'll pay a visit...
Neelam...
He's here, Nano.
Only I get the news.
Whenever he comes here,
The cacti in Nano's lawn blossom.
Oh God!
You'd left,
But
Left here a barren,
Desolate world.
Woeful faces,
Startled eyes,
Hearts beating and stopping;
It was feared
That Ammi Begum
May not be able to take this sorrow,
But
Her little games of cricket served her well.
She'd known
That the player can get bowled
Even
On a ball he could've easily scored a four on.
By the way, your wound's alright now.
You think it's alright.
I feel like an old wound's been opened again.
Munshi Alam,
May I ask you something?
Why did Neelam throw a pebble at me?
Apparently, she couldn't find anything better.
She
Saw you outside the graveyard, didn't she?
What else
Could she find there besides a pebble?
What should I prepare for dinner?
Nothing. I'm not hungry.
You're not right now.
Soon, you will be.
What, now, does the stomach know about serious wounds?
Ammi Begum
Didn't have anything for two days, too.
I don't know how long
The others starved themselves.
They started eating again, soon.
Just like they always used to.
They used to laugh,
Have a right merrymaking...
And play cricket, too?
No.
Nobody there plays cricket now.
So did the pebble strike him,
Or did you just pick one up and fling it towards him?
Hit him right on his forehead, Ammi Begum.
Blood gushed out like a fountain before my eyes.
Stop it, Nano...
Let me
Have a good laugh, you wee lassie!
It's about time the rapscallion's reckoning began.
It delights me to hear
That the reprobate is getting sentenced,
And the sentence is being carried out in the present instant itself!
Didn't he say anything in return?
No.
He just kept staring at me, wide-eyed.
The esurient lad!
Look at how he came here, running, the moment I signed the will;
Otherwise,
He'd been in hiding for eight long years.
I've given him half the property from Suraiyya and Fatima's share
Of the bequeathal.
I thought Mashood Ahmed may ask me when I go up there,
Now,
You can't send photocopies up there, otherwise, I'd shove one in his face, saying,
'The piece of land that goes to your son'
'Is one where cacti blossom, Mashood Ahmed'!
Has he brought his wife and children along?
He was alone there, Nano.
He must be staying at one of those hotels...
Ask Dastoor to send him the will,
And say, 'It'll take time for Kaneez Begum to die'.
Everything shall be divided after my death.
His accursed self will be before my Maheen's eyes.
Give him his share of the money and kick him on the back, saying,
'Begone'!
'Go back to where you came from'!
In your place, I'd blooter him!
But I wouldn't be there...
What happened that night?
Tell me, what happened that night?
When?
The night of the wedding.
When I'd left.
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
In the tale of love
In the tale of love where do these turns come from
That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart
Did you see that?
Even as Judgement Day approaches,
The expressions of companionship don't change.
'Expression'
Is an English word, Ammi Begum.
Shut up, Dastoor Ahmed.
Look over there.
She cares for the birds even to this day.
The twit has no idea
They'd fly away the moment they get the opportunity to.
She was saying,
'Ammi Begum's fine now'.
'I'll be leaving shortly'.
What's it to me?
I'll fall ill again!
Come.
Here.
I had my reason for leaving her, Munshi Alam.
I have evidence for everything.
You have but regret.
Perfidy has no reason, and
Regret has no evidence.
I'm dying, Munshi Alam.
You just feel you're dying.
I've seen
Those who die.
They quieten,
Are petrified,
And forget even to blink.
Today,
You shall get a certified copy of the will.
You
May leave before nightfall,
Otherwise,
One of these days, I may say to you in person that I
Find your very existence
Miasmic.
Talk to me, Munshi Alam.
Please, talk to me.
Tell me what happened that night.
You're under Dado's oath.
Have a bit more.
I'm leaving, Nano...
Go.
Start running faster.
Once you've learnt to speak loudly,
For once,
Come here
And show me.
I would like to
Capture that moment in my eyes.
It's not an order, Chief,
Just my wish.
Alright, Uncle.
I'll be back, Ammi Begum.
Whatever is it
That I should bless you with, my dear?
He kept looking for a trace
Of where you were.
The clock struck 10.
There were so many calls from Kaneez Mahal,
He
Answered one with uncertainty,
And didn't answer a handful.
And when Dr Imran told him
That he's left,
He made a run for it.
Everybody over at Kaneez Mahal had their suspicions,
But
Everyone played their part in the pasquinade.
Looking at each other,
They'd smile for no reason.
Everyone was distressed,
And nobody knew what was going to happen.
Then
Came that moment.
He barged into Kaneez Mahal suddenly, panting,
But everybody's eyes searched for you by his side.
But
You
Were nowhere.
You'd
Left.
Where's that bleedin' bridegroom?
Where is he?
Where's Maheen?
C -- Come with me.
Come.
His phone's switched off.
Let it remain switched off, mate.
He'll be here.
He's left.
He took off and threw away his sherwani,
And left a letter addressed to you.
Give me the letter.
Dear Maheen,
It has been a pleasure
That this chapter of our love began,
And we fell in love;
What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance
Such love that you agreed to marry me.
Splendid.
Does one wager oneself in one's quest for revenge?
And your sister Fajr,
She always kept guessing you'd fallen for me!
You silly girl,
At least you could've thought of Gulrez, if none of them.
He kept writhing in love like an animal to be sacrificed,
And kept on doing what you wanted him to.
Never before had I wished that you should taste defeat by my hand,
But my heart says that I should leave you bitterly defeated today,
And show you, Maheen, that to triumph in the name of love,
One has to yield.
I depart a victor,
And I say this as I leave,
'Bless you'
'With this closing checkmate'.
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
Ask all you will what comes out of love
The heart is its creator, and ends up being destroyed by it
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV