What's up?
What?
Suraiyya came here,
Met neither of us,
And took Ammi Begum into the room.
Who am I?
Come.
Where?
Out in the sun.
Sit for a while.
Mehru...
When did you start talking like Ammi Begum?
Ever since I realised
That she says only what's best.
Merci beaucoup.
I talked to her as a mother last night.
I said,
'You asked for time'.
'It was our fault'
'That we didn't ask you how long you wanted'.
She looked back, surprised.
She couldn't believe I was saying that!
Then, she said,
'About'...
'2 or 4 days'?
I didn't stop there.
I said, 'Even if you don't accept',
'Don't refuse'.
Don't keep someone waiting so many years just to refuse...
Don't you think it's a job well done?
What about him?
Who?
The one who'll leave me tongue-tied in the doghouse.
You take care of him.
A lad spoilt in the West can't be corrected in the East.
As if he were ever...
Don't you say it?
'Loafer, wastrel, Londoner tramp'!
I lie about it.
So that no one except Jiya likes him.
Now, I've even started believing it.
He's a loafer... A wastrel...
The Londoner tramp!
Why, Ammi Begum?
Why do you lie?
I hope to keep
One promise, at the very least...
That I'm saved from being tongue-tied in the doghouse or from the doghouse if not.
What's going on, Maheen?
It drives me crazy...
I've never seen it like this!
The Granny doesn't like it when two cousins are making peace.
The lad's Aunt didn't let him in when he brought flowers and perfume,
When everyone's thinking about him,
That he better be married off to someone he doesn't even love!
What the devil is going on?
No idea.
But I do know
That it'll be fine if I agreed to marry Gulrez.
Why don't you?
I have, Fajr.
But my heart doesn't.
Fantastic...
Sometimes, I begin to curse my heart.
I mean, whatever's wrong with Gulrez?
He looks nice,
Is of good character,
Does his 9-to-5 job...
Loves me, too...
And...
We've been engaged since we were kids...
What's the big deal...
What?
No idea...
Forgive me but I don't like it one bit, Ammi Begum...
Mum and daughter talk about everything in classified meetings,
And Dastoor's called upon only to hear the decision.
Put a sock in it...
I've called you for your advice,
Not to order you.
Leave it be.
I know it well enough.
I was called for 'advice' the last time as well, but it ended with an order.
Would you sit,
Or would you rather that I send you out?
Why wouldn't I sit?
I'm someone too, after all!
Orders, ma'am?
Mehru...
I hope you remember
What Munshi Alam Deen had said.
I do.
He'd said,
'If he doesn't want to marry Jiya',
'Just prod and ask him'
'Who he wants to marry'.
Nah, I don't intend to prod...
But go, Dastoor, and ask him today.
I'm sure his answer will put you on the rack.
You're very angry with me, right?
Because I didn't obey you?
You think I've left you helpless?
No, Dado...
And as for my respect and regard for you, I can even sacrifice my life for you.
-Cut to the chase...
What do I say?
I've been asking myself why I just couldn't obey you.
Why can't I just marry Jiya...
But I've realised today
That I will never marry Jiya.
Who, then?
Tell me, who do you want to marry?
Maheen.
It's been so long!
Why are you so late?
Gulrez wasn't well.
He took a pill and went to bed.
I was worried about what I'd do alone if things got bad.
No...
But you always drink a glass of water...
What are you looking at?
What happened?
Sit.
Dad used to say...
A mother's heart can also be found in daughters and sisters.
But I don't think any mother would be so motherly as you are.
So?
Which is why I'm sometimes afraid of you.
Please, don't fear me...
Or the mother in me.
Just speak your heart out.
You wouldn't be able to hear it.
I'm a mother, right?
Let me tell you
That the Lord gives mothers courage unlike any other.
C'mon!
The worry kills me!
Waqar Ahmed has made it clear that he'll marry Maheen.
So? I mean --
As if Waqar Ahmed's words are a Royal edict
That must be followed!
Yes.
It is a Royal edict now.
That's what we've been fearing.
We?
All of us.
Uncle Dastoor, Aunt Suraiyya, me...
And, most of all, Ammi Begum...
How hard we've tried that it not come to this!
But, in all honesty, no amount of wits and wisdom can change what's willed.
But she said she loves no one else!
She said everything in it.
She doesn't love Gulrez.
In the tale of love where do these turns come from
That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart
The world's ending, is it?
Had a nightmare?
What, then?
The King's gambit, Maheen!
What do you mean?
Who did it?
Waqar.
That's what you woke me up for?
C'mon, now, back to bed!
Not another word about him!
As if you can sleep now!
I can!
No need to tell me anything about him.
Who he meets, what he does, which gambit he plays -- I want none of it!
Really?
As if I'm lying!
I'll take my leave, then!
Please!
He's told Nano who he wants to marry.
Hey!
Jiya, right?
One of them French girls?
Who?
You'd die where you stand --
I mean -- where you sit -- if you heard it.
One of Nano's maids, is it?
It doesn't matter to you, right, who he marries?
Why should it?
Sweet dreams, then.
I've heard your reply.
Reply?
What do you mean, Fajr?
Mum's the word!
It ain't gonna remain hidden for long!
Khushi Mohammad will give you the good news in the morning.
Oh yeah?
I'll ask in the morning myself.
He said
That he'll only marry Maheen Aurangzeb!
I've decided...
That the property will be divided tomorrow.
And next week,
We'll give him his share and send him to London forever.
Forgive me, Ammi Begum,
But this is no solution.
Do you have a better solution?
I'll talk to Maheen.
No one will talk to Maheen.
She'll never agree to marry Waqar.
What if she did?
I'm her mother, Ammi Begum.
I should know, too,
What else I don't know about my daughter!
If there were any such thing, I would've gotten wind of it.
I know very well
That she'll create a ruckus over it.
It just can't be!
The girl's interested in someone, and the mother hasn't the foggiest!
How can that be?
I'll ask Maheen.
I tell you, she'll break his face for real.
What are you looking at?
Don't you believe me?
Remember how they looked like mortal enemies?
Now...
Stay tuned for what they have in store...
Are you worried?
Ashamed is more like it, Suraiyya...
Strange
That, after his parents died,
He's asked his Dado for something for the first time,
And Dado's so helpless
That she can't give him anything except his piffling share.
It'll be enough.
Even if he's unhappy,
I'm sure he'll settle for it if he saw his share.
Forgive me, Mashood Ahmed...
But you left Kaneez Begum to judge this perplexing matter,
And to judge is to be so heartless
As to be blind to the grandson's wish...
Ever thought
How families come into being
And stay together?
What is it that makes us say firmly, 'These are our traditions',
'And these are not'.
Traditions are not built on casual exchanges of words,
But by giving your word and honouring promises,
Even if it means laying down your life,
And, in the interest of fairness and justice,
By throttling your own wishes.
I know what you're here to tell me.
But you don't know that it's just a wish.
I haven't insisted that it be fulfilled.
Splendid!
What a wish!
More like a bombshell you dropped on all of us!
You've left many out of breath and many more gasping anxiously.
And you're here acting like you're innocent!
Got a signal from the other side?
Signal?
Don't tell me that 'signal' means just a signal in London.
I mean...
The green light, you know. Doesn't it mean something else?
Of course. It's like, 'Go ahead'!
So, ol' chap, did Maheen say, 'Go ahead'?
Blimey, Uncle... Who knows what you're saying...
Told her?
Who?
Maheen, of course!
She doesn't have the foggiest.
How do you know?
Turn back before this very instant if you value your life!
I'd even say, go and tell Ammi Begum
That you were kidding.
I meant every bit of it.
But if you want that Maheen marry Gulrez,
I have no objections.
I haven't challenged the family by telling you my wish,
Nor insisted that you change your decisions.
Do what you've promised.
Congratulations.
Another one's desires have been sacrificed on the altar of 'justice'.
Hearing you, I figure
Maheen wants the same.
She doesn't even want to see my face!
She --
I just felt if there's anyone I should marry, it's Maheen.
Can you keep it locked in your heart forever?
Of course.
Where could it go if let out?
I can't speak a word before her, let alone let my heart talk!
Just helpless feelings, Uncle...
Can be chained now...
Nobody hears a word if a kid's strangled the moment he's born.
What do I tell Ammi Begum?
Anything, really.
But please, don't say that I was kidding.
Feelings can be locked away...
But not the truth, Uncle.
Here's your tie.
No need.
Why?
You don't go to office without one.
I'm not going to office.
Then?
I'm going to meet Nano.
It --
Would be better if you didn't... For a few days...
Why?
Just -- Don't...
Why are you stopping me?
Wait for Maheen's reply.
I don't know why, but I have this feeling that if you went to Nano's,
She'd feel that you're there to beg...
I never beg.
You know that.
-They don't. Maheen doesn't.
That's what she'll think.
She won't.
I won't let her.
Why must you be so adamant?
I had a nightmare last night.
Somewhere, in the eye of the storm...
You're shutting the doors and windows...
You're waiting
For Wali...
Then, there's a knock on the door...
You open the door.
It's Wali...
You ask him to come in quickly,
And shut the door.
Wali's quiet...
Almost unusually...
Shocked...
Distressed...
You take out a bottle of cold water from the fridge.
Give it to him...
He gestures a no...
Even though...
He always has a glass when he gets back...
So you heard everything?
I thought you'd dozed off after taking the pill.
I'd actually dozed off.
I'd taken the pill.
Enough of your theatrics.
You heard everything.
I don't listen in on you and Wali.
Oh?
So you really had this dream?
Go on, then.
I'll tell the rest to Nano.
So that's why you're going...
No.
I'm going to tell her I won't marry Maheen.
What rubbish!
-Not rubbish...
I saw that you
Were very worried.
The sister's mask had fallen off your face...
Revealing every bit of the mother.
The mother worried by every cough of her child...
What've you become?
I've decided...
That I won't be the kid
Who'd ask his Mum for the moon to play with.
I just want the moonlight.
What'd he say?
He said he wants to get even with you.
He might've been joking.
He'd joke about marrying me?
Just ask him.
He may be serious.
I'll feed him his teeth!
That's what you ought to do.
What?
Feed him his teeth!
I do what I say, Mum.
Ah,
So you're waiting to finish breakfast, eh?
Do you have any idea what she'd do?
Yes.
Just what she ought to.
C'mon, finish your breakfast.
Hello?
Hello, Uncle Munshi.
Hello there.
Give the phone to Ali.
He's gone to school, Fajr.
Who goes to school on Doomsday?
Anyway...
Got a helmet?
Helmet?
Find one, Uncle, pronto!
What'd you do with one?
Jeez...
Find one and give it to Waqar. Quick!
Has he...
Asked for one?
No!
It's a gift from me!
Good morning, Uncle Munshi.
'Morning.
Where's Nano?
In her room.
She doesn't come out very much these days.
Gulrez!
Waqar!
How are you?
Fine.
But, blimey, mate, it's been two months since I'm here, and we're meeting for the second time today!
The third. Not the second.
No way.
We did.
Last night, I met you in my dream...
Good one.
It's not a joke, Waqar.
Although it is like one.
We don't need to meet those we want to meet.
We meet those we think of.
Now, I've got to meet Nano,
But I can't meet her in my dreams.
Why?
I'd have to ask for her permission
Even to meet her in my dreams.
Go.
She's in her room.
Who is it?
It's me, Nano.
Gulrez.
Come in, my dear.
Here to meet me?
Yes, Nano.
Skiving off work, eh?
I just did...
When did that happen?
I've never seen you
Skive off work.
Something's changed, Nano...
They say great men aren't bound by habits and rules.
Their habits keep changing,
As do their rules.
I've heard the same, too.
But...
Who told you
That you'd become a great man
By skiving off work?
I thought
I should do something
That shows everyone
That Gulrez means business.
What are you up to?
I had a dream...
A bolt from the blue...
Bolt, eh, dear?
I'm already in the middle of a thunderstorm.
You'd better do something
That gets me out of it.
And that
Is just what I'm here for.
The dream was a sign...
What are you saying?
I'm honest, Nano.
I saw an old man with a long white beard.
He said,
'There's two kinds of lovers'.
'One, le peintre, working on his masterpiece of love'...
'Painter'!
Ah, yes...
'Painter'...
And the other?
'And two, the kind who buy masterpieces to adorn their walls with'.
So, which one
Would you be?
Certes, not the one
Who'd buy a painting to adorn my wall with...
So...
What'd you do?
I...
I'd just paint my masterpiece.
I'm done with it now.
My story ends there.
And...
Who'd adorn his wall with your painting?
Waqar.
Waqar Ahmed.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV