Umm...
Could you...
Return the photocopy?
Huh?
Photocopy?
Aye...
'He thinks I've fallen for him'...
'The poor prat'!
'If this be love, dear'...
'May you'
'Groan in agony'...
'"Amour"' (Love),
'"Je te déteste"' (I hate you)...
Here's your
Photocopy...
Feel free
To let me know
If you need anything.
Hello?
Give your Mum the phone.
Ammi Begum?
Nah, Aunt May.
Mum! It's Nano!
Here.
Yes, Ammi Begum?
Mehrunnisa scoffed at me.
Hey!
Did it hurt you?
I can't believe it!
I can...
When an otherwise-duteous daughter-in-law scoffs at you...
The mother-in-law should admit she's ruined everything.
What are you saying?
I didn't give in before her.
I blamed everything on the blighter!
But Suraiyya,
She's got a point.
What?
I...
Broke too many hearts to keep my word...
That actually you, Ammi Begum?
Nah,
It's your Aunt May!
Honestly?
I don't get it.
Last night...
I saw it myself.
I saw just how much they love each other.
They'd
Die if separated.
I'd been cruel to you once...
When I got you married to that wretched Aurangzeb...
You took it quietly...
But I wonder
If Maheen would take it lying down too.
But --
I --
How much longer can I make my family gulp down this poison? How much longer can I reign supreme?
I've got to be fair for a change... Concede my defeat before love sometime...
Got to admit that love - even between two twits -
Dwarfs our authority.
And Gulrez?
What about him?
It happens when love is one-sided...
You get hunger, not food...
Anyway, bye...
Hang up already! I'm tearing up!
And --
I'm crying for the one
I'd slapped hard last night.
For real?
Can't you comfort me?
Say I'm not all that bad?
What are you saying?
It's hard to find a mother and friend like you in the world.
Thank you, Suraiyya.
Thank you very much.
You're speaking English?
It's okay if you really have to, sometimes!
Now --
Please hang up...
Before he slips away.
Maheen...
Maheen!
Maheen?
Where's Maheen?
Gone to see someone.
Who?
Gulrez.
Gulrez?
Why?
Waqar said he was just taking her for a ride last night.
And that he doesn't really love her at all.
So what's she gonna tell Gulrez?
Anything.
Perhaps even tell him everything and say... 'Good riddance'!
Good riddance?
Good riddance of someone who couldn't appreciate how much he's loved!
I say, don't stop her.
Let her have it her way.
She said as she left,
'Love's pointless'.
'Matches are made in Heaven'.
Stop her!
Call her! Ammi Begum's given in!
As if it makes any difference.
The man she turned the engagement down for refused.
She'd die but never marry him!
Good Lord...
Is he happy?
The twit was lying!
Someone must've told him to --
Nobody told her to do anything though.
Anyway...
Forget it.
Fix an auspicious date with Ammi Begum.
After the call last night,
Even I've accepted
Gulrez as my brother-in-law to-be!
Bless him, will you?
Why are you so quiet?
Have some?
Good news.
The tramp from London refused.
He ain't marrying me!
Oh?
This ain't good news for me.
Hey!
I'd call it bad news.
The separation of lovers
Makes the ground tremble.
Like an earthquake!
And - who knows - that's why the ground's gonna break on Doomsday.
Oh please. Nothing's gonna happen!
He doesn't even love me!
He swore before Nano, Uncle, Aunt, and Munshi Alam!
He was lying.
Someone made him say it.
I'd like this 'someone' to try me!
You take a while to appreciate the solemn vows of love.
What was that?
Lovers
Are given to pitying.
He had pity on me.
Splendid!
Hear that, Neelam?
He's bewitched!
Absolutely.
Only a true sorcerer
Could sacrifice his love for his corrival and say he's leaving for London.
He's leaving for London?
If he didn't already.
In fact, it's essential
For his spell to work!
Well guess what, I've begun to loathe him!
I know that.
You blow hot and cold too often.
One cold lie...
And you got all hot-headed.
But tell me...
Even if he actually turned you down,
Could that ever change love into loathing?
You turned someone down too.
On the day of the engagement.
You refused to wear the ring.
I don't loathe you one bit.
Why is it that your love
Grows to loathe your love so quickly?
If you ask me...
If that's how you define love,
I'd loathe it too.
Let her finish.
-I won't.
I've been gravely wronged!
He had pity on me!
There can be no greater insult than pitying a lover.
I won't stay quiet.
I'll tell her everything.
What?
You called him over.
Showed him my letters to Maheen.
As in,
Gave him reason to have pity.
Swear by me if I'm lying.
C'mon?
I've burnt every single one of them.
Charred my treasure to ashes because he had pity on me.
That's how much it's hurt me.
Look...
How low I've fallen...
It's Neelam's fault.
She cried before him.
He had mercy on me.
So please, tell me...
If someone had mercy on lovers,
Which upright man out there would dare to fall in love?
We don't hear much about love of late,
So don't humiliate
The rare man who's fallen in love.
Hey...
Promise me...
Yeah?
My Foxy's leading your wedding procession.
I swear by you.
Your Foxy's gonna lead my wedding procession.
♪ In the tale of love ♪
♪ In the tale of love... ♪
♪ In the tale of love where do these turns come from... ♪
♪ In the tale of love where do these turns come from ♪
♪ That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart ♪
♪ That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart... ♪
I feel so guilty, Jiya.
I love Maheen so much, but...
I don't want to marry her.
Why not?
Poor little Gulrez...
He loves her much more than I ever can.
So?
What?
I'm afraid
He may die
On the day of our wedding.
Talk about Maheen.
Who does she love?
She never said it, but...
I know there's something between us.
The way she called and stopped me...
It felt like if I didn't turn back...
She'd die.
No one's gonna die.
I mean --
You can't be serious! He's gonna die, she's gonna die...
Just think about your life!
I have.
Sometimes, I think that without Maheen...
I'd die...
That leads me to think how he...
He's written hundreds of letters to Maheen in these ten years.
He burnt them all because of me.
Now, he's holding on to the ashes...
How does he have the letters he wrote to Maheen?
He never sent them.
He could never bring himself to.
He'd write them, go through them, and think he'd told Maheen everything.
Wow...
He never asked me to get out of the way.
He got out of the way for me.
What's so funny?
Who's the Gang Chief these days?
Please, Jiya...
I'm very serious.
I'm very serious too.
Who's the Chief?
Maheen.
Maheen Aurangzeb.
And is he in the Gang too? Gulrez?
Maybe...
But it's so irrelevant.
Perhaps... Perhaps not?
I mean...
Maheen's my best friend...
She never told me she loves you.
Aye,
She always said,
'I'll teach him a lesson',
'I'll make him pay for the slap',
'Settle the scores', 'kill him off where he won't find any relief'... Stuff like that...
She says that when she's furious.
Your problem is not
How much Gulrez loves her.
Your problem
Is you believe
She loves you.
What?
What d'you mean?
You think it's completely irrelevant, don't you?
You'd do well to make sure.
What? Make sure of what?
It's so simple, Waqar.
Let her say she loves you.
You don't know her.
She'd never say that.
I know her, Waqar.
That's why I say, don't think your Gang's irrelevant.
Maybe
I'm wrong about it,
But
You should not take any chances.
Granted, she's got quite the ego...
But
Sacrificing her love
With her silence?
Impossible.
Looking at Gulrez pains me.
Hearing him, you'd think he isn't even from this world.
He doesn't love me.
He worships me.
But I can't help it.
His love and devotion are no good to me.
The twit's not really my type.
But the one I hated for all these years,
The one I planned to get even with when he'd come back...
I can't settle any score with him.
Not when I've fallen for him.
Can't believe it's happening, but it's real...
Good Lord...
If he didn't hear my call and turn back,
I swear it would've killed me.
Who's the Gang Chief these days?
Perhaps it's not so irrelevant?
Maheen's my best friend...
She never told me she loves you.
Why don't you tell 'em everything?
Say those fiery words
And shatter my ego for Nano to see!
Aye, she always said,
'I'll teach him a lesson',
'I'll make him pay for the slap'...
Sorry for disturbing you.
It's okay.
Grab a pew.
So... What is it?
You gotta write the last page for me.
Hmm?
Just one?
Aye.
Give me your draft.
I haven't got a draft this time.
I'll dictate.
You write.
Okay... No problem.
Write down...
'Everything went'
'As we'd planned'...
Just a minute...
Lemme take a look at the previous pages...
You took the samples with you.
I need a moment to study the handwriting.
Okay...
Take your time.
Uncle Qutb!
I've been screamin' at the top of my lungs! Can't you hear me?
Do I look like Qutb?
Want something? Go to the kitchen.
I'm too busy with my studies.
Where's Uncle Qutb?
With Mum.
And where's Mum?
At Nano's.
At 1 a.m.?
Nano's orders. 'Come at once if convenient. If inconvenient come all the same'.
Uncle Qutb drove her because the driver's wife's sick.
Anything else?
You better have something.
Why?
Who knows, the news from there may kill your hunger!
I've got nothing to fear. Gulrez ain't marrying me even if they all begged him.
You'd die for that London tramp, wouldn't you?
Can it!
To the dickens with him!
We're out of options...
Anger's not gonna do any good... Nor will soothing anyone...
The point, plainly,
Is that Gulrez is out of the picture.
My sweet Fatima's poor wee lad...
Go on...
About?
They've both proven
That Kaneez Begum is moron number one.
So...
You three get to decide and tell me this time.
No way, Ammi Begum.
You get to decide.
Why don't you say anything?
You're listening quietly as if we're talking about the neighbour's girl.
I've lost, Ammi Begum.
No one asked for your confession.
Confession?
I told you...
No big deal speaking English when you really need to...
Back to business...
Okay...
As it pleases the Lord.
As in?
If we can't take up arms against love...
There's one...
Against two...
The one...
Is entirely one-sided... Always has been...
Ration me rum if I understood a word Mehrunnisa just said.
Spiffing...
Get up.
Go ask Munshi Alam to get us all a cuppa.
Go on.
Are you happy with the proposal?
You wouldn't say you can't face Gulrez, would you?
She's talking about Waqar and Maheen.
Why are you still here?
This ain't for you. Go.
Go on, Suraiyya.
Say you accept it or that you will stand by your word to your sister.
I can't stand by my word, Ammi Begum...
You're right...
Gulrez is out of the picture.
My sweet Fatima's poor wee lad...
Please don't say that... It pains me so much...
Don't stop me.
I'll shed a few tears every time he'd face me...
The poor lad...
I can give him my blessings... And my sympathies...
But his love's one-sided...
I can't give him his love...
She'd rather die for Waqar Ahmed...
God be with ye.
-God be with ye.
Neelam...
Don't wake him up.
Put him to sleep if he gets up.
Ask him he's got to wait if he asks for breakfast.
If he wants to go to work, stop him.
Scold him if you must.
But why?
I've got my reasons.
Care to tell me?
I can't.
But don't worry.
It'll be out soon...
You'll find out later today.
I hope you've got sleeping pills...
Give him one in his tea.
What is it?
It's nothing, really...
Just...
My intuition...
A gut feeling that warns me...
About?
I'd rather not want to say it.
God be with ye.
Peace be upon you, Nano.
And upon you, peace.
Had breakfast?
No.
Just sent Wali to work.
Gulrez is sleeping.
I'll have breakfast when he gets up. We eat together.
Okay...
I'll get back to you
After breakfast.
Please, go on.
I don't want to wait until breakfast!
You'd better.
Plus, that twit's sleeping...
When he gets up, ask him
If he can augur.
Augur?
Back in our day, we could.
We may not love as much...
But we'd augur much more... But it seems now...
What is there to augur about?
What is it, Nano?
How do I tell you, love?
Wali's not around...
Gulrez's asleep...
You're out there all alone...
What if something happened to you?
Don't worry.
I know you're brave.
But bravery, my dear,
Can only last so long.
Tell me...
When was the last time you cried?
I don't cry now.
You're off form, so to speak...
In that case, you better have breakfast first...
Get back to me when you've had breakfast.
I'll tell you everything
If the Lord wills thus...
Hello?
You're marrying Maheen to Waqar?
Me sainted uncle...
That's some fine augury...
I mean, just think about it.
It's that poor twit who loves her,
But you're the one auguring.
Because I love him, Nano.
Look...
You better not start crying now.
Just think I'm helpless...
No truth can conceal your grey-haired lies better than the truth of your helplessness...
You're there, aren't you?
Yeah.
Promise me...
You'll have your breakfast like nothing happened
And tell him cheerfully, with a smile -
'She' --
'She didn't deserve your love... She wanted a loafer layabout like herself'!
Aren't you sending us sweets?
Wha -- Sweets?
You're not brave either.
You will need to be, Nano.
Good news ain't good without sweets.
Please, send us some.
I'll wake Gulrez up.
Hold your horses, Neelam, or he'll die under their weight!
He's already dead.
He gave his life without an ounce of fear.
I'm just cross as two sticks to wonder
Why he couldn't augur and see the writing on the wall at all!
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV