Ready?
Aye.
Breaking news!
Not so fast. Keep an eye out.
Hey!
Please, Fajr.
If Mum saw me having tea and biscuits,
She'd think I'd give in to hunger.
You're not going to University again.
Don't even think about it!
It's my last semester.
Sorry! Mum's orders!
No way you're getting out of here.
Can it!
Told you! The game is on!
I say,
Instead of shouting or fighting back, just give in.
Forget your studies.
You off your head?
D'you know how much it'd cost me?
That's what they all say.
You don't think how much your decisions cost everyone.
Shut up!
You ought to bless me, Maheen!
I may be the last ray of hope for your doomed love!
Soooo sweet of you!
Done?
Not yet.
Mum's here! Quick! Hide!
Have something...
What have we here?
She hasn't had anything...
Good.
Good riddance of her
If she starves herself to death!
She's got this awful headache for the last one hour!
Big deal.
We've all had an awful headache since last night.
Out.
Lemme massage her head, Mum!
Just do as you're told.
And aye, where's the keys?
Keys?
Why d'you need them?
I've been ordered to lock the room.
Very good!
Enough!
The only out... Is a pall!
Juliet's pall, I beg thee, must be most grand!
You blighter!
And aye,
You're not going to University again.
I will.
Even if I have to jump out the window.
You don't know me, girl.
I'm Ammi Begum's daughter.
I'll char you with your obstinacy.
Speaking of her...
Could you tell Nano
She's making a big mistake
By taking up arms against love?
Those who hate love will be blown to bits.
At least have something before you go to bed, love, okay?
Ask him
Why he went with her.
I didn't.
She took me.
As if he's a kid
Who lost his way and went with whoever held his hand!
She was ashamed at what she did.
Just
Ashamed?
So she'd kill and say sorry
Because she's ashamed!
Who'd she kill?
Why, everyone standing there!
Wali,
Me,
You...!
At long last you name the one who actually died.
But I didn't lose my life to her.
They say you give your life for those who hold it dear.
Well said.
Wali,
Just tell him he's not seeing her again.
Why don't you say it?
I think he understands.
He won't see her again.
Good.
Logically, after so much insult, I thought, too,
That I'd never see her again.
But she's a girl...
And most like a girl...
She'd hide what lies in her heart so well
She wouldn't have the foggiest herself!
Thank goodness she found out.
In fact, thank goodness she found out in time.
I'm the only one insulted right now.
Love's been spared the ignominy.
Wait.
I'll go see.
Hi.
You're angry?
Won't you let me in?
Please go back.
We're mourning the recent death of his heart.
Praying for his soul.
It's best if the killer stayed at an arm's length.
What's this?
A lunchbox.
What's in it?
Food.
For?
Yours truly.
Ours, who?
Don't you think
That makes no sense?
It makes perfect sense to me.
Who you're about to give it to
Is truly not ours!
You've started talking like Ammi Begum!
He hasn't had anything since yesterday!
He refused to order anything.
The only thing he gets here is our wrath.
Send him as much as you like.
Where does he live?
I can't tell you that.
Whoa.
You refuse to tell your masters?
Here.
What are you doing?
Way to go, Mehrunnisa!
Could you be any more rebellious?
You'd cook food with your own hands
For the kids who've grown up to slander the family and bring it disgrace!
I won't marry anyone else, Mehrunnisa!
What was that?
Why'd you marry anyone else?
After you're gone, everyone's gonna ask me to.
I can turn them all down, but if Ammi Begum told me to...
Get a grip on yourself, M. Dastoor.
Mehrunnisa
Ain't leaving you
Behind.
If Ammi Begum found out what you're up to,
She'd kill you for real!
She called me at work.
Asked me to send her
New cartridges.
If you don't want to be at the wrong end of the barrel,
Just let him starve to death!
Thought yourselves so clever, didn't you?
Ammi Begum was just outside, watching, hearing!
What are you looking for?
Here's your lunchbox. Get going!
Before the bugger starves to death!
You better sit too.
Spend your last few moments with me?
What are you looking at?
Munshi Alam...
I won't let him out of my sights.
Stay on my six!
Quickly!
Hello?
Hello, partner!
Make it quick. I'm being watched!
We're sending him food.
Don't tell me!
I've seen it myself! Munshi Alam packed a lunchbox for him!
Where does he live?
We'll find out tonight.
We're tailing Munshi Alam.
Who's tailing him?
Ammi Begum!
Although Mum and Dad think they're tailing him.
I don't get it.
Have you got a black suit?
Aye.
Maheen does too, I'm sure?
Aye, but --
Put it on.
Why?
Waqar ain't comin' back alive.
Munshi Alam thought he could outfox us.
How d'you like them apples now?
I'll catch him red-handed,
And drop the London tramp
At the airport.
Hmm...
What about Maheen?
I mean, he was almost at the airport...
Maheen called to stop him.
If he deserves punishment for coming back,
What about the one who stopped him?
Don't worry. She won't be spared.
She's marrying Gulrez.
At last...
So you concede that marrying her off to Gulrez is a punishment.
Is that rebellion I catch a whiff of in your voice, Mehrunnisa?
Not just a whiff, M. Dastoor Ahmed...
More like a rank stench,
Not of rebellion,
But of the truth that rots in your heart as much as mine,
And I'm sure
Ammi Begum's.
Except she covers it up for the sake of Gulrez.
Like anyone else her age, she thinks she can stop lovers.
I dare her to!
I wonder if you can say any of that to Ammi Begum's face...
I can.
But I'd rather you not marry someone else.
But then...
If not me, who?
Could you?
Before you get her the new cartridges,
Gather your courage and say it.
There!
Your pointless banter made me lose sight of Munshi Alam!
No idea if he went right or left...
Left!
Hello?
You alone?
Aye.
HVT bagged!
Oh, God...
Where?
At the farmhouse.
Who bagged him?
Mum, Dad, and Dado!
Poor kid.
I'll break the news and get back to you!
Okay.
Hello?
Bad news!
Yeah?
He's been done over.
Good!
Why do you 'good'-'very good' everything?
I'm delighted!
I mean,
The world's changed,
But not the loathing some people have for love!
It's always been this way.
Two fall in love,
And two hundred hate it!
That's how it is
In 2008, as in 1908...
Anyway, can't talk. Gotta write my diary!
All my fault...
I thought I could be friends with all...
It's cost me dearly...
I raised all my kids with so much love...
Only to see them grow into rebels...
They hate
And love who they want.
Their love does not rest until it's quaffed the blood out of others' love...
The quandary
For my unfortunate self
Is that the one quaffing the blood
Is a piece of myself,
And whose blood should he drink
But the one
Who has a special place in my heart?
How can you stay in one piece when parts of yourself go up in arms against each other, Waqar Ahmed?
I heard the words of those who fear me just so they can please me.
What did you say?
'Not just a whiff, M. Dastoor Ahmed'...
'More like the rank stench'
'Of the truth that rots'
'Inside you, as inside me',
'Hoping to get out someday',
'As it does'
'Inside Ammi Begum, I'm sure',
'Except she covers it up'
'For the sake of Gulrez Akhtar'...
And also...
'Like everyone her age, Ammi Begum thinks she can stand in the way of lovers'...
'I dare her to stop love if she's so powerful'!
What do I tell you...
If love could be stopped so easily,
Elders like ourselves
Wouldn't be watching over you young'uns.
Love is not stopped, Mehrunnisa.
The kids are.
They're told,
'Don't go this way',
'Don't look that way'...
But, alas, there's times we fail...
Sometimes, we can't stop them from going or looking...
You can't make a garland
Without piercing flowers with a needle.
Likewise,
You have to pierce all relations with a cold but tearful spite
To hold them together like a wreath.
Elders like ourselves, Mehrunnisa,
Don't just
Brag about our place merely on account of our age...
It's a thorny throne of responsibilities up there.
Responsibilities
Force us to deal justly.
And justice...
Has a penchant for landing us in a fix...
There's one Maheen,
Coveted by two -
Both dearer to me than my life...
Tell me...
Who gets Maheen,
And who, bad news?
In that moment,
I just decided, thinking
That the Lord loves His creation
Far more than all of us combined,
Yet even He cannot please everyone...
You gonna get going, Dastoor Ahmed?
Or do you intend to look at my face
In this accursed place?
C'mon.
Let those who want
Stay here.
You!
Seraj Akbar?
Aye?
Jiya.
From Mir Mehtab's office.
Mir Mehtab...
Come in.
Please.
Nine...
Ten...
Eleven...
Peace be upon you, Mlle Maheen!
And upon you, peace.
How are you?
Fine, by the Lord's grace.
Are you going to University?
Yeah.
May I, Mum?
What are you looking at?
The door ain't the only way out, you know.
Bye!
Eleven...
Go on...
Twelve...
Thirteen...
Fourteen...
Fifteen 'ere...
And...
Sixteen.
That's sixteen in all.
I say you'll...
Get it back in five days.
Haven't you got family?
I mean --
D'you live all alone?
Haven't gotten married.
No wife. No kids.
Just loved once...
That experience taught me
You love one
And marry another.
I thought I could go on with love...
But to be honest, with nothing in your pocket,
Love hardly makes any difference.
I talk a lot, don't I?
M. Jamshedi told me
You're a handwriting expert.
I'm a poet! A poet!
A writer.
But when that doesn't work,
I have to do some of these odd jobs on the side.
By the way, someone who can copy handwriting is no handwriting expert.
Get it?
As in, copy it exactly?
I could write what I want
And you'd think you've written it yourself.
But
I don't write less than ten pages.
Don't worry. You'll be writing much more.
But
I don't want the slightest mistake.
Here.
Write something here.
Lemme show you.
Go on. Write something...
Peace be upon you!
Here.
Have a look.
'I positively loathe Maheen'
Here.
10 gee. Your advance.
10 gee... Advance?
Maheen!
Maheen?
He's here!
Who?
Your killer!
D'you know Mir Mehtab?
Aye.
Very well.
You'll get an additional 40 gee in three days.
Feel free to ask me if you need more.
Anytime.
As long as you live.
Okay?
But there's one condition...
And what would that be?
You're taking this secret with you...
You're taking this secret with you... Into your grave.
Agreed.
Peace, Aunt.
Upon you too.
Thought I'd come here when I heard the news.
Aye.
Come.
Sit.
Want some tea?
No.
Like I care.
Actually... I think I'd have a cuppa...
Zeenat!
Get some tea for Waqar.
Ma'am.
How's she, Aunt?
Never been better.
The shooter had a lousy aim.
If I got hold of him,
I'm gonna fix him with my boots!
I'm sure she's scared.
I'm sure you know now
She doesn't fear bullets.
I hear
You left everything behind?
And now... You're back?
Aye.
I was in hiding, but
Dado found me.
When she got to me, I felt she wanted me to come back. So I did.
There goes your plan to run off to London...
Aye.
I ain't going to London now.
What are you looking at?
Nothing, Aunt.
Nothing, really...
Her room's upstairs.
Aye.
I know.
Don't even look her way.
I just thought I'd check on her --
Don't even think about it.
Ask me all you want.
You just told me she's fine.
Of course. So she is.
Any idea who the shooter could be?
What good is it?
He failed miserably.
What?
Forget it.
Nothing you should be bothered about.
If I got my hands on him,
I'll sort him out!
How?
And why?
My blood's boiling, Aunt!
Just shut up,
Have your cuppa,
And go back.
May I see her once?
What d'you mean?
I mean --
I'd see her and ask her how she is.
If you don't mind, of course.
Take the cup!
I'm asking Zeenat!
Take the cup away and leave.
And what are you looking at?
Get up.
Say goodbye and get out.
Okay...
Peace indeed, Aunt...
Aye?
Hope you didn't hit!
Good.
That's enough.
What it is is, she's a friend.
My life.
I won't kill her so easily.
Bullets don't nearly hurt as much as grief.
Grief does not kill
In one
Swift shot...
Bye.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV