Here.
Keep it with you.
I don't dare touch it either.
Take all the time you want in one shot
And think over it.
He thinks I'm insulting him...
Innit?
-No...
He says you only need to ask...
And he'd give you a hundred years...
Wow, that's cute...
Would you get me a cuppa or...?
Of course. I'll brew it myself.
Mum... Mind if I ask something?
I do.
I mind you speaking English. As does Ammi Begum.
Alright... Mind if I ask something?
Go on.
Is it normal in families?
Elders wanting the kids not to make peace.
Who are you talking about?
No one.
Just -- Curious...
You mean Maheen and Waqar?
Whoa, you're smart, Mum.
Not all that much.
It's a bit difficult, aye...
I mean...
Surprising.
The decisions of the elders are wise. Prudent.
That's all you need to know.
I thought you said God's decisions are wise.
Clam up!
My mouth, aye.
But never my eyes and ears.
In the Gang, we say,
'The game's a bit dodgy'!
Why'd you go there?
Love is not for the beggars!
Lovers do not go about with a bowl...
Begging, 'Please, Maheen Aurangzeb',
'Give me a bit of your love for the love of God'!
Love is not a malady
That you look for someone who can cure it.
I love her.
I take pride in the fact.
And I take pride in the fact that she doesn't love me back,
Because love is so courteous as to give the right to refuse.
She didn't refuse.
She wanted time, aye?
For all I care,
She can take a hundred years!
I would still have time to give her
Even when I'm not around.
Gulrez...
I think we had to talk to her. Ask her. Just once.
You didn't.
She's been asked once.
We've talked to her once.
Asking her... Talking to her a second time... Is like begging!
I swear to God,
I don't even want Maheen in charity.
Gulrez...
Don't get all worked-up and furious.
Girls have all sorts of problems.
Some don't like to let love near their selves.
Some love but keep it locked in their hearts.
And some -
Like Maheen -
Don't love anyone, but...
Believe in love.
She just doesn't know who deserves her love.
One's got to get to know her heart...
Take a good look...
That's why I'd gone to her.
I wanted to make sure there's no one else in her heart.
And I assure you, there's no one.
Does that mean
You didn't even see me?
Fajr!
Where are you off to?
Waqar's here!
Back inside!
Peace, Aunt.
Upon you too.
Know why I'm here?
I know everything.
You want to make peace with Maheen.
Whoa!
-Don't 'whoa' me!
You can't.
Don't worry. I'll say sorry if I have to.
I even brought flowers.
And perfume.
Try her.
Gimme the flowers.
Aunt!
What --
What are you doing?
Aunt!
Aunt! Stop it!
Wh --
What d'you think you're doing?
I'm not like you.
I'm following my orders.
Get out.
And don't set foot in here until you're ready to marry Jiya.
Who in the world ordered you?
Who else could it be?
But I won't tell you that.
Splendid...
I ought to say that too.
Don't you look too splendid to be making peace?
No way.
We'd rather have you two up in arms.
What are you looking at?
Go back.
Don't expect me
To let you in or something.
You're forgetting something. You're my Aunt. You love me so much.
I've forgotten everything, m'boy!
I've been ordered
Not to care about who you are to me.
That's who you are today - no one!
I don't even know you!
I tell you, if I got furious --
-Aye? What are you gonna do?
I --
I won't set foot in here!
Don't.
No one over here
Gives two hoots.
Get going!
Back to your Dado!
Double time!
Okay, bye.
Bye.
I swear, Maheen...
He brought flowers for you.
And some perfume.
He said he wanted to make peace.
He said he was ready to hear everything you'd say quietly.
Where's the flowers? And the perfume?
Mum destroyed the flowers
And threw the perfume in the lawn.
But why?
She said she won't let him in
Until he's ready to marry Jiya.
Nano told her. I'm sure.
So what?
What's up with Nano? Doesn't she want the kids making peace?
Wait.
Lemme have a look.
Hmm!
Mhm...
Hello?
It's Suraiyya.
Go on.
He was here.
With flowers and perfume.
Told you!
Won't you ask how I dealt with him?
Pray tell.
Threw it in the lawn and didn't let him set foot inside!
Good.
He said,
'Don't forget you're my Aunt'!
Hmm...
'You love me so much'!
He wanted to make you all sentimental about it...
I know.
But I didn't give in.
I said, 'You're no one'!
'Get out'!
Did he?
Promptly.
Spiffing.
You may've just saved the family's honour today, dear.
But... Tell me...
If he doesn't want to marry Jiya,
How does that dishonour our family?
I'll tell you someday...
I've done as you asked... Couldn't you tell me now?
Tell me...
Does Maheen know he was here?
No idea.
She does know how he left.
Aye.
Good.
How'd she react?
She was laughing.
Howling. Doubling up.
Now she's suckin' diesel!
We're safe now.
Safe from?
Don't even ask about it...
It's sick!
It's sick enough I had to kick him out!
Alright...
Venture a guess...
When Munshi Alam said his important thing...
D'you remember it?
I do.
What'd he say?
He said, 'Ask him'
'Who'd you marry if not Jiya'?
Why don't you tell me the answer to that?
I mean -- He won't actually marry her --
But who d'you think he'd name?
How'd I know?
I do, Suraiyya Begum.
The blighter's mind may be English,
But I can read it in Urdu.
I've reached 73 raising kids like him...
Who'd he name?
You sitting or standing?
Standing, Ammi Begum.
Take a seat.
Okay?
Don't tell anyone.
I won't!
Your dearest
Maheen, of course!
Didn't I just say sorry?
Please, forgive me this one time?
Gulrez!
Don't think I mean it when I say sorry.
Everything's fair in love and war.
But what happens in love
Happens not in war, Neelam.
Gotta say, though.
I've got her to hear it!
What you could never say!
It's okay.
I'm starving.
I'd like to have dinner.
Neelam was here today.
She asked me
If I ever
Went to buy a book
And bought perfume instead.
I said,
Aye.
She said, 'Don't get the perfume this time'.
'Get the book'.
'Just for once'...
'Go through one of its pages'...
'If you think it isn't worth it',
'Get all the perfume you want'.
I know
Books
Don't have that sweet scent...
But...
A good read
Is redolent
With sweet words...
Which is why, this time,
I feel I ought to get the book
Instead of the perfume!
But whenever I think about it...
Why do you show up in the way?
Step aside!
Out of my way!
Go back where you came from!
Dinner, Neelam!
I'm honestly knackered.
Lovely.
She's thinking. You're waiting.
Wonder how you would doze off.
That's the limit...
Know what, Neelam...
When she left your birthday party,
It hurt me so much.
Whether or not she's thinking...
Whether she asks for time... Or gives us some...
I can doze off now...
Quite peacefully, actually...
My heart says
You're about to get your answer.
I've got a feeling she won't take time. Or refuse.
Dinner?
Don't believe me?
That's what I like about her.
She kills...
But never gives anyone false hope.
No idea what you're made of...
You're so hopeful since you met her...
Good, though...
She's changing...
Dinner?
Know what, Dado's got a big problem...
She thinks of something
And wants it followed like a commandment.
She asked me, I said no,
But she still called you!
Why'd you say no?
Tell me...
Why'd you say yes?
Know what Fajr told her after you left?
What?
She said
You love me.
Like she's wrong.
Or maybe that's what you think.
Or maybe... You don't even deserve to be loved.
Jiya...
I'm not fit for love.
Good.
Good answer.
I brought you here to tell you
That whatever Dado said
Was not my decision.
Oh!
So you've come crawling back!
Ammi Begum came...
You crawled back!
What's your problem, Waqar Ahmed?
It's not like I'm dying for you.
It's just that Ammi Begum called with a proposal...
I thought I've got to get married.
I know you.
We're friends.
Ain't too bad after all.
But you said you don't want to.
I don't want either! I don't care!
Got your wallet?
Eh?
Aye.
Good.
Don't forget to pay the bill.
Tell me, Ammi Begum.
What's he gonna say with his head in your lap?
Suraiyya knows what he's gonna say.
No...
I haven't the foggiest.
God knows what he'd say...
What does it mean to surrender completely?
He surrendered?
'Course, my dear...
Those who concede
Have to accept all the conditions of the victor.
Who's the victor?
Absolutely spiffing, Mehru.
If he surrendered to me,
Who d'you think is the victor but me?
He loves someone else.
That's what I think.
What can't happen in ten years?
I dare him.
What are you gonna do?
I said we're having roasted aubergine. So we will. Willy-nilly.
Don't try to get anything else on the stove.
I don't get it, Ammi Begum.
I do.
What'd you get?
He doesn't like roasted aubergine.
What are you gonna tell Jiya?
I've given her my word.
Made a promise too.
I'm gonna honour it.
Did you call her father?
What do I tell him?
Let me sort things out here first.
The blighter may not have won,
But he hasn't quite surrendered yet.
Jiya's very nice.
Lovely too.
No idea what Waqar's looking for.
Just pray he doesn't do something crooked!
Rascals like himself would nag you to get them the moon to play with one day.
I'll have to talk to Jiya...
Assure her...
Or she'd think the old lady went back on her word...
Hi!
Hi.
'Sup? Here to pull me up again?
No, partner!
Just here to tell you you've succeeded!
Don't get it?
Smell something?
Where?
I'm wearing your perfume, mate!
Thank you so much!
Truce?
Could you do something for me?
-Yeah?
Marry Jiya.
I'm just friends with Jiya.
That's precisely why, Sherlock!
It takes a while to make friends with your wife. She's already your friend!
Could you possibly hope for better?
You here to say that?
No.
One more thing...
If you make a place for yourself in someone's heart, learn to stay there.
You don't learn it that easy in London,
But girls' hearts are not leaseholds
That you can leave
At your leisure.
See you!
And aye,
We're friends!
You twit... When we've talked to you,
When we said he's gonna marry you,
Why d'you need to listen to his cock and bull stories?
Ammi Begum's given you her word.
Come over anytime you want.
See him. See us all you want.
If you stay before his eyes,
You'll begin to make your place in them.
By the way,
Do you know how to play cricket?
No, Ammi Begum...
Why don't you learn it, love?
Call me coach! I'll train you!
Why'd I want to learn to play cricket?
You don't know...
But he absolutely loves cricket.
He loves to play with the ladies!
Learn to play, wager everything, and win him over!
I say he's all yours.
No, Ammi Begum.
He's not.
And to be honest, I don't want him either.
What are you saying?
You were so delighted to hear the proposal the other day!
I liked how you proposed to me.
Just a minute...
Gimme the phone...
C'mon!
Lemme talk to her.
Hello?
Hi, matey.
How are you?
Don't even ask.
Why'd you refuse?
How 'bout you tell me
Why d'you want to force Waqar on me?
Can't you find someone else for him?
You saw him?
I mean...
One of these days?
What good is it?
Is it something he said?
He isn't fit to be loved, mate!
I can't even think of a man so unfit!
Please find someone else for him.
You're hiding something, aren't you?
I swear, I'm not.
I mean it.
He doesn't suit me.
He's nice. Sweet.
But just sweet and nice doesn't do it for me.
I'll talk to you later.
Please tell Ammi Begum I'm sorry again.
What'd she say?
She said sorry.
If you make a place for yourself in someone's heart, learn to stay there.
You don't learn it that easy in London,
But girls' hearts are not leaseholds
That you can leave
At your leisure.
Hello?
Hi.
I hope you were not sleeping.
I was just about to sleep.
Go on.
I'm awake.
Good.
Jiya, let's... Discuss the proposal?
What proposal?
Dado's proposal?
That chapter's closed.
I've told Ammi Begum you're unfit to be loved.
You're angry.
Of course not.
Why'd I be?
You thought you couldn't love me.
I thought, too,
I couldn't possibly love you!
Just a sec.
Can we forget yesterday's convo for a moment?
Why?
Maheen said
I ought to marry you.
Maheen?
Aye.
At least she gave me something to think about.
And I think she was right.
Talk to you tomorrow?
Why tomorrow?
I'm knackered.
Good night.
Look at me.
We need to talk.
You made peace with Waqar?
Know why?
You'd be in sin if I didn't.
You shook hands with him too?
Of course.
We made peace. Became friends. It's but natural!
Stay tuned
For what he's gonna do.
What?
Don't ask me.
Tell me...
What'd you tell Neelam?
Ask me about what Neelam asked me!
I know what she'd ask you.
Tell me what you said.
I asked her to read my diary.
She'd find all her answers in it.
What's in your diary?
I've written that I want to fall in love with Gulrez.
I'll marry him the moment I do.
Get married.
Fall in love when you want.
You can't be serious!
Just --
Say it plainly.
You kicked her out!
You asked for time. Now you're showing her your diary. What else are you gonna show us?
You're in the mood for a fight, Mum!
Not with you!
I'm fighting myself.
You don't seem to budge.
And Ammi Begum
Says all sorts of things...
The sort that'd give you sleepless nights!
That why you're up?
Forget about sleeping.
Just tell me plainly...
How much more time do you want?
Just decide in one go
And tell me exactly
How many days, months, or years you want!
Gotta say, that's some fine Queen's English!
Just answer my question!
Well...
Not more than...
A couple of days?
Take a couple of years if you want,
For all I care!
But don't you dare refuse, Maheen!
Or there will be blood!
Okay...
Back to your diary.
I'll ask you in a few days.
Dado says girls are like birds.
Playful...
Gourmands...
Who'd fly away in a flash!
I ain't that silly, you know.
But this is something I don't quite get.
I'm pretty sure you don't get it either.
You live in London.
I hear it's a proper nightmare to find a girl there.
There's millions of English roses there.
Who says you need to look for one?
Dado.
She says you only find chits there.
Maybe one or two ladies among the lot... But that's about it.
Well, then, ask her
How she defines a lady.
I've asked her.
She said, 'A lady keeps her dreams locked safely within her heart',
'And lets unfulfilled dreams'
'Flow away with the dripping oceans of her eyes'...
But why are you telling me any of this?
You're (in)famous for making friends with girls.
Dado says boys and girls ain't never just friends.
And it ain't proper to marry your friend.
Proper?
That's weird.
It's not, Waqar. I mean, look at it this way...
You can be friends with many girls.
Aye?
As you can be with many boys.
So...
Is it proper?
Aunt?
Here alone on Sunday?
Hey...
I know why girls are like birds.
Cage them,
Send them from one branch to another,
Or one country to another...
They'd accept their fate
Quietly.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV