Wait here, Fajr!
I'm sorry.
No.
I didn't even ask you, Maheen...
Let's talk in the morning, shall we? I'm sleepy...
The night's going to be long. Besides, everyone there knows your decision.
It isn't wrong to refuse... But it should be done properly.
I haven't refused.
I just couldn't... Accept that bolt from the blue.
It almost felt like... A conspiracy... Not my betrothal.
You twit... As if I'd conspire against you!
I'm your mother!
Looking at you, I get a feeling that sometimes, you end up conspiring even when you don't want to.
That's what happened with you...
I felt like it wasn't an engagement...
It was my punishment for stealing his Foxy!
I was so scared I shoved the ransom in his face!
Get to the point... What now?
Everyone there thinks you've refused.
Tell them I haven't refused...
I need time to think.
How much?
No idea...
I may just accept it right away!
And I may spend the whole night thinking...
And what'd it mean if you spent the whole night thinking?
You accept it, don't you?
Why don't I have the right to refuse?
-Would you rather refuse?
Blimey, Mum, let me think!
Also think...
Ammi Begum might have a heart attack if you refused.
There!
Did you hear that? She's here.
Well, at least we know she hasn't had a heart attack!
Thank goodness. You can tell her what you want. I'll get going.
Mum!
Not today.
Just tell her I'm sleeping.
I want to be sure when I talk to her.
We've sworn never to lie to each other. Gangmates, you know.
Where's Maheen?
-Sleeping.
But how?
How could she just crucify us like that and go to sleep?
Please, sit...
Your daughter practically spat in Kaneez Begum's face before everyone, and you're asking me to sit!
Don't even think about it!
Ruined my birthday, and killed the joy of Waqar's return!
Why'd you have to drop the engagement bombshell? Remember her stopping the car?
Stopping the car?
When you asked if she were married off to someone like him, and she said that's how her life would come to a halt.
Ah, yes...
That's what happened.
All your Mum's fault.
She says just about anything!
By the Lord, Ammi Begum! You asked me to say --
-Did I ask you to say it right then?
You've learnt nothing from me, Suraiyya.
What kind of twit would get everything done before even talking to the girl?
So she's got no time to think, no time to decide, no time to refuse.
You do know it works only when she loves you too, don't you?
Do you still think she'd refuse?
She won't!
She's asked for time. She's thinking.
Thinking...
So she's got another option...
What do you think?
She's hoping to get you? Good girls have always got a few options.
She picks one and all the rest get the bad news.
In that case, I'll hear the bad news.
No one's saying that!
Running 10 kilometres tormented like this here won't get you anywhere!
Okay...
So she's got the right to refuse, but I haven't got the right to be tormented?
Gulrez!
May I say something?
-You better not, Dastoor Ahmed!
He's a gonner...
Who?
The poor Gulrez.
And finally, the Foxy will get to outlive him...
Don't worry.
She hasn't refused.
She's just asking for time.
I'll have a cuppa.
She's just asked for time to think.
I love my Foxy.
Love can be an augurer, a parrot...
I know when she's gonna work and when she's gonna stop on the road.
I don't take her for a ride when she's not in the mood.
-Balderdash!
You're underestimating love.
-I'm underestimating your augurer!
Love is very different for boys and girls.
Boys augur, girls think.
Just let her.
Why are you standing? Sit down.
She's asking for time to think. What do you think she'll say?
I mean... Why are you so positive?
If she's asked for time...
My experience says she'll aceept...
And if she did not?
Gordon Bennett... Don't ruin my nice little cuppa, Fajr...
Where's Waqar Ahmed?
It's 2, Suraiyya.
He ain't crazy like you to be up all night.
Been there since 10.
Used to drop by every now an then... But it's been 4 years now.
What about me?
Nice to meet you.
But I'm surprised we became friends so quickly...
I don't believe that a boy and a girl can be friends...
I do.
No jealousy between them.
Because no friendship between them!
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV