What in the world is your problem, Dado?
What d'you think I am?
A blimming circus-monkey who'd dance to your tunes?
D'you think I'd fall in love with Jiya just because you want me to?
That I'd agree to marry her if you forced a ring into her finger?
As if hearts beat
Or love by your will!
When I said I ain't marrying Jiya, I mean it!
Ammi Begum!
Mehrunnisa!
-Dado!
-Ammi Begum!
What happened? Dado? Dado!
Open your ey --
Call the doctor!
Dado, I --
I promise you -- I'll marry Jiya...
I swear by you I will, Dado...
Dado...
Look at me, Dado!
Mum...
Get some water, Aunt!
Dado?
Dado...
I swear by you, I'll marry her... I promise you...
Neelam!
Ammi Begum's inside.
What happened to her?
What is it, mate?
Just pray.
What?
Pray she comes to.
It's bad. Real bad.
What are you saying?
Someone's struck her heart.
It almost stopped.
What?
She's fine now...
Why don't they let me in?
I stopped them.
Because I figure the last person who said anything to her
Was you.
The last person?
As in, before she fainted. You said something to her.
Goodness...
She better not see you. Not now.
I haven't seen someone her age
So sensitive...
Anyway, I'll get going.
If you need anything, you know I'm just a call away.
No...
You're not going anywhere.
I won't let you. Not until Dado's fine.
She's fine!
She'll come to if everything's alright.
She's out of danger.
But...
But?
What was it?
Whatever did you say to her, mate?
Anyway...
Don't worry...
She'll be fine...
But don't even think of going in.
I'll get going.
Bet you folks thought
Ammi Begum's pushing up daisies.
That blighter almost had a heart attack.
You'll see in the morning...
He'll be at my feet,
Agreeing to marry Jiya.
I'm going over to her place tomorrow.
I'll put the ring on her.
However do you do it, Ammi Begum!
Someone's got to, Dastoor Ahmed...
If the old can't act,
They get heart attacks for real.
What d'you call it?
MI.
Hmm.
That's what his attack almost gave me.
I beat him at his own game.
He's outside.
Troubled.
He's looking at everyone
Like it's someone to bail him out of the nick!
Cut the apple, would you?
Let him...
Let him sit outside like a common criminal. Tell him
He's getting out in the morning.
I crack up the moment he looks at me.
Don't you dare, you twit.
You're gonna ruin everything.
What d'you get
If he marries Jiya?
I mean --
Why are you doing any of this?
Shut up...
You're with me because I love you.
You know just as well the kids ain't allowed in here.
Not cricket, Nano.
Why d'you want him to marry Jiya if he doesn't want to?
Let him marry whoever he loves.
Okay...
So you want one of them Englishwomen in the house.
Jiya's such a nice girl. We all know her. Plus, she's his friend!
It means something to be friends!
There's always something going on!
That's cruel.
You're siding with him!
Can't believe you'd side with the enemy!
He's my enemy. Not yours.
He's tormented for you outside.
Can't believe you're enjoying grapes in here.
Hear that, Mehrunnisa?
Aye.
Aye, go on?
Now that you're speaking...
Why don't you say something back? Something she deserves?
I'll be honest, girl...
I'm afraid of him.
My heart says,
'Beware, Kaneez Begum',
'Or this cruel man'
'Will bring the family disgrace'!
M. Waqar...
Would you like something?
No.
So...
Will you just have tea all night?
Aye.
Just tea.
You may leave...
I --
Sir...
What are you so afraid of?
What else d'you expect?
She fainted in my arms!
Just try thinking out of the box!
How?
Why aren't the three of us allowed in?
I can't go in. That's obvious. You two are kids.
No, partner.
They don't think we're kids.
They think we're on your side!
As in?
As in,
Which malady
Could heal the moment she'd hear that you're ready to marry Jiya?
She's not sick.
She gave her word...
To Jiya.
Whoa...
D'you think she'd do the same with me?
Jesus...
No, no...
What 'no, no'?
I'll do as I want.
I ain't marrying any Jiya for the sake of Ammi Begum's word!
Good that I know what she can do now.
Shut up, mate.
You think she's acting?
Everyone is, I swear!
Did you see how Munshi Alam quietly turned in?
He's the type who'd stay up all night if Ammi Begum has so much as a headache!
Has she come to?
She will.
That's what the doctor said, innit?
Please, Uncle...
Why d'you say that?
What've I done?
Oh, I don't know... Caused her to faint!
What's next?
Wait.
Aye?
Go and tell her I'm ready to marry Jiya.
She'll come to in a moment.
No.
I ain't saying anything.
You'd go back on your word.
I swear! For real!
I won't go back on it.
Think again.
What?
Think carefully about it.
I've thought a lot, Uncle Dastoor...
Besides, Jiya ain't that bad.
I just thought
There could be problems
Because I don't love her... Yet.
So?
Are you sure you won't now?
Aye.
Because I guess I'm in love with her...
What?
I mean it.
Out here, I was thinking why I couldn't fall in love with her.
Guess what, I just did.
Way to go, m'lad!
Bless you!
I'll go tell her!
Congratulations!
Congratulations, Ammi Begum!
Mission a success!
He said he's ready to marry Jiya!
He's fallen for her!
What?
Aren't you all happy?
You left the door open, Dastoor Ahmed!
Just a sec!
Congratulations!
Congratulations, Ammi Begum!
Mission a success!
He said he's ready to marry Jiya!
Maheen...
I don't have an affair with Jiya.
Keep up with that arrogance and someone else will get her hands on him!
The twit...
The handsome twit...
Not so fast, Munshi Alam!
You're not going outside!
Let him play solo cricket for now...
Let's enjoy the match...
I ain't going out to play or something.
I'm going to the dry cleaner to get Mr Dastoor's clothes.
To the devil with his clothes!
No one wanders close to that lad!
We're sending him to Coventry!
I don't think he has any business there.
Besides, I'm pretty sure he can go on his own if he wants.
D'you even know what it means to send someone to Coventry, you nyaff?
Isn't someone howling too much?
I still remember your quiet face before your marriage.
I almost thought you're mute!
I'm gonna strike you off the will! You ain't getting a bit of my property, movable or immovable!
If my life is spared, may I speak freely? Something important.
Hmph!
You'd say
Something important!
You can't say unless you've heard it, can you?
Go on.
If he doesn't want to marry Jiya,
Is it that hard to ask him
Who he'd rather marry?
What if he named some Mary, Jane, or Susie?
Aye?
He'd name her.
Not get married right away.
To be honest,
He's got a point, Ammi Begum.
Ammi Begum!
Ali's here!
Quickly!
Stop him!
Don't let him inside the lawn!
Double time!
Aye...
Heya, partner...
I see you're up to some solo cricket.
No, mate...
Dado refused to play.
Stopped Munshi Alam and Aunt too.
What are we for?
Gonna play cricket first thing you're back from school, eh, you muppet?
I've done my duty, Dado.
No one can stop me.
You'd play with this loafer, this wastrel?
He's a proper knave, I tell you!
No way you're playing with this London tramp. C'mon.
Whoa, Dado...
Remember how you'd kiss his picture before he got here?
I'd rather spit in his face now.
'Owdy, Nano!
'Ow' what?
(She says hi.)
C'mon, you twit!
Inside!
Not so fast, Nano!
Got a match lined up!
A proper good one at that! We're playing for 10 gee!
Against?
Him.
When'd that happen?
He called.
You twits decide everything over the phone, don't you?
You'd disobey me...
And learn gambling from this professional spieler?
C'mon.
We ain't gambling, Nano!
It's a prize for the winner and a punishment for the loser!
Lemme go already!
Get the lawyer, Munshi Alam.
I'm finishing the deed of disownment before their match is finished.
May I leave?
Get the lawyer ASAP.
No.
I can't stand by you in this crime.
What'd you say?
I mean it, Ammi Begum.
Watch your mouth, Munshi Alam!
You ain't going to the dry cleaner either.
I'm not.
I'm going to play cricket in the lawn.
I've chipped in 1,000 for the prize too.
You?
Aye, me.
Aye, Nano?
You comin' for the match against him, you twit?
Just a sec!
He's challenged me! We're playing for 10 gee!
He challenged me too.
Playing today is tantamount to staging a coup against Kaneez Begum!
Really?
Everyone's in on it with him!
And the little ones,
The wee kids...
The snakes in the grass are accosting me...
Adamant to play today.
Not to mention
Good old
Munshi Alam.
The blighter has joined the ranks of the enemy!
Fair enough!
Eh?
They're all up in revolt!
Aye...
I can see that...
This calls for some proper politics.
Edicts and decrees don't work in affaires de cœur.
You advising me or telling me
That I'm wrong about the kids?
That I take the wrong decisions for them?
It's not like that.
I just mean -- Don't stand in the way of love.
Love doesn't bother how powerful Kaneez Begum can be.
Watch your tongue, Maheen Aurangzeb.
Fear that London tramp.
He schemes more subtly and strikes more savagely than the East India Company!
I look into his eyes every day
And see through him.
The blighter's looking for someone.
Who?
It'll upset your world if you heard her name...
Just tell me if you're playing today.
If you are, you better not set foot in here again.
He loses his share of my wealth, and you of my love.
Hello? Aye?
I got your text.
A certain Kaneez Begum was to call.
Maybe
About your marriage?
So?
She...
Didn't.
She will.
Okay.
I thought
She was to call yesterday.
It's about marriage.
Takes time.
Aye.
I can understand.
Okay, if she
Talks to you...
What'd you say?
I'll say
I accept.
Fine.
By the way...
Could you send the boy's picture?
Could I see his face for once?
You don't need a picture.
He'll be with her.
See him all you want when they visit.
Okay... A -- Alright...
Okay.
Bye.
Guard! Open the gate!
C'mon.
Where to?
Get in. I'll tell you. Quick.
I'll call you back...
Neelam!
Neelam?
Monsieur?
Where's Neelam?
Madame just left.
For?
No idea.
Alright. Go.
Her phone's switched off!
Maheen!
Boo!
I saw you coming.
Thought I'd have some fun.
You better not.
We've got a few things to talk about.
Whoa...
That sounds frightening...
I wouldn't dare...
Look carefully...
I'm the more frightened.
Know what,
I took you into my lap when you were young.
You slipped and fell on the floor.
I got an earful. That's when I started fearing you.
Guess what,
Nano says I've got a screw loose
Because of the fall!
What are you looking at?
When you were young...
You always...
Looked lovely smiling.
Do or die, partner.
Ammi Begum ain't surrendering before this here brat.
Who'd you call a brat?
Ooh...
I get it.
Go.
Get her.
Very funny.
She doesn't listen to me.
She does as she wants.
Hmph!
Not good enough.
Lose to Maheen and you've won against Ammi Begum.
What?
I mean, get going already!
Bring her along!
Tell her she's got to play this challenge.
Like she'd listen to me! Wow...
She'd say something that'll make me never want to see her again!
She'd say something?
Just...
Let her.
If you took it quietly,
Don't you think she'd be embarrassed?
I know her.
She ain't that cruel.
Okay.
Come with me?
C'mon, partner.
Why d'you need our support?
Get me the keys --
-M. Waqar...
Mlle Jiya's here.
What do I tell her?
Did you tell her I'm here?
You're outta your mind!
Stark raving mad, all of you!
I...
I know what your silence means.
I know what asking for time means.
I know what leaving my birthday party means...
They all know too.
But that's how we are.
We'd rather blindfold ourselves
Hoping to walk down the road we dream of.
Right now, you're the only one who can lead us down it.
You want to hear my answer?
I want you to give us... Yourself.
I beg you in the name of love.
Who doesn't know
Love and life aren't given out of charity.
But I like to delude myself
That I can get both.
You've got the right to refuse, but
I was determined
To ask in a way
That'd leave no option.
♪ Love's testimony is not to be asked of it ♪
♪ It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes... ♪
I don't love him, Neelam.
If you did,
I wouldn't be begging you here.
You'd be begging to be his instead.
Alright,
What'd you do if I were him and he were me?
You love someone else?
No.
Alright...
So...
Ever
Gone to buy a book
But felt like buying a perfume instead?
Aye...
Not this time.
Get the blimmin' book.
Just for once...
Have a look at one page. Just one page.
If you think you made the wrong choice...
Get any perfume you like.
Wow...
Way to shoo Jiya away!
I didn't shoo her away, mate.
I said I'm not home.
I'll see her tomorrow.
By the way, know what, Dado called her.
She's sent a proposal.
What?
You heard me.
What'd she say?
What d'you think?
She seems only too excited.
Blimey.
What?
Don't you think I ought to get married?
D'you even know what it means to be 'only too excited'?
Go on.
She loves you.
Oh, please.
For real!
Your friendship
Was never just that.
It was love at first sight!
She'd die for you.
Ooh.
Then, I'm sorry to say,
She's dead.
But where are we headed?
We'd get ladies' perfume and some white flowers first...
Why?
Well...
I thought I'd make peace with Maheen, mate.
Really?
Aye.
I figured conflict's costing me too much.
Making friends with her will sort everything out with Dado.
You mean it, don't you?
I mean it.
Yes!
Why aren't you home, Suraiyya?
I'm out shopping for groceries.
Get back, you twit!
The world's about to end!
What happened, Ammi Begum?
The London tramp, you know?
Yeah?
Me giddy Aunt...
You and your blasted 'Yeahs'! He's about to make peace with Maheen!
That's great news, Ammi Begum!
They're ready to bury the hatchet!
I'm putting you on jankers when you're here!
Get back right away, you twit!
Stop him!
Stop him?
Just tell him it's Ammi Begum's orders.
He can't see Maheen.
What are you saying?
He's my nephew.
Forget everything about it.
Forget that you even know someone by the name of Waqar.
For the love of God, Ammi Begum...
For the love of God, Suraiyya...
You'd be begging for it if you don't.
The rest is up to you.
Wonder what you are doing here...
Just walking by.
Stopped when I saw you.
Good.
Go.
Sit.
Here.
I pour my heart into this diary.
Everything I can't even tell myself.
And everything
I've always wanted to tell you.
It's yours to read.
Forget reading it,
No one else dares even touch it.
Why me?
Once you've read it...
You'd believe too...
That when I ask for time...
I ain't really asking you...
I'm just asking myself...
I've written about Gulrez a lot in my diary.
'I want to fall in love with you, Gulrez'.
But I guess I never could...
Like -- Someone's jinxed us.
Or -- There's a wall between us.
Who?
I'd tell you if I knew.
But I think
It's just my mind... There's no one.
Yes or no, I've always thought about Gulrez.
Never anyone else.
There can't be anyone else.
Not possible.
Here.
Keep it with you.
I don't dare touch it either.
Take all the time you want
In one shot
And think over it.
He thinks I'm insulting him...
Innit?
-No...
He says you only need to ask...
And he'd give you a hundred years...
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV