Wait, Neelam.
I've got something I'd want you to listen to.
Today, all of you will have to listen.
Remember when you'd told me
That I'm your brother
Just like Gulrez was your brother?
Please, Neelam...
Just listen to me for once.
Come, Wali...
You should be here, too.
I'd grown quite close to Maheen...
But as soon as I found out
That he was her father...
The man
Who'd destroyed
My family...
I decided to get even with him...
Sometimes,
I'd pity her...
But then,
I'd listen to Mum's recorded cassettes
And
All my love for Maheen
Would change into bitter hatred.
I'd long thought
Of killing Maheen with the same weapon
That
Had been used to kill Mum...
Her handwriting...
The diary...
Maheen's diary...
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
All day, all night...
She'd be lost in that diary of hers...
At last, I found the man for the job...
That bloke
Was quite the expert...
He just
Needed one look at someone's handwriting
To create an exact copy...
And then...
I --
I looked for another diary.
Had him write the content I wanted...
'Maheen's diary' lying on the table...
Getting her
And her family
Out of their house...
And then provoking
Someone like you
So much that you couldn't resist reading the diary...
But my hard work...
My hard work...
Opened the door to every success...
But you were the best of them all.
You took the diary along, too!
I regret
That I've ruined Maheen,
But I'm glad that I've avenged Mum.
I loved Maheen so much,
And I'd battled myself to get to despise that love,
But when I'd won, I felt so much pity for Maheen
That I thought I'd call her,
And tell her that when we, enmeshed in unexpected trials, ask what our fault had been,
It helps to know
That besides the property,
One inherits the debt of the sins of one's father,
And, regrettably,
It is the upright children who have to pay it back.
You can come out now, Dad.
Your debts have been settled.
I've paid it back with the blood of my yearnings.
I...
Your daughter...
Maheen Aurangzeb?
You don't need to worry about anything.
Enjoy yourself.
Feel free to keep sinning.
When it's time to expiate,
The kids will take care of it, of course.
Otherwise, what good would your kids be?
Just a minute, Neelam...
Allow me.
I want to take Maheen along.
Where?
To Dado's.
I won't get forgiven without her testimony.
I promise I'll leave her here once I'm forgiven.
She hasn't got anywhere else to go.
Take her if she wants to go.
Thank you.
What should I say?
Won't you say that I was innocent even now?
You're not innocent, Waqar.
But you're no longer the one who's wronged Nano.
You had your reasons...
Don't worry.
You'd be acquitted if I said it to Nano.
Be happy that the next death's been postponed.
Why is she like that, Wali?
Like what?
Just once did he say, 'Come with me',
And she agreed?
It'd hurt you if I said something, Neelam...
Just say the truth, Wali.
It may be bitter,
But it wouldn't hurt me.
They love each other,
And Gulrez...
Gulrez had just jumped in to die...
Why didn't you get married?
Nano thinks you'd have a few kids by now.
And the eldest one would be
About five years old?
That's one thing I like about you.
You didn't get married.
You're staying here, aren't you?
I won't leave again.
Good for you.
You'd get your wish -
Become the chief of the gang and all...
Waqar Ahmed?
Come.
What were the portly guards at the gate doing?
Why didn't the wretches shoot him?
If you'd rather have an innocent man shot,
How'd you face Dad, Dado?
There, now!
The enemy's broken through the gates!
Dado...
Don't you dare touch my feet!
I walk on these two feet
To Gulrez Akhtar's grave!
And you!
Why did you bring him here?
Whoever's he to you?
He's my Uncle's son.
My cousin, Nano.
Get him out of here, Mehrunnisa!
Hand him a copy of the will
And say,
'Even a hundred years of your weeping'
'Will fail to moisten our arid eyes'!
He's not going out, Nano...
The poor man's innocent.
He'd been... Led astray...
Jiya had a diary just like mine made,
Had someone write what she wanted in my handwriting,
And kept it before his eyes for him to read.
If you read what Jiya had had written in the diary,
You, too, would feel that Maheen's cheating on Waqar!
He's got Jiya's recording.
I've listened to it.
It's all Jiya's fault.
Why did Jiya do all of this?
Jiya's gotten even
With Dad through me...
Who's Jiya?
Tehmina Khatun's daughter.
Her only child.
But you loved her, Waqar Ahmed!
Is the faith of those who love so frail?
Cared to ask him that?
Only the Lord will ask him about that, Nano!
What does he want now?
He's come to ask for forgiveness.
Alright.
Tell him I forgive him.
He may meet the others before leaving
He may come again
After I'm gone.
He's grown on Dastoor Ahmed.
Mehrunnisa,
Give me the yellow pill.
You take the yellow pill at night, Nano.
Why'd I take it at night
When I'm having this headache right now?
Forgive me, Dado...
For Gulrez's sake, forgive me...
Thus, before reaching the destination, I choose to take a detour
For those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart
Hello?
You're right, Wali.
She never loved Gulrez.
Neelam...
I've read both her diaries.
Hello? Neelam?
She's furious.
Just wait.
She may kick him any moment.
No, but there's an occasional grey hair on his head.
He still looks dashing.
Not one bit old.
No.
He's staying here.
I asked him in the car.
He said, 'I won't leave again'.
Obviously.
There's no grief left,
Nor any complaints of him.
'After all', I thought, 'He's my cousin'.
I'd have to listen to him if he became the chief!
So, I thought I'd get it straight with him.
Who are you talking to?
Ali.
Let me talk, too.
Ali...
Talk to Waqar.
Hello, partner.
Ali...
Ali?
It got disconnected.
No, Waqar Ahmed,
He hung up.
For a moment, I thought I'd kick him in the face,
Or call Dastoor and ask him
To call the police.
The police?
The blighter was guilty of breaking and entering.
He may have gotten a terrorism charge on his head.
What's up over there?
Maheen had brought him in, with his hand in hers.
When the guard stopped him,
She scolded him,
'Can't you see'
'He's with me'?
Blimey...
I was shocked.
I felt as if
She won't even forgive him on the Day of Judgement.
As it turned out,
She softened at the sight of him.
She's bubbling from within!
It's been wisely said,
'A girl never forgets'
'Her first love'.
I'm afraid of her,
Her fresh smile...
Her holding his hand for the first time...
-No, Suraiyya...
She's had mercy after hearing that story about Jiya.
She had me listen to the entire recording.
Hearing it, I felt
That all debts have been settled.
It's
All over now.
Don't worry.
She's happy now.
Her gait's lively.
She's put on a dupatta instead of a cloak again.
Wait and watch.
In a few days,
She'd be back to playing cricket, too.
Ali would be back in about a month.
Fajr, too,
Would be back by next year.
She'd stay here, too.
That
Leaves us two players short...
One from their side,
And one from ours.
Are you talking about Waqar and Gulrez?
I'm talking about Gulrez.
That other cove, I'm just mentioning
The way that wretched Oliver Cromwell's mention
Follows King Charles'.
It'd be good riddance if he just left.
And, given how he's been treated here, hopefully, he would've left already.
Has he dropped her?
Yes.
Blimey, look at her...
Got in his car so quickly.
Well, she's their responsibility.
She would've gotten in with him only if they'd allowed her.
Find out
If she's gotten back or if he's led her into having dinner or something.
No.
She's gotten back.
Did you call her?
No.
I found out
When he got back.
Got back?
He got back here?
He set foot inside?
Yes...
Did you have him sit?
No, Ammi Begum.
He went to his room without sitting or saying anything.
His room?
He --
The blighter's here!?
He's staying in a room at Kaneez Mahal?
Throw him out right now, Dastoor Ahmed!
Throw him out!
Out!
Wali...
Where's Maheen?
In her room?
She's not in her room.
Alright, I'll go and check.
Come to me
My heart beckons to you
Weary of weeping and wailing
Save my love from this calumny
Come to me
My heart beckons to you
Weary of weeping and wailing
Save my love from this calumny
Come to me
The grim reaper approaching
My life changed course towards you
As the evening of our separation went by
The longing to meet started stinging at me.
This heart grows anxious
Pay me a visit in my dreams sometime
Come to me
My heart beckons to you
Weary of weeping and wailing
Save my love from this calumny
Come to me...
Dastoor Ahmed!
I was at the door.
I thought I'd be here the moment you call.
I'd like some tea.
-Before you've rinsed your mouth?
As if the English care about such trifles...
We have tea first.
Get me tea.
Has he left?
I'm talking about that blighter.
What are you looking at? Just tell me he's left.
There he is.
At your feet.
He's been there all night.
Good Lord...
The twit knows every trick to give someone a fright.
Wake him up, Dastoor Ahmed.
He may get a stiff neck.
Waqar!
Get up. Ammi Begum's worried you may get a stiff neck.
-Just wake him up.
No need to tell him what Ammi Begum says.
Dado...
What are you looking at, Dastoor Ahmed?
Get him out of my sights.
Drag him away if you have to.
Come.
Take it that you're not getting forgiven.
Just a second --
Just a second, Dastoor Uncle.
I swear by you, Dado.
If I left this time,
I'm never coming back.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV