He's gone, Maheen!
Mum insulted him so much he won't even be there at the wedding!
Whose wedding?
Yours. And mine!
God, her barbs! She literally asked him to just say goodbye and leave!
She even asked the servant to take away his teacup!
She didn't.
I swear she did!
You've all just got one for theatrics!
You should be happy. Love without enemies is as bland as an arranged marriage!
That's what bothers me! No open enemies!
What d'you want? Everyone out guns blazing?
I want a storm that may almost kill us!
What?
Lock us up!
Don't let us meet - or see each other's face!
And when we get caught meeting in secret --
-Yeahhh?
Imprison me in here! Lock the doors!
And what about him?
He's a man. I'm sure he can take a proper beating.
You off your head?
Not any more than your average lover!
I mean, just imagine for a moment...
Uncle Dastoor...
Munshi Alam...
Waqar Ahmed...
And Gulrez...
All of 'em giving him a proper pasting!
And he...
Wounded, bleeding,
Chanting my name,
Banging his head outside our place!
Screaming -
'I'd die without my Maheen! I'll kill myself'!
Blimey, Fajr... We'll be all over the news! Just imagine!
Where are you off to?
I'm late for Uni!
Is he there?
I heard
Him march in...
Climb the stairs,
And hole up in his room...
I
Even heard him slam the door.
What happened?
I've insulted him so much he won't forget for ages.
Lovely.
Please tell me
You didn't let them see each other.
What are you saying, Ammi Begum! He tried looking up, but I stopped him.
'Don't you dare look up there'!
Lovely. Well done.
And the girl?
What's up with her?
She's in her room.
Hurt by his wounds.
She didn't even go to University today!
Don't let her if she wanted to.
What?
Why not?
Tell her she's not needed there.
Not cricket, Ammi Begum.
What about her studies?
So much has happened for that to matter...
I mean, who bothers study in love?
But if she went to University, they'll get a chance to see each other.
That's right...
But it's her last semester.
It's the last thing on her lovesick mind, Suraiyya... Never forget that.
I pity him though...
He looked so frightened...
Blimey, Ammi Begum... I almost teared up!
Have some shame...
You're getting in the way of my word.
Everyone up there in the Heavens
Would be cursing you at this moment!
If I got Gulrez Akhtar's fiancée
Married to Waqar Ahmed,
I'd earn their curses too!
So forget it
And save yourself from disgracing the departed.
Or, when it is my time,
No one would look at me the right way...
Hang up, now...
And face the wretched lovers with all your might!
Hi!
No 'Hi' or 'Hello's here.
Greet properly if you have to, young man.
Peace, Aunt.
Hmm.
Ammi Begum's forbidden me from wishing you peace.
How'd you like that?
Put him in his place!
Have some shame, Mehrunnisa...
'Put him in his place'...
Did you have to say
I forbade you?
Why couldn't you say,
'I don't want to talk to you'?
That'd put him in his place
And show me you're standing by me
And keeping my word.
Tell me, Mehrunnisa...
Don't you pity Gulrez?
I do, Ammi Begum.
A lot, in fact.
But it's all Maheen's fault!
It's not her fault.
This blighter
Knows every trick to charm hearts.
His time with his English roses
Has earned him
Quite the experience!
Ahh...
No one loves the 'experienced', Ammi Begum!
One look at them and you know
They're 'experienced'!
They both look like complete newbies to me!
They're scared...
Yet so unafraid...
Hello?
What is it?
I've been going through your letters.
What is it now?
You don't get it...
I read these over and over again...
I love them so much.
You've read them so many times.
You didn't write anything in this one...
Just... Her name...
Nothing more, nothing less...
And at the bottom... 'Yours, Gulrez'?
D'you know
When I wrote that one?
When?
The day she said,
'Looking at you, it seems'
'You want to say something'...
Why didn't you tell her?
That's when I found out
I can't say anything to her.
You're mad.
Am I?
What d'you think I should've said?
'I love you'!
Of course!
What's funny here?
The helplessness of love...
I swear, Neelam...
Imagine the helplessness of the love
That needs you to say in so many words...
'I love you'...
Anyway...
Here's an idea...
Hmm?
Keep that letter...
And burn the rest.
Why?
I feel like it's the only one that matters...
The rest are just... Useless...
Anyway, get back to work...
Tell me...
Yeah?
Why'd you call me?
Just --
Thought I'd have a chat...
Check on you and see if you're working hard!
I swear
I'm working very hard.
Don't worry.
I love you.
I love you too.
Why don't you marry Gulrez?
I don't like him.
But he's good.
Perhaps better than him.
Give me his number.
Hey!
Like, for real?
Just give me his number.
I'll talk to him right away.
What'd you say?
What else?
Show some sympathy...
And tell him not to grieve.
Show him he can fix his broken heart with another girl.
I'm at your service if you don't mind!
Whoa, you're shameless!
Not more than you!
You're passing me the lover you rejected?
Gee, Jiya...
I'm so worried...
I fear he may curse me!
I would too!
Hey!
Why would you?
For a while, I actually thought Waqar could be mine once you're married off to Gulrez.
But you robbed me of the glory [Waqar] of the moment in a flash!
I swear I've got no idea
How it happened
Or why...
No idea at all...
But love's a virus
That strikes the healthiest of girls!
Started seeing him yet?
I doubt I ever will.
I mean, just look at Mum's fury! She looks like she'd rip me apart!
And Nano! God forgive her!
She's boycotting us both!
She said, 'No one's talking to them'!
And, 'Don't even greet them back'!
Oh, really?
I'm sure you've called each other.
I swear we haven't.
I don't dare.
Why?
Honestly?
Hmm?
I'm a bit shy...
Hey!
What happened?
Just a minute...
There!
Mum just locked me in!
You know, it's so romantic!
I love it!
Mehrunnisa!
Suraiyya's locked her in!
What d'you mean?
Locked her in her room!
Ahh...
Sent her to Coventry!
What'd she do there?
Oh, can it...
You know, as they say in English...
A boycott...
I'm talking about that!
She will stay in that room,
Locked until she accept's Gulrez's proposal.
She ain't gettin' out!
Don't believe me?
I do, Ammi Begum...
But I pity you a bit too...
Wonder which lad out there's got the nerve to pity me.
They call me Kaneez Begum.
And they call her Maheen Aurangzeb.
She'd make mincemeat of you and Suraiyya and cut you down to size!
Oh, I'm looking forward to the battle, Mehrunnisa...
I'm looking forward to the day they see just how ruthless Kaneez Begum can be.
Fair enough... Let's see...
Please, do...
And tell everyone about it after I'm gone...
That Kaneez Begum
Could behead for her family's honour,
But never compromise.
Hmm...
What'd you do
If...
She didn't have dinner?
Okay...
I know your cold heart's too numb to feel that...
But what if
She took a handful of sleeping pills?
They say
They work best
Without food.
I'm sure she can take four...
But
I'm not so sure about the fifth...
What if she accidentally
Took six...?
I'm sorry, Ammi Begum...
What d'you mean, 'I'm sorry'?
Curse my tongue.
Just --
Ask Suraiyya
To have a doctor at the ready.
I'm sure it's nothing to worry about...
She's a smart and educated girl.
Surely, she'd never even think about taking six...
Good Lord...
Ahh...
First... Promise me
What you see and hear here
Stays in here. Between us.
I promise...
These are the letters
He's been writing to Maheen for the last ten years
But never sent to her.
Could you
Go through them... Just once?
Honestly?
I never wanted to fall for her.
I'm sure she never wanted to fall for me either.
So I don't need these letters...
One look at you tells me just how much he loves Maheen.
I swear, I'm not in the way of his love.
His love's the only one standing in his way.
Could you --
Think about it...
And tell me - If I forgot everything and went to London,
Do you think she'd accept Gulrez's proposal?
Why'd you ever come back?
She stopped me.
I couldn't go on.
Just refuse.
Just say --
'I don't love you'... Or even...
'I hate you'!
I can say I don't love her...
But not...
That I hate her...
Wait.
Don't leave just yet...
Sit...
I'm very cruel, ain't I?
Not one bit.
A sister's love, like a mother's, is 100% selfish.
Know what, Neelam...
I'm ashamed of myself...
I think...
If I married Maheen before Gulrez's eyes...
How could I look him in the eye as I take her with me?
Your pained groan would curse me.
You're my sister too...
Who'd want his sister's curse?
Look... I've never seen her -- Never talked about anything...
So tell me...
Think carefully...
When I see her...
What d'you want me to say?
I mean, I need a punchline
That I say
And she leaves, spitting in my face!
What are you doing? Easy there...
For my sake...
You're disgracing me in my own eyes.
I guess I'll have to come up with something myself.
May the Lord help me say something so bitter
She'd kick me out of the country the moment she heard it.
You have my word...
I may not be like Gulrez...
But I'm your brother...
No...
For my sake... Not another tear...
Just --
Give me two days... I'll show you what I can do.
What are you gonna do?
Tell her
I hate her.
I swear.
But promise me...
Come what may,
You won't tell Gulrez anything.
C'mon. I want your word!
Now you're suckin' diesel.
If I don't see you before leaving for London...
Just know the job's done.
Bye.
C'mon, mun, say goodbye!
Keep it there
And leave.
Not so fast.
Take it back.
What?
I ain't eatin' anything.
Then remember,
You won't get food when you want.
I'm callin' the shots here.
Keep on with your cruelty. Don't tell me how to react.
Fair enough.
You won't get anything until 9 p.m.
Guess what, I ain't havin' anything at 9 either.
You intend to starve yourself in here?
Ain't your problem.
Listen here, girl...
If you think this is gonna make me have mercy,
You're very wrong!
No mercy!
That's what I want!
You locked me in.
I choose to starve myself.
You should be happy.
I'm helping you be doubly cruel.
Keep at it and you'll die in here!
Wow...
How romantic!
Romantic!?
Stay tuned...
It'll be a sight to behold when my pall is lifted...
It'll be all over the telly!
I can almost see your and Nano's picture on either side of ours...
I swear,
They're gonna blow you all to bits!
A poor girl
And her poor lover...
Thanks to these two...
Who conspired to kill 'em!
To the dickens with them!
And what are you waiting for? Take it away!
Out!
Don't let the door hit you...
Don't worry.
Don't forget the lock the door behind you.
Who's this for?
Maheen...
She refused.
Peace, Mum.
To you too.
Is Maheen okay?
Perfectly.
Why'd you send the food to her room? Can't she come down here?
She can't.
Shut up.
Why not?
N -- No way I'm stayin' quiet...
S -- She's locked her in her room!
And hid the key in her scarf.
What?
She sent some food for her, but Maheen refused to have anything.
Go.
And take that away!
No one else is gonna answer the phone.
Hello?
I hope she's had lunch.
No.
Don't be so cruel... Give her something.
But how?
She refused it!
Don't worry...
Hunger will make her have second thoughts...
She won't.
She scolded Qutb
And asked him not to bring her dinner.
I hope you heard that.
Of course...
Surely...
She's got no sleeping pills around?
Aye.
She's always got them.
What are you saying?
Only the truth.
Why'd you ask about sleeping pills?
I'm off my head...
They say
They work best without food... They don't need a moment...
So they do...
You twit...
Hang up right now
And keep her away from them!
Heavens...
And...
Yeah?
Unlock the door. Let her go where she wants.
We give up?
We ease her.
But never
Give up like that.
Stay tuned...
I'm comin' up with something so baffling, so powerful...
It'll scare away all this fear of sleeping pills...
Enough for now...
Don't tarry about!
How long d'you think she'd need to take a few?
Okay...
So, what d'you think?
Don't you think
It's all so... Theatrical?
What?
You know... How...
You're about to kill your selfless love for Gulrez?
And leave for the other end of the world?
The only thing that's left
Is you taking the blame for her.
Don't even think about it. She knows her films.
Shut up, Jiya...
Although...
It ain't all that theatrical...
What?
You know she'd actually be green with envy at the sound of your name? A while back.
So?
So...
How 'bout we make her greener?
How?
Blimey, Sherlock...
If she saw me flirting with you, don't you think she'd kick me out herself?
Why'd you flirt with me?
With anyone else,
She'd know I'm faking it.
Oh...
So you're gonna slander me to convince her?
Guess what,
All the writers try their best to show that the hero's innocent.
'Poor lad'... 'Sacrificing his love'...
They don't know
It's the girl he fakes it with
Who's sacrificing something for real.
No, sweetheart.
I won't be her.
I'm sorry, Jiya... I didn't mean it.
I just wanted you to help me out.
Okay...
I'll try something...
So...
You just want to be out of her life somehow, yes?
Aye.
Simple. How 'bout you marry me?
How 'bout going the whole nine yards
And leaving me with your sacrificed hide?
It's all I'll be content with...
So...
You just want to be out of her life somehow, yes?
Simple. How 'bout you marry me?
Don't go anywhere, Waqar... For my sake...
Just refuse.
Just say --
'I don't love you'... Or...
Even...
'I hate you'!
Maheen?
Maheen!
Translation: Aditya Misra Â© GEO TV