Punish me any way you like.
But, before you do anything...
Just... Hear me out... For once?
I just did.
That's enough for today.
I'll hear the rest if we see each other another day.
Have it your way...
I hope...
That you never come here again.
Only a father
Could come back
After being
Kicked out so many times!
Close the door!
Playin' alone, I see!
Where's
Mr Fracture?
No idea.
Hi!
Hmm!
I guess you're over the grief of your injury by now.
I guess you've got a taste of how it feels by now.
It's a minor fracture. It'll heal.
It was a minor bruise. It healed.
If it's healed...
Brace yourself for the next one.
Why didn't you go after him?
For the love of the Lord, Neelam...
He ran like he wasn't Gulrez...
But a spirit!
Okay, I'll call him.
No good.
He left his phone in my car.
He was in a hurry.
Good Lord...
You're worried, aren't you?
Of course!
So am I.
What's he gonna do?
You'll find out in a few minutes...
My heart's sinking!
It's nothing like that.
Don't worry.
You know where he's gone, don't you?
Aye.
He's betting everything he's got.
What?
The way I did...
And won.
What are you saying, Wali?
Just pray he plays his move and wipes the floor with his opponent.
Oh...
You mean he's gone to see Maheen?
You are so intelligent!
It's so simple, Wali.
When Gulrez's type bet everything,
They play a gamble where the first move is the only one that's legal.
I'll talk to you later...
Got to pray for now...
Gulrez!
What's with the panting?
No --
Just --
Had to dash...
Where's Aunt?
Aunt and Maheen ain't here.
Go to my room.
I'll get you a cuppa. And some kebabs.
No...
No kebabs...
Just the cuppa.
She made them!
Really?
Gotta try 'em, I guess!
Where were you all these days?
Where were you?
Me or her?
It was no good, really.
My paying a visit won't change nothin' here.
As if my paying a visit would.
Which bowler thinks if he's got the wicket before throwing the ball?
Just throw the ball, mun!
That's why I'm here.
I'm gonna bowl a yorker
That'll take the wicket!
Now you're suckin' diesel, man!
I hope... She won't mind it?
Mind?
Why are you worried about that?
No...
I don't...
Just remembered... She breaks stuff in her fury...
She does, aye.
That's why we never leave any vases in her room!
Scared yet?
No vases...
No fear.
By the way...
May I call her? I'm sure I can tell her everything.
No way.
You can say it,
But she can't know your feelings!
Aye...
I never thought about that...
And...
It looks a bit... Shameless, to be honest...
But I think... I'd seize her hand and pull her into a corner...
Who told you it looks shameless?
Seize her hand, pull her into a corner, and say...
Thought anything?
-What?
What are you gonna tell her?
You're underestimating me... I've thought of the finest things to say!
Then stay here! She'll be back in two hours!
Two hours?
She's gone shopping. It's Jiya's birthday.
Oh...
Good...
By the way...
Didn't you go to college?
Just one class today.
Thought I'd skive off.
Very bad.
Where's Aunt?
At Nano's.
Great.
What?
You scared of her too?
No, it's just --
If I seized her hand...
Aye?
I'd die of shame if Aunt saw me!
You don't know anything, do you?
Aunt would be delighted to see it!
She's waiting for you to play your move!
Guess
That's your kebabs!
Could you show me that one?
This one, ma'am?
-No, the other one.
5,500.
I don't care. Pack it.
And this orange one!
Excuse me...
Yes, sir?
How much for this one?
It's sold out. Except the blue one.
No, I want the orange one.
She just bought it.
Not yet, she didn't.
Maheen?
I almost thought it's your doppelgänger.
If you've bought it, okay, I'll get something else.
Forget it.
Or sell it
To whoever you want.
5,500?
Yes.
Here.
Excuse me!
What's your problem?
Wanted to tell you something.
And say sorry for the slap.
Say it's okay quick or they'll think there's something going on between us!
Shut up!
I've asked the cook to have dinner ready by 1.30.
No... I think I'll pass.
But she won't.
She said she wants lunch ready by 1.30!
By the way,
Why won't you have anything?
I say, fill yourself up before she gets here.
Eat like an SIL eats at his in-laws.
Hold your horses, Fajr.
Not so fast!
I mean it.
Any opportunity could be your last, Gulrez!
As they say in the Army...
'You can get in, but there's no getting out'!
Where'd you learn that?
There...
What?
It doesn't suit you!
I mean, you're just a wee girl!
Oh, please, Gulrez,
I ain't all that wee!
I see a man's face
And I know what's on his mind.
Every wee girl grows up fast
Thanks to the cads.
A couple of 'em have asked for my number too. For real!
Please, Fajr...!
Swear to me...
What?
1.30... Or 2.30...
You ain't leavin' before talkin' to her!
Blimey...
We're all wasting ourselves,
Grieving for you, but you!
You don't seem to care!
I mean, gather some courage, mun!
I've got a lot of courage. And when the time comes, you'll see it!
Well, guess what, the time's come. But it'll go after 1.30.
What?
I mean... Hide somewhere in the lobby as soon as it's 1.30.
Why?
Jesus, mun...
She'd be back at 1.30, Sherlock!
So?
The moment she sets foot here,
Seize her hand and pull her into a corner!
Oh...
I get it now, mate...
The name's Fajr!
Okie doke, Fajr...
Just wait for 1.30...
Yes!
That's like the brave man you are!
Thought I'd come shopping. Jiya's throwing a party tonight. It's her birthday.
That wastes my shopping.
How?
I wouldn't be caught dead there. Not with you around!
She's your friend! Your best buddy!
Anyway, enjoy the coffee... I'm paying.
I can pay for my cup, thank you!
Alright, honestly...
Are you just angry over the slap or do you actually hate me?
Honestly?
I've got no idea
If it's just a bit of anger or if I actually hate you.
Why'd you come here for coffee then?
You asked me.
You said you'd say sorry.
It felt kinda nice.
Sorry...
Say that you're ashamed...
And you shouldn't have slapped me.
The Colonel would've thrown us in the nick if I didn't slap you!
Still...
You shouldn't have slapped me.
Okay, I shouldn't have. Fine?
Hmm.
What 'hmm'?
Say it's okay!
Promise me
I'll be the Chief
As long as I live.
How long will that be?
Shut up!
Don't worry, Madame...
I ain't here for long.
I'd leave as soon as you get married...
I get married?
Pretty soon, yeah.
Don't act like you don't know it.
Poor old Gulrez is dying for you.
And aye,
I saw him running...
He said he was going to see you.
Said he'd give the news in 10 minutes.
Running?
Wasn't he in his Foxy?
The blighter's in for it.
Why?
For loving you?
Know what the mannies say in London?
They say you better not let her know you've fallen for her,
Or she'd kill you off where you won't have an ounce of relief.
He sent you?
Who?
C'mon mate, I was just shopping when I happened to see you!
Anyway...
So... Aren't you serious about Gulrez?
Is there someone else?
Please, Waqar...
Just askin' as a friend!
When'd we become friends?
How 'bout just now? Not a big deal!
So...?
C'mon!
Your hand's gone a bridge too far.
No?
Mind your hand, Waqar...
They're all watching!
Since you've brought it up... Mind if I say something?
You won't find someone like Gulrez.
He'd die for you.
Okay, bye!
Gulrez!
She here?
No. It's 1.35.
Hide in the lobby! She'd be on her way!
Ah, yes.
And hey...
Don't worry.
I'll take care of everything else.
You would?
How?
Anyway...
Don't worry.
I'll face it all.
Come what may!
Hello? Maheen?
Did Gulrez get there?
He's right here. Just had lunch.
Where's Mum?
At Nano's.
When'd he get there?
No idea.
Something special?
Definitely.
He's waiting for you.
He said he's here to see you.
He seems serious this time!
And - I mean it - very brave!
Brave?
Aye, like a bowler
Who takes a good look at the ball before throwing it?
Determined to claim a wicket this time?
That's what he looks like.
He even told me, 'You underestimate me, Fajr'!
Where's he?
In the lobby.
Wherever he is, he's waiting for you.
Tell him to come over to Nano's.
That's where I'm headed.
Gulrez!
Blimey, mate...
You made me jump.
What are you doing here?
1.45!
Come.
Where?
I'm waiting!
No need now.
She's waiting for you now.
Where?
Come with me.
Let's work on plan B.
Plan B?
What about plan A?
She's gone over to Nano's.
She ain't coming here.
Please, sit down.
You came here to do something, yes?
I just told you.
Then remember...
You won't get this chance again.
What chance?
When you're determined to strike when the iron's hot,
It's do
Or die!
Over to Nano's now?
So intelligent!
I'll seize her hand before everyone,
And pull her into a corner!
I'm gonna remember that the next time someone says, 'Gulrez hasn't got the guts'!
I say that...
I ain't that brave.
I can strike from the lobby.
Not over there.
Thank you for the lunch.
It was very nice.
Does she know I'm here?
Aye.
Who told her?
Me.
Did you tell her how long I've been waiting?
Aye.
She still went to Nano's?
Jesus, mate! You and your questions!
Didn't I just tell you?
It ain't a question, mate.
I'm just... Reflecting on it... And her...
I'm trying to guess
What'd happen if I struck
When the iron's hot.
I swear...
It'd burn me...
Bye.
He said sorry...
And that he shouldn't have slapped me.
Then took me out for coffee,
And extended a hand, saying,
'Let's be friends'!
And?
What?
I said, 'back off'.
Hmm...
As in, 'No way we're making friends'...
Yes!
Spiffing, m'girl.
Making friends with the enemy amounts to surrender.
Who knows you better than me?
You fight
To win.
Right.
Hey!
If he wants to make friends,
What's the problem, Ammi Begum?
The wretch's a proper London tramp.
Who knows what he means by 'friendship'!
Hey...
If he extends his hand again,
Let him have a taste of yours!
What are you saying?
You live for the sound of his name, Ammi Begum.
But when he wants to make friends with her, he suddenly becomes your enemy!
Put a sock in it, Mehrunnisa.
Oh, please...
I'm not a kid.
I know him inside out.
Nano's right.
The London tramp
Is friends with God-knows how many girls.
I don't think he's the type.
No way Mashood Ahmed's son is that type.
Don't pronounce a judgement just yet.
Upbringing changes people.
No one's guessing anything here.
I'm just reading what he said.
What?
Not long ago, he was telling Gulrez here...
'Tales of love aren't heard of'
'Outside India and Pakistan'.
'In London',
'We have'
'"Friendships"'...
Hey!
He was telling Gulrez a lot about his 'friendships'.
The poor lad left begging forgiveness!
Good Lord...
That what he's like?
I tell you,
This lad's gonna trouble Mashood's soul... Not give it some peace...
Don't say that, Ammi Begum...
Blimey...
You don't have to look far.
On his way back from London --
What's her name?
Your friend, you know?
Jiya?
Aye, her.
He brought her along.
I hear they talk on the phone for hours.
Sees her in private too.
His injured arm...
Aye?
Who d'you think he went to see in that state?
Who?
That blasted lassie, of course.
No way, Nano.
She ain't the type.
They just met on the plane
And became friends at my mention.
I'm 75 now, girl...
I can see right through a girl 75 feet away.
Anyway...
What's it to us?
Whether Jiya's that type or not...
God keep her happy.
It's her birthday today.
Is it?
Happy birthday to her.
You going?
No.
Why?
Didn't you go shopping for her party?
Stop speaking in English, for the love of the Lord!
Of course,
Ammi Begum.
So...
Why aren't you going, love?
Because he's going!
Perfect.
Let him go all alone, the blighted London tramp...
In the tale of love where do these turns come from...
Here's your 25,000!
We don't want a penny of it!
Your Foxy is parked on our porch.
Come and get it.
Does she know I'm here?
Aye.
She still went to Nano's?
Jesus, mate! You and your questions!
Didn't I just tell you?
That those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart...
'Alone on the abode of the Chosen,'
'As I was breathing my last,'
'With the memories of days past by my side,'
'As I was charting out the map of my life,'
'I was thinking...'
'For the sake of this life I have'
'Been through many hardships;'
'Endured many wounds inflicted on me'
'Battled many sorrows...'
'In exchange for this life,'
'Death used to scare me...'
'And my mother, credulous and naïve,'
'Would get affrighted...'
'A drop of dolour pinched me then,'
'A scratch darned a cleft then,'
'And said to me, Be quiet!'
'Every woe shall be auctioned;'
'Every scuff shall be chaffered;'
'For all the gloom you will brave,'
'For all the gashes you will take,'
'You shall be recompensed in full.'
You wrote that?
-Not fair, Neelam.
Why'd you steal it?
You twit! I didn't steal it!
I've just been reading... And... God, it's so sweet!
Why don't you read it to her?
Who?
-Maheen.
I swear, she'd be dying for your love.
Oh, please...
She'd rather laugh it off.
She'd say, 'Never thought the numbskull mime could rhyme'!
I went to see her.
Whoa!
And?
I almost gathered the courage to talk to her.
I was afraid, but swore I'd tell her everything.
Good! Did you tell her?
Tell who?
She ran off to her Nano's
The moment she found out I'd come to her place.
You could've gone to Nano's!
How?
I love her.
I'll face her. But never tail her!
Know what,
Love and poetry
Speak to the heart.
To someone so uninterested... Best to pocket the poetry part and lock the words in your heart.
Ain't she shining so bright?
Munshi Alam!
Aye?
Could you go with the driver and give it to Jiya?
If she asks about me... Just say -- I couldn't come.
What if she asked why?
Tell her you don't know.
And if she asks why my phone's switched off, tell her -- The situation forced me...
I'm not going to Jiya's birthday party.
Feel free to go there.
Munshi Alam!
Uhh...
Change of plans.
You guys enjoying here?
Have some juice. Please.
I'll be right back, okay?
Where are you?
Happy birthday, Jiya.
What?
Sorry I couldn't be there.
'Sorry' my foot!
Get here right now or I'm comin' to get you!
Stop it, mate... What about the guests?
I can't come. There. That's it.
Why?
Big deal, mate. Easy.
Yeah, big deal. Go on.
I'll say the same. I can't come.
Please, enjoy the party. And save some cake for me. I'll have it tomorrow.
You don't know me.
There's no party without you!
I'll send everyone back.
What? You crazy?
Is Maheen there?
Aye. So?
So, your best friend's there. What else d'you want?
I'm giving you 30 minutes. If you don't come, I'm sending your Maheen back.
No birthday. No celebration.
30 minutes or?
Hi! How are you, Sania?
Happy birthday!
Thank you so much!
Your time starts...
Your time starts... Now!
Ahoy, matey!
You're here?
Just called Waqar.
I mean --
He promised me he'd be here.
He'll be here.
We'll wait for 30 minutes.
Aww, thank you!
Good for Maheen, though.
She went to Nano's from the mall.
Or Gulrez's courage would be lying dead here.
Why?
You don't know it, Mum, but he was gasping for breath as he got closer to his moment!
He was having cold sweats too.
Stammering too.
And when he found out
Maheen's gone over to Ammi Begum's? What'd he say?
I said
He ought to go there and say it for all to hear!
Impossible.
That's what he said.
Sorta. Impossible.
The utter poltroon.
For a moment, I felt
He's not one.
He just...
Fears her rejection.
She won't.
She's just toying with him.
Translation: Aditya Misra Â© GEO TV