Hello!
Who is it?
I thought you'd recognise my voice.
Your voice
Sounds familiar.
You sound like my dirty rotten cousin.
Who are you?
Your dirty rotten cousin.
Hey!
How dare you call me?
Heard you cried that day. After the slap...
So?
I feel guilty.
Are you seriously 'so'-ing my sympathy?
Listen, Waqar Ahmed,
Don't you dare call me again.
You're not allowed. Get it?
Alright, but I've got one last thing to say to you...
Go on.
I hate you.
I HATE YOU TOOOOOO!!!
You blighter!
Six.
Again!
Everyone remembers the slap...
Including Dado!
But no one bothers to ask what she was gonna do.
She nicked the Colonel's puppy.
Big deal. It was so cute. We couldn't find another one like it.
C'mon, Fajr... We would've been in the nick for the next six months!
Why me? I was just a kid!
See?
What?
I leave home for a few days and you turn into pirates proper.
Easy, Waqar.
Dado and Uncle Dastoor are members too.
Dado doesn't even know
She stole the Colonel's puppy.
Aye, she'd only care about the slap...
Anyway... I slapped her... Big deal!
Does she have to be furious about it all her life?
I've been here four days.
She never even said hello.
She won't.
Like I care.
I just said because... It doesn't look proper.
I'd rather keep it between us.
If she keeps at it, I'll finish her where she won't have an ounce of relief!
Whoa...
Whoa what?
Goodness knows who she thinks she is... Her type are the maids in London!
Want me to tell her that?
Be my guest. Like I fear her.
You don't really have to though...
I just said it in a fit of rage...
By the way...
How much
Does the Gang have right now?
Hmm...
Not more than 2 grand.
2 grand in four years!
Wow...
Remember you had 90 grand when I left?
She ain't a good planner...
Not about money, at least. We almost got 50 gee from Dad,
But she opened the letter again just five minutes before, and started crying...
'I can't blackmail anyone in the name of love' and stuff...
What letter?
-Dad had a friend...
His classmate. She once wrote... 'Sorry, Dastoor, but I can't marry you'.
Followed by her entire story!
Ooh...
She also returned the 25 gee we got for the Foxy.
We'd worked so hard to get our hands on it.
Why? Had pity on Gulrez?
No. She got furious.
Over the engagement.
She virtually took the laddoo [sweet] from my mouth!
Gotta say...
Maheen ain't marrying Gulrez.
She will.
What it is is she loves to toy with her food before she eats it!
She'll have him sell the Foxy!
Blimey, mate...
He loves her!
She knows it too...
But she hates his Foxy.
Hmm...
'Hmm' what?
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV