You'd dance again today?
On leave today.
Tomorrow.
You'd dance at the wedding tomorrow?
I'd promised Fajr.
Have some shame.
Shame?
About what?
What do you want to prove?
That you don't have the slightest grief?
C'mon, mate.
I have a lot of grief.
But so what?
They're happy, and that's all that matters.
He's a friend... My elder brother.
And she's my cousin...
Ex-fiancée.
Shouldn't I be delighted?
A friend of mine, a doctor -
He says, 'If you have to brave some grief',
'Run a race'.
'Exercise'.
Someone said on TV yesterday
That dancing is the best workout.
Would you look at how intelligent I've become!
I can see that...
Tell me,
What'd you wear tomorrow? The same old suit?
No.
I've bought a new sherwani.
I'll don it and stand right next to the groom.
They'll be asking,
'Who's the groom'?
Everyone knows
Who the groom is.
I've heard you've met.
Care to tell what happened?
Just the usual. Chatting around...
Topped with a quarrel.
Another quarrel?
She doesn't forget the slap from four years ago, Dado...
She will.
How?
Hit her back with one after the marriage.
She'll forget the old one.
Splendid, Dastoor Ahmed.
You remind me of my mistakes every time you speak.
What mistakes?
If I'd taken him to the doctor in his younger days, Dastoor wouldn't have been like this...
Just listen quietly...
It's better if you don't speak.
Sure.
And yes, laddie...
She was talking politely, right?
Yes.
Give her a gift
On the night of the wedding.
What, Dado?
Bring your cheek forward and say, 'Slap me right here',
'But please forget the slap four years ago'.
As if she'd forget!
She'd be embarrassed, to say the least.
Alright, leave the slap.
Tell me, did you talk about anything else of a particular sort?
Of a particular sort, Dado?
The romantic sort.
Blimey, Ammi Begum!
You're speaking English!
I can't help it if he doesn't understand otherwise!
Tell me, will you, you twit?
Nothing much, really.
Did you say 'I love you'?
No?
You muppet!
Why not?
Boys say it straight to the face.
I was about to say it when Fajr got there.
Alright...
The show's finally on the road, eh?
And yes,
Where's your 'friend'?
'Friend'?
I mean --
Your mate, your Jiya...
She's turned stone-cold ever since she heard about your marriage. Doesn't even come here.
She doesn't even try
To kidnap you.
Honestly,
Something's fishy, innit?
No. I've talked to her.
She's coming to Maheen's and would stay there until tomorrow.
Save your experienced eyes.
Looking too far will only harm your sight.
I'm done.
I'll write my diary for the last time tomorrow,
And I'll end it with
'My Waqar' [=my honour, pride].
I'll leave a margin.
You will write the rest.
I leave every word of my fate for you to write.
Just keep picking words
And penning the story.
I used to write,
'This happened today'.
You will write
What happens tomorrow.
There, now!
Hey!
Let go!
Easy there!
What happened?
Nothing.
I just felt like
Hugging you and crying on your shoulder...
Honestly, why are you crying?
You wouldn't tell anyone, would you?
I won't.
I promise.
I was thinking while writing my diary
That I've picked a fight with him so many times,
Hated him so much for so long...
But for what?
He'd slapped you!
What's the big deal about that?
I gave him his deserts proper!
Blimey...
You're softening up for him!
I've only realised now, Jiya,
That I love him so much.
I would've died without him.
She had a golden bindiya on when I entered the room.
By my bindiya!
Hold it, Mum!
Eh?
Alright, go on.
Seeing me, she jumped up, saying,
'Have some shame! You can't enter a girl's room without her permission'!
I said, 'It's my Dado's room'!
Touché...
Go on.
I took the next step...
The next step?
Let me finish, Dado.
'Slowly edging forward! You're looking like a villain'!
I said, 'Look at yourself, Maheen! Mistaking the hero for the villain'!
She must've said, 'Whatever will become of you, you shameless twit'...
Aye.
That's exactly what she said.
Go on.
And when she started running, I grabbed her han --
Gordon Bennet...
That's it.
La fin.
What?
Didn't you let go after you grabbed her hand?
How could I ever, Dado?
I love her so much.
Bless you.
God bless you!
May I go?
Go, my dear.
It was a pleasure to hear it!
Thank you.
May I go?
Would you rather sit here with us?
Look at your age!
Very funny!
Hello?
Is it Waqar Ahmed?
You've called Waqar; Who else can it be?
May I compliment you?
Please.
You're dirty rotten!
A flip like no other in the entire blimming world!
I never thought you could fall so low and flat,
That you'd be so cheap
As to tell everyone about your meeting with your lover like a tale!
You even said you'd grabbed my hand!
God forgive me!
And you told all about it to your Dado, Uncle and Aunt!
Good Lord...
I'm marrying that type!
Wait and listen, Maheen...
I've heard everything you had to tell.
That was just a joke, Maheen.
Dado was nagging and I gave in.
Tell Jiya, too,
Should she nag you tomorrow!
Then some other friend,
Or neighbour.
What's it to you?
Are you in your senses?
I've been knocked for bleedin' six, Waqar Ahmed!
I'm ashamed of myself.
About what?
Fair enough.
Your type doesn't even know what shame is.
It's no big deal, Maheen.
Everyone was delighted to hear it, so I thought I did the right thing.
But if it's hurt you, I'm sorry.
What was that?
It's difficult...
What's difficult?
I can't figure it out...
I think I've taken the wrong decision.
Stop it, Maheen. I'm saying sorry, ain't I?
You'd better not!
I don't like sorries!
Why are you lying?
You'd said the other day, 'Keep saying sorry to me'
'As long as I live'.
You told them about that, too?
No, Maheen, I didn't tell everything.
Go ahead and tell them.
It's no big deal.
It's not like anyone's stopping you.
I swear by you it didn't hurt me.
Recounting it, I was so happy...
I felt you were with me,
And I was telling you that I've just met you...
Why?
Why did you feel so happy?
Because I love you.
I love you very much.
Done?
Done with what?
Is everyone sleeping?
Why are you asking that?
Go and tell everyone, will you?
Go and tell them, 'I've said "I love you" to Maheen'!
No.
I won't tell them anything now.
Why?
Aren't you happy now?
Don't you feel
That I'm sitting before you
And you're saying to me, 'I love you, Maheen'?
You blighter!
You said every bleedin' thing, but saved this for last!
I think I'm rather afraid of you.
You'd better.
I can change my mood any moment.
And promise me
That you'll always fear me.
I promise.
Saying out of fear, eh?
Yes.
Love me a lot, eh?
That's it, aye.
I don't fear anyone just like that.
Guess what,
Someone's been listening in!
I know Jiya's sitting by your side.
Hey...
Never fear me,
Because I love you very much, too.
No.
The groom would get here in the evening.
He'll get ready
And leave for over there.
I mean, it should at least feel something like a wedding procession!
Don't worry, Jiya, there'll be a grand procession for the wedding. You'll see.
Alright, get here quickly.
What'd Jiya say?
She says the groom will get ready here, and the bride at Nano's.
Good idea!
I mean, what's with calling the bride and groom from different rooms
To sit on either side of the priest?
I won't like it that way.
Yeah, it'd be great. If only Ammi Begum agreed to it.
I'll talk to her!
Hold on! Finish your breakfast!
Just look at her!
She used to live like a widow when she was getting engaged to Gulrez!
I was the first one to figure out
That she loves Waqar.
How did you figure out?
Blimey, Mummykins,
Could anyone hate such a handsome cousin of hers?
She was just putting up an act
Of how much she hates him!
Almost accosting everyone,
'Has anyone got the brains to see how much I love him'?
Yes?
The groom would get ready and leave from over here.
And
The bride?
She'd be at her Nano's.
As in
He's bringing a procession.
Obviously.
There'd be a grand procession at the wedding.
Good idea.
The women would be delighted.
Innit?
I say it from my heart, My Lady!
Alright,
I'll ask Munshi Alam to decorate my car.
No.
Not your car.
Gulrez's.
The...
Foxy?
Yes.
The Foxy.
There, now!
Haven't his trials ended?
This is no trial, Nano.
It's the dying wish of the departed.
Alright, I get it. We'll talk later.
We're picking the best lehenga for you.
I'm deciding, too.
Love you, Nano.
Bring your ear over here.
Yes?
Love you too!
Crazy lass...
Gulrez's Foxy?
I'd ride that?
Splendid.
It's her wish, laddie.
But why?
Because it's his wish.
His last wish.
He, as in,
Gulrez?
Who else could have a last wish these days?
He's the poor lad...
Alrighty, M. Gulrez...
The wedding procession will be led by your Foxy.
Happy?
Wow...
As the Lord wished! [praise]
I've gotten the AC working so well it'll give you the chills!
Good Lord!
Let me ride it too, Gulrez! Please!
We'll go for a ride, sure!
Once we've dropped the bride home.
Sure.
Come.
Over here.
Look at this.
These earrings...
He'd gotten these made from his first paycheque...
And these bangles when he'd been promoted.
And this pendant...
He'd bought it on the tenth anniversary of his engagement.
And this bindiya...
Know what, Wali...
When she was younger,
She'd take the bindiya out of Nano's jewellery box, put it on, and show everyone.
When he's in the mood, Gulrez says,
'The bindiya suits her'.
What'd you do with these?
What could I do?
I'd put these on her today.
We'd send her
Decked up as a proper bride.
Here.
He's my brother, too.
And yes,
The lehenga she's wearing today
Is the one I'd bought...
I said,
'A proper bride'
'From our side'...
Just think this marriage is more of a conspiracy.
Guess what's gonna happen to her right after the marriage!
-What?
She won't be the Chief of the gang anymore.
Because a married girl cannot be the Chief.
Yes!
There!
Now you get it!
And the new Chief will be...
Gulrez!
What's going on, folks?
C'mon, my dear.
Get your things and put them in Gulrez's Foxy.
And get go -- It's 6!
6 already?
Alright, who's coming with me?
Just
Just me.
Alright, Dado...
I'll call my friends here.
Just a minute.
-I give you five minutes.
I want to see you after that.
There, now!
The Reverend's here already.
Good evening.
-Good evening, Reverend. Please, come in.
Good evening, Reverend.
Hurry up, Jiya, he's started already!
Hey!
Why the hurry?
How 'bout a meeting before the wedding?
Put a sock in it!
He ain't catching a glimpse of me before the wedding.
No way!
Double time!
Hold on.
Let me get ready...
I want to see
How he looks at anyone else with you there!
Envying me, eh?
A lot. I swear.
Do you know how?
How?
The way one looks at losers.
C'mon, now!
Coming.
Sit down.
How's it going?
Honestly!
I swear by you,
I'm delighted
To see two lovers meet.
So delighted I can't believe it.
Forgive her.
Are you nuts?
Forgive her for what?
Didn't I say,
I'm very delighted?
And what about your love?
Would it ever let you be delighted?
Let me tell you something...
One never demands something in love.
One commands.
To love back is a favour,
Nor an obligation.
C'mon, now, my dear.
Be happy.
Gulrez...
Maheen's texted me...
She's asked me to request you
To hold her hand
And bring her to the Reverend
When she's ready,
And whisper to her,
'I forgive you, Maheen'.
It's her wish.
Or else, she wrote,
She'd apologise to you before everyone.
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
C'mon, mate, talk about something, or just put some music on.
I'm very worried, Jiya.
I'm afraid I might just die if I, as the bride, saw him.
Are you out of your mind?
As if seeing your groom could kill you!
Not the groom!
Gulrez...
Alright, then,
I'll ask Gulrez to stay away
Until after your marriage.
No way, mate.
I've asked him to hold my hand
And bring me downstairs when I'm ready.
Brilliant...
'Toro, c'mon'!
Yes.
Because if I've wronged him, I want that I die to see him.
Jeez, mate!
What is it?
Your hurries made a mess!
I've left my bag back there!
Jeez...
Should I turn back?
No.
Drop me and go.
Do you know where you've kept it?
Of course.
I can't believe it!
Your Foxy's no less than a proper car!
Very funny...
When she's in the mood for it,
My Foxy can make the best of cars bite the dust!
Oh, really!
And when she's not in the mood?
Then?
She just stops...
Listen to this one...
Ever since your marriage's been fixed, I swear,
She's been running so well! Never stopped once.
Wow...
Would you like some tea, sir?
Of course. Plus something to eat, if you have it.
Alright.
Sit down, mate.
Aunt Suraiyya said 8 p.m.'s the time of departure.
As in, we're leaving at 8.
I'm hungry. Let me have something!
Okay...
You really shouldn't be hungry, though...
But, I guess...
As you like it...
Look at me, Gulrez...
Forgive me, mate.
Come on, Waqar,
If you keep on embarrassing me like that, I'd feel as if I'm feigning my delight.
That's not what it is.
I'm thoroughly delighted.
I'm really enjoying this.
Yous twos were sent here to get ready.
And you're sitting here, having a nice little chat!
Why are you here?
To keep an eye on the two of you.
And because I'd left my bag here.
I hope you're not worried.
Oh, shoot...
You must be a bit afraid.
-Why in the blazes?
'My sometime sworn enemy, now my wife' and all...
Fair warning, lad...
Something else may be going on...
Shut up!
Hi, Gulrez!
Hi.
Don't you like me?
No --
I like you very much.
Marry me, then.
Great...
There's you,
There's you, shameless, only too...
And there's this guy...
And there's this guy... So shy...
Alright.
You'll go to Maheen's room to get ready,
And you to Fajr's.
Alright.
Good.
Okay.
Please don't mind anything I've said.
I was just kidding.
Yeah.
I know.
You hardly know anything...
I might as well be very serious!
I'll get my bag.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV