You're lucky.
You almost got pulverised.
What d'you mean?
Your fracture's minor. Mercifully.
You'll be fine in a few days.
Naw, boyo...
You just got your deserts.
Feel like acting another fracture out?
Oh, please...
Don't even think of playing cricket for a few days.
Pressure on those two stitches ain't gonna be pleasant.
Ah, just lovely...
So... Who's driving?
Me, of course.
Don't use your right hand.
May I?
Please, take care.
'Course.
Hey...
-Hmm?
Fear God.
You're the type who gets punished instantly.
Alright, Reverend.
God be with ye.
Yeah?
It's switched off...
Good Lord...
What are you so worried about?
He left without a word.
Now, his phone's switched off...
Crucified me... More or less...
He's not a kid.
I'm sure he's havin' a ball.
He'd have to wear that bandage 'round here.
I'm gonna take it off for everyone to see and blooter him proper.
I'm sure you won't blooter him.
You're just saying it for Maheen to hear.
Promise me, Nano...
You got to blooter him if he's actually lying!
Oh, can it... D'you seriously think it'd look good? Me blootering that 6-foot lad?
Would he look nice, getting himself beaten?
Paper tigers don't look too good either.
He deserves a proper slap... At least...
Forget it... Your slap won't even scratch him.
Allow me. I'll smite him proper and knock some sense into him!
Good Heavens...
Haven't you been waiting for four years to do that? Hold your horses...
Aye... But one day...
I'll get even.
Whoa...
Gotta say...
That's some big words from the wee girl.
He's here.
Just bring him here.
I'll give him a taste of what he deserves.
Peace, Aunt.
Hey!
Gulrez! M'boy!
How are you?
How's she?
Heard she got hurt.
She bumped into Waqar and fell.
It's just a scratch.
Where's she?
In Ammi Begum's room.
Oh...
Peace, Uncle.
Upon you too...
Remembered your Uncle, eh?
I got a new car for you, you twit.
But you! You were sleeping in your Foxy's arms.
Ever gonna change?
Never, Uncle.
I can see that.
Hey!
It's Gulrez!
Peace, Aunt.
Upon you too. How are you?
Great.
Oh, please.
Your fiancée gave you the finger. Called off the engagement. How's that for great?
So what?
It's only called off for now...
Don't worry.
She's just playing with you.
I know it.
She'll say in a few days...
'Alright'...
'Gulrez ain't a bad choice at all'!
Neelam ain't here?
No. She's gone to the shrine with Wali.
Shrine?
She'd light a lamp.
Make a wish.
Whoa!
What's her wish?
No idea.
Hmm!
Pretty sure it's Maheen's acceptance,
For which she'd make regular offerings at the shrine, innit?
Go check on her.
No way...
Hey!
Why are you here, then?
That's what I came here for.
But I don't dare...
Keep up with that,
And she'd trample you under her feet!
She's not the type!
She just thinks...
You've attacked her with this engagement thing.
She's just a bit angry.
You siding with her, you twit?
Not her, Aunt.
I'm siding with the truth.
Hmm...
He got flowers?
No.
Gorblimey. Nothing for the sick!
The blasted Scrooge!
To think he wants to get engaged to me.
Haven't you brought flowers or something?
Flowers?
You just... Came knocking?
Why're you pulling him up, Dastoor?
Blimey, Suraiyya...
He's visiting the sick.
His fiancée, no less! Couldn't the Scrooge spend a penny?
Tea.
No.
I'll get flowers first.
I was so frightened
I forgot I had to bring flowers.
Waqar!
What happened?
Nothing much... Just got hurt...
Oh God...
Looks serious.
Aye...
But just a bit.
But it's okay. No problem.
So...
Where are you off to?
I'll be back.
Gotta get some flowers.
See you. We'll have a nice chat.
I'll be back in... 15 minutes?
Bye.
So...
How's your arm?
Two stitches on the elbow.
Hmm...
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
Blimey... Two stitches... As if the fracture wasn't enough.
Nah,
I'm sure he just forgot to mention it.
Go to Ammi Begum. Quick.
She's looking for you.
'Course.
I'm going to see her.
HVT in AO!
Has he brought flowers?
Not the flowery bloke.
The dramatic one!
Ah...
Hi, everybody!
Peace, Dado.
Likewise...
Come here, m'lad.
Here.
Sit by me.
C'mon.
Ahh...
What are you up to?
Heard your elbow's pulverised.
Yet you're going about the city, driving with one hand!
I haven't seen another one like you. Not in the family at least.
Dado... What it is is...
Aye, what?
It ain't pulverised or something...
Just... Broken...
What are you lookin' at?
Only what you want them to look at, of course.
What's those pills for?
I heard about your broken arm.
But
Never any wound.
It's nothing, Dado...
Just... Two stitches.
Blimey...
One bump and you fell apart...
Show me!
-Hey!
What are you doing?
I'll open it and chant an incantation for you...
You won't need the plaster, the bandages,
Or the pills!
-OW!
Dado!
It hurts real bad!
It's real bad, Waqar Ahmed...
You've been busted!
-Ow!
Goodness! It kills me...
M'boy -- Dastoor Ahmed!
Dastoor!
Come here!
Goodness...
Relax, Dado...
Dado! Calm down!
Dado! Hey!
Help her!
Uncle Dastoor!
Uncle Dastoor! Dado!
What happened, Dado? Easy...
Dado!
Uncle Dastoor!
Uncle Dastoor! What happened to Dado?
Dado!
What happened?
Blood?
Dado...
Ammi Begum!
Ammi Begum! Lemme --
What happened?
When she heard about the engagement, she was drained of all cheer.
Almost felt like... She'd refuse...
She said she needed some time to think...
I'm at a dead end, so to speak...
Who knows how long she needs...
Three stitches.
It's gonna take a while now.
All thanks to you, you blighter!
You told me he was just putting up an act!
Tell me...
Is he?
What do I tell you?
He was, to begin with!
Oh, put a sock in it!
Your little jokes cost my lad
A quarter gallon of his blood.
M'boy...
Three stitches.
Not to mention the pain that refuses to go away.
What's it to me?
Nothing, I know.
But the least you could do is check on him.
Can it!
Fear the Lord, Maheen!
What's three stitches and an armache to a man?
Girls shouldn't be so heartless!
Someone's a turncoat!
There...
Someone else too, aye?
What?
The sight of his blood
Nearly killed you too!
Not his blood! Just the sight of blood!
The name's Maheen Aurangzeb.
They hate how I hate 'em!
Why are you crying?
Something you're afraid of?
What if she came here with her prayers?
I don't know what happens when prayers clash.
Whose prayers get heard?
The prayers of those who love truly.
Then wipe those tears.
No one loves as truly as him. I guarantee!
I'm here to pray she loves truly too.
I know her too.
When she will, she will love most truly.
Love Gulrez... Right?
You're afraid too...
Now you know why I pray...
Now you know why I cry...
There's just the two of us in here, right?
Aye aye.
Could you stop 'aye aye'ing me?
Just say yeah. Say my name.
No...
I respect you a lot.
As if
I don't!
You're two years older than me, Waqar.
Fair enough.
The flowers and the card...
They're for her, yes?
Aye.
But they're yours now.
Please, get well soon.
You touched in the head?
You brought these for her.
You can get me tomorrow.
I wouldn't dare give these to her.
Curse you.
You know who's standing between you and your engagement? You.
You know why she left the party at the mention of the engagement?
I swear I don't.
Be a man! Act like one!
Seize her hand and pull her into a corner. You can find one easily in this mansion!
Just say...
'I love you. Always have. Always will'...
Whoa there, Waqar...
She'd break my hand.
She won't rest until she's got Nano to beat me.
Well then, you can rest assured she won't agree to get engaged to you until Doomsday.
Ask why.
Why?
Girls hate cowards!
They like tough guys.
Know what...
I'd die
If I seized her hand.
That's how I feel.
Alright.
Plan B.
Yeah?
Just ignore her.
Tell Dado
You're not in the mood to get engaged right now.
As in,
Refuse?
Not that!
It just means... You're okay with the engagement, but okay if not!
Except... I'm not, Waqar...
I've been very disturbed since then...
Never felt hungry,
Even at the sight of someone eating.
Never slept peacefully,
Never had anything but nightmares.
You know that, Gulrez.
Keep it to yourself.
Don't make your feelings public.
Just keep it to yourself, or...
Or?
Or the public will use them against you.
Ever loved someone?
I mean,
You speak like you have.
We don't believe in fairytales in London.
You like a girl, you take her out for coffee, have a chat...
Drop her home, come back... End of story.
You don't even miss each other?
Not at all.
Sometimes, aye... When you come across her number when looking for the new one's...
Sometimes, you call her too.
And
She's okay with it?
Of course, mate!
Because it cuts both ways!
Tales of love aren't heard much outside India and Pakistan.
The rest of the world's moved on.
Like, seriously!
How can the world go on without love?
I don't believe it.
Time management is the name of the game, numbskull.
Everyone's out to conquer each other.
Jobs, careers, promotions...
Amidst all this, people don't have time for anything else.
And, to be frank, love wastes a lot of spare time.
I never thought that way...
'Bout time you did.
Just make friends with a bunch of girls and you won't have time to think about your engagement.
What happened?
I should get going... Neelam and Wali would be back...
Hey...
Do seriously think about what I said.
I got a point.
Aye.
Definitely will.
Alright, see you. God bless you.
Take care.
I will.
We'll celebrate when I'm better.
Lemme know when you've made friends with a girl, okay?
Sure...
I will.
Bye.
Bye...
So cute.
OW!
I ain't exactly delighted to see Waqar.
Why?
He doesn't think about girls the right way.
Who?
All girls.
He doesn't think they deserve to be loved.
That's what he's like.
Aye.
Just your typical London lad.
'Time management's the name of the game, numbskull', he said...
'People hardly have the time',
'And love wastes a lot of time'... Stuff like that.
What'd the numbskull say?
What could I say?
I just listened to him. Quietly.
It's no use arguing with his type.
Hmm...
You ought to have blessed him... 'May you fall in love with someone'!
He doesn't love!
He just makes 'friends'!
With God-knows how many all at once!
I'm sure he's got no shortage of brats in London.
Tell me...
Hmm?
He said tales of love are unheard of outside India and Pakistan...
And the rest of the world's moved on...
Moved on to?
What'd be left of the world if it moved on from love? Didn't you ask him?
I didn't.
Because I'm sure he would've had a most wicked answer to that.
What's happened to Waqar in four years?
He was not like that when he left.
My prayers seem to have worked.
Whoa...
Wonder what you pray for.
I mean,
If your prayers turned him
Into a cad and a wastrel...
Don't even start.
This game of blessings and curses is not for you.
Have your dinner and go to bed.
Good night.
So... What happened?
Nothing.
She said we're staying over.
I thought we'd stay there tonight.
Did Gulrez see her?
No.
Who did he get the flowers for, the blighter?
You haven't a clue, do you?
Gulrez gave the flowers and the card to Waqar!
Splendid...
He's a goner.
He got flowers for her
But gave them to Waqar!
As in, gave her flowers to her worst enemy!
Keep at it and you're a goner, Gulrez Akhtar!
Go to bed.
It's not that, Mum.
She's not angry.
Just... Sad.
Hardly different, is it?
Fury... Or grief...
She ought to grieve.
He came to check on her but didn't even ask her how she was,
Gave her flowers to the man whose mention gets her into a rage.
Don't act like you're so smart.
I know everything.
So...
Why'd you come back last night?
I was sleeping so peacefully.
Because of Gulrez, yes?
He gave your flowers to Waqar.
That's what Mum says.
Not me.
What d'you think?
I mean...
Waqar's arm bled like a fountain last night,
But it was Maheen who was a sight to behold!
She finally had pity on him
When drops of his blood fell on her feet.
I swear, she almost died back then.
Big deal. As if he's an actual sworn enemy.
He's her Uncle's son.
No wonder it kills her to see him bleed like that.
Shut up, Fajr.
Why don't you say it?
It's a lot easier.
You don't need to shut her up.
It's nothing like that.
So... You gonna make friends with him?
Are you gonna shut up, Fajr?
Back to breakfast. Ain't you getting late?
Aye. Back to breakfast.
No need to act smart 'round here.
Okay, fine.
But remember this...
The times, they're-a-changin'!
Will you please shut up?
Will you?
Honestly...
What happened to her?
I just told you.
She shivered for a moment.
Turned white.
She looked at Waqar
Like she'd tear up any moment.
Wali...
He's changed completely!
A Londoner through and through.
He was teaching me his English tricks.
Such as?
'Seize Maheen's hand and pull her into a corner'!
'And say',
'"I love you"'...
'"Always have, always will"'...
That it? The English trick?
Innit?
D'you actually think one could do that to Maheen?
And say that?
That bloke's a goner.
She'd make mincemeat of him.
Know how Neelam and I got married?
I know.
There was something between you. Some spark or something.
There was nothing.
She wasn't even ready.
Until... I did just that on Ammi Begum's birthday.
Seized her hand,
And pulled her into a corner.
She looked at me
With eyes that could kill.
I didn't fear her.
I said...
'I love you',
'And I want to marry you'.
'I promise I'll keep you happy. Forever'.
She agreed?
Not right then.
Her burning eyes looked into mine for a few seconds
Before she pushed me away and ran off.
How'd you get married then?
She gave me a gift on my birthday.
A small packet.
Her letter
Greeted me when I opened it.
The only thing she'd written was,
'If you can actually keep me happy forever',
'I don't see why not'!
Blimey...
It must've been quite funny.
Not at all.
Lovely is more like it.
A 'yes' in love
Ain't never funny.
It's always... Plain lovely.
But to hear it, a man's gotta be one.
Let's just say she got here the moment you left.
Who?
The girl in the car.
My eyes were fixed on her.
I couldn't blink once.
She that lovely?
You're talking about lovely! I'm thinking of who she was and which car she was driving.
I couldn't see a thing between the bright headlights!
If you couldn't, how d'you know a girl was driving it?
A boy would've pulled the brakes.
Ha ha... Very funny...
Hey!
What happened?
What's up with Gulrez? He's running on the road!
Jogging maybe?
Who jogs at 10 a.m.?
And in the middle of the blimmin' road?
I'll get back to you.
Gotta follow him, check on him. Bye.
Okay, bye.
Gulrez!
Not so fast, mate!
What's up?
Why are you running like someone's after you?
No...
No one's...
Just going...
To see Maheen...
Big deal.
As if she asked you to come running.
No, Waqar...
I realise
You were absolutely right...
How?
On the way to the office,
Wali
Told me the same thing
As you!
Me?
What'd I say?
You don't remember, do you? I do!
I'll do just what a man ought to today!
What should a man do?
You'll get the news in ten minutes!
Stay tuned! Get ready to change your view 'bout me!
Did I ever say something about you?
You called me numbskull.
Remember?
I'll get going.
How'd you get in?
You opened the door, DIDN'T YOU?
STOP IT!
I'm your father, Jiya.
You leavin' here quietly
Or d'you want me to call the cops?
Call 'em.
Tell 'em your father's guilty
Of breaking and entering your place.
Tell 'em he's begging you
To listen to him
Just for once.
He thinks he can convince you
That he was guiltless.
What is it?
Yeah?
What've you got to tell someone who's seen everything with her own two eyes?
Please, leave this place.
If I don't see your face,
I feel like I'm missing you.
But when I do see your face,
I see my mother's wounds.
Because they filled out the charge sheet
Against me before your eyes!
You were told that all of it
Was my doing.
Don't you dare suggest my mother was in the wrong.
I'm here to tell you
She wasn't in the wrong.
Oh!
So it occurred to you
After she died!
It didn't occur to me.
I swear, I've just found out
That she was innocent.
I had my reasons
To blame her.
I've got a ton of reasons to blame you too!
Don't forget I'm an eyewitness, M. Mir Mehtab Ali!
I'll take your leave.
You better not come here again.
Or I'd think you're here with another excuse
To claim your right over this place... And me!
Jiya...
This isn't my place.
It's all yours.
I've left it to you.
Should I say 'Thank you very much'?
Look at me, Jiya...
Never forget that suspicion and mistrust
Are antithetical to justice.
Punish me any way you like for my sins,
But before you do,
Just hear me out.
I just did.
That'd be enough for today.
I'll hear the rest
If we meet again.
As you wish.
I hope
That you never come here again.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV