She even read the letter,
And read it out, too.
But
Not a tear fell from her eyes.
Just...
Ammi Begum...
She didn't weep, either,
But it felt as if
The light had gone out of her.
Nano?
It's nothing, Nano...
He must be mithering!
He'll be coming anytime.
Ammi Begum!
Right, I'm fine...
He's --
Saying he'll be coming.
Where's he gone?
He won't be going anywhere!
Don't ask such absurd questions!
The blighter's just up to some buffoonery!
Nano,
Get up!
It appears you've been run out!
Surely, she's laughing, Ammi Begum?
She's crying, you twit!
She's just putting up a show of laughter.
What's this letter?
He's sent me a letter.
A love letter!
Show me.
No way!
You'd read your daughter's love letters now?
Is this the time to write love letters?
Get the guests something to eat.
He'll be -- A tad late.
That's what he's written?
Should I call him?
His phone's switched off...
Honestly, Maheen,
What has happened?
It kills me!
May I tell the truth, Nano?
It kills me, too.
The blighter's fled, leaving me...
I will remember you then, and then I will forget you
And then I will forget you
Thus, before reaching the destination, I choose to take a detour
For those we hold dear to us are the ones
Who break our heart
Whatever will happen to you, Kaneez Begum?
We apologise for hurting you with this indecorum;
The fact is
A problem's come up.
My groom,
Waqar Mashood Ahmed,
Has left me and fled.
It's almost 11 p.m.
We'll wait for him till 12.
Don't misconstrue this wait to mean that we're looking for him.
Not at all!
To look for recreant deserters is not a custom we practice.
One who's gone
Is gone.
We just say,
'May God keep him happy'.
I will keep with me the memories of our conversations and of you
I know he's not coming.
But, just in case...
Therefore, we'll wait until 12.
You may wait until 12 if you please,
Or have dinner and leave.
I'm saying all of this
On behalf of Kaneez Begum.
What it is is,
She's a tad woeful,
So she can't talk.
This apology of mine with folded hands...
Take it that Kaneez Begum is apologising.
Dastoor Uncle,
Ask Munshi Alam to serve the guests dinner in the lawn.
I'll be coming shortly.
Listen, Maheen!
Why did you say,
'We won't be looking for him'?
Because we won't be looking for him.
Alright, tell me,
Does love need one to look for someone?
And, if you do go looking,
Do you ever find someone?
You tried looking and lost;
I was right there by you,
But you couldn't get me.
That's not how it is, partner!
If one deserts in love,
Or loses his way,
Then, one who searches for him is a sinner!
Apparently you've turned into a Priest the moment that twit's left!
Pronouncing judgements like that!
It's truly exhilarating, Nano!
What a twist he's given this story!
You're weeping, aren't you?
Not at all, Nano!
He'd be cursed if I wept.
I'd actually fallen for the dastard!
No!
May he
Remain happy wherever he is.
What about you?
He'd said the same!
'What about you, Maheen'?
That's brilliant, partner.
You do
Exactly what you say!
What are you looking at?
Sit.
Have some juice
And tell me
What I should do.
Please, Ammi Begum, sit.
Whatever will happen to you, Kaneez Begum!
What happened when the clock finally struck 12, Munshi Alam?
Please, go on.
She never let the clock strike 12.
Suddenly,
'Climp, clomp',
Echoed her footfalls as she descended the stairs.
Everybody's eyes were on her.
Who knows
Who it was that she was looking at!
Perhaps she was searching for someone.
Who are you searching for, Maheen?
Gulrez.
Where is he?
In Ali's room.
He's sitting with Ali and Fajr.
Uncle,
Please don't go anywhere.
And ask the Reverend to sit.
The bridegroom's coming.
If I may say so, Gulrez,
He's picked a fight with the wrong girl.
She'd clobber him proper!
How would one who couldn't forget a slap forget deserting her on the wedding day?
Why this corner meeting?
I'd heard
You're set to become the Chief.
Splendid.
Sitting in the Opposition,
Dreaming of ruling!
You can't.
I won't.
Good boy.
So, pray tell,
What were you talking about?
What are you looking at?
I'm your chief.
Tell me what was going on.
I was saying
That he'd picked a fight with the wrong girl.
Yes!
He's picked a fight with the wrong girl, Fajr.
I'd clobber him proper!
Relax, Maheen.
Why don't you relax, mate?
And --
Be done with this corner meeting!
So what, if the enemy's fled?
You'll see when he shows up again,
I'll give him a piece of what he deserves!
I'll leech his blood!
I know.
I haven't forgotten his slap,
How could I forget him deserting me on the wedding day?
Will you help me?
Me?
Are you asking me?
Of course, partner!
Tell me,
Will you help me?
You don't need to ask!
-Yes.
I will.
I haven't let the guests leave.
I've stopped the Reverend too.
I've said, 'Wait',
'The bridegroom's coming'.
You got a call from him?
I didn't.
I got an idea.
Idea?
Have you had dinner?
Come on, Maheen?
As if I'd have anything with all the gloom in the ambience!
Surely, you would in an ambience of merrymaking?
Of course.
Hold my hand, then.
Take me to the Reverend.
Ah, right,
I'd said I'd take you to him.
No, my sweet spoony,
I'm not having you sit by the Reverend.
You'll be sitting by my side,
And saying,
'Reverend',
'Commence the nuptials'.
What are you thinking about?
Don't you love me?
Please help me, mate.
Let the blighter be stupefied
When he lands in London
As if
The life has gone out of him!
Do you love me?
You?
I don't even despise you.
Let alone the question of love, Monsieur.
I'll ravish you from here.
Such bounties, O Love, are all one gets from you in benefaction
I will laugh wholeheartedly at this, I will embrace the heart with rapture
I will remember you then,
I will remember you then, and then I will forget you
And then I will forget you
Thus, before reaching the destination,
Thus, before reaching the destination, I choose to take a detour
For those we hold dear to us are the ones who break our heart
For those we hold dear to us are the ones
Who break our heart
Reverend,
Commence the nuptials.
Has the groom arrived?
He sits before you.
Madam,
Do I have your permission?
You may begin, Reverend.
Begin in the Lord's name.
In the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
All praise be to Him, the Lord of the worlds.
And the consequence of the righteous
And peace and blessings be upon the Prophets and Messengers
The Prophet Mohammad and his family and companions.
That's good.
That's what was supposed to happen.
What?
What did you say?
Do you know, Munshi Alam, that she never wanted to marry me in the first place?
She loved Gulrez.
She just wanted to get even with me.
Ammi Begum very aptly said
That you inherit half her property
And the entirety of her odium.
I'm serving you an ultimatum until tomorrow.
Take the papers of the will,
And flit back to where you came from!
Munshi Alam!
Look at this.
Read this.
I have proof.
Yes, she's left.
Vivified me
With her touch, and left.
Yes.
Right.
Now I'm just waiting
To get up and start walking.
Come here sometime.
Show your face around here.
Leave that be.
You say it,
And I listen quietly.
Alright, listen,
That blighter's around here these days.
Got wind of the will being drafted somehow,
And showed up the very next day.
No.
Would I let him get in?
'Around here' as in, he's arrived in Karachi.
Yes,
He must be staying in one of those hotels.
He must have.
He must have kids too.
What do you think I am?
Even if he showed up with his kids,
I won't let him get past the gates of Kaneez Mahal.
I've told the guards
That I don't care if a dog or a cat gets in,
But he must never be allowed in.
Listen to the next one.
He paid a visit to me in my dream last night.
He fell at my feet, apologising; I, too, kicked him right in the stomach, saying,
'Don't you dare pay me a visit even in my dreams'!
I'm talking to Fajr.
I'm going tomorrow.
Please, Munshi Alam, just tell me one thing.
She's happy, isn't she?
I mean,
The two of them are happy, aren't they?
Gulrez, too, sees me as the culprit?
There.
He knew that I was doing the right thing.
She's very good, too, Munshi Alam, but...
Putting up this façade of a marriage
To exact her revenge...
It was simply not cricket.
Trust me, Munshi Alam,
She was doing something very wrong.
Thank goodness I found out about it in time.
I felt like
Telling Gulrez everything,
But to be quite honest,
I'd begun suspecting
That Gulrez was in on it with Maheen.
At the very least, I can meet Gulrez, can't I?
First,
Have your tea.
We'll talk later.
Munshi Alam, why can't I meet Gulrez?
Because Gulrez is dead!
Forgive me, mate.
Come on, Waqar,
If you keep on embarrassing me like that, I'd feel as if I'm feigning my delight.
That's not what it is.
I'm thoroughly delighted.
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
Thank you.
What happened?
I'm seeing you smile after so many years.
How many years?
I felt as if I've never seen you smile widely or laugh.
I'm laughing now.
Why?
What's happened now?
I think you should go and pick up Daji from the school.
It's almost 12.
What good is writhing and smouldering in your remembrance
Is anybody there in the room?
Give me your hand.
I want to touch and feel you.
Did the two of us actually get married?
Did you say
'Yes' to my name?
Did you say,
'I accept'
'Gulrez Akhtar',
'Son of Mehmood Akhtar'?
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
Yes...
This is the same hand
With which you'd write your diary;
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
To me, it felt
As if you're writing my destiny...
I used to think
That my life would've been one well-spent
Once I held your hand,
And
Sometimes, I'd feel
That Death won't dare come near me
If I just seized your hand firmly.
If you
Ever chance upon him --
Him --
Waqar Ahmed,
Tell him,
That as he departed,
Gulrez said 'Thank you' to him.
Don't let go...
I'd die if you did...
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV