Will you come?
Tell me honestly.
You won't betray me, would you?
Done?
You'll see
I rise in stature the day you don't start.
Everything that had been planned for the day get scrapped.
What are you doing?
I thought I'd find out
How today's going to go.
Don't go to the office today.
This is what's wrong with you folks.
You take a leave in moments of merriment,
As you do in moments of grief.
This, Neelam, is well and truly submitting to grief on your knees.
Think about it -
I couldn't get her, but got the grief of not getting her.
So what's the price of this grief?
Now, would a Scrooge such as myself
Let so valuable a sorrow go by him?
Shall I go now?
Go.
Shall I start the Foxy?
Start it.
Dad?
What happened?
I'm your mother, Jiya...
Your mother who, by the time you get to hear this,
Is quite possibly no longer around...
The doctors are trying their best,
But the more they try,
The more I pray
They fail...
After I'm gone, I know
You're gonna face the disgrace I did...
Who knows,
By the time you find out the truth,
You may have begun to hate me too...
The truth, my little doll...
Is... I'm innocent...
Aurangzeb... My friend from college...
I always wanted to marry him.
Always, as in...
When your Dad was nowhere in the picture.
I couldn't get Aurangzeb... So...
Like every other girl in such a situation, I gave in to my parents' will.
That's how I got married to your Dad.
Come out.
Why?
She's here to see you.
But why?
She says she shouldn't have created a scene before everyone.
What should she have done?
What can I say? Why don't you ask her yourself?
She's blocking the road.
Tell her to move the car aside.
She won't.
You gotta get off
And listen to her.
I ain't talking to her.
What? You gonna curse her now?
Like my type could curse anyone!
I can swear if you want.
He ain't coming.
Why?
Says he won't talk.
How dare he?
-Hold your horses, Maheen! Let him have his way here!
You're a worse politician than Nano... Left the Government and joined the Opposition in a sec!
Well, guess what, Gulrez is now the Opposition. Because you toppled his Government last night.
On your feet.
C'mon.
Double time.
Get in the Foxy and stay on our tail!
And you...
Drive!
Will it start?
Yeah.
Why not?
We were living quite a happy life
When, seven years later,
A ghost from the past
Came knocking...
I was startled to see him,
But he'd grown too close to your Dad.
And I had been so stupid
To do as I'd been told
And hide my past
From my husband.
He'd come to our place regularly.
He never mentioned anything about our past in the beginning,
But...
Things changed some 8 or 10 months later
When he begun to remind me
Of our solemn oaths as unsuccessful lovers back in the day...
I put on my guard,
But could never muster the courage to tell your Dad...
Then, one day, he came to see me when your Dad was not around...
I kicked him out.
But, after a few days,
He broke in again.
Unfortunately for me,
Your Dad was not around again.
But he was furious.
As if he had a right over me!
He showed me my old letters
And tried to blackmail me.
I said I didn't care,
And I wouldn't hesitate to tell my husband about everything if I had to.
That's when he lost it.
He seized my hand.
I pushed him away and struck him with a vase,
But by then, a car had stopped outside...
He made a run for it, rubbing his face,
But - curse my luck -
Your Dad had seen him...
C'mon! Back to it!
Quit bummin' around!
How much further are we going?
Lemme catch my breath!
Going through it all... It was almost like... I lost my mind...
I could never imagine Aurangzeb doing any of it... Not least to me!
I was startled to see your Dad walk in.
It felt like being caught red-handed.
He asked questions
And I said whatever I came up with.
That was the moment
That ruined my life
Forever.
By the time I came to,
I was at my parents'.
Your Dad had begun investigating...
And - curse my luck -
The man he went to
Was none other than
Aurangzeb.
To cover for himself,
He presented your Dad with a bunch of my letters as proof of my betrayal...
Saying I'd written them after our marriage...
I swear, Jiya...
Forget writing letters...
I never even thought of him after my marriage...
I wish your Dad had come to me with those letters
So I could tell him
That he had written them.
He was an expert at it...
He could copy anyone's handwriting.
He'd used my letters to write new ones to serve his purpose.
The blame was all mine as your Dad just saw the handwriting
And sent me
Divorce papers...
Do you know why he was with me
On the day of the accident?
I had convinced him
After much begging
To tell your Dad the truth... And confess his sins...
To tell your Dad... That I was innocent...
But when fate strikes,
It kills you off
Where you don't get an ounce of relief...
He had an accident
And died right there...
He died, Jiya...
But robbed my life of everything...
Who could be more unfortunate
Than a woman whose husband bears not her pall,
Nor sheds a tear at her grave...
I am that woman today.
May God protect you. Always.
When you see your Dad,
Ask him
If he could weep for me at my grave someday.
Perhaps his tears would be able to wash the blot on my name...
Come with me.
You're angry with me, aren't you?
Not at all.
I'm very happy.
You must be eager to slap me on my face.
Do you know why I've brought you to this secluded spot?
So you can slap me hard.
You will be able to vent your anger,
Leaving my esteem untarnished.
I know I've hurt you.
I also know that the curse of a broken heart is baneful.
But I'm not stopping you from cursing me...
All I'm saying, Gulrez, is... I'm innocent...
I've played life like a cricket match in my ignorance.
You're not bad at winning me a match,
But my heart said
That he should be the one to lead me to victory.
So,
You couldn't make the team.
Now,
Do you forgive me or will you slap me?
Why are you smiling?
Who apologises in love?
You never apologise
To one you've never loved.
And --
About all your insult? What about that?
I'd written you a letter...
'Never give me woe,'
'For I can endure it.'
I've hurt you so much --
So bad...
Please forgive me...
Again?
I feel I'd never be able to meet your gaze if I'm married to anyone else...
What do you mean, 'anyone else'?
You're talking about Waqar.
Why not name him?
Actually, I haven't really decided...
I mean -- It could be him...
You glunterpeck! He's an all-rounder!
Your team won't do without him.
Let's go out to lunch.
Lunch?
I thought I'd give you a treat from the gang's fund if you didn't slap me.
Come!
Right here, my friends!
Enjoy yourselves!
What's this? 'Enjoy ourselves' on these bleeding 200 Rupees? Keep them!
How much do you want?
500.
I've called you 'friends'. You folks should be ashamed of yourselves, demanding money like that!
Bugger off!
Where did you get this Foxy?
Gulrez gave it to me.
Gulrez gave you?
Where's Gulrez?
With Maheen.
What?
Not 'what,' ask 'why!'
Yes, why'd he go with her?
What are they up to this time?
He shouldn't even greet that blighter back after everything that happened last night!
He didn't greet her back,
Because she never greeted him.
She stopped the car, bossed around, and took him with her.
But where?
Somewhere she could apologise, and Gulrez would say with terror in his eyes, 'I forgive you!'
Oh.
So now she'll apologise to him.
And he'll forgive her!
Shouldn't he?
-No way!
Never!
Give us our 200.
'Bout time you wised up! Here!
Naff off already!
Aren't you ashamed of yourself, like, ever?
You broke the engagement last night, but you're seeing him today!
Care to tell me
What you're up to?
What d'you want this time?
I wanted to say sorry.
I don't remember you saying sorry to us.
I will...
But first, I had to apologise to his broken heart.
Our hearts are broken too.
Mine... Ammi Begum's...
Dastoor and Mehrunnisa left this place in disgrace!
No one's heart is broken here.
They're just... Troubled by the fact they couldn't keep their word from years ago.
I'd decided last night
That I won't slaughter my heart with my silence for someone's promise...
Wait!
Come here.
Where's he?
Went home.
No way he's going home.
Ammi Begum would break his legs!
I'm talking about Gulrez.
And I'm asking about the blighter.
What do I know?
When'd that happen?
What d'you do with this phone? Scratch your head?
I'm sure you've talked... Found out everything... Got word he's safe wherever he is.
So, again, where is he?
No idea.
The blighter must've gone in hiding! But don't worry... There's no place Ammi Begum can't reach!
Not his fault, really. I bet he didn't have the foggiest I'd stop him.
I dare him to set foot here.
Don't worry, he won't.
Isn't he coming here with a proposal?
Hey! Why does everyone think there's something going on between us?
Good heavens, girl...
You broke your engagement,
Stopped him from leaving...
What else should we wait for before we think you're interested in him?
No idea.
But I'm really sure about it...
The weirdest thing - that's what Gulrez thought too...
Send her to blasted Coventry!
Coventry?
Aye. She's not going anywhere. Not even to University.
Okay, but what's that gonna achieve?
Confiscate her phone,
And if you have to, cut the landline cable!
She'll fight back against this tyranny with obstinacy.
Precautions, my dear, are not tyranny.
But that's what she'd think!
Who cares what she thinks?
If she starts arguing about it,
Tell her that for what she's done to our family,
Generations to come would never forgive her.
Are we clear?
Yes.
Remember, Suraiyya...
If love like hers ever got to win,
Elders such as ourselves would be left getting the groceries like servants.
Evidently...
And yes...
Yes?
Lock her room?
Like, for real?
Don't let her out
Until she changes her mind
And heart...
Where's the twit?
Waqar?
Don't even mention his name...
Just tell me
If he's in town or gone for good.
No one knows
If he's in hiding or gone.
I told you
He's not going back.
You don't know the force that's stopping him.
She's just a puny little girl, that sissy.
Remember the last time she keeled over while bowling?
Someone get some sense into him.
Tell him what I'm talking about.
She's talking about the force of love.
No way.
She never said they love each other.
If you talk about love, don't you dare talk about anyone but Gulrez!
He loves her...
Because why not?
She's his fiancée... Always has been!
Anyway...
I'll sort it out myself...
Just... Find out about the blighter...
And make it clear to him
That it's best for his health
That he leave this place!
London?
He can go to hell, for all I care!
By that logic, Maheen ought to go to hell too...
She's more guilty.
I mean --
She'd got engaged!
She ought to have thought about it!
She's under his spell!
The blighter knows every wicked English trick in the book... He knows how to get the girls under his spell!
It'd be good if we found out by the evening.
Or, I've decided...
I'll get
A declaration of disownment published in the newspapers tomorrow.
That's why I never wanted to send him to London...
My heart said if he stayed there,
He'd learn the wicked ways of the blimmin' East India Company.
Could you read her feelings?
Feelings?
Dado's missing him.
Hmm...
She can do anything when she's furious, Jiya.
She'd slit our throats to keep her word.
Disappear. Right now.
No.
I can't.
She'd be left all alone.
She's not afraid of her.
She is, mate...
But I know she's very brave.
Very daring.
Strange, Waqar...
If she were that serious about you...
Why'd she have to put up this act with the engagement and all?
She could've said all of this way back...
Poor Gulrez...
Imagine what he'd be going through.
He must be on the rack.
It's so insulting.
I know, mate.
But...
-But?
As in, you've got an answer ready!
I thought people feared breaking hearts...
Never knew you'd be so ready to justify it!
That's the problem with all the winners.
Triumph blinds them
To everything those who lose have to go through.
I care about Gulrez too.
It hurts me to think
That our union would break him.
Did you meet?
Who?
Gulrez, of course.
No.
Just see him.
Check out what losers in love look like.
I'll see him.
Say sorry too.
And?
You'd snatch his Maheen for just a puny little sorry and slip away sharpish?
Here's a tip -
Never see him again.
You're confusing me, Jiya.
You seem to forget that Maheen and I have the right to love as much as Gulrez.
You're mocking me for breaking a heart.
What if I broke two?
Two?
Yours and hers?
Wow...
Ever care to check
If she's actually in love or just taking you for a ride?
C'mon, Jiya, we're friends.
That's why I'm saying it.
I know her better than you.
She doesn't speak the truth.
But aye, I wouldn't say the same about her diary...
Scared?
Don't be.
She broke her engagement for you.
Called you to stop you.
Says a lot about who she'd write about.
But still...
Before you meet your love for the first time...
Please, go see Gulrez.
Just once? To ease him, you know.
Okay, I will.
Although it hurts me...
I'm ashamed, really...
No idea what I'm gonna say to him...
But I'll see him.
I've got to.
Translation: Aditya Misra Â© GEO TV