foo
So,
How do I look?
Like a cricketer!
Come on now! It's going to be fun! You've got to beat everyone!
Tell me any story you want and be done with it.
I've decided
To listen to everything you say today.
What do you think?
All this pleading before you
Is just to tell you some story?
The truth is
My heart does not want even now
That I dig up
Your mother's grave before you.
That is out of my control now.
But I can't bear to stand before my daughter
As the culprit.
Start narrating...
What's in it?
Those letters
That your mother wrote to her beloved.
Before starting the story,
You need to read these.
Waqar Ahmed,
Fajr Aurangzeb,
Mehrunnisa Dastoor, and Ali Dastoor.
Announcing now the lineup for Maheen's Losers,
Who named my team?
It's the jury's decision.
Your team will be 'Maheen's Losers' until you win.
We'll see about that. Announce the lineup.
Gulrez will be playing for me.
You don't need to ask.
Gulrez will be on your team.
Announce the names.
Maheen Aurangzeb,
Gulrez Akhtar,
Neelam Wali Ahmed, and... And...
Kaneez Maruf Ahmed.
Imagine you're playing against the British Empire.
But the fact is that I'm not as great a cricketer as he's making my name sound like.
Toss the coin.
Gulrez will toss the coin for me.
May I go from our side?
No.
I will go.
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV