What are you looking at, Dastoor Ahmed?
Get him out of my sights.
Drag him away if you have to.
Come.
Take it that you're not getting forgiven.
Just a second --
Just a second, Dastoor Uncle.
I swear by you, Dado.
If I left this time,
I'm never coming back.
Das --
Dastoor Ahmed!
Dastoor Ahmed! Stop him!
Ask him to not leave!
Tell him I've forgiven him!
Every breath of mine craved to see you, you glaikit...
I used to pray
That my Waqar come back.
That I depart only after seeing him.
Forgive me, Dado.
I'm wicked.
I have made a mistake.
I've been wrong --
What's this?
Yesterday, she was willing to rain bullets on him.
She'd asked Dastoor Uncle
Why the guards had not opened fire on him.
That if he'd broken and entered,
He'd be charged for trespassing.
And today
Melted like wax.
That's how he is, Aunt.
He calls out and everyone yields.
Even his enemies develop empathy for him.
And I'm sure
He'd be in Nano's lap right now.
Like someone from play school.
As if he'd get angry if not given his toy.
An infant.
Like our Daji.
She's feeding him breakfast.
You heard that, Neelam?
Nano's feeding him his breakfast.
Stay tuned, Aunt,
For what's coming next.
What's coming next?
What do I know?
But what's it to kids
Who knows what they'll ask for and when?
Tell Nano
If he asks for something, she has to give it to him.
Alright, I'll disconnect for now.
I'll have my breakfast.
Neelam's made some fine sandwiches.
Club sandwiches.
Eat quickly
I've got something important to talk about.
I'm all ears.
Why not get married?
Why have you stopped like that?
Look at yourself
Your hair have started turning grey.
Do you intend to remain childless even at this age?
No, Dado.
No?
As in?
I don't want to get married.
Why not?
Just give me one genuine reason.
Whom will I get married to?
Ammi Begum
Someone's calling you.
Yes, Dastoor Ahmed
Here's something for you
Take Wali along, and head for Maheen's.
Maheen's? What's the occasion?
It's time for 'Happy New Year', son.
'Happy New Year'?
That's three months away.
Why, then, are you asking what the occasion is?
Alright, Ammi Begum.
I'm on my way.
Where to?
Maheen's.
What's the occasion?
'Happy New Year'.
Splendid.
Alright, I'll disconnect.
Get a move on quickly.
Alright.
Yes, so
What were you saying?
What was I saying?
You were asking
Whom you'd get married to.
I have found a girl for you.
Rather, you had found her.
The one
For whom you've come here from France.
No, Dado, it's noth --
And
For about four years,
She's been seeking you.
No, Dado, it's nothing like that.
Get in the car, dear.
I don't have the time,
Nor you the leisure.
When it's time to settle old debts
It's just as well that you requite yours.
Greetings, Uncle.
You called upon us suddenly?
Is everything alright?
You look worried --
What happened?
No idea.
Ammi Begum called and asked me to get here this instant.
'Happy New Year..'.
'Happy New Year'?
Must be, if she's said it.
'Happy New Year'.
Is Nano coming?
No idea.
What do you know then?
She was not in the mood to listen.
Why do you think she's called us?
You guess.
I think Nano's here.
Hey
What are you looking at like that?
I'm not changing my bequest.
Whatever I'm leaving everyone, it's as it was.
But today,
I've come to ask you for something.
Let me know when you're generous.
At your service, Nano.
Bless you.
If you
Said something like this, it'd give me strength.
Yes, Nano...
You may ask for our heads.
Give your head then.
Return Maheen to me.
She's not mentioned in the will,
Thus
I've come to say this with you as my witnesses;
Come to think of it
Maheen is rightfully Waqar's.
Do a favour and
Give Maheen to Waqar.
What are you doing?
I have no objections.
Just ask Maheen.
If so she desires,
You may take her right away.
Where is she?
In her room.
Go.
Ask her.
I will keep with me the memories of our conversations and of you
Such bounties, O Love, are all one gets from you in benefaction
I will laugh wholeheartedly at this, I will embrace the heart with rapture
I will remember you then
I will remember you then, and then I will forget you
And then I will forget you
Come in.
Nano's here, Maheen.
I know.
She wants you for -- Waqar Ahmed.
She says
As per the settlement, you're rightfully his.
Then --
What did you say?
I cannot say no to her.
I cannot say no either.
I'd asked you
If this is ultion,
You'd said you were safeguarding;
You'd said I was Waqar Ahmed's treasure in your possession,
I'd said I'm love itself,
And only those get love
Who deserve it;
Else in ceremonies of espousal,
The girl gets a boy
And the boy gets a girl.
One doesn't just get love, Gulrez Akhtar.
Who's it?
It's me.
Neelam.
I'm coming.
Waqar is here, Maheen.
Yes --
I'm coming.
Did you hear that?
He's here.
I'm going.
Listen.
Promise me.
Yes?
Your wedding procession will be led by my Foxy.
Look at this anklet.
Isn't it nice?
And this bindiya [forehead jewel]?
Good morning.
Wow.
You've brought jewellery.
Show me this bindiya.
Isn't it beautiful?
Is it just you who liked it?
I'd seen you one day
In Dado's room with a bindiya adorning you.
I'd bought this that day.
And this anklet
Way earlier.
I -- I'll be back.
When you wear these,
The clinking will fill the air.
You're trying to win my heart.
I'd won your heart.
But lost the wager as I left.
And now I have no idea how much atonement is due for that moment of perfidy.
You'll get to know about your atonement soon.
Show me the jewellery.
This locket!
It's fabulous.
Doesn't it look beautiful!
What else have you brought?
I'll bring you whatever you want.
A gown just like
The one I'd worn that day,
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
Those bangles,
Too fragile to touch,
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
My bangle's broken...
That feeling of exhilaration
That won't let me sleep, that happiness
That I have you,
Ask all you will what comes out of love
And if you can, bring back my eight long years for me...
Those eight years whom nobody asked
How they've gone by.
The heart is its creator, and ends up being destroyed by it
Tea's ready.
Sunday.
Yes, dear; Sunday night.
She's accepted it.
She's happy with it.
She's so lively when she talks.
Tell me
Will you be here?
No.
Cricket after the marriage, she says.
Tell me - you will be here, won't you?
No --
She's said no.
She says she'll be here after the wedding.
Why are you saying that?
What's with your gang now?
Alright,
But remember
She'll miss you.
Both of you. She'll keep asking
Why you're not here.
Alright, talk to Dado.
I'd talked to him; he's not coming.
Have some shame.
You've slipped in two English words.
Anyways, how are your studies going?
Surely, I will.
I'll get back via WhatsApp too.
Sorry, Ammi Begum.
There's no Urdu word for 'WhatsApp'.
Anyway, Ali. Disconnect for now.
Ammi Begum's phone is ringing.
Yes, dear.
She wants the same gown.
The same as?
The same as she wore last time.
Great.
Now what do I do with this one?
She's not wearing that one.
Let me talk to her.
No Dado, there's nothing to talk about over this.
She's said it, and that's it.
Alright.
Disconnect the phone.
Bye.
Take this gown away.
She doesn't want it.
She's said that she'll wear the same one to this wedding as well.
Take it away.
You'll do everything as I desire?
Yes.
You're settling debts.
I'm just trying to make you happy.
I'm chuffed.
I've been waiting for you for eight years.
Waiting for this Sunday night for eight years.
They say you should never ask lovers
How much they love they have.
For nobody can ever express.
But I can, Waqar Ahmed.
So tell me.
How much do you love me?
So much
That Gulrez died
And I lay waiting for you.
That alone is what's good about you.
If one waits for you, you do come in the end.
You've never asked me
Since when I've been in love with you.
The day you slapped me.
That's when.
I was furious then.
But seeing your fingers imprinted on my cheek would melt my heart.
Oh?
You used to fight with me over it.
Not with you, Waqar Ahmed.
But with myself.
I was afraid
That you may come to know about it.
And when you did come to know,
You slapped me again.
If that had been on my face,
I'd never have married Gulrez.
But the second slap was your departure,
And took along those marks of your fingers.
Now go.
Don't meet me before Sunday.
I long to meet you too
But not now, Waqar Ahmed.
I'll see you on the wedding day itself.
Love's testimony is not to be asked of it
You've never asked me
Since when I've been in love with you.
The day you slapped me.
It pulls out tears and drops them from the eyes
They say you should never ask lovers
How much they love they have.
So tell me.
How much do you love me?
So much
That Gulrez died.
I'm here.
I'd told you you just need to call me.
Why have you come here yourself?
I'm like my Foxy.
I can get up and move any time I want.
Come here.
Sit.
Make yourself comfortable here
And talk to me.
Wali says I'll be fine soon.
Yes.
What about it?
I know you'll be fine soon.
On the contrary...
I'd much rather it go on like this.
I prefer it this way.
You looking at me time and again...
Getting scared...
I used to think I'd die for nothing
But now I feel I'll leave you in tears, Maheen...
You'll break those bangles in your grief...
Your weeping and wailing will know no bounds...
Truly,
It will be exhilarating...
Shut up!
Hey!
Listen.
You --
Why are you all so afraid of dying?
And here
It was only after I died that I realized
Such is life!
Go to sleep.
No, Maheen.
Sleep scares me.
Please come here.
Sit by me.
Ask me what I'm looking at.
What are you looking at?
Clicking your photograph.
Ask me how.
How?
When someone gazes their Maheen
Like I am
He actually clicks her photograph.
But
This is the kind that cannot be printed.
It remains captured in the eyes.
Now ask
What I will do with your photograph?
What will you do?
I've heard there are houries there.
I'll say,
'If there's one like this, alright'.
'Otherwise, stay away'.
Such bounties, O Love, are all one gets from you in benefaction
I will laugh wholeheartedly at this, I will embrace the heart with rapture
I will remember you then
I hate tears.
I will remember you then, and then I will forget you
And then I will forget you...
Translation: Aditya Misra © GEO TV