Jaysus, this alarm!
Get up, Shahrukh!
Jaysus, not again!
Where's the blasted button?
Everyone's gonna get up except you!
Shahrukh!
Get up, Shahrukh!
Get up already!
This ain't gonna work...
Wait. I know what to do...
-Just a couple more minutes...
Get up right now, or you know there's gonna be floodin' here!
-Don't -- Don't!
Why do you have to set so many alarms?
9.30 already? Jeez... First day at the office and I'm late! What's the boss gonna do?
Mind your step!
My car!
My car! Shahrukh!
Shahrukh! No --!
It's my car you're -- Jaysus!
Shahrukh, you bugger!
We ought to kick these two out. Proper pain in the neck, these two...
About chuffin' time.
Help me, O God! May I not lose another job!
He had the nerve to take my car!
Yeah, Glucose?
I know you took my car! You know I had a meeting!
Can't you let your friend borrow it? I ain't asking for your life or something!
Well that's because you've already taken it! And - what nerve! Not even sorry!
No thank yous and no sorries in friendship, just -- Hey!
Glucose...
I had a teeny tiny accident...
An accident! It's my car, you moron!
It's all your fault! Calling me when I'm driving!
But -- Shahrukh!
It's a woman!
Just a minute.
Out.
What've I done?
I didn't do it.
What do you mean? Can't you see my car here? You bumped in and broke the bumper!
The bumper...
What about my car?
Well, ma'am... Can't you see your car's parked right in the middle of the road?
-Hello?
Are you out of your mind? Can't you see the stop light?
What stop light?
To the Devil with her! Get back to me!
Alright, let's not block the traffic. Pull over. We can talk.
Come.
To the left.
No idea why women have to drive at all!
I'll be waiting!
You messed with the wrong woman!
Yeah, Glucose --
-What the devil do you think you're doing?
Calm down.
I've only got one car!
-Mind your glucose. It's her car that took the blow. Not yours.
You're in for it! I'll be waiting!
Jeez... I'm so late...
C'mon...
Where'd she come from?
I'm a gonner...
Where could she be going?
Where's my lift? C'mon, now...
Excuse me...
Excuse me?
Mam...
My heart's-a-skippin' a beat!
That lift doesn't work...
Use this one.
Excuse me...
Good morning.
I'm Shahrukh.
The man from the stairs?
Yes...
It's my first day.
Being punctual, are we?
Mr Abbas asked about you...
That's one of three. Three hits and you're out.
I'd already drafted your termination letter.
I'm so sorry... I work hard. I'm ready to put my heart into it.
Good... Just hold on to your heart, okay? Don't lose it to someone here. Mr Abbas can be very strict.
What do you mean?
I'm telling you because you're good at heart. Mr Abbas doesn't like flirts.
Is he something of a heart-throb? Mr Abbas, I mean.
He doesn't like flirts in his office.
Consider yourself kicked out the day he saw you with a woman or the day one of them complained to him.
What's with all these restrictions? You all single?
How'd you guess?
He's meeting a director right now. Wait here until he's done.
Fair enough...
Komal...
We need these submitted ASAP, okay?
Why didn't she say anything to me?
You bet she complained about you, Shahrukh!
No, you're talking to a kid born yesterday. Of course I know! And how much more do I have to wait?
I know the kind of blue I want! Yeah -- Hold on for a moment... Yeah?
I wanted to show you these options, sir...
-And they're telling me you haven't even sent them the options!
I had a small accident on the way... That's why I got late. I was about to send the options, but I wanted to show you first.
-Go on.
Yeah, how much is it? No way I'm paying you that much!
We know many others who'd do it for much less!
You?
What are you doing here?
I --
Mr Abbas asked for you again. Double time!
Hey!
What are you doing? It's expensive.
Don't touch anything.
Sir... I -- Sorry...
-Well, nice to meet you, Mr Sorry! Lovely name. Easy for you to introduce yourself and apologise in one breath!
I'm Shahrukh, sir... And I'm sorry... I mean -- It was a mistake, the accident...
You had an accident too? Guess what, the lady just now had one too. World Accident Day, is it?
What about the programme?
-Yeah, about that...
Hey! Who asked you to sit? Right... Go on.
Komal...
Yeah?
Who's the bloke seeing Mr Abbas?
New associate producer. It's his first day.
Last day, more like.
What do you mean?
Jeez...
Let me know when he's back. I'll tell Mr Abbas all about him!
He's got a heart of gold...
Aww, sweet li'l Komal...
All that glitters is not gold.
Get it?
Hey!
I'm helping you because you're nice.
No, thank you.
I don't need any money.
Not that sort of help!
-So?
You've lost this job. Find another one.
But why?
Did the bossman approve the termination letter?
Not yet. But it won't be long.
Because Anoushay's gonna complain and get you kicked out.
Anoushay?
You hit her car, remember?
I'm helping you because I like you.
Do something about Anoushay, before she... You know...
Thank you for telling me.
You're nice.
Yeah...
But I don't let the lads know...
But... Now that you know, I'm not really hiding it from you...
All out of ideas...
That nasty cur!
Let's see...
Good morning...
Shahrukh.
Just in case you didn't know, you ruined my day! Hit my car and ran away, but oh dear God, you have the nerve to come and stand here shamelessly --
I can grab a pew if you ask.
I wanted to say...
It's all my fault. I'm really sorry.
All your fault?
Yes.
Good.
So you accidentally hit my car?
Of course.
And you just accidentally blurted out that I can't drive?
Mhm hmm... And I suppose you just accidentally ran away sharpish?
Of course...
You got a job here accidentally too, yes?
-No. Not the job.
But I'm ready to pay you back for your losses.
All my fault, I'm really sorry. I shouldn't even be on the road when you're driving.
What do you mean?
I mean...
I'll pay for the repairs... Every single penny.
Good.
I say, take this pencil and note it here...
Right...
Just a minute... Please record it.
On my phone?
Go on.
Rear bumper... Okay?
Backlights - original.
And indicators - original... And...
-Hold on...
They didn't look original?
Oh they didn't?
-Nope.
Fair enough...
So they didn't...
-A cuppa for me too, please...
-I'm calling Mr Abbas.
-Why?
I want to ask him if they were original.
Of course they were original! I saw them!
And?
Oiling.
Wait... What's that got to do with this accident?
Oh, yeah... What's that got to do with the accident?
-Yeah.
It's got nothing to do with it, yes?
-Yes.
Okay.
-Where are you off to?
Going to ask Mr Abbas if it's --
-Got everything to do with the accident! Of course!
Sit.
Jesus...
Fill up the car.
-Hey --
Fill up the car?
But you drive to work everyday!
Yeah, I don't normally need it... But then I don't normally chase a wazzock around town either!
And don't you dare think I'm saying any of it because I can't get it myself. I have the money.
I just want you to learn your lesson.
Okay.
Get it all fixed by tomorrow, or Mr Abbas will be fixing you.
Don't worry, I --
-Okay, goodbye.
Thank you.
I know...
It's harder to earn a place in flat share than in someone's heart...
We're looking for a place... We'll move out as soon as we've found one.
-So very kind of you, sirs, so very kind.
Anytime, mate.
And -- I needed some -- to get the car repaired...
Who've I got except you?
I'll pay you back in three days, when I've got my paycheck.
Shahrukh, you blimmin' prat! I'll kill you!
Outta my way!
You blimmin' hit my car!
-That's what I was talking to them about! Money to get your car fixed!
Get my car fixed?
Of course.
Really?
Really. I'll return it once I've got my paycheck.
Here.
Kamal... Ghafoor... Give him what he wants... He's a good kid, I assure you, he'll pay you back.
Yeah I'll give it back when I've got my paycheck.
Jeez...
C'mon, mate, at least 2,000? You know how it is these days...
Ghafoor...?
Robbin' us of our peace and now our money!
Thank you.
Now you better get my car fixed!
Of course, mate.
I...
I don't know how I'll be able to return this favour...
-Well, return the money, for starters.
100% fixed. In perfect condition.
Happy?
About what?
You just paid for what you damaged.
No... I mean... Let's end this crossness between us, okay?
-Excuse me!
What are you talking about? Who do you think you are that I'd even be cross with you?
Go. I'm busy.
A special offer from the mechanic. Free repairs if anything goes wrong before tomorrow evening.
Lovely.
So... If you could just give me your number...
I can give it to the mechanic.
Wait... So you don't remember your own number?
Yeah... Shame I never had to call myself.
Oh...
Yep, I was right...
-Here...
Please type here.
Here.
-Please save it.
Can you read? Good, can you use a phone? Know my name?
-Of course.
Save it, then!
Get going!
Cheap! Cheap cad!
Hello?
-Yeah, Komal...
I've given your number to the mechanic. Let me know if he calls.
Okay.
Thank you.
You git! Why didn't you get the car fixed?
I did... Got the car I hit fixed... Or she would've had me kicked out of the job!
You took the money from us to get her car fixed?
I told you! I mean -- Just look at his face! Can you read the blasted 'Danger Ahead' sign?
The landlord says he's kickin' us out if we didn't kick youse twos out!
Why didn't you come with me to see the new flat?
My dear mates... It won't be the end of the world if we spent another day here!
Who are you calling?
Someone from the office... Need to talk to her about the project...
Let me guess... It's her car you hit.
No secrets from you... She's gonna be your sister-in-law!
Okay... But tell her it was my car that hit her!
Of course!
-Also tell her we're about to get kicked out of our flat!
Ringing...
What d'you expect? The phone ain't gonna start talking to you, I mean!
Hello? Who is it?
-Hello...
Hi...
It's...
It's... Shahrukh.
The car accident... Remember?
Yeah, I get it, Shahrukh. How are you, handsome?
'Handsome'?
What was that?
That --
Was my heart speaking out...
I mean -- An echo from my empty heart... An echo, yeah...
Wow... You're so romantic! Just like me!
I can hear the echoes from here...
So... I hope you had no trouble with the car?
What car?
Jeez... You gonna talk about the car again?
Yeah... I thought I'd bring it up... Get this show on the road, you know...
So... Why'd you call?
I wanted to tell you that...
You...
You've got a lovely smile...
So don't be angry again, okay?
Really?
And... You've got beautiful eyes...
-Sweet Mary, never knew Dr Shahrukh was an eye specialist!
-Shut up!
Who was that?
No... No one really...
It's the telly!
We interrupt this programme for a special news bulletin... Love is in the air this time of the year because of a shortage of eye specialists. You're watching Geo News.
Wha --? Hello?
What is going on?
Nothing... Nothing at all...
Something going on in the nearby apartment... Maybe something there?
Where are you?
On the terrace... Want me to video call you?
Actually no... The signal's weak...
The signal's weak...
So...
How's everything? Wh -- What's your dream?
My dream... Well... I want my Prince Charming to propose to me with a nice, lovely flower...
Wow...
How innocent...
Well you may've just found him!
A bit weird, yeah...
But I just want Anoushay to know her dream man's here...
Anoushay... I love you!
What are you looking at?
N -- Nothing...
You want to keep this job or not?
-Get going quick, Shahrukh! Before Mr Abbas sees you!
How does His Royal Highness look?
Jesus, mate... I mean -- Your first impression wasn't even so bad that you...
But you said you'd like it if...
If a clown came in like that?
No way!
Goodness, women these days! Going back on their word so quick...
You said it's your dream that your Prince Charming propose to you with a flower...
Hello? What are you high on?
Get going, bro... I'm busy.
Blimey, that's some fury... 'Bro'!
What's next? You gonna say you never said anything about the prince and the flower?
-I didn't. Please, get going!
Okay.
Give it to someone else.
I thought the days of the Monarchy were long gone!
-Well --
In any case, I wouldn't want to let go of a chance to serve Your Royal Highness!
Please, come to my room.
Blimmin' Clown Prince of Clotland.
Pray leave.
What did he say?
Offered his seat as my throne. I said I can't imagine my boss out of this job.
He gave me the first warning.
It's your last warning!
You'll be out of this job if anything happened now.
Come here!
Where are you?
We had to go see the flat, remember?
What's up? You look worried.
Never mind...
Barely saved my job...
Not sure how long you can keep at this trade... Seems you're more after the maid!
By the way... They won't keep us any longer.
Tomorrow. Today's just not the day.
They've let us stay when no one gives a lift... When no lover gives his Facebook password...
Tomorrow... Please...
Have it your way...
Yeah?
You didn't call me...
Do you think I'd call you after that insult?
Sorry... All my fault...
I was just being figurative...
But I'm glad you did it for me... My prince with the flower...
'Glad'? You what?
-Yeah...
You're glad? You asked me to leave!
I wanted to save you from Mr Abbas!
Is she touched in the head?
One way by day, another by night!
What?
Nothing... Why'd you say you don't like clowns?
When did I say that?
Goodness, women these days!
Okay... I'm sorry...
Fix your mood, will you? I can't sleep.
Hmm... Okay...
Bye.
I'm taking the day off tomorrow. See you the day after.
Move aside, Katie... Now where've I kept it?
What?
Where could my cell be?
What are you looking for, Dad?
My cell disappeared!
Scientifically speaking, cells divide. And multiply. They don't disappear.
-Ehh?
Not that cell, genius. Of course he's talking about the cells in the jail!
I got it, Dad. Right here!
Dad's not talking about batteries. He means his cell phone!
And...
Here's your cell phone, Dad.
Thank goodness...
What was that?
Quick IQ check.
The ball bounces back if you've got a high IQ... In your case, I'm afraid it's mostly empty up there.
Very funny...
Just a minute... I didn't call you here to help me find my cell phone.
There's something --
I know! There's something you want to tell us. Right, Dad?
Obviously... I don't think he just wants to have a chat? Please be quick, Dad. I've got to go to work.
Speaking of which, I see the channel's started going downhill ever since Anoushay got a job there!
She's the only one who works. The rest of you just throw a spanner in the works!
That's why I never took the risk...
Sergeant Molabux...
Yeah...
No, send them...
Right away.
You know my address.
Okay.
Done...
Blimey...
Good news!
The matchmaker called.
Someone wants to see Nigar.
Good morning.
We're looking for a flat... To rent... Have you got any?
One in Guriya Colony...
-Okay...
But no one lasts there for long...
Rented for one month, free for the next two...
Why? A ghost?
Aye, a ghost and all sorts o' witches there.
I want nothing like last time.
-Don't worry, Dad.
We'll come up with something new...
Don't you dare!
You won't find matches that suit us, Dad...
Get going, Anoushay. I'd hate it if you took the day off... The folks at your channel might realise they can do just fine without you.
The sarge doesn't let the estate agent rent his place out! Still, if that's what you want, go try your luck.
Dad?
-Yeah?
What's this?
What are you doing?
No bell here?
Good morning.
-Good morning. Bless you.
We wa --
-I know. Sergeant Molabux knows the man when he sees him!
Come.
I think he really meant it. About the ghost, I mean. Who d'you think told him?
-C'mon!
Bless you!
At ease, gentlemen...
Where are your Mum and Dad?
They're in Hyderabad.
Hello...
-I'm Katie. She's Mickey.
My younger daughters...
How about a cuppa? Or a cold drink?
We'd love both.
Nigar!
Two cold cuppas, please!
My daughters are very simple and homely.
I just love his jokes!
Meet Nigar, my eldest daughter.
Hello.
She's made it all herself.
Uhh... How much do you earn?
50 gee a month...
That's great...
When I have a half-decent job, that is.
So... Which of you is the lad?
Ehh?
We're both lads...
Oh? I thought it was just you...
I wonder why he's surprised to find out about you!
Bet you couldn't see it!
Have some more.
Thank you.
Nigar's my eldest daughter...
Uh -- Okay...
I want to get her married first...
What do you say?
Aye, that's how it is... 'First come, first served'...ish!
I told you!
Why's he asking us? Just ask about the rent!
Mind if we have a look?
I'm sure we can decide better if we have a good look first...
I'm sure you've had a good look at Nigar already...
Yeah -- How much do you want?
I mean... Advance and all...
'Advance'?
'Advance'!
'Have a good look'... Lord...
Oh I'm gonna tell you everything!
Where's he off to?
Getting his gun...
What? His gun?
What's up with him? Welcoming us, giving us a treat, introducing us to you, and filling us with lead when we talk about the rent?
You want to rent this place?
Of course!
Put the plate down.
Put it down! Christ, put it down already!
-I warned you!
You ain't gettin' out of here alive!
No, Dad! They want to rent this place!
-Wait, Dad!
-Listen, Dad!
It's a mistake, Dad!
-They're just looking for a place to rent!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky Entertainment