You ain't gettin' out of here alive!
No, Dad! They want to rent this place!
-Wait, Dad!
-Listen, Dad!
It's a mistake, Dad!
-They're just looking for a place to rent!
Dad!
-No, Dad!
-Wait!
Not so fast! They just want to rent this place. Let them have a look!
-Dad! Scientifically speaking, we ought to let them have a look.
-Easy, Dad...
They want to rent this place?
Yeah...
Okay.
Come.
Go!
Double time!
Here --
-It's not for them!
It's for whoever's coming here with the proposal...
Ever thought you could help your sister out? Miss Lazybones!
Alright, I'll get back to you. After I'm through with these lads...
So, Sarge... We like the place.
I take 6 months' advance. Then you hand me the cash every three months on the day you get the bill. I'll deposit everything myself.
Uh, Sarge... I was wondering if there's a discount or something...
Out! Get out!
I knew you're stone broke before I even saw you!
-No, I've got some here... As an advance...
Besides, I only rent this place to married men.
I've got four daughters.
Yeah! He's married. I tell you, he is.
Yeah... Aren't you?
-Yeah... I am.
Got a family?
Yeah.
-Yeah. Of course.
Then what are you lookin' at? I wanna see 'em before you bring your things.
-Come.
Blimey, why'd you have to lie about it? You got me in a mess!
Why not? Besides, who's gonna throw us out when we've moved in?
By the way, it doesn't look like a bachelor pad if you ask me!
But we're looking at trouble if he finds out we --
Good day, Sarge. Come. Grab a pew. Make yourself at home.
How about you get out of mine instead? Out!
Why? What is it?
-Lemme tell you...
Where's your wife, eh?
Wife...
She's --
We should tell him...
What it is is... She's -- Gone to her parents'... We had a domestic...
Oh... Gone to her parents'...
Very sorry to hear it... WHAT D'YA THINK I AM? I've spent my life at the police station!
What'd they bang you up for?
He's the Sarge, so, of course... He's off his head...
D'you see something over here? Perhaps a sign reading 'moron'?
I can see it but I'm not sure if it says 'moron' or --
How 'bout you take a look from outside? Out!
Your wife is your key to this place!
You were right...
He's raving mad... Now we've lost our things and money!
How'd I find my wife now, eh, smarty-pants?
You've got to... If we want to stay there.
Why don't you marry one of his daughters?
I'm sure it'd save you the ren --
Found her!
Where?
The veiled lady over there!
But she's got kids!
Forget that! Just -- Hold these, will you?
Hello again, Sarge.
-Hello...
My wife...
Your... Wife?
Right here.
Greet him.
Bless you.
She mute or something?
No... Just... Veiling her voice.
He's like your father. Greet him.
Good day, Sarge.
-Good day. Bless you.
And how'd she know I'm a Sergeant?
-I told her, of course.
Oh, he suspects everyone...
Please give us the keys so we can go...
-Ah, yes, the keys...
Come.
Wait.
I haven't even welcomed you properly...
Perhaps you'd like a cuppa?
-Thank you, sir... We'll pass.
It's time for her prayers... She's gonna bless all of us.
How long have you been married?
5 years.
-3 years.
She says 3 years, you say 5... What is going on here?
You can add up our threes...
Three and three... And five! It doesn't quite add up.
It does if you subtract the 6 months she spent at her parents' and the 6 I spent at mine! 6 - 1 = 5!
I get it now... But, I wonder... Why are you wearing men's shoes?
I'm -- You know... Veiling my shoes...
Veiling your shoes?
Fair enough... First time I've heard of it though...
Anyway... Make yourself at home here.
You can take that veil off...
Shahrukh! This man's asking me to take off my veil! No way I'm staying here! Let's go!
No... Wait...
-I didn't mean it like that...
What was the, uh, domestic about?
When?
You know, when...
So you were making it up, eh?
No, sir...
The thing is, my Uncle asked her to take off her veil...
She almost left me!
If you tried to force her, she may leave me again... Forever, this time! Please...
No way...
Don't worry...
Don't mind trifles like these...
Make yourself at home here...
Just let me know if you need anything, okay? Go.
Katie, Mickey, Anoushay, Nigar...
Dad... I've asked you so many times to say our names in the right order... Like, I'm the eldest, so say my name first... You slip up every time.
What? Yeah? Go on!
What is it, Dad?
Our new tenant has moved in with his wife...
But... I don't know why... I have my suspicions about his wife...
Why don't you let her husband worry about that?
These suspicions killed Mum!
So where do we come in?
Go and... Tell them we're eating together.
Okay. I'll tell them we're having dinner with them.
-No.
Tell them they're having dinner with us.
Okay.
Where's your wife? And who's dancing?
Dancing?
Ah, yes...
My...
Oops, sorry...
My wife has an upset stomach... She's gone to the loo.
I bolt the door from the outside too!
The bolt inside was broken...
We're here to see her.
She's gone to the loo. Come back tomorrow.
She's coming out tomorrow?
Oh, she takes ages! She delayed our wedding by a day!
You could've fixed the date for a day later. No delays then!
Alright, we'll wait.
How do I throw them out?
Is that a lizard?
A lizard?
Been ages since I laid my hands on one! Ooh, it's hunting season!
I'm hunting her this time!
Either way, I'll throw it... At someone!
Blimey, they aren't even scared of it!
Where is it?
We're getting bored.
How 'bout you show us your wedding album? Where is it?
-Yeah.
Throw 'em out already!
-Calm down... And hang up before you get us both killed!
But all the women are veiled... They look the same!
That's my wife's family for you...
How d'you identify her?
Very simple. I just ask.
How much time do you need, man? It's a blimmin' furnace in here!
Shut up! It's easy for you to say that from in there! They've cornered me! Bye!
Dinner? No th --
-Aye, we're having dinner with you tonight... But downstairs.
But -- Not today... I mean, just look at how sick she is!
First time someone's turned us down...
I smell something dodgy!
Tomorrow. I promise!
Thank you.
Did any of you see her?
No... But we saw his wedding album... She's veiled in every picture!
What does he do?
Nothing much, judging by his salary...
He's turned off the lights... I just saw... Do you think they turned in so early?
Turn off the lights! Or they'll think we're up and barge in!
First time I've seen you scared of girls.
Where are you taking my laptop?
There's a virus on mine. I need to do some things... I'll mail it to myself from here.
Sleep early. We gotta leave first thing in the morning, or the Sarge will start interrogating us again!
Good point.
Something's not right...
But no idea what it is.
I'm impressed by you, Dad...
But no idea why.
I'll see his wife before going to office. Find out everything about her.
Why are you so quiet?
I was wondering... Why do you always behave like you don't know me? At the office, I mean...
I'm afraid of Mr Abbas...
Oh?
We should go out someday...
Sure... How about the bistro at the crossroads? See you there.
Bistro?
No... Something better... The coffee shop near the shop? 4 p.m.?
Okay. Done.
Great. See you. Bye.
Bye.
I'm the Sarge's daughter... I'd like to meet your wife.
My wife?
Ah, yes... Her... She's in the washroom...
Call her, then.
Uh, no... She takes ages... She's in the washroom until the evening... Washing... Her face! Over and over again! Would you believe it?
Until the evening?
-Yeah.
OCD or something?
Yeah. That.
-Makes sense...
♪ It's a wonderful world! ♪
Who's singing?
No one? It's -- My wife...
The cold water makes her sound manly...
I'm sure you're getting late... You should get going... I'll tell you when h -- she's out.
Okay, I'll be back in the evening.
-Sure thing.
How do women live in this? I nearly break a bone ever other second!
-Keep your voice down!
And speak in a womanly voice... What if --
They're here...
Hey! How you doin'?
Hi!
Going somewhere?
-To the office, yeah.
Just a second...
Wow... She's smart!
Step aside... Please take that veil off. We want to see you. I bet my face glows more than yours! Nigar's losing this one!
We're getting late... C'mon, Glucose...
Glucose! What a sweet name! Scientifically speaking, that makes her husband very likely to be diabetic!
Sweet Mary, what's she saying? May you stay healthy!
Come!
Outta my way!
So sweet!
Looks like we've rented trouble, Shahrukh... You realise we're gonna be thrown in the slammer if we got caught?
-So be it! It was you who said I'm married! Now stay quiet!
Aye, where to?
Hey...
We're going to the office.
I suppose your wife's here?
Yeah.
When did he come in?
Just about... Now?
He's dropping me at the office.
-Yeah...
Okay. Go.
Take care!
Peep-a-boo!
Not cricket! Then again, it's his place.
Gor blimey...
But what's he looking at?
If I'm smart, it doesn't mean I have to do all the thinking!
Scientifically speaking, you don't need to think much if you're smart! Just like...
I say, let's go ask Dad!
-C'mon.
Dad!
-Whoa!
How many times do I have to tell you - tell before you yell?
Scientifically speaking, it's wrong to peep into someone's place like that. Legally too!
Lemme tell you... I won't let you take anything from inside. Willy nilly.
Do I look like a thief?
Worse. You look like a cop.
You have no idea... This bloke...
Shahrukh - he's a blimmin' cruel husband.
Locked his poor wife in!
-Poor girl...
Say 'poor wife' again, Dad?
Poor wife...
Blimey, he looks like a poor old man when he says 'poor wife'!
We saw him leave with his wife!
No way! He just left with that rascal who was with him when he first came here... He said his wife's upstairs...
Scientifically speaking, cops retire from duty but never from suspecting people!
We've got to break open this door!
No need... Wait and watch...
Alohomora!
-Eh?
-Ehh?
I think the spell doesn't work for locks made by this company...
Mrs Glucose!
Open the door! It's us!
Wait! What are you doing?
Freeing a poor woman locked in by her cruel husband!
My wife's right here!
Gotcha, Dad!
You said she's upstairs!
You said it... I just nodded! What d'you think, Glucose?
Yeah... That's what happened... I think...
Glucose? But wasn't her name... Razia?
Yeah, it is, but I like to call her Glucose because... She's so sweet...
Okay...
What'd you feel when you married him? That you're marrying him or treating him? Glucose?
I -- I forgot my laptop up here... So sh -- he's brought me back so I can get it... Excuse me...
Glucose...
Dad!
I thought -- Just -- checking the hinges, you know...
Take care.
Bless you...
Bless the two of you.
Hi!
Bye.
Why don't you talk to me?
I only talk to people I like.
What's up with your memory? Head over heels for me at night and not even talking to be by day!
Anyway... What's the programme today?
Oh, nothing much, although I do feel like smothering the life out of a creepy cad!
Poor Mr Abbas!
-Poor you, more like!
Don't bother. A wink or a smile might just kill me!
Mind if I say something? Actually - I don't care if I do - you're such a third-rate flirt! Cheap!
I expected worse.
Anyway... What about the date?
Check your phone...
I mean going to the café for a nice litt --
Don't even think about it!
Who does he think he is?
Such a weird girl!
Hi!
Bye!
What about the date?
♪ Just like good old-fashioned love... ♪
Always busy with your blooming ball! Careful!
Your cuppa...
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking...
Why Shahrukh's wife doesn't show her face...
You're thinking that I'm thinking about what you're thinking.
And Nigar's thinking how I know what you're thinking...
And Mickey's thinking about what she should be thinking about!
Jesus, I lost my train of thought in that mess!
You were thinking why Shahrukh's wife doesn't show her face!
Ah, yes...
Scientifically speaking, it's their problem. None of our business.
Scientifically speaking...
I'm thinking the veil...
May be hiding a man!
Splendid! I guess great minds do think alike!
I'm sure the veil hides someone - a man or a woman. And we're gonna find out who he - or she - is!
How?
I'm thinking of something... Think with me...
Anoushay!
Hello?
Hello. Where are you, Shahrukh? I've been waiting at the restaurant for ages!
Really?
I didn't come because I thought your mood was off...
Come here quick. I can't wait much longer!
Coming... Right away!
Wow!
When do you plan to start shooting this?
The set isn't ready yet, sir... Gotta work on it... Lighting, and all... Before we start shooting.
Lovely... Tell your team I'm waiting for them in the conference room.
Get all their termination letters ready! Kick 'em out! I've been waiting two weeks and you can't even get a blasted set ready! That's awful leadership!
Sir -- I'll go -- Ca --
-Go call them! 'I'll go -- Ca --'... Jesus, it's been two weeks already, what are you even doing, like the set -- Komal!
Blimey, Anoushay... Where are you?
Hello? Where are you? That fat cow Komal's here! Sitting at the table... Snoring! She's wearing so much lipstick it looks like she's been drinking blood!
And look at her confidence! As if whoever she's waiting for is blind! She's mad, I tell you!
I'm right here! Where are you?
Right here!
Oh...
I'm sorry I --
I was just fooling around!
They all just fool around with me! Come.
Yeah...
Oops... I forgot to lock my car... Just a sec. Here.
Your car? You don't have a car!
Not fair! You gave me Komal's number instead? I've been saying God-knows-what to her thinking it's you!
Ever thought you could - I don't know, maybe - use your brain?
I almost went on a date with her!
Are you serious?
Poor Komal!
Poor Komal or poor me?
If it isn't your girlfriend!
I'll make you pay for this!
Getting nervous before your girlfriend, eh?
Hi, Komal!
Hi!
How're you doing?
Fine... Just this little headache...
Why?
K -- Ko...
What do you even come here to do? We're a bloody live channel! You even understand what that means? What the hell is wrong with you?
I want this show on air from next week! If you can't do it, you better leave!
What's the problem, Monsieur le directeur?
We haven't even finalised the set...
Oh...
I showed him two designs but he didn't like either of them... I've got a third one here...
Here... Sir?
Oh, this...
This ugly piece of crap!
Let's ask around. D'you like it?
You? What d'you think of this? Nice?
And you, Komal? Like any part of it?
What d'you expect people to say when you can't say a word about your set? When you can't comment on your own work?
Is that what a month's output is for you? It's been two months, Anoushay... Is that how you work?
Komal... What d'you think we should do?
Termination?
Very good.
Give it to her.
If that's how you perform, I'm gonna have to prepare a new team! We can't go on with you folks! This is terrible! Terrible!
Sir...
Just a minute... Please.
Anoushay...
Why don't you show him the set you showed me?
Which one, Shahrukh? I don't think I showed you any --
Just a minute... I'll show you, sir...
I've talked to a set designer, who --
Have a look at this, sir... It is mind-blowing. Out of the world!
No channel in the world has anything like it! Yeah, c'mon, take a look!
The lighting looks fantastic... If we can pull this off, yeah... It'll be great!
Why didn't you show him this one, Anoushay?
Wow...
Good. Excuse me.
You designed it, Anoushay?
-Of course!
Very nice.
But, sir --
-Please, not now... Not when he likes it!
The problem with her, sir, is she's as hesitant as she's talented... She just lacks confidence! That's all...
I think it's a good one! Well done, Anoushay. Appreciate the effort. I like it.
Okay, carry on, everyone. Start working on the set tomorrow.
Good job.
Oh, and...
By the way...
Give her that letter back. I don't think we're gonna need it now.
Good job, Anoushay...
Have a look at your set?
You said you'll make me pay... But then, all of this... I don't get it.
It wasn't easy to get this job, you know... Had to step in to save it...
But he was firing me...
You're so talented... I'm sure you can get a job anywhere you like... I had to save myself! After all, I almost didn't even get this one!
Wow... That's a rather convoluted pick-up line...
Would you like to hear a more straightforward one?
Who made this set, by the way?
The same friend whose car I was driving...
He's bringing us together... Indirectly!
Got to throw a pick-up line in every sentence, eh?
So... Is it for free?
No. You've got to pay for it... With your number.
7.
I mean your mobile number. Not your shoe size.
Note it down.
Here. Write it yourself.
I want your number this time! I'm still paying for the last time!
It's mine.
-Okay.
Hey...
Yeah?
Nothing...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky Entertainment