foo
What're you doing here? Got a job here?
-Hey...
No, I'm designing a set for them...
Anyway, see you.
-Good luck.
Thanks.
I'm gonna kill you!
-Calm down...
Calm down my foot! I can live as your 'wife', but I can't take an attack on my credibility! They say I've stolen the design!
I'll pay you for it...
-Oh you will? Really?
I'm gonna kill you for real! You blasted cheat! I don't wanna see you again, Shahrukh!
-Hey! Easy! Calm down!
Good day... You're the Sarge, yes?
I knew it when I saw you!
We're Shahrukh's parents.
-And I'm his landlord.
Please, come in...
They'll be here in a sec...
Hear the royal 'they'? He respects his tenant, I tell you!
So...
Shahrukh never mentioned you.
He doesn't need to... I mean, everyone's got parents...
Everything alright?
-Well...
Shahrukh's getting engaged... So we thought we'd come here...
As in... He's marrying a second?
Excuse me?
I'm a professor... I forget some things... But I sure as anything can't forget my son's marriage!
What d'you mean? He's married someone here?
So... Haven't you seen his wife? Although, to be honest...
I haven't seen her either...
How are you so sure if you've never seen her?
-Aye.
She likes to cover up so much... I doubt even Shahrukh's seen her!
Ehh?
Shahrukh!
Would you see who's here? Mum and Dad!
Hey...
You could've told me...
Aye... So you could hide your wife somewhere!
What?
-You didn't tell them you got married?
Let's talk in my room?
First... Is it true? You married here?
-Yeah?
Married...
Aye?
Tell them...
Aye...
-Outta here...
-But Dad! Wait!
I'd never forgive him if he were my son, but... It's up to you...
I'm never forgiving him!
But --
-Your Dad is so upright!
Dunno about your Mum, but...
Aye, never...
Bless her too... Your parents are so upright! How could you even think of it?
I didn't! I -- Let's talk in my room, shall we?
No, we're outta here!
-Let's hear him out...
-Wait -- Dad!
Okay. What've you got?
No good, sir... If he had the guts, he wouldn't have hidden it in the first place...
Yeah... We're practically forcing you to say it because we dropped in!
I say, no point in listening to such a treacherous son...
Yeah, right...
He's betrayed us... Broken our trust...
It's no use... Come!
Hey! Dad! Wait! Mum! Lemme explain! Just gimme a minute!
Outta my way!
Such respect for your dad! Lovely jubly!
Learn summit from 'im.
Who was it, Dad?
That blighter Mahruk -- Shahrukh's parents... They didn't even know he's married!
Blimey...
Wonder if his wife's in the dark too...
She's who he's married, genius!
Shahrukh!
Ain't you too happy?
I'm sure it's because you've met Mum and Dad?
How d'you know he's happy?
Scientifically speaking... A quiet man is happy... But a quiet woman isn't.
A Sarge may retire from the force... But never from suspecting others!
I always had a feeling your Mum and Dad don't know you're married!
How?
The sources of journalists... And the informants of the force... Are always classified...
You're low on brains. Get a drip ASAP.
Where's your Glucose?
We had a domestic... She went to her parents'...
Mum, Dad, wife... That's three people you angered in one day! Way to go, mate!
A very productive day, if you ask me!
Productive? How -- ?
He got it.
You got to stay here with your wife... So come back... When she's back!
I -- I'm gonna need some time...
Scientifically sp --
-The question ain't scientific. Wives ain't scientific.
Here's a tip. Take your wife to a mall. Anywhere you find a sale... Get her what she wants, and her anger's gonna cool down for half off.
By the way, Dad... As a retired husband... Why don't you give him some tips?
You think this is Wives 101?
Get going.
You were to stay here with your wife. Come back with her and I'll let you in. Get going!
-But -- She -- Wait! Sir -- Hey!
Glucose, boyo! What's wrong with you?
You proved me a cheat! Ain't that enough?
Anoushay gave me her number for it, mate! Thanks to you, my love story's gonna reach its happy end! You're my hero!
Oh, can it... You know, a cop would be a better friend than you. You'd lose 99 times but gain something the 100th time.
That's stretching it... You'd gain more than a few times with me... Anyway... Shall we?
I don't wanna live with you.
-What've you got? This road?
The Sarge won't let me in without you...
Hey!
Take your blimmin' veil!
I'm off!
-But where?
Shut up!
-Not cricket!
You off your head? Look -- Even the car --
Just started!
Blimey, that's some real ego! Well then! Have it your way! Get lost! Besides, who's gonna know who's behind the veil?
Jaysus...
Got something for me? Give it away in the Lord's name... He'd bless you!
Looks like He just did!
Wonder what you mean.
I can give you lots. Good food. As long as you do one thing...
That's wot they aw say... I daan't trust them na...
I'm different... Just -- Put this veil on and come with me...
What d'you mean? I don't get it...
Wot do ya mean? I daan't get it...
You don't need to... Just put this on...
Wot 're ya doin'?
-Just put it on!
But why? Geroff me! 'Ey!
-Just put it on... And come with me!
Why daan't ya put it on yourself? Blimmin' idiot!
Hey!
Give me Hammer and Tack me Syrup of Fig! Curse ya!
Gimme the veil!
Gotta say... Lovely gathering...
What's Katie thinking?
I wonder how we can get a look at his wife...
Me too...
Not cricket! How can you think what I'm thinking? Back to your own thoughts!
I heard she's a bit 'round the twist... Always washing her face!
What d'you care? You're a bit 'round the twist too...
I've got an idea.
-Yeah?
I'll pull her veil off the moment she steps in.
Unveil every secret!
Lovely...
Where's she, by the way?
Had a domestic and left... And Shahrukh's gone to make up to her.
Who's Shahrukh?
Blimey, Anoushay... You don't pay attention to anything, do you?
I mean -- She doesn't even know our tenant's name!
Christ knows what she's so busy with...
What's the surprise about? He's our new tenant.
He?
But -- I saw someone else in the morning!
I'm sure you saw his friend. He's here sometimes.
His wife's always in her veil by the way. You saw her?
What?
He's married?
Yeah.
I tried my best, Sarge... But... She won't listen...
You don't just try... You gotta beg!
If you want to control her... Say you're marrying someone else!
She'll do as you say!
I tried, but she won't cover up!
I expected better.
What, having fewer rows?
-No.
You've got a wise girl right in front of you, but you won't even ask her!
Aye. Allow me.
I meant me...
Big words. Remember how Dad always said he was an honest cop?
Shut up!
You don't leave your wife - or jewels - at your in-laws'. Or you won't get them back.
Now go, get her.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky Entertainment