Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
You're my sister for just a few moments,
Until Dad starts speaking from your mouth.
You should remember, too, Afzal,
You're Molvi Subhanallah's son.
Go to sleep early.
Dad wants to meet you before noon.
And don't you dare raise your voice.
Better stay quiet when inclined to lie.
He's even worried that you may have to suffer for your lies.
Take the cup.
What are you doing?
I won't let go.
What's the big deal now?
At the very least, I can hold your hand.
Let go!
I'm getting angry!
I don't fear your fury.
And I never will after 15th December.
Let go! What if someone sees --
What's the big deal with that?
They'll just think of it as our expression of love.
No, it's not that.
Let's meet tonight?
Tonight?
Hush! The walls have ears.
On the terrace?
Yes, on the terrace.
Let go now!
When?
Nine o'clock!
Why not eight?
D -- Dad watches the news at nine.
Oh...
You promise?
You tell me.
You'll be there at nine?
Oh
I'd be there at eight-thirty.
Ohhh...
When will the night fall,
And when will it finally be nine...
Come here.
I was listening tales of her childhood shenanigans.
God forgive.
She used to hold the dog by his ears!
Hey!
I never knew there were such dogs --
I mean --
The kind that'd let you hold them by the ear?
She's talking about puppies.
Oh.
Thank you.
Mum, we're not leaving this evening.
Why?
I've got to meet someone at 9 p.m.
Here in Hydarabad? With whom?
Mum, you know one of my friends --
With him.
Leave it, he must be having plans.
You can leave tomorrow morning.
Yes Mum, we'll leave tomorrow.
Is she still asleep?
No, she's just a bit coy.
Hold it right there.
Do you know
He's told everyone about the meeting tonight.
What?
Yes.
Said he's got to meet someone tonight at nine before Dad.
The blighter!
Don't call him a blighter like that.
He's not said whom he's meeting tonight.
I'm calling him a blighter because
He grabbed me by the hand in the morning.
And refused to let go.
Stop laughing.
I felt that I should hold the meeting right at that moment.
Bring him to the terrace and drop the bombshell on him.
Please don't do this.
There's an elegance and decorum even when it comes to breaking hearts.
Piece by piece,
Slowly,
One subtle blow,
Then another.
And anyway,
Science hasn't verified something like 'broken hearts'.
Without proper precautions,
It can shatter like a glass pane.
Then I'll break it in a manner
That verifies your claim scientifically.
Oh God!
At first glance, he looked like a real gentleman.
Now, he seems neither gentle nor a man!
Mind your anger until 9 p.m.
Or Mum will think you're about to wage a war!
Peace be upon you.
-And upon you too.
Don't bring me along into the market, Molvi Sahab...
He'll come to know.
I swear by you, he'd kill me.
Do not fear anyone if you're doing something good.
I'm right here.
I won't let any harm befall you.
And upon you, peace.
So what do I have to do?
Come with me to him.
And say without fear what he's done.
Before him?
To his face.
And
Those letters you used to listen to
Do you remember
Any of what the girl used to write to him?
In most letters, she just writes,
'I'll die without you'.
God forgive!
Where does she live?
In this city, apparently.
Because he only has her letters.
No envelopes.
She lives nearby, so to speak...
Yes...
May I go now, Molvi Sahab?
I told you to go to him,
And present every piece of evidence.
No, Molvi Sahab.
If I go before him -- I'd deny everything -- I'd swear
That I never said anything.
God curses the liars!
Where are you off to now?
If you believe what I said, it ends thus --
Else just think as if I lied to you.
He doesn't gamble,
Doesn't smoke weed --
Nor does a girl write letters to him --
Listen --
Listen to me!
The boorish --
And upon you, peace.
May you live long.
I can guess about the local matches.
But who broke the news of the India-Pakistan match to him?
And -- to the devil with the matches!
He even knows about the letters.
How can it be?
It's been Sir Timmy!
He knows everything.
He didn't name my friends,
But he mentioned it all.
'Reads out her letters to his friends'!
You're doubting me?
You're talking about doubt?
My friendship is at stake.
Alladio!
Don't talk about Alladio.
Lad's a selfless servant.
You're accusing him because he's poor?
It must've been Sajid.
No --
Why would Sajid tell?
Alright, disconnect the phone.
Dad's here.
The meeting's about to start.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
Talk as a father.
Not a Molvi.
Call him.
Call him here.
Would you like some water?
I said call him here.
He's coming in a few minutes. He's afraid.
Strange.
He's fearing me
And I him...
Tell him to come.
I've come without evidence.
I'll talk differently.
Peace be upon you, Dad.
And upon you, peace.
Come.
Sit.
And you may leave.
Shut the door.
Arifa was telling me you were fearing me.
I was happy.
Why were you fearing me?
It's nothing like that.
Yesterday, you'd mentioned gambling --
Weed --
I was ashamed of myself.
I was afraid
About how I could answer what you'd ask.
And you forgot the one about writing letters to that girl.
Anyway.
That chapter has closed by itself.
I found no evidence of any of it.
The poor devil who'd informed me
Didn't agree to testify.
The poor soul ran away, frightened of you.
You're henceforth acquitted of all three accusations.
So rejoice.
You're - God be praised - acquitted
I've got to answer for my crimes.
My mother's no more,
Else I'd have been acquitted too.
What have you done, Dad?
I'm guilty of
Raising my dear child by rightful means.
There's another crime.
You've achieved renown in the neighbourhood,
And I'm helpless before you.
And thus I've decided to spend the rest of my days
In the seclusion of the Mosque.
No Dad...
Not in seclusion.
You'll stay at home.
I cannot stay here.
Why not?
Because you're here.
And because of you, I fear what fate awaits me.
Ruqaiyya!
Stop leaning against the door and come inside.
Listen to me.
Blessed be you.
I have failed to find evidence against your son.
I am ashamed of myself
And therefore leaving this house for the seclusion of the Mosque.
Pack the essentials and give me leave.
What are you talking about, Molvi Sahab?
You'd said it yourself
'Talk as a father'.
Now you bear witness,
I have talked as a father.
I'm exiling the Molvi to the seclusion of the Mosque.
Go!
Fall at his feet!
With your head at his feet, apologise!
Dad!
Forgive me for all my sins!
For God's sake, forgive me!
Right.
First, offer your noon prayers.
We'll talk later.
See?
He hasn't completely forgiven you.
But he will.
Purify yourself
And stand in the foremost rank.
That's what he's hinted at!
Go!
It's you!
Headed for the Mosque?
Yes.
When did this day come?
Today.
Dad said, offer your prayers, or else --
Or else?
I -- I'm getting late.
You're out on the streets,
Don't laugh like this.
The bloke you were talking to
He's a known ruffian.
No --
He's gone to pray.
Don't turn to look back like this, look ahead.
It's not proper for girls to do so.
What is this, Aunt?
He's my best friend's brother.
Molvi Subhanallah's son.
You don't know
But Alladio tells me everything.
He's with those yobs
Gambling --
And who knows what else!
He might,
But he's going to pray now.
Peace and Mercy of God upon you.
There is no God but God.
Hear me, O God...
I begin in the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
You are Peace, and from You is Peace.
Amen!
Give us our lives in Your surrender, and admit into the Safety of Your Peace.
You are the Most Praised, the Most Sublime.
The Lord of Majesty and Bounty.
And blessings of God be upon Mohammad and his companions.
And hit him so hard,
The very sight of her makes his forehead sweat.
Must've hit him on the forehead!
Come in.
Is the stitching done, will it be done tomorrow?
What are you doing? Get your hands off!
What were you doing?
Just kidding.
And I will do so after our marriage too.
Why did you come in my room?
You'd said, 'Come in'.
Oh God.
Get out.
Out!
This isn't right.
You get angry every now and then.
And I --
I've been waiting for 9 p.m. since the morning.
Nothing can change our plan for 9 p.m.
I swear.
I'll not be a minute late.
I was getting bored alone
And thought if a little meeting before the night --
Hey!
Splendid!
Nothing so splendid.
I'm leaving.
Chap sneaked into the room.
I thought it was you.
Anyway.
Are the dresses ready or will they be 'tomorrow'?
Not tomorrow, the day after.
He said he was cutting vegetables with his wife when he cut his hand.
Splendid!
What?
Nothing.
I said nothing.
Come.
Here.
Dad --
Why have you brought me here.
I swear that thing about the letters is false.
I swear by you!
Who mentioned the letters?
I talked to Monseigneur.
Saw him praying and told him about you.
He leard about your BA qualification and said, 'Bring him to me'.
'I'll give him a job'.
Come. Come here.
Come here.
Tell me, how big is your heart?
See for yourself.
The fact is,
I'm afraid.
Dishonour may create a problem.
We're the kind who'd die for honour.
Times have changed.
People compromise on honour a little.
Perhaps.
But why are we talking about this?
Let's talk about something else.
Right --
What did I start on --
I think we have an understanding.
Should I say it?
What?
Please don't be disturbed to hear it.
I won't be. Promise.
It's bad.
But best told.
If such things come out in the open after the marriage,
Even lovers get divorced.
God forgive!
Place your hand over your heart.
Place your hand!
The thing is
I love someone else, Mehtab.
Since childhood
He was a classmate.
We used to write letters everyday,
And now, we talk for hours over the phone.
He says, 'I'll die without you'.
And
Before the date was fixed, I used to say the same.
But now, it seems
I have to sacrifice my first love for Dad's sake.
You must be feeling very bad,
But --
-No.
I don't feel bad at all.
Rather, I'm chuffed to see
That you didn't conceal your past like other girls.
You've got courage.
Said it all to my face.
I swear by you,
I admire you even more now.
I'm proud of you.
Everything about honour aside,
Your past is none of my concern.
Was this the compromise you were talking about?
Hey -- Wait -- Wha -- Ruined the sleeve there!
Look, Mum! My sharp dressed brother!
God bless!
Ward the evil eye off him!
Do I look good?
Sightly, I swear!
It's 'as God has willed'!
Ward the evil eye off him.
Do anything you want to, many eyes will be fixed on him today!
Look at him, Dad!
I am looking.
This is how gentlemen look. Just perfect!
Right. Turn away.
Don't stay before my eyes too long like this.
And as he leaves, have him walk under the Qur'an.
It's his first day at the office.
And
The bloke looks sightly indeed!
Don't look back if a sweetheart looks at you.
These looks could kill!
God is happy with me
Or perhaps
With you, Ruqaiyya.
To be honest, Dad
He is happy with me.
I'd prayed with tears in my eyes that day.
Like this.
With my hands folded
Saying,
If the noon meeting does not bring good news,
I will be found making up for omitted prayers.
God forgive you!
Threatened God?
Where's the threat in this?
If, angry with you, I say that I'll not eat, is it a threat?
It'll be a threat when I won't do something for you.
Which I do without failure.
Yours and His.
Alright, don't list your favours.
And don't reason in ignorance.
And you just have a jolly time standing.
Pack him bread and an egg for lunch.
Alright.
He'll be there until five!
Come.
Go.
Keep the bag in the car.
Hey!
Where are you going?
You'd said she's not coming to see me off.
Obviously.
How can she come to see you off with Dad standing there?
That's why I was going upstairs.
She might be crying.
What?
It's just that
The moment of goodbyes
Is a fatal one for lovers.
And this restriction on seeing me off
What state must she be in?
Aunt's in the car and Mum and Dad are waiting for you.
What's she doing?
Anyway.
That's not something I need to ask.
She must be distressed.
Don't look up.
Dad often finds excuses to check.
Sorry, but
His habits are 1913-ish even in 2013.
But anyway,
Tell her it'll be like this after the marriage too.
Will she trouble herself weeping and wailing like this?
I may even have to go somewhere for eight to ten days.
I'll tell her.
And also tell her it's a mere four months until December.
Here I go,
And there comes December.
God willing...
Alright.
One more thing.
A secret
Tell her
Not to talk unnecessarily over the phone.
What do you mean?
I can't tell you the whole thing.
Just tell her indirectly
To let bygones be bygones.
Stop!
Wait.
Yes.
Now, begin in the name of God,
Bow your head, and walk on.
Wait a second!
You left your lunch box here.
Dad!
He said the tie and the lunch box didn't match well enough.
Won't leave a good impression.
One who submits to God
Leaves an impression with his humility, my dear.
He has humility, Molvi Sahab.
He's doing his duty.
Will he be humble only if he has his lunch box?
Go, my child.
In the name of God.
Go.
O God, the Most Exalted.
Oh!
Overjoyed at him having gotten a job, I forgot to ask... What's his rank?
And how much will he earn?
He's appointed as a clerk,
And will earn 10,000.
That's it?
You made him a clerk...
With third division all the way from matric [GCSEs] to BA,
Monseigneur has been generous enough
To not ask about experience
Else I'd have said,
He's a proper gambler.
And he, too, can see so well through a man,
As to have him in the accounts department!
God is great indeed!
If the noon prayer had its effect,
He will prosper,
Or else it'll be another albatross around my neck.
My neck
And his tie make such a combination!
It's only four months until December.
They shall pass.
My foot!
Don't trouble yourself weeping and wailing.
What?
Farah Mehtab sounds so good!
And you sound so bad!
You can have it in writing.
The December shall never come
When Farah Ibrahim will get married to Mehtab Chawla.
Or so it can be said that 2013 will end with 11 months.
For the first time, there will be no December in a year!
Bye!
Hey, Afzal!
Right there, old chap, complete with trews, shirt and a tie!
Who decked you up?
What do you mean?
I deck myself up.
You're going on a date!
I'm going to the office.
Office?
You know Sheikh Ibrahim Cotton Mills?
I'm the Accounts Officer.
Sheikh Ibrahim?
Leave Sheikh Ibrahim.
I'm an officer!
What a spunky lassie his is --
Whom are you talking about?
Don't show your depravity.
Think of people's daughters as your sisters.
Third division in matric [GCSEs],
Third division in inter [A-Levels],
Third division in BA,
And your name?
Afzal [The Excellent One] Subhanallah.
Subhanallah Afzal [The Splendid Afzal] suits you better.
Subhanallah is my father's name.
Experience?
Zero.
No third division here?
I've not started work that would gain me experience.
Why has Monseigneur appointed you?
On my father's recommendation.
Who is your father?
He's a priest at the Mosque.
He leads Monseigneur's prayers.
Oh...
Miss Rosy!
Yes?
Take Mr Subhanallah Afzal
Have him sit by you,
And show him how to fill a voucher.
Just filling vouchers?
Teach him whatever he can learn.
Alright.
Come.
Go.
Sit.
Come a bit closer to me.
Yes?
I said come a bit closer, so that I can show you how to fill a voucher.
Alright.
Mr Chengezi was insulting you so bad.
Didn't you feel angry?
A bit.
But you were smiling.
Do you know why?
Why?
One day, I will insult him.
Back to work now.
Who is it?
Lubna!
-How are you?
Come in.
-Take this; come back after an hour.
If it isn't our sweet Lubna!
Peace be upon you, Aunt.
And upon you, peace.
How are you?
You're here after months.
I have brought sweets for you.
Sweets? Why?
Something related to a marriage.
Yes.
-Isn't it?
Marriage?
You're so shameless!
You're telling us when you bring us sweets?
Whom are you getting married to?
Ask who's getting married first!
Farah?
Yes.
Thank goodness she has found someone.
Sit down and talk,
I'll get some tea.
First have some sweets,
Then I'll tell you the bitter reality.
I've had sweets, now tell me!
Stay easy, girl!
Let the sweets sink in!
Let's go inside.
Now you fill this voucher.
Say, Ibrahim Cottons sold cloth worth 1,000,000
And the buyer gave a cheque of 1,000,000.
This white one is the debit voucher.
It's written on it,
But because of the white colour,
It can be seen
Rather easily.
The bank is the debit and sales are the credit.
Now
Fill a debit voucher.
Fill it.
Are you married?
You didn't mention this --
I'm asking this.
Tell me if you're married.
No.
Not yet.
Then there's a lot I can teach you.
Don't answer the phone.
Mr Chengezi minds it.
And he can't take personal calls at all.
What does he do if he can't take it?
Yes Babloo?
7 p.m. sharp.
What is it?
A match against the old colony lads.
Floodlight.
Why are you laughing?
I can't play.
Can't play?
What's this guff?
I've put 50,000 on the line.
10,000 for you if we win.
Shut up!
No more matches now.
I've started working now.
I'm on duty.
You're doing this for more cash, eh, bugger?
Alright
15,000 for you.
That okay?
-I won't agree even to 20.
Now, disconnect the call.
It --
Was a friend.
A punter.
Gambles on matches.
Think of this as the last call you answered in this office!
No, sir.
This was the first call.
Miss Rosy, tell him!
Tell him how to behave in the office before teaching him how to fill vouchers!
I'd warned you.
Didn't you see him
Crawl back?
The crab.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital