Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Allow me, then.
I'll marry Afzal.
You're still awake, aren't you?
Yes.
Are you alert or should we talk later?
Why later?
Talk now.
Do you remember that we had a meeting right here by this door?
Yes, we met.
I remember it well.
This was no ordinary meeting...
We had none of those 'Hi's, 'Hello's, 'Bye's or 'Good night's...
I think I'd come to you to convince you that I don't love Afzal.
Why, do you?
Shut up!
Let me complete.
-Stay back while you talk --
You slapped me last night.
Ah, that!
So I wasn't dreaming after all!
So you'd actually asked me to allow you to marry Afzal?
That's what you said, right?
I did, but --
But what?
How long has this been going on for?
What's been going on?
Don't hide anything now that it's out in the open.
Tell me.
You love him, don't you?
You're the one who writes letters to him under the name of Farah, right?
You're going ahead of yourself, Farah.
I'm looking ahead, Lubna!
Oh God...
What a guileful girl you are!
All of it was happening right under my nose, under my name, and I knew nothing of it!
It's nothing like that.
Now that you're abandoning him,
I thought
I should marry him.
I never thought he was appalling.
Think how appalling you are to me right now!
I'm beginning to despise you!
In fact, despise is a small word --
Loathing is more like it.
Have you had your breakfast?
You want to talk to me about breakfast?
You'd better have some.
Or you might just eat me up.
What will I eat you up?
You'll eat yourself up like this.
Farah,
If it hurts you, you can decline.
But don't say all these harsh words to me.
Don't tell Mum and Dad.
Why shouldn't I?
That's unjust, Farah.
Remember, Farah, how I used to conceal everything when you asked me to?
So you've fallen so low?
What are you talking about, Farah?
If a girl thinks about marrying Afzal,
Will it be a sin to do so?
Belay the idea of 'a girl'.
Let's talk about me.
Is my marriage to him not acceptable?
Is he a leper or a pariah or something?
I always found him so handsome...
Yes,
He's a Molvi's son,
So he's a tad poor...
But he's got a heart too.
You write him letters, don't you?
Why would I write him letters?
Do I have a phone to grind spices?
Although, to be honest,
Writing an SMS does not have the romantic appeal of a letter.
If you say another word,
I'll spit in your face!
Relax, Farah.
Sit down and think calmly.
When he is of no concern to you,
To the Devil with him!
He may love whoever he likes,
He may marry whoever he likes!
He loves you too?
Hey!
If you ask me with such fury, I'm not disclosing any secret.
D -- don't
Don't slap me!
You're incapable of being slapped!
You're a top-class vile
Gadabout!
Gadabout?
When you offered me a job the other day,
I regretted my decision as I went back.
I told my wife,
'I've angered my would-be boss'.
She'd laugh if I told her today
That the boss had come to his servant asking for a job.
Look, Shahnawaz, mate.
Afzal has apologised for everything
That happened that day.
Sorry as in 'very sorry'.
How say we get back to work now?
Back to work as in having him work for us,
Right?
Yes.
Look, Babu Hamid,
Don't make me risk this.
Your friend vents his anger on anyone.
I assure you he won't.
Ask him if he assures us.
Yes, I do.
Think carefully -
The toffs sometimes vent their wives' share of the anger on security guards.
Many even hurl abuses.
I won't listen to abuses.
Will you beat him in that case?
Would you look at that, Babu Hamid?
I'm looking.
But tell me - who'd listen to abuses?
Well, yes, there's a point there.
But I can't trust your friend, Babu Hamid.
Come, Afzal.
Thank you.
Wait.
You're hired.
I can trust you now.
Have you seen how they fear your anger?
Yes.
Some folks from the neighbourhood,
Wali,
And this friend of yours.
But I...
Fear that a man should fear another.
But I fear when I think what you'd get working as a security guard.
10,000 a month?
You're not worth 10,000 a month, Afzal.
Your estimates run like my Mum's.
That's what she thought.
But nobody gives me more than 10,000.
My first job earned me 10,000 too.
Yes, it did have quite some cachet...
I'd wear a shirt and trousers to job, with a tie...
I'll wear a uniform here.
A blue one!
To be honest with you,
You're expecting too much from me.
I'm not a man worth more than 10,000.
It's now been proven.
I'd get 10,000 if I work at Ibrahim Cottons,
And 10,000 if I work as a security guard.
What will you do for your family with 10,000 a month?
Everything I'm doing is for my family.
When I can take care of my own expenses, I've saved my family 10,000.
Does your Dad earn enough?
He doesn't earn.
He collects it directly from Him.
From whom?
He's a priest at a Mosque.
He gets 40,000 to 50,000 as his divine reward.
Peace and Mercy of God be upon you.
O Lord!
Grant the childless a virtuous and righteous child;
Grant some peace to the hearts of parents;
O Lord!
Grant children such elegant civility that they can forgive their parents' fallibilities.
What's he doing in Karachi now?
-I don't have the foggiest.
Ask him to come back and join at my office again.
He's not in contact with me.
He must be calling you sometime?
His phone's switched off since the day he left.
But
He...
Will contact me. He can't live without me.
Where in Karachi is he?
I only mention Karachi because
He used to say he'd go to Karachi before he left.
He didn't seem to be that type.
He isn't that type.
I don't know what got into him
That he severed all ties with us too...
I have full confidence in him
But his Mum worries...
Starts talking to God directly!
As if to say,
God Himself gave him a ticket and took him to Karachi.
If you say,
I can get someone in Karachi on him.
If he is in Karachi, it'll only take some 4 or 6 days to find out.
That will be a huge favour on me, Monseigneur Ibrahim.
Once I find out where he is
I'll arrive at his doorstep
And bring him straight to your office.
Alright.
Now, give me permission.
Please don't forget it.
Don't worry, I won't.
Goodbye.
-Goodbye.
Thank the Lord, he's fine.
But where is he?
A prophecy cannot tell where he is.
Then how can it tell he's fine?
Mum! What are you saying?
If you can name the neighbourhood, I can find out the rest!
You're giving in to emotion.
That's all a prophecy could tell.
So tell me about someone who can look at his numbers and get to his neighbourhood.
Who could look at his numbers like that?
For there is no such technique.
Don't forget
That you're Molvi Subhanallah's wife.
Don't get swept away in emotions to believe in some unenlightened prophecy.
To be honest,
If there were a technique to find a lost son,
I swear by God,
It wouldn't be known to anyone but the mother.
It'd be better
That you ask Molvi Sahab
To go and find him.
My child,
I think I should be going now.
Hey!
Mr Karim Ahmed! Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
You're --
Leaving?
Yes.
I'd come to prophesize about your Afzal.
Now, I can prophesize too, but
Ruqaiyya doesn't quite believe me.
When it's about her son,
A mother fears even his father.
There's always a suspicion
That you may end up comforting her
In the name of prophesising.
I take your leave.
-In the name of God; come.
Thank you very much.
Take that as well.
Alright, I'll have something sweet [= I bring good news]
We'll get to know in a few days
Where he is now.
Why should I believe that?
If we'll get to know, what's with these 'few days'?
Because
Monseigneur Ibrahim has agreed to it.
He said
He'd be able to find him in a few days.
Just pray
That he
Had left for Karachi.
What do you mean?
Has he not gone to Karachi?
Good Lord, it doesn't mean that.
It's very likely he's gone to Karachi.
But your son
Makes unlikely many such things that are highly likely.
He's gone there.
When he said he'd go to Karachi,
Take it as if he dropped a hint.
Don't worry.
Our efforts to find him will begin in Karachi tomorrow.
Monseigneur Ibrahim has many contacts.
He's promised me
And I'm sure he would find him.
It's also possible we may find out tomorrow or the day after?
It is indeed.
Arifa!
Get some dessert for your father.
Yes, his name's Afzal Subhanallah.
No.
I'm not saying 'Subhanallah' [praise the Lord] because of something he's done.
Yes, 'Subhanallah'.
That's it, Monsieur, I'm mentioning his father's name!
You'd actually find yourself praising the Lord if you meet him!
He must be around
25, 26 years old?
Picture...
I can send you tomorrow morning.
No, he won't be in a posh neighbourhood.
He doesn't have so much money.
Alright.
You'll get his photograph tomorrow.
Okay.
I felt pity for Molvi Sahab today.
He didn't mention anything except righteous and duteous children in his prayers.
I'm thinking I'll call on him one of these days
To give them hope.
Why not call on him tomorrow?
Give him some consolation over tea,
And
Bring a photograph of Afzal when you come back.
We're going to need one to find him.
Alright.
I'll go tomorrow.
But...
But what?
Wouldn't it seem rather strange -
Farah's mother asking for Afzal's photograph?
Why would it be strange?
Say it plainly, 'We're trying to find your son'.
'We'd need his photograph for it'.
Now he's no minister
That I'd say his name, and those looking for him would say,
'Oh'!
'You're talking about him'!
But Farah will ask why we're looking for him.
You'd only know if you met her psychiatrist!
What would I know?
He asked me the moment he saw me, 'Do you know someone by the name of Afzal'?
I said, 'Yes, I do'.
Smugly, he said, 'He's fled from Hyderabad'.
'You'd better find him and bring him back, or else --'
-'Or else'?
'The affliction will become immedicable'.
What's her affliction?
By the Lord, Irsa Begum,
Don't ask me the name of this affliction.
I've tasted blood...
Slumbering in my veins, it has now awakened...
Hey!
How long have you been here?
What is going on?
What's going on? I'm just singing a song.
Oh wait, I got it wrong, let me try again...
I've tasted b--
-Stop it, Lubna!
Get me through to him.
To whom?
That blighter Afzal. Who else could it be?
His phone's switched off.
Give me the number that's active.
He doesn't have any other number.
It's impossible that you're singing [romantic] songs from Ram Leela when you have been out of touch with him!
We're not in touch right now.
I do try his number every night before I go to bed.
The wretch keeps it switched off!
So it's gotten so far!
There are no limits in love.
Things can go to any lengths.
Don't forget you're Sheikh Ibrahim's daughter!
I never forget it.
Let go of my hand.
I'll only marry him if things go forward.
I'll not elope with him.
Alright.
I'll go and tell Mum.
Get ready
We'll call him from Karachi and get him married to you!
Really?
What does it look like?
I swear, Mum won't say no if you talk to her!
She'll even convince Dad!
You'd talk today, won't you?
Not today.
But right now!
There!
My heart was right in saying that.
What was your heart saying?
That
It is only on Farah's face that you can see such fury.
She's like a candle on the inside -
She'll melt as the slightest of warmth touches her.
Right,
What is it, Farah?
Where's Dad?
He retired to his room after the news bulletin.
Please, sit.
I'm sitting now.
Go on.
Say something; Get on with it.
Get Lubna married off.
Splendid.
So this is what you'd wanted to say.
Is it you who's got this itch,
Or her?
Tell me!
Where does this thing about her marriage come from?
It hasn't come from anywhere...
I was just thinking --
She'd just as well go to her home.
She'd go to her home and you'd be lying around here.
When did I say I'd be lying around here?
Do you want me to talk to your Dad?
To Dad?
Why?
What will you say?
He should know too
That his sweet little girl is thinking about the entire family now.
Also,
You'd better not show me that you're certifiable.
I used to act up like this
When I was stopped from marrying your Dad.
Act up?
Don't worry.
Your Dad's picked up a lead, and he'll dig something up about him in a few days.
About whom?
As if you don't even remember his name!
You're talking about Afzal?
Of course.
Why is Dad looking for him?
Has the doctor prescribed any medicines or just shooed away after taking his fees?
He didn't prescribe any medicine.
In fact, he said I'm perfectly fine when he heard my history.
He's lied to you.
But he's told your Dad the truth.
Please, listen to me!
I --
I've made a promise.
Whom have you promised?
And what have you promised?
I walked up to the terrace
She was on the swing singing a song from 'Ram Leela'!
What's 'Ram Leela'?
Deepika's film!
I'll tell her Dad --
-What's the need?
Don't you remember that you'd said,
'When a girl sits all alone, singing',
'She's yearning to get married'.
Well,
You've even proven this adage false!
Neither did you sit all alone,
Nor sang a song,
And dropped the bombshell that was Molvi Subhanallah's son on us.
Anyway,
I'll listen to the song from 'Ram Leela' from her!
Go now,
And have faith, instead of thinking of unnecessary things,
That in a few days,
He'd be back at the crossroads around here.
Or perhaps gambling on a match
With the old colony lads.
Here.
Put your book down and have this before it cools down.
Right,
So what were you saying?
What was I saying?
The same
You were telling me about Afzal's wife.
For the love of God, Mum,
I'd told you he's not gotten married yet
And that he has no girlfriend either.
Girlfriend?
I mean, he's not having an affair with any girl either.
When did you ask him this one?
I asked everything when I'd brought him his tea.
Why?
Hey!
It's because you'd said
He'd be married or have found a girl.
So I thought I'd better ask.
I should know, too,
If your guesses are correct or you just say what you feel like.
What'll you do now?
I mean, what are you up to?
What would I be up to?
I'm just asking.
What should I do if he suddenly disappears one day?
He's deposited some advance for now.
We don't need to get worried.
Besides, he's a Molvi's son; he won't defraud.
I'll have two or three delicacies cooked tomorrow.
Why three?
Surely, two would be enough!
One, chicken, and two, some vegetables and lentils.
Desserts just once a week.
And the same old 8,000 a month.
What's with the month, Mum, it'll go by in a flash!
Who could it be at this hour?
Who else could it be?
Wali won't be coming now.
It'll be one of the tenants, or perhaps Samina.
I'll have a look.
I've brought sweets!
Just so little?
Why, though?
Oh God!
You haven't gotten married, have you?
Not at all!
I haven't gotten married.
I've gotten a job.
God bless you!
Thank you!
Where have you gotten a job?
I mean -- what's your designation?
Just a pastime?
Just a pastime.
Hello there!
Why are you sleeping here?
Just --
No idea.
You forgot your promise, didn't you?
Promise?
You'd said it firmly last night,
'I'll talk to Mum about you and Afzal'.
'In fact, I'll get him here from Karachi and get the two of you married'!
There!
Chickened out, eh?
One needs guts to stand by someone, Mademoiselle Farah Ibrahim!
Remember
I'd put my life on the line for you!
I'd talked to her.
Hey!
Why didn't you tell me?
Stay back when you talk!
Did she agree to it?
I don't know
Whether she'll agree to it or kill you!
For now, I've just said you want to get married!
I've not named Afzal.
Why not?
You're actually saying
That I should mention him by name?
Hey!
Do you still doubt me?
Come on, Farah.
I'm very serious.
In fact,
I'm thinking of getting Afzal's name
Tattooed on my arm!
Honestly though,
It did occur to me
That you'd not be able to name him.
The thing is,
I know your problem very well.
What's my problem?
You do have one, Farah.
It's just yesterday
That your marriage to Afzal was being planned.
And now, out of the blue, you'd name me,
And Mum and Dad would get to know the true story,
It would knock them for six for sure.
What's the true story?
Do I have to say it over and over again?
Alright,
I'll tell you everything when I'm back from the University.
Oh God, I'm late!
I'd better get going. Have a good day!
Wait.
Yes, Mum?
Was Farah telling me the truth?
What did she say?
You were on the terrace last night singing songs from 'Ram Leela'?
How's the film?
It was great --
No, Mum, it ain't good --
I haven't watched the film.
Just listened to the song.
Come back from the University,
And we'll talk.
Alright.
Bye.
I'll lose 40-50 million but go on with the business!
Peace be upon you, sir.
Did I forget to greet you, sir?
I think I did.
Remember me?
No, sir?
I remember meeting you but I don't remember where.
Yes, sir.
Look here.
Remember me?
No, sir...
The name's Mehtab.
Right, sir.
You still don't remember me?
I'm trying to, sir.
What's your name?
Afzal.
Afzal...
What happened, M. Mehtab?
It's nothing.
Peace be upon you, sir.
You're the same, aren't you?
The same, sir?
We met at Sheikh Ibrahim Uncle's!
Do you remember now?
Listen!
I watched Ram Leela in the afternoon.
It isn't the kind of film you twits should be watching!
It isn't the kind of film you should be watching either.
And -- I didn't watch it, Mum --
Just listened to the song.
I sang it because I found it good.
It was good that your Dad wasn't home!
Otherwise, I would've said that I'm watching it because of Lubna.
God forgive...
But the song was good.
Wasn't it?
Put a sock in it!
Don't sing it again.
You'd be doomed if Dad heard it!
What does Dad know it's from Ram Leela?
Leave that be.
He'd have watched it already.
Anyway,
You were on the terrace, singing, weren't you?
Yes...
What are you up to?
Up to --?
I'm your mother.
My hair haven't turned grey,
But I'm experienced enough to know the signs of girls who sing songs sitting all alone like that.
Tell me,
If you are in love with a boy too, tell me his name.
I'll talk to your Dad today.
For God's sake, Mum --
So do you intend to hide it for a year or so too?
Look, my dear,
The two of us are used to taking such shocks.
You can't put the wind up us by naming any stone broke dosser!
Name any lad who isn't even 'Afzal' [the best] in name.
Shall we talk tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
Alright, we'll talk tomorrow.
But remember
The lad should be a real one.
Don't hire someone for 200,000 and present him before us.
No way, Mum --
I won't do anything like that.
I promise.
So you've handpicked him!
That's great.
Long live my daughters.
You've taken up your father's responsibilities with such timing!
May I go?
-Go.
Warn me an hour before naming the lad tomorrow.
Warn?
Just give me a hint that you'd be naming him in an hour.
And why is that, Mum?
What if the doctor is busy at that time?
No way!
Your Dad's blood pressure shoots up in minutes.
It won't come to that.
It's screaming to come to that, but you can't hear it. Go.
And keep on singing -- whatsit,
'I've tasted blood'!
God forgive!
Don't come in!
And don't you dare touch the door to my room without my permission!
Talk only from where you are!
Call out to me right from there.
I'll only talk if I'm in the mood to,
Otherwise, you don't need to call out a second time.
You're picking up a quarrel with me!
That's what's to be decided now, Lubna Ibrahim -
Whether I'm picking up a quarrel with you or you are with me!
Then you, too, should only call out to me standing at my doorstep.
I'll only talk if I'm in the mood to,
Otherwise, you don't need to call out a second time.
'Come to your doorstep' my foot!
Ohh...
I can understand everything...
Everything.
I should be of help to you
Even as you feign love,
And you'll cumber the path
Of my true love?
Splendid!
You truly love him?
The one who came with a proposal to marry your sister?
Hello?
All of that was an act.
You were playing your part, as was he!
He wasn't just playing his part. He'd actually brought his parents.
And that -- Engagement ring...
Do you remember?
I'd even texted him a message to mark the end of the job and his love!
So you think
He had begun to love you?
Well,
I wouldn't call it love.
The blighter used to have an exchange of letters with someone,
And wanted to marry me!
-Please, Farah!
Don't cast such an aspersion on my Afzal!
On your Afzal?
He's yours now?
He will be.
When you yearn for someone so ardently,
He cannot end up anywhere else.
But
What do you know about ardent yearning!
I've tasted blood...
Slumbering in my veins, it has now awakened...
Listen!
Where to?
-To Samina's.
Today's her wedding anniversary.
As in, it's been another year.
Is hers the kind of wedding one would commemorate?
Her husband does every year.
After all, it's her husband's 'love marriage' to her.
In two years of this 'love marriage', she's been beaten by her 'lover' some 200 times!
Only God will ask about this.
What will you give her as a gift?
Why would she need one?
She has a far greater need for cash.
I'm thinking I'd give her a thousand.
And who will get the security guard his food?
I'll be back before he is.
And who'll tell you he's back?
Well,
I get to know
The moment he sets foot in the alley!
May I go now?
Yes.
Go.
But please do tell me when you're back
How you get to know the moment he sets foot in the alley.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital