Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Splendid.
So to speak, she's getting married, and not getting married.
It's a marriage for one and not for the other.
Does she really love someone else?
No.
She was lying about the letters and the calls.
What do you mean?
She just said it casually that she loves someone else.
God forgive!
Ask why she said it.
Why did she said it?
-To raise an issue of honour.
It's been raised.
Not like that.
He was delighted to hear it.
He said,
'I have begun to admire you even more'.
'I'm proud of you'.
'Unlike other girls, you didn't conceal your past from me'.
Oh, so that's why the date has been decided.
Yes.
But when the date's been fixed, how can she not get married?
You don't know her.
I know her.
When she's said she'd embitter us with these sweets,
She must mean it!
But
It's only four months until December.
And when I said this,
She said that this year will have 11 months,
Where will there be room for December?
Mum!
Keep the door open.
Your laughter would resonate downstairs.
Where's your brother, the loafer?
Have some shame.
Would you call him a loafer now?
What has he done now?
You're saying as if you don't know.
I swear by you, I don't.
He's not gone, is he?
He's gotten a job!
That's great!
You don't know, your father has hired him in the accounts department at the mill.
Oh?
Left wearing a tie,
A fine, sharp dressed gentleman!
I swear, he looked fabulous!
Sometimes, I feel he should've been born in a family like yours.
He'd wear dazzling suits,
Shining boots,
A hundred kinds of ties...
Travel in a luxury car,
Attend royal parties near and far,
Have a ball of a time.
But anyway,
Thank God
He's got a job today,
He'll prosper tomorrow.
We'll have a car too,
Then I'll talk to you.
Talk to me -- what?
I mean I'd then show it off, dear!
We'll definitely come across,
Right around the lane with the Mosque,
Your car from one end, ours from the other,
I'd blow the horn and say,
'Move aside, my good man'!
Surely, you --
Don't mind?
Not at all.
Dad used to be a supervisor in a cotton mill.
He travelled seven miles on a bicycle.
He'll find prosperity too, one day.
Cars, mansions - he'll get all he wants.
But tell him surely
To mind his character.
Prosperity won't be far that way.
And
Here comes my security detail.
I'll take my leave.
Bye!
Yes, Babloo?
Take it for 20.
20?
Not a penny more than this.
Look, Babloo.
I'm not that kind of Afzal anymore.
I've gotten a job.
A job that does not allow me to answer calls.
Look ahead
What's before me?
My boss Mr Chengezi is staring at me with his eyes ablaze.
He face doesn't redden with rage,
It blackens.
Look, Babloo.
Forget me.
I'm developing a habit of living on my salary.
You and --
Don't use a four letter word!
I can't hit you back with one.
Because
On the seat next to mine sits a sweet lady.
Alright, disconnect.
You bugger!
You're the worst dastard.
Foul words!
Tell me
What did you do before you becoming an accountant?
What would I do?
Loafing around or
Bulldozing around.
But sir
I'm not that old Afzal.
If someone looked at me like this then,
The way you are now,
I swear by you, I'd have clawed his eyes out.
But sir,
Boss is boss.
I've accepted you as mine.
Although in all honesty, you're doing such things as made me want to --
What?
Leave it, sir.
You should accept it too.
I'm not the old Afzal.
What'll people think?
What will they think?
Such a friendship since Day 1 that Rosy drove Afzal home?
Who cares?
Honestly though,
Why this inconvenience?
My home isn't too far.
It's not too far to you.
Won't you be away if you go?
I think you're right.
But please,
Drop me at a slight distance.
At a distance?
-It's the neighbourhood.
Someone might think something wrong about you.
Mate, you're a man and yet you're afraid?
I'm not a man...
W-- What?
I mean
I'm not afraid.
But it's that women's honour is delicate
I just care about that.
Straight ahead from here.
Excuse me.
Yes, Babloo?
It's 6.15, you bugger.
Not again?
Does 20 grand not make your mouth water?
It does, old chap, but --
A word's a word.
I've given Dad my word.
Alright -- Let's seal it for 25.
25?
Turn around.
Turn around? Okay...
Mr 'Turn around'!
I'll give you 30.
And if that's not acceptable,
Bugger off!
Turn around again.
Now,
Stop here.
Stop it, stop it!
-What?
Yes, I'm coming.
Leave me here, I'll get a rickshaw from around here.
Mum!
It's him - Afzal!
The loafer!
Where'd he get a car from?
A girl is sitting in the car; she's driving.
She might be injured or something...
Oh God...
Look at him
He's left the girl here.
Cap'n!
Afzal's here.
The bugger.
If he hadn't come now, there would've been no gambling left in the world.
I like it.
What?
When there's a match outside the colony, Dad can't possibly know.
Don't drag your Dad into this.
You've got to win us the match.
Consider it done.
Modi,
Get the stuff ready.
You saw Afzal with your own eyes?
Of course.
Saw him get out of the car and run away in a rickshaw!
And you saw that he was with a girl?
You and your questions.
I took the same girl to the doctor.
Do you know who she is?
Who?
Works in the accounts department at our mill.
Rosy.
Rosy?
I thought the blighter wanted to earn a living [= rozi].
He's not going to change.
What's your concern if he changes?
He's my friend's brother.
Everyone's got his eyes on him.
The poor girl
All her dreams are because of him.
I'd gone to give her the sweets,
When she told me it's his first day at the office.
He's got a job at the accounts department of our mill.
Wow.
A job at the accounts,
And a fiddle on the first day!
Fiddle?
-What else is it?
Got the accounts officer head over heels for him on the first day.
And you
Why have you given her sweets?
Won't sweets be distributed now that the date's been fixed?
Mum asked me to go to Molvi Sahab's first.
He'll have some and give his blessings.
Oh God... Help me!
Splendid!
You bugger!
Who'll score runs for us if you let them score so many?
Come to form.
Alright.
Easy there!
Yes!
Great!
Where'd he go on a rickshaw?
What do I know?
He must've been headed home the way he ran.
He isn't here.
He's not even answering the phone.
Why would he?
He must have another one somewhere?
Another -- what?
Do I have to tell you?
Keep on remembering God.
Ignore God's infinite mercy on your brother.
Wait.
I'll find out.
My maid's son Alladio
Yes?
He knows everything.
Alright, I'll wait.
Please ask him and tell me.
Okay, bye.
Hey
Please win us this match.
I've borrowed 50,000 --
-How do I win this?
65 runs in 4 overs...
Do something.
Let me see...
Where is he?
Playing a match in the old colony.
Gambling over it?
20 more in 1 over...
It's all on you now.
Why's everything on me, you bugger?
Have I ever scored 20 in 1 over?
I swear
Go for the sixes, Afzal.
That I will, Babloo...
Will try my best.
You are under her oath
Whose?
The one who writes you letters.
What was that, you bugger?
Don't you love her?
Look,
We can win only if you hit a six.
Please, mate.
Hit one.
Leave it be!
Right, show me the dough.
Yes.
Right here.
Look, I've
Found him.
I've brought him home.
When I arrived there, the match
Was going on with vigour.
Ruqaiyya, I swear, if you had been by my side,
You'd have sunken into the earth out of disgrace.
Labouring devotedly like an ox at an oil mill was our Afzal
His guts haggard,
But resolve firm.
You kept on asking,
And she,
His sister, but empoisoned my ears,
That my son
Gambles.
God forgive! God forgive!
You, blear-eyed,
View pouring blood, toil, and sweat,
And striving for a victory as gambling?
Look at him.
This.
30,000 Rupees.
He's earned it.
On every banknote
You can see my Afzal's blood and sweat if only you'd look!
Step out of the house and see
Look at your son's trials and tribulations!
Listen to the praise of his good name echo!
You'll realise, then,
Our Afzal juggles two jobs at the same time.
Yes.
Hey!
Why are you standing?
Sit down, son.
Sit down.
My son, you...
You're standing as if you've done something wrong.
I'm the one who's been wrong, son.
I listened to them and to God...
Remained too preoccupied with the Mosque and prayers...
And didn't shave off this beard [abandon all of this] and go along with you.
Now, I will.
I will go with you now.
For the first time, someone else has given the call,
And I don't know
Who's led the prayers.
Enough of it all!
Enough of doing God's work.
My Afzal [excellent one] has outvied me!
Earns what he likes when he likes...
Without the obligations of his five prayers with purity,
Nor the pain of bowing and obsecrating again and again.
I will go with you now.
Do you know, when you,
So openly
Collected your money, how much it hurt me?
Such overt and unashamed
Gambling is not proper.
Now, when I'll be with you,
There --
Will be some secrecy.
You
Can play your match, and
I will take the money.
Hey?
What are you looking at?
Get him something to eat.
Feed him well,
Regale him.
Take this.
From today, this responsibility, too,
I leave in your hands.
Just think as if
Molvi Subhanallah is dead!
The wretch has been ensepulchred beneath the sweet redolence of banknotes!
Stop, Molvi Sahab.
I swear by my love and purity.
Put on this turban,
And throw this wastrel out of the house.
I, too, proclaim today -
'The righteous and the sinful cannot live under one roof'.
Get out of here, you blighter!
I will take it as if I'd given you birth for the times,
Raised you, and handed you to the times.
Get out! Out!
Before my motherly affection surrenders before your sins!
Pick up your things from here,
And begone forever!
Out of my sights!
Go!
-Stop --
Stop it, Ruqaiyya.
Stop it.
It is not my desire to separate a mother from her son.
Tell him to stay here,
And keep on causing me misery.
Now, if I
Separate a mother from her son,
Will God be pleased with me?
I'm faced with a difficulty on either side.
Don't turn away and leave, Molvi Sahab.
Exercise your authority as a father.
Whack him.
Slap him so hard
That the pain of it stings at him forever.
You're accosting my helplessness.
You should at least know so much
That seeing the son's temerity
Has brought tears to the father's eyes.
The courage to slap is not left in him.
Let him rot in here.
Do not proclaim greatness before fate.
For the crime of living under the same roof as him,
I shall offer
Two prayers of forgiveness.
Then, let us see what God wills.
Perhaps
Out of this pain,
He will become faithful!
Don't worry, my dear, your name won't come up.
Forget that you said something that I heard.
Oh God!
What happened, sister?
I told his sister
Mentioned your name too...
Disconnect the phone, quick!
I'm dead then, sister!
You won't die.
Disconnect. I'll ask his sister not to name you in front of him.
Hello?
Has he been caught?
Yes.
Talk about Alladio...
Oh yes --
Please,
Don't tell him Alladio ratted him out.
The poor chap's getting worried.
I won't.
What happened to your voice?
You haven't even thanked me.
Thank you.
But I request you, Lubna,
If you get wind of something like this again,
Please don't tell me.
Go now; she's said she won't tell him.
Thank you.
What won't she tell?
And who won't tell?
You'll be delighted to hear.
The loafer Afzal --
Arifa's brother --
Yes?
I've had him nicked.
Nicked?
He was gambling on a match outside the colony.
I called Arifa and told her,
And I've come to know Molvi Sahab's caught him in a raid.
Are you in your senses?
What have you got to do with him?
Something, certainly.
He works at our mill,
He's got the accounts officer head over heels for him,
That gives us a lot to do with him.
Now, just watch -
Molvi Sahab will skin him alive.
Beware!
What 'beware'?
Don't even mention his name!
Given that he's Arifa's brother,
Molvi Sahab's son,
But I despise the sound of his name from your mouth.
He's an A1 loafer --
And gambler.
Right...
Why do you despise it?
I say, to the dickens with him,
It's not as if I'm having an affair with him.
Arifa had pleaded before me, so I thought I'd ask Alladio.
What do I know him?
I turn away if I come across him.
Stop talking about him!
Why are you crying now?
I'm wicked, am I not?
Yes.
You're wicked.
You made Dad cry.
Now, even a lifetime of weeping
Cannot possibly recompense those tears.
Listen.
Remember this
I'll spend my lifetime weeping,
And find peace only when I have recompensed those tears.
I'm serving the food; come and have some.
I'll die of hunger but not have a bite.
I went to the office,
Having decided
That I won't gamble again.
But that blighter Babloo --
Kept on calling, and I kept telling him that I won't play.
But --
I fell for the lure of 30,000.
He's not a blighter,
I'm the blighter!
If I'd the slightest hint
That Dad would cry like this if he came to know,
I'd never have played.
I swear by you.
If you think
I'm lying under my oath by you,
Then I'm not wicked,
I'm the most vile and dastardly.
Alright...
Have something to eat...
I'll talk to Dad if you have some food.
I've never given an assurance,
My heart says that he'll forgive you.
I'll have something.
Give us our lives, O Gracious Lord, in Your Surrender, and admit into the Safety of Your Peace.
You come with an endorsement?
I've come to assure you.
He swore by my head for the first time.
I swear today that he won't gamble again.
He won't smoke cigarettes or weed.
He'll be honest and principled in his work.
He was weeping because you had shed tears.
I'd said that even a lifetime of weeping cannot possibly recompense Dad's tears.
To which he said,
'I'll weep all my life'
'But find peace only when I have atoned for them'.
Will he pray?
We'll know at daybreak.
Just forgive him. Don't strike a deal.
I forgive him.
Come on. Have dinner with him.
With that unfaithful liar!
With that newly faithful.
I have agreed to what you've said.
But remember
He'll finish you off as well
Where there'll not be the slightest relief. Yes.
Hey, Afzal!
You bugger!
I heard you won 30,000 yesterday?
You'll earn the bucks and not tell me?
Hey, Afzal!
It's him.
Whatever his character may be like,
You got to admit he's got those looks!
Hey!
What happened to your head?
Got injured.
Your heart was injured and you've bandaged your head?
It's a real one, I suppose?
I've had an accident, sir.
That was bound to happen.
Let's see where it's struck him.
Excuse me, sir?
There's no costing or budgeting in love.
You never know how much you may end up spending.
It must've cost 10,000.
What?
Getting the car repaired, what else?
Not at all. It's only cost 2,500.
So to speak, the first meeting cost you 2,500.
-Good morning! Good morning, sir!
Good morning... Morning, Sir!
'Morning. Very good morning.
I don't see you injured?
Or is it that you've been hurt on the inside?
Miss Rosy?
What happened to you?
You got injured?
Yes.
But how?
You were fine in the evening.
It's in the evening that I had the accident.
A car hit me from behind when I was taking a U-turn!
You may leave.
Would you happen to have a pen?
I'd like some tea.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital