Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Have you thought of a name?
What good will that be?
Who'll come to meet my family?
Pick one so we know whom to talk to.
Shut up.
What's it to me? I'll shut up.
But what'll you do about Mum?
She'll ask you when he's coming the moment you reach home.
I've thought of an answer.
Tell me.
I'll say he's out of town.
He's gone to Karachi.
Right...
That's a fine answer.
But then, Dad will ask for his mobile number to talk to him.
I feel like crashing into a wall!
If you want to crash into a wall,
Is Mehtab too bad a choice?
Marry him and think as if you've crashed into a wall.
Not Karachi.
America.
Don't drag America into this.
It's aready got its hands full with its own share of quandaries!
Try to understand the situation.
I'll say he's gone to America.
He'll be back in a few days.
And if he doesn't come for a few days?
I can find anyone in a few days.
She'll also ask why you didn't take the driver along.
Think of an answer to that too.
It's him, isn't it?
Arifa's brother?
You're right...
But what is he doing here?
He should be at the office right now.
He's an A1 loafer.
Must've found an excuse to skive off work.
You left the driver here when you left?
I, too, remembered on the way that --
I'd left the driver at home...
You've not mentioned when he'll be coming.
It'll be sometime after the evening.
But he won't come for a couple of days.
Why not?
He's -- Out of the country.
Where is he?
I don't know --
He had a few options...
He'll tell me where he went once he's arrived.
At the very least, we can talk over the phone.
It'll be alright once your father is satisfied.
He's not slept peacefully all night.
Turning from one side to another,
He'd say with visible fear
As he glimpsed the gun,
'Get this gun off the wall'!
Get it off then...
It's not about the gun.
Your Dad is unsettled.
He was asking the boy's name over breakfast.
What could I say?
You've not even told me his name.
He was mumbling over it as he smoked his cigar in the morning,
Saying repeatedly, 'A boy whose name is unknown to me'
'Is going to become my son-in-law'.
It's just a couple of days, Mum...
Everybody will come to know who he is.
I -- I'm not hungry at all.
Ask Aunt not to knock on our door.
Wait!
At least tell me his name.
I'll tell your father instantly when he'd ask at night.
I'll say, 'Make do with just the name for now',
'You'll get to know the rest later'.
Tell me. What's his name?
Afzal...
You didn't mention what happened to her...
It's nothing.
Nothing?
Why is she unconscious for so long if nothing's happened to her?
-It's a shock.
Perhaps she's suddenly heard some news, or...
Or?
Are you, by any chance, getting her married to someone she doesn't want to marry?
You can find this out too?
I can't find it out,
But I'm a family doctor. This is why I'm asking.
Yes, it was planned...
We'd fixed the date too,
But then found out she's not happy with it.
What did you do?
That which a good father should do.
I'll call to decline today.
Good.
Tell your family not to utter his name before her.
By the way, what's his name?
Mehtab.
What a nice name!
Anyway, she'll come to soon.
Don't meet her before she's stable.
Why?
In such cases, every honourable girl fears her father.
Okay.
I won't meet her.
Who's this Afzal, Lubna?
What's she asking?
She's asking who Afzal is.
Why is she asking instead of telling?
The truth is
It's gotten into her mind
That I didn't mention his full name
Is Afzal not his full name?
No.
In fact, Afzal isn't his name at all.
I meant --
'Afzal'
'As in the best'.
What do you mean?
I'm not talking about his name.
I meant his character.
He's the best in character.
There's no one like him, so to say!
Anyway...
I can understand that.
By God, I thought for a while
You're talking about Molvi Subhanallah's son.
God forgive!
God is the Greatest
Farah!
Farah, wake up!
Get up! Mum's left!
Peace and Mercy of God be upon you...
God forgive all my sins...
O our Lord, give us good in this world and good in the Hereafter, and protect us from the punishment of the hell fire.
Who's this Afzal?
That blighter?
Molvi Subhanallah's son?
The loafer, the vagrant!
You named him and said I love him!
That's what you think about me!
You thought you'd name someone like that,
And I'd stay quiet!
Just because I'm in the soup?
To the dickens with it!
It's better that I'm in the soup
Than out of it with the help of that loafer extraordinaire!
But if you mention his name again,
I'll claw your face apart!
Listen to me, Farah.
I changed my statement.
Mum, too, had thought I was talking about Molvi Subhanallah's son.
So?
Who were you talking about?
I was saying that he had the best character.
Unrivalled and unlike any other!
Oh my God...
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
I'm so wicked, am I not?
I slapped you so hard...
I'm sorry.
Please...
Hey!
What took you so long?
Greetings, Mum!
That's great!
You've finished your lunch.
Hold on.
What's the matter?
Why aren't you saying anything?
We'd asked you to become a good man.
Don't become so good that we start fearing you.
I'm going to look for my degrees and certificates.
I don't know where I kept them.
Why do you need them now?
I've gotten a job on Dad's recommendation,
But that can't prove I've earned a BA.
Oh...
May I go and look for them now?
Don't.
All those documents are in Dad's cupboard.
I'll get you those in a short while.
Get me some tea.
Right away!
Come, Monseigneur. It's time for the 9 p.m. news bulletin.
I know.
Switch it off, will you?
What's the matter, Monseigneur?
Something bothering you?
Nothing wrong as such,
But it weighs on my heart to remember whatever's been said...
She's come to now.
She's had her dinner.
If you have any suspicions or fears,
Call her and tell her openly.
I'm not talking about her.
Whom are you talking about?
I mean --
Molvi Subhanallah's son...
What's his name?
Afzal?
Yes, Afzal.
No.
It's not like that.
Even I'd thought she was talking about that Afzal.
But found out later that that
Was a remark about his character.
I'm talking about his character too.
I found out today that he was harassing our Accounts Officer.
Thumbed a lift from her and tried to assault her in her car!
The blighter!
Look at him!
This is what the son of a priest is doing!
I say, throw him out!
I did.
But I'm regretting it.
Is this something you should regret?
Feel good
For you did the right thing.
If Molvi Sahab's reputation is the cause of your regret,
Say to him the moment you meet him,
'This is what your son is like'!
That's not what he's like.
I have a feeling now that that's not what he's like.
I've seen that type.
No one like that
Speaks before his boss with such firmness.
Nor kicks away a job he got mere days before and says, 'Please tell my father'.
'I, too, want to see how much my father distrusts me'.
I've asked about that girl.
Just 15 minutes ago, I got news that she was having dinner with Chengezi at a restaurant.
Chengezi is my Chief Accountant.
He's the one who'd issued the memo to him.
If that's so, why don't you reinstate him?
I would, but I have to know if he will come back.
I don't think so.
This is your BA degree,
Your FA [A-Level] certificate,
And this one's for your matric [GCSEs],
And your character certificate.
Shall I massage your head?
No.
Not today.
Why not?
It's this massage
That's got your grey cells working!
I need just so much grey cells to work
For me to go on like I am.
You're vexed because you're a clerk?
Don't be.
Great men have such beginnings.
Do you know about what Abraham Lincoln was?
Or what Edison used to do?
Talk about me, Arifa.
I'll never become a great man.
So Hazrat Sahab used to tell a lie?
Mum tells me
Hazrat Sahab would seat you in his lap.
And say, 'You'll see, Subhanallah',
'He'll grow to become a great man one day'!
Don't laugh like that.
Hazrat Sahab didn't tell a lie.
It's gotten into you that you can never become a great man.
Who's this Afzal?
That blighter?
Molvi Subhanallah's son?
The loafer, the vagrant!
You named him and said I love him!
That's what you think about me!
You thought you'd name someone like that,
And I'd stay quiet!
Just because I'm in the soup?
To the dickens with it!
It's better that I'm in the soup
Than out of it with the help of that loafer extraordinaire! But if you mention his name again, I'll claw your face apart!
Who is it?
You're still angry with me?
Okay.
How about you slap me?
Leave that be. What's this?
Slap my elder sister?
The one I've taken is enough.
There, now.
Sorry.
I promise. I won't ever slap you again.
Leave that be, Farah.
Just tell me
Why do you despise Afzal so much?
I don't despise Afzal.
Who is he?
He's my best friend's elder brother.
And you know how nice she is.
I also know
That Molvi Sahab is a good man.
But what is he?
How can the two of us judge what someone is like?
You'll scold me now
That I'm naming him.
But please, try not to.
Tell me, logically speaking,
How can we know what someone's like
Or what one's like based on what you say, when we hear about them?
I have a simple logic.
He's nobody for me.
Yes,
I found out two days ago
That he works at our mill.
Alright, he's our employee.
A slacker, at that!
Don't you remember?
He was out in the grounds watching a cricket match during office hours!
He's no longer our employee, Farah.
Dad ousted him.
Miss Rosy filed a complaint against him over harassment.
Perturbed over it, Dad was out in the courtyard for an hour.
Why?
Because he felt after he came home that he wasn't the culprit after all.
He was cursing himself.
Who told you?
Mum.
She also told me he didn't have his dinner.
Then Dad does not know
That I saw him come out of Rosy's car with my own eyes.
The poor girl must've given him a lift,
And he'd have thought he's got her head over heels for him.
Yes...
That may have caused the accident.
She'd have been defending herself.
Please go and tell Dad.
Alright. I will.
And please do listen to anything he says.
Hey! What'll he say?
-What could a regretful man say?
Mum was saying he'd apologise to him
If he could have his way.
And beg forgiveness of Molvi Subhanallah.
If that's so, why not ask him to come back?
Reinstate him?
He's not coming back, Farah.
Why won't he?
He's Molvi Subhanallah's son.
Kicked away the job he'd gotten on recommendation.
Do you know
When he used to gamble over matches,
Arifa would tell me about it.
But she never said,
'My brother is the type who cannot respect a woman's honour'.
I asked once
That he must have someone he loves.
She said, 'He must be having someone',
'But never tells anyone her name'.
Where's he gone?
To meet his friends?
He'll just have a chat and come back after a 'See you'.
When will he be back?
Before you go to bed.
Meet me somewhere else, my sweeting,
This pauper's presence in this princely concourse is not proper;
For souls besotted with love to walk upon
These trails etched with the marks of regality is not proper;
This meadow on this bank of the Yamuna [holy river], this château
These sculptured doors and walls, arches and niches -
An Emperor, by the weight of his wealth,
Has but made sport of the love of the penurious,
My sweeting,
Meet me somewhere else.
No.
I'll not smoke.
I'll have some tea.
Would you look at that!
It's him, isn't it? Arifa's brother?
You're right...
But what is he doing here?
He's an A1 loafer.
Must've found an excuse to skive off work.
It's him!
Who?
Afzal!
Stop by the cart.
I'll have some of this roasted corn.
How many?
Get as many as you like!
Look behind us!
Is he coming?
Afzal?
Yes!
No.
He will.
Here he comes!
Which way is he going?
Crossing the road over to the other side.
Did you see that?
What?
-He's not headed for our office!
Our office is that way.
Listen!
Call him back yourself.
He may come back if you ask him.
Alright, I will call.
And if he doesn't, talk to Molvi Sahab in the evening.
It'll get this off your heart.
If he doesn't come when I ask him, I'm not talking to Molvi Sahab.
What difference does it make?
-It does make one.
This thing struck me.
He'd said it rather confidently,
'Please mention this to my father'.
But now, I don't know what I'd say to his father.
Mr Afzal Subhanallah!
Come.
Afzal...
Subhanallah?
Yes.
Matric [GCSEs]...
FA [A-Levels] and BA...
Third division throughout.
But your character certificate is remarkable.
Usually, third division folks...
Aren't so remarkable.
How come you're so good?
Any experience?
I've worked two days at Ibrahim Cottons as an accountant.
But the experience wasn't good.
For them or for you?
For both of us.
Can you speak English?
I can understand what's written.
Speak a little, too.
Narrate the story of the thirsty crow.
Sir?
Thirsty crow, my dear chap.
Don't you remember?
'Once upon a time, there was a crow who was very thirsty'.
Do you know English?
What do you mean?
That's what I wanted to say.
'What do you mean'?
I'll narrate this one to my friends now,
'There was a crow'
'Who was really hungry'.
Hello?
Am I talking to Afzal?
Yes?
Sheikh Ibrahim here.
Peace be upon you, sir.
And upon you, peace.
Look, my son, I realised later that none of it was your fault.
And I regret admonishing you over it.
No, sir.
There's nothing to regret.
It's okay.
I've called you to ask you to come back.
Come and take your place at our office.
Thank you, sir.
But forgive me, sir.
It doesn't please me to take up a job on Dad's recommendation.
Perhaps you're --
-No, sir.
No 'perhaps' here.
Dad wanted me to get a job so that I could correct my ways.
His desire has been fulfilled.
I've corrected my ways.
I walk from place to place in search of a job now.
It has made me aware of my father's hardships.
And, in all honesty, once one has corrected his ways, he does not take up a job on recommendation.
Thank you very much, sir.
Yes, sir?
How many children do you have?
Three, sir...?
Two sons,
And one daughter.
What's your daughter's age?
12 years, sir.
And Miss Rosy?
How many children does she have?
No, sir...
She's not even married.
Give Miss Rosy three months' worth of compensation,
And out her.
Sir?
If you 'Sir' me again over this, I'll issue the same orders for you.
Right, sir.
Promise me
You'll never mention her again
Nor will you ask her name.
Just think as if
There is no girl.
There's no name.
Just a dream...
That delights me when I imagine it.
And if this isn't acceptable either,
Go and ask for Dad's opinion on it.
If delighting myself with a dream is sinful,
I will henceforth not.
Don't go this way.
We head along this route everyday.
Turn right, will you?
I know a shortcut.
Right, how's everything?
Fine.
Is it time for your break now?
It will be in a couple of minutes...
Have your lunch properly.
I will.
I've cleaned your room.
Thank you.
I
Found the key to your cupboard.
Key?
Don't worry. I didn't see anything.
Where'd you find it?
Don't ask me. I didn't even have to look for it.
That's my treasure in your possession!
That is why I stopped short of unlocking it.
Stopped?
It occurred to me that I open and read all the letters.
But then thought
God is watching.
Please
Keep on fearing God.
Alright, I'll disconnect.
Have your lunch.
I am about to.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital