Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Why are you taking me along?
You'd go and knock his door!
Why me?
This.
This is how you knock a door.
And what if Molvi Sahab greets me?
What, then?
He'd hit me here with his shoe!
He'll say, 'There is no power but God's! What are you doing here, you gambler'?
So you gamble for real?
No!
I play matches.
Molvi Sahab thinks it's gambling.
There he is...
Look!
If we win the match,
I'll give you one grand!
One grand?
Turned tail at the sight of me, eh bugger?
I'm your friend!
You're no friend of mine.
You're a sworn enemy!
My reputation has been besmirched because of you!
Have some shame, bleedin' bugger!
I've earned you thousands --
-I have earned them!
Such 'earnings' repulse me now!
Alright -- One last time...
What?
A match with the old colony lads...
You bugger!
We're playing for 100,000.
So?
I'll give you 50.
That's five months' pay, you blighter!
It's about time Dad came
And I swear by you, he passes by this road everyday.
Just say yes and I'm leaving.
Have some shame.
Read the Qur'an.
What do you think?
That I've not read it?
Go and read the commandment about gambling.
The ground beneath you will begin to tremble!
You --
Just pray that I win a big one.
I swear, I'll go on the pilgrimage.
Then listen to Dad's judgement too,
He said, 'Your friend Babloo is a sinner'!
What are you talking about?
You want that I lose the match!
I want that you win.
But just win the match.
A victory in gambling is your defeat.
Your Dad's bewitched you for sure.
You're betraying your friend!
One who supports gambling is no friend, Babloo.
Don't talk about loyalty to me.
What
Was this last line you said?
Dad --
Babloo was saying --
I heard the rest.
Repeat the last line.
Which one?
The one about loyalty.
I was saying --
'One who supports gambling is no friend'.
'Don't talk about loyalty to me'.
I will go straight to Hazrat Sahab's grave,
And tell him,
'My Afzal'
'Has become a great man'.
He'll be enlivened to hear this!
I've found out about that girl.
Who?
The one
Who writes letters to him.
Who is she?
I won't tell you her name.
So where's the news for me?
I already know about the letters.
I don't know about the one who writes them.
What do I tell you, Mum!
It's all been going on sub rosa!
If love is blossoming between the two for real,
You could say a storm is brewing up!
Why?
Is she disreputable?
He is. Very disreputable.
Your 'most excellent one' [Afzal]!
Do you want to give me a heart attack?
No, Mum!
You'd be delighted to hear it.
I've had a heart attack.
Let me recover.
Then I'll talk to you.
What are you doing here?
Waiting for you to wake up.
Everything alright?
Mum said, 'Wait by her until she wakes up, and bring her along the moment she does'.
Reason being?
He called.
He?
Your Afzal.
He asked when he'd be meeting Dad.
Why is he so impatient?
It's just yesterday that he had a scorching fever!
The fever's worn off,
And Mum's asked how he is countless times since the morning.
'I saw him sneeze myself'.
'He was shivering too'.
And so on...
Then, I told Mum
That he's ready to meet Dad.
Good Lord...
Well, it's all favourable to me so far...
It's happening exactly as I'd thought.
And may what is unthought of never happen.
And it's highly likely
That it'll come to be as I'm thinking it will.
What are you thinking?
Don't ask.
They say you should fear the possibility
Of something bad coming true when you say it.
Come now.
I'll wash my face and hands,
And then leave my room only then.
At least tell me.
Tell what?
What does he like?
Does he prefer meat or beef?
Or just fruits like you?
Mum's asked for two kinds of fish to be cooked.
But she said she'd prepare the lentils and vegetables only after asking you.
Is he coming today?
No.
He's not coming today.
But he'll come one of these days.
Then what is the meaning of this?
All these preparations?
The thing is, you'd vowed to offer a hundred additional prayers,
But you've been spared after a mere 12.
Your wish will be fulfilled.
The meeting with Dad has a ceremonial touch to it, sweetheart.
Then, it'll be Molvi Subhanallah
And Aunt Ruqaiyya's turn.
Oh God...
Thank God!
No one has been so successful in love before!
I'll say that the lentils be cooked in the finest clarified butter,
And any vegetable will do.
For God's sake, wait!
I can't wait.
Mum's grey cells are working at full efficiency!
And may what is unthought of never happen.
And it's highly likely
That it'll come to be as I'm thinking it will.
They say you should fear the possibility
Of something bad coming true when you say it.
Shall I say it for tomorrow?
Yes.
But if it rains tomorrow, he should come the day after.
Why would it rain tomorrow?
The poor lad gets a fever in the rains.
This is why I get worried.
Shall I invite him for dinner?
Yes, invite him for dinner.
But have him eat something before the meeting.
He'll not take a bite if something provoked his ire.
But why are you talking about all of this?
She's sleeping.
How much longer will she sleep?
She's vowed to wake up to good news.
This isn't new, Lubna.
Now, she vows to do something ever so often.
Have you watched Aina ('The Mirror')?
As in, the film?
The one starring Shabnam and Nadeem?
Yes.
I've watched it thrice!
Your Dad cried while watching it.
The same story is going on here.
My Dad bears an uncanny resemblance to Shabnam's!
No way!
Your Dad is very soft-hearted.
Shall I tell her then?
Tell her what?
'Wake up, you're about to get good news'!
Hold it there.
There's a difference between weeping over a film and marrying off one's daughter.
It frightens me to think, Lubna,
The poor girl will have the previous night's leftovers for breakfast.
Anyway,
Leave it to God's will.
For now, go and tell her when he's coming.
Dad thinks I've become a great man
Because I refused Babloo's 50,000.
Because 25 years ago, his Hazrat Sahab had seated me in his lap and said,
'Subhanallah'!
'Your son will grow to become a great man one day'!
Very good, mate.
You've been scoring a third division all throughout.
But I...
I've not been able to make the grade in my BA four times.
That makes me a greater man.
I know I can never become a great man.
I couldn't be a puny clerk.
I lost the job I'd gotten thanks to Dad on the second day
And I lack the courage to tell Dad...
I leave everyday with this untruthful tie,
And Dad is so delighted to see this...
Hey!
And where'd you get this cell phone from?
And where did yesterday's suit and boots come from?
Someone's asked me to feign love for four months.
She's purchased everything.
And she's paying me 200,000 every month for it.
You've hit the jackpot, you bugger!
He's selling out his conscience, you bugger!
To the Devil with conscience!
He'll be earning 800,000 in four months!
He can buy back the honour he sold.
What will you tell her?
Whom?
The one whose letters you read out to us.
-Leave it be, mate. Easy there.
This news ain't flashing on your TV screens.
Keep it up, Afzal.
With 800,000 bucks,
Nobody will ask you
If your conscience is alive or dead.
I was thinking of the same.
-Splendid.
Think of it,
And work on it.
No.
I'm thinking I'd not take the money.
Are you touched in the head, bleeding bugger?
Who leaves the money that was agreed upon?
Who charges any money to love?
At least be happy now.
He's coming tomorrow to meet your father.
And your father will call to decline Mehtab today.
What does this mean?
Don't ask what it means.
I mean, are you going to accept him?
We will get to know after the meeting.
What are your intentions?
Last night, your father was watching an old film of Mithun's.
Which one?
'Pyar Jhukta Nahin' (Love Never Capitulates)
You're going to accept him?
You're unnerved as if
Your own intentions are changing.
N -- No!
I'm chuffed.
But --
You should be in a right mard.
Take some time --
Then agree to it.
At this rate, he'll think --
Farah was just helplessly waiting to be taken.
But you are helplessly waiting to be taken!
When word gets out in the neighbourhood,
The girl is left helplessly waiting to be taken, so to speak.
Alright, don't change your intentions now.
Let what is ordained by God happen.
Alright, tell me
Does Molvi Sahab know about this?
I don't know.
He will get to know today.
How?
Your father said he'll offer his evening prayers there.
Dad will go to the Mosque to tell him?
Anything auspicious should start there.
For God's sake, Mum,
Why are you in such haste?
This is but natural, my dear.
If the girl shows haste in falling in love,
The parents show haste in getting her married off.
By the way, why are you getting worried?
He will agree to what you say.
Agree to what?
The same
About pursuing your MPhil in London.
In fact, he can go along.
He'll get to visit London too!
That's been decided already. Why don't you tell her, Farah?
He was delighted to hear that he's getting a chance to visit London!
There.
Don't tell this to your Dad!
Or else it'll be the first question when he meets him.
And if
He says, 'Alright',
'I'll get to visit London too'!
Then, God willing,
He won't have the chance to get you!
[Prayer for blessings and goodness in times of calamity]
Afzal!
Why are you sitting here?
Come in.
Are you well?
Yes. Never been better.
The fever's weakened you.
It's not weakness, Mum.
He's hiding something that he's ashamed of.
Tell me.
I'm right, am I not?
Hold it, Arifa!
Alright.
I'll hold it.
Tell me, now.
Should I get you some yahni
To cure the weakness, or chant an incantation for your depression?
Be ashamed of yourself if you are, Monsieur Afzal.
Spare yourself and tell the truth!
What's the worst that can happen?
Dad will curse you,
Mum will slap you.
I'd weep when I hear it.
But why should I weep again?
I've wept once already.
Say that you're not a clerk anymore.
To be precise, say that you're not even a clerk now.
Swear on my life if I'm lying.
Wager my head again if you like!
Say that she's mistaken!
She's just voicing unfounded suspicions!
Say something, my brother.
Or shall I have your Mum talk to your Mr Chengezi?
She'd believe it if he told her.
Forgive me
It occurred to me yesterday that I'd conceal it,
But I thought while praying in the afternoon
If I started concealing truths about you from Mum and Dad,
It would make me no better than you!
A fibber!
And then, it occurred to me during my evening prayer
That you're not evil,
You're the most vile and dastardly, Afzal!
Listen to the truth now.
A girl named Rosy worked there.
He's been ousted for harassing her.
His leaving every morning, wearing his trousers and shirt, with a tie,
He just pretends before us that he's going to the office!
In reality, he's into something dodgy that's gotten him a mobile worth 40,000 in a mere 4 days!
Say it...
Please, say it
That she's just told a lie...
She just told the truth, Mum...
But the truth isn't like what she's said it --
You blighter!
You're right in saying I'm no longer a clerk,
But everything else is a lie.
I swear by you.
Believe everything you like,
But never believe that your brother could harass a girl,
Nor think that I'd do anything Dad would think of as sinful.
This phone
Someone's given me this.
I've also gotten a new suit and ties.
They've hired me for a job.
But it isn't a job,
It's a trial for me.
And to emerge triumphant in this trial,
I'm staging a spectacle with them.
It's supposed to take four months,
But I've got a feeling it'll only take four weeks.
I'll look for a job then.
I concealed it from Mum and Dad because they were very happy
And I didn't want to ruin their happiness.
Why didn't you tell me?
You were happy too!
I realised today that you can be more furious than Dad!
You could've asked for once before creating a scene!
Still, I'm not angry with you.
I'm pleased to see your fury.
You've blown me to bits.
And if you're embarrassed, don't let it show up on your face.
And your tears
Are like Miss Rosy's accusations.
They can rattle my world.
What is it now?
Nothing at all.
What do you mean?
Everything I told you was a lie!
Just one bit was true, Mum.
He's left his job --
But you're under my oath, please don't tell Dad!
He's found another job.
He's working there.
Peace be upon you, Dad.
And upon you, peace.
Everything alright, sire?
You came to answer the door today!
I wanted to meet you
Talk to you...
Peace be upon you, Dad.
And upon you, peace.
[Begin] in God's name.
What is it?
It's nothing really --
Just --
Someone had bought him a new mobile, so he was saying,
'I'd ask permission of Dad'.
'I'll ask if I can keep it'.
Has it been purchased through rightful means?
100%.
You've brought it?
Yes.
Why are you asking me if you've brought it?
Now,
Don't ask me about these trifles.
Let the Molvi
Remain at the Mosque.
Just don't do that
Which you would be ashamed to do.
Has someone gifted it?
Yes.
How say you give something in return too?
Who's gifted it?
Will you ask everything now?
'Let the Molvi remain'
-Alright.
Alright, now, tell me
How are you?
I'm fine, Dad.
Ah, yes...
Monseigneur
Showed up
Today.
After his evening prayers,
He stayed with me for quite some time.
We
Kept on talking about this world and the next.
It seems he's very pleased with you.
'Someday', he said as he left,
'Come along with Madame to our place'.
What did you say, then?
I said, 'Certainly, why not'?
There's one thing I like very much about him
He always sits at the back when offering his prayers.
People like him
Only believe in God's greatness
And not their own.
So will you pay him a visit?
Sure, if he asked with such mesmerising emphasis again!
Don't worry
I'll call Lubna and ask her to stop her father.
Stop him from doing what?
Emphasising that Dad pay a visit!
Won't it all come out in the open if Dad went there?
Yes...
That's right...
Here's a surprise for you.
How many surprises have you in store for me?
This is the final one.
Go on.
I've also found out about the girl who writes you letters.
Tell me who she is.
I know her name, address, and lineage
But I'll never tell you!
Hello --
Peace be upon you, Monseigneur.
And upon you, peace.
I'd been eagerly awaiting your call.
Indeed, it took me a while to decide on it.
The other day, Madame was talking about a decision too.
I'm getting worried by the very mention of it.
I would like to humbly request something of you.
Please be courageous enough to listen.
Is everything alright?
The thing is,
Our plan for the marriage,
The date we'd fixed and all,
Is no longer possible.
Excuse me.
What's not possible?
Farah has rejected the proposal.
What?
What's the matter?
She wants to continue her education.
And she
Isn't quite accepting of Mehtab.
Pardonne-moi, Monseigneur,
She's lying.
She's got an affair going on.
It's a very old one.
They used to exchange letters and talk over the phone for hours.
But Mehtab had even forgiven this.
He shouldn't have.
When the girl says so much herself,
A gentleman should behave like one.
What do you mean?
I mean, I beg forgiveness of you,
And I'm remorseful for not being able to fulfil the promise I'd made my friend.
Your friend's dead, Monseigneur,
Only the living would feel any remorse.
Tell me
What will I say to those whom I've given the good news?
What will I say to my family,
Before whom I'd said proudly,
'My daughter-in-law won't be from the family for I'll fulfil the late Esquire's promise'!
Tell them it didn't come to fruition.
The girl's family reneged on their promise.
I, too, have to answer these questions, Madame.
But I do not fear it.
My family's honour isn't dearer to me than my daughter's life.
You're siding with her, Monseigneur; she's ensnared you in her sweet talk!
Stop the girl if she's taking a wrong step!
Don't back her!
Look, Madame,
Don't say what is improper.
This decision grieves me too, but --
By the Lord, Monseigneur, think of how much it'd hurt Mehtab.
He'd vaunt his wife's qualities among his friends!
'How sweet she is', 'How good and chaste she is'!
May I speak freely?
This marriage is not possible.
La fin!
How can you 'La fin' it like that, Monseigneur?
Is this a joke?
You'd fixed the date with us and you'd marry her off to someone else?
What if something happened to Mehtab?
Nothing will happen to him,
He'll feel a bit of sorrow,
And then he'll heal.
It happens, Madame.
Kids' wishes do vacillate sometimes.
Don't say such things, Monseigneur.
One should keep a close watch on daughters!
Leave my daughter,
And keep a watch on your son
So that he may not do something!
Goodbye.
Listen, Monseigneur --
Farah?
You've not slept again?
You've been awake all night?
What is it this time?
Are you alive?
Or are you dead?
Alright,
If you're dead,
Plummet right when I touch you.
And have no fear,
For the dead feel no pain.
May your enemies die! [ = 'What am I talking about'!]
Hello?
Where am I?
Platform #2,
And your train
Departs from Platform #1,
And, God willing, by the time you come to your senses,
Your train would've left.
Where are you going?
Have some shame, Farah Ibrahim!
There are things to do besides plotting and politics!
For instance, I go to the University to study,
And I had to take a leave yesterday because of you!
You're going to the University?
Any doubts?
No doubts at all.
But I'd request you
To not go today.
I'd made an excuse about how I could go alone yesterday,
But I'll go alone today!
Let go of my hand!
Please don't go...
You talk about pursuing your MPhil in London,
But is this how your studies go
Skiving off twice a week?
I'm sorry, I can't help you.
If you went to the University,
Dad will scold you.
Oh...
Dad will be delighted
If you slouch about here,
And Dad will scold me
If I go to the University?
He'll say,
'Have some shame, my dear'.
'There are no classes on Sunday'.
It's Sunday?
Yes.
Where would you go today?
The cricket ground by the old colony.
I'll go and sit there.
I answer your phone from over there and have my lunch there.
Which reminds me, my lunch box --
I say, don't go today.
Are you out of your mind?
You'd have Dad beat me with his boots!
You'd be beaten with boots
Even if you leave.
Leave it!
Dad will be delighted to see me.
Won't he be a bit worried
To find out that you're off to the office on a Sunday?
Take off your tie.
Dad's about to come out of his room.
Our complot shall end today!
He'll pay a visit tonight,
Have dinner with Dad,
And Dad will say, after a solemn meeting,
'Alright, my son',
'You pass my trials'.
'Bring your parents now'.
That's it!
Our plot ends here,
And the politics begins.
Have you ever thought what kind of politics this would be?
What do you think?
I've been awake for nights for sheer amusement?
I have thought it out.
Thought over every aspect of it.
And I've come to the conclusion
That Dad will accept him.
By the Lord, Farah,
Even the blind can see as much.
They can, certainly,
But they won't see.
Didn't get it?
Listen, then.
He won't come to meet Dad in the first place.
What?
Are you insane?
He's eager for this meeting.
To the dickens with him!
And Dad?
What will you say to him?
He asked the moment he came back yesterday,
'Right, Irsa',
'So he's coming tomorrow, isn't he'?
To add to it, Mum's preparations --
-Will all go to waste.
So you'll call to stop him?
Is that it?
Yes!
Won't Dad ask?
Will he keep waiting for him at dinner?
Would you look at how intelligent you are!
It's taken me an entire night to think about this,
And you caught up in a moment!
Wow!
May I continue hence?
Continue!
I'd concede your greatness!
Good Lord, it's written all over you
That everyone will keep on waiting but he'll not come to dinner.
If he were supposed to come at 9 p.m.,
He'd switch off his phone at 8.30.
Dad will ask where he is,
Mum will be left staring at you,
And you'd hide your face out of embarrassment.
And when it's 10,
You'd shed a few counterfeit tears,
And run upstairs with evident vexation!
Isn't it?
Hey!
Exactly like this!
How do you come to know?
Because I watch films by your side.
I presume you'd not have thought of anything beyond this?
What's the need to?
If he doesn't come, Dad will think,
'What an uncouth bounder'!
'He'll only make my daughter weep'.
Your film goes on nicely up to this scene;
The last thing everything afterwards will be is theatrical, and Dad will present it before you!
When I'm running the show,
Everything afterwards will happen as I like it!
Stay tuned,
I've got such a thrilling finale planned,
It'll make your head go round!
You'd be left asking me for months,
'Tell me, Farah',
'How do you even come up with such things'?
Call him.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital