Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Sit down.
Have your breakfast.
I'll get it.
I will get it myself.
Come on, my good man,
Sit; Have your breakfast.
She'll get the phone for you.
Why are you ringing with the phone?
Bring it, my dear.
Farah speaking.
I know you won't say anything
But that's okay.
Just listen carefully.
You'll be invited to dinner tonight.
You'll be delighted to hear this,
But don't use 'Don't worry'
When acting out your delight.
Say as soon as you get the invitation,
'Thank you, sir'.
'I'll be there on time'.
Are you listening?
Well,
You would be.
Next,
You won't come to dinner tonight.
At 9.15, I'll call you, worried,
Asking you
Why you're not coming.
Disconnect the moment I call you.
I mean
No response.
Then,
You will keep your phone switched off until 9 a.m. tomorrow.
At 9.01 tomorrow,
I'll talk to you again.
I'll tell you then
What you're supposed to do next.
Here.
It got disconnected.
Alright.
Have a look and see who's called you.
Must be a friend's.
After all, it's Sunday.
Someone must be calling me to play cricket.
This is the good type of cricket, isn't it?
Yes.
When will you have your breakfast?
We will.
Monseigneur's asking.
About
15 minutes from now?
Did that gag you?
This is called crisis management.
I figured last night
If he came today,
As you said he would,
His parents would be invited in a few days.
That starts a chain reaction, now, doesn't it?
Plus, our Dad
Is such a quick decision-maker!
One of these meetings, he'd call me,
Have me sit before Molvi Sahab,
And say,
'Here, Molvi Sahab'!
'Begin in God's name, and put the ring on her'!
He'll begin in God's name,
And I'll begin a monody!
And there
I'd be gone for good, Lubna!
Out of Mehtab
Into Afzal!
Why aren't you saying anything?
At least appreciate me!
I am appreciating you.
So far, it's happened as you'd thought it would.
So it has been.
And so, fear God, Farah Ibrahim!
Only God has such power.
Everything happens as He wills.
You're bent upon scaring me!
You'll know about crisis management
When something unprecedented will happen!
What will happen?
That's what's not known.
But I have a hunch
God suddenly stops
A person from becoming a God himself!
Hello?
Am I talking to Afzal?
Yes. It's me.
You --?
This is Sheikh Ibrahim speaking.
Yes --
Sir, I recognised your voice.
Peace be upon you, sir.
And upon you, peace.
How are you, my good man?
I'm good.
Fine.
It feels like you're lying when you say 'fine'.
Not at all, sir.
I don't lie very often.
In fact, I used to,
But not at all now.
Alright. Tell me you're not busy in the evening?
No.
Not at all.
Can you meet me at 9?
Of course I can, sir.
Alright,
Then we'll meet at 9 for dinner at my house.
Sharp at 9 o'clock.
Right, sir.
Shall I send a car at a quarter to 9?
No, sir.
It's just about two furlongs.
I'll be there
If I just sauntered down the road.
If it rains, if you get drenched,
Come regardless.
I will, sir.
You don't worry.
Okay; Bye.
Hello?
Did you get the invitation?
I did.
Then do as you've been told.
You don't worry.
Leave it to me.
I hope you remember everything?
Of course.
Alright; tell me,
Why don't you say anything
When Farah calls you?
I can't bring myself
To say something to her.
It's gotten too far, Mum.
He's going to their place for dinner tonight.
Where?
To that girl's place!
But there's one thing I don't get.
The younger sister's inviting him,
And the elder sister's stopping him!
What do you mean?
I mean, the elder sister's a tad haughty
And so, she's throwing a spanner in the works.
God only knows what you're saying and what you want to tell!
Stay tuned
For one breaking news after another.
Get a few new gowns ready.
And
Send the jewellery you've kept in the chest for polishing.
I'm auguring a gathering one of these days.
There, now!
It's not as if he'd want to be handfasted to any Mary, Jane or Susie and Molvi Sahab will say, 'Praise the Lord'! [=Subhanallah]
'Get ready and come with me, Ruqaiyya',
'I bear glad tidings that we've found a daughter-in-law'.
She's no Mary, Jane or Susie.
You'd be awestruck to hear about her!
You'd turn to look at your Afzal over and over,
Repeating,
'The blighter's hit a jackpot'!
Fear God, Arifa, you're calling your elder brother a blighter!
I was just --
Saying it as you!
You do say it occasionally.
So what if I say it?
It's rather rude.
Take these away for washing.
Stop him!
Hey --
Stop!
-Leave him!
Step a--
-Why are you beating him?
The bugger borrowed a hundred thousand for one day!
And now he says he'll return it next month!
Why don't you step aside?
-Halt!
As if this would solve anything!
Did you borrow a hundred thousand?
Yes.
What did you do with it?
Lost it in a match.
Will you get your 100,000 Rupees back if you batter him?
Even his father would give me the money!
Don't bring in his father.
His father won't give a penny.
Stop playing Dad [=guardian] to him and step aside!
-Hey!
I'll get my money at all costs!
I know how to lend,
And I know bloody well how to collect!
-Take his money, then
Not his life.
Will you give me the money?
I'll give you.
Oh?
So you would give me the money.
Yes.
Take your money from Sajid at 8 p.m.
8 p.m. means 8 p.m.
Rest assured; I mean it when I said it.
Come and collect your money.
Make yourself scarce now.
I'll deduct 2,000 Rupees if I saw your face before 8.
Go!
Begone, you bugger!
Thank you, mate!
Thank you very much.
Mr 'Thank you'!
Pull out 2,000.
2,000?
I have 98,000.
So,
You'd actually give him a hundred thousand?
I'll have to give him the money
Now that I've given him my word.
Now, give me 2,000.
Take all of it!
I don't want all of it, mate!
Just 2,000.
Here.
And make yourself scarce 'round here.
If Dad saw you,
You'd be deemed worthy of being murdered [the ultimate sinner]!
Go, now.
Alright, then.
Tell your father that Babloo
Won't ever gamble from this day on.
I'm under your oath.
What's this?
I'm thinking of what I'd wear tonight.
Splendid!
You're so serious
As if he's actually coming tonight!
Why don't you tell Mum too?
She's preparing some cates for real!
You daft demoiselle,
One's got to prepare to act or act to prepare.
And you must stand out from all of us
Full of colours!
Lost, dreaming of someone,
Dressed to impress!
What?
How else would Dad know
That you're delighted he's coming?
Forget for now
That you've asked him not to come.
Imagine he's coming
He'll come,
And the wait drives you mad:
You're eyeing the clock every so often,
Checking your makeup in the mirror,
In fact, even if you don't need it,
Retouch your makeup just to show Mum!
Turn away
If your gaze falls on Dad,
Act coy and move aside.
It'll only work if you do all of this.
What'll work?
It's strange
That you've hatched up this plan
And I'm filling you in on the details!
Tell me.
Look, sweet damsel,
When he doesn't show up at 9,
And switches off his phone at 9.15,
Won't Dad redden with rage?
And seeing your preparations will only add fuel to his fiery fury!
Sure will!
Then, instead of saying yes to him,
Dad will say to you,
'Think carefully, girl',
'You've still got time'.
Sit back and think, then.
For 4, 6 or even 10 or more months,
Take a year or two if you will!
And then, say to him,
'Dad',
'I've realised my mistake'.
'Afzal's not the right type'.
Then?
What, then?
You've been bailed out of Mehtab,
And Afzal will fall like a house of cards.
You pack your bags for London!
Where are you off to?
Let me see, too,
What I'll wear tonight!
Here.
Here's your suit.
Thank you!
Thank God I got there on time!
The bleedin' laundryman
Had bundled your suit with your Dad's clothes
To send it to your house!
Whoa!
And thank your Dad too
For he said the moment he saw it,
'This suit isn't Afzal's'!
Dad was there too?
He'd just arrived.
I greeted him and skedaddled!
Good.
You're going there again, aren't you?
Yes.
You'd wear the same suit today?
Is this your suit or your uniform?
I'd gotten all drenched in the rain that day
I couldn't show it off nicely.
I will today!
When I'd purchased this,
She liked it.
I hope you're very happy!
Let me tell you in advance that your father's going to say yes to him!
Hey!
Why are you so agitated?
Not at all!
She's not agitated...
She's just a bit demure...
Anyway,
This isn't how you look demure!
C'mon!
Here.
Would you look at this!
How sweet she looks!
Why hasn't he come yet?
It may be that he's a few minutes late...
How come?
I'd asked him to be here sharp at 9 o'clock!
Should I call him, Dad?
I'll call him.
Right,
Where are you, my good man?
Okay.
He's not coming?
Why won't he?
Go and get him inside,
He's at our doorstep.
It was still 10 seconds to 9
When I was at your doorstep.
Your father called the moment I thought I'd ring the bell.
I hope I look good?
Your father thunders when he speaks!
The first thing he said over the phone was
'Where are you, my good man'?
I greeted him in a moment,
And he quietened.
I'd called to ask you if you remembered everything
And you'd replied, 'You don't worry'.
Yes?
So was this what was asked of you?
Come in now.
Peace be upon you, Uncle.
And upon you, peace.
You're looking handsome!
Thank you, sir.
Peace, Aunt.
And upon you, peace.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Sit.
After you.
I have some other chores to see to,
Sit here and talk to Uncle for now.
Please, sit.
-Alright.
Thank you.
And why are you sitting here?
Come with me
And sit with Farah.
At ease.
I won't ask you anything that will require you to strain your mind for no reason.
Why has he come?
He doesn't know either.
The blighter!
I won't give him one penny!
He doesn't need the money anymore.
For he'll be getting you along with everything in your bank account!
Shut your gob!
It's more than his face is worth!
-Don't talk about his face.
The rapscallion looks so dashing!
He's wearing the same black suit again.
What are your ambitions?
Have you ever thought what you'd do,
What you'd become?
Not at all.
But I'm looking for a job, sir.
I've not told Dad that I've been ousted from the old one.
Hasn't he found out?
How would he when I've not told him?
I leave
Every morning as if going to my office,
And come back in the evening.
Dad thinks I'm coming back from the office.
But I'm
Trying, sir.
You should be thankful I've not told him.
Thank you very much, sir.
Have you ever thought about the status
Of the one you love?
How she spends her life?
Why?
I've never been able to bring myself to believe
That I could ever get married to her.
Has she never asked you either?
She must have told you not to gamble on matches!
No.
So she says you can?
She doesn't say so either.
Surely, you aren't nervous?
Not at all.
Imagine, I accept your marriage to her,
And in four months, you do, indeed, get married to her.
What will you do then?
What are your career prospects?
What are your ambitions that I can trust to assure me that you'll be able to keep her happy?
One doesn't trust career prospects, sir;
It is the man whom one trusts.
And I have full confidence in myself.
I'll earn to be able to feed her.
I'll do everything I can to keep her happy.
At first, I couldn't believe it, Farah!
I couldn't bring myself to accept that he's come!
When I opened the door,
He was before me, smiling shamelessly!
How you'd repeated everything to him
That he should say when he's invited, 'I'll be there',
But he's not to come!
And yes
You'd also said to him,
'Switch off your phone at 9.15'!
What good will it do to remember this?
Who's thinking of any good?
I'm just estimating
The potential damage!
Shut up!
Splendid!
It's killing me to worry about you,
And you're saying 'Shut up'!
Alright, I will shut up!
But listen to one final thing
You'll be cursed by that blighter Mehtab!
Where are you going?
Just --
I'll take a stroll around the house.
It's better that I ask when we'd have dinner
Than sit by your side quietly!
You're concerned about the food, Lubna!
So should I stop eating too?
Just because
He showed up despite instructions not to!
And why are you worrying?
What happened to your 'crisis management'?
Now that he's here,
Just take it as if --
Imagine, rather, you've called him here yourself!
Meet him like you'd meet a dolor non grata -
Beckon to it, give it a place in your heart,
And then say to it,
'To the dickens with you'!
To the dickens with you!
And if I told you that your marriage to Farah isn't possible,
How would you react?
I wouldn't react, sir.
Why?
Won't you feel sorrow?
It didn't seem likely I'd say yes after today's meeting.
Surely, I would feel sorrow, sir,
But I've come here with the firm belief that I don't deserve her.
I have nothing, sir.
Just dreams...
But I don't have reason to believe they'd ever come true.
I do say that I'd do everything I can do keep her happy,
But how long will I keep trying; how long she'd be happy with me...
The truth, sir, is that I don't even come up to Dad's expectations.
And you're her father.
You're getting nervous, aren't you?
Not at all.
Then why don't you say
'I'd react if you reject me'?
'I'll take a stand against everyone for her'!
Because I never would, sir.
Even for her, I'd never take a stand against her father.
I can take a stand against everyone else.
How many suits do you have like this one?
Just this one, sir.
It's nice.
It suits you.
Thank you, sir.
Wear this one when you come tomorrow.
Come where, sir?
To the office.
Sharp at 9 o'clock.
The same as you do everyday.
Right, sir.
I'll be there at 9.
Don't say anything!
I'd found out before you entered this room.
You bring bad tidings.
Okay.
Just hear as much
That the meeting's over,
And it's time for dinner.
Retouch your makeup
And get to the dining room, double time!
It's quite possible
That the moment you get there,
Dad will
Announce his surrender before your love!
Your father says Arifa would know where he is.
Dad's right in saying so.
When will he be back?
He would, soon enough.
An hour at the most?
I can swear to you
I won't even mention it to your father,
But at least tell me
Where he's gone
And who she is.
Ask all you will about her looks, and I will tell you.
But I won't tell you her name without his permission.
Just pray that he succeeds today!
I won't pray before I hear her name.
Well,
Love doesn't need prayers.
Why doesn't it?
Oh?
Wouldn't Majnun's mother have prayed for him?
And Ranjha's mother, I've heard, died in his childhood.
But Punnun and Farhad's mothers were fine.
Did their prayers work?
They didn't, did they?
So has my Afzal become Majnun [ = crazed in love]?
Speak something good, would you?
Let your mouth utter only good things.
Don't look at how their love ended, Mum.
Look at their place.
The poor ones died in the absence of a second option,
Else the legends would be talking about their children too!
Don't worry, Mum.
You Afzal will be the most excellent ['Afzal'] of them all!
How do you eat at home?
Dad says
One should eat with one's hands, so that's how...
So eat with your hands.
It's no good acting coy and running away now.
Sit.
Why don't you eat, my dear?
Why did you stop?
Sure.
I'm sorry, Dad...
But please don't proclaim any decision just yet.
I want to talk to Afzal about something.
Just for ten minutes?
And Lubna will be with me.
Please?
Okay.
I have no objections.
Talk to him about it.
Thank you, Dad.
Would you be done with it quickly?
Should I
Keep standing, or may I sit?
Sit!
You'd said
You'd not come.
Who'd said it?
So you're acting here as well?
You loafer!
I'd said it.
I'd called you myself!
I'd repeated everything to you to make it clear!
No you didn't?
No as in?
You didn't call me.
You didn't explain anything.
Would you look at that!
How he can look me in the eyes and lie to me!
I didn't look you in the eyes...
Didn't lie either.
Farah had called before my eyes
Using my cell phone.
She was explaining everything elaborately!
I was listening to it here as you were over there!
I swear by God, no!
I didn't hear a word of it!
He's telling the truth.
He's swearing by God.
So was I
Talking to my angels?
What's the matter?
I mean
Did you ask me not to come?
Exactly.
Good Lord!
But who answered the phone, then?
Whom did you talk to?
Did I say anything?
Have you ever said anything in reply?
You quieten the moment you hear my voice!
You don't even say a 'yes' or 'okay'!
I do wish you peace [greetings].
What do I do now?
What did Dad say?
He's called me to the office tomorrow.
He said he'd meet me there.
You won't go there.
How can that be?
How could I disobey him?
How could you disobey me?
You're serving me for 200,000 a month!
But you'd said the designation is a grand one!
She's calling me a servant!
You're worried about your designation?
Just a minute, Farah.
Care to tell me
What you'd do if Dad proclaimed his decision
Of getting the two of you married?
What could I do in that case?
So you'd marry me, eh?
No, I didn't quite say that.
You're just being naïve, Farah.
He isn't here to get married to you.
Just tell me
Do you have a way out if Dad proclaims his decision?
My brain's paralysed, Lubna!
You'll see in a while
As my heart stops beating too!
Don't get all worked up like that.
Let Dad proclaim his decision.
What?
He'll not just proclaim his decision,
He'd kiss him as his own,
And seat him on the exalted throne as his son-in-law!
What will I do then?
And what will he do then?
Perfidy?
That's what had been decided upon, isn't it?
He'd act to love you from the depths of his heart,
And then break yours.
Right!
I'd forgotten it!
And it isn't my fault either.
After Mehtab's chapter closed, I'd begun to think
He, too, should do his job, take his money, and get going!
Look,
Four months of acting is something that neither I can do, nor he.
I can.
What can you do?
I mean,
I'll show my love
As long as it's necessary.
And when it's required that I be perfidious,
I would be perfidious.
Do it tomorrow.
Splendid.
Dad will say yes today,
And he'd two-time you tomorrow!
Don't you think
It's too early?
It's been ten minutes already.
Come, Mademoiselle.
Monseigneur says it's been ten minutes.
Alright.
Listen.
If Dad talks about the marriage,
Say,
'Alright, thank you'.
Don't say anything else.
I won't.
And if he said,
'Bring your parents one of these days',
What would you say then?
I'd say, 'Alright'.
'Thank you'.
Are you nuts?
Don't you dare talk to them
Or bring them here!
No -- I won't.
I'd say, 'They can't come'.
'T -- Talk to me'.
What will he talk to you about?
And why would he talk to you about the marriage?
What should I tell Monseigneur?
Tell him we're coming in ten minutes.
Alright, listen.
You don't need to get nervous.
Stand firm with your love for now,
We'll work on the schedule -- for your perfidy later.
Come with me, now.
Okay?
C'mon!
Come.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital