Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
I'm afraid.
That's good.
What do you mean?
You're saying it's good that I'm afraid?
Do you know why I'm afraid?
I do.
You're afraid he's married the Farah from the letters,
And you think he'd come back from Karachi
With two of his kids.
And you're also afraid
That the kids would recognise you instantly,
And, calling you 'Aunt', embrace you.
Why would they embrace me?
And how can they recognise me?
Farah,
One never forgets
The one who wounds him.
So, your name would be mentioned often
Before Farah and the kids.
There!
You're getting goosebumps, aren't you?
Do you know what that means?
What does it mean?
Well,
You know what it means, too.
You're wishing that you die before seeing that day.
Which day?
C'mon, mate,
Don't act so innocent.
One gets the chills when one's so perturbed.
God forgive...
However did you even think that
He'd marry the Farah from the letters,
And he'd have two kids who'd - God forbid -
Call you 'Aunt' the moment they see you?
Get out.
Think again,
I'd actually leave.
Remember how you'd pleaded with me to get me here?
I'm not my problem; you are!
I'm going to the psychiatrist in the morning because of you.
Dad's booked an appointment in the evening. He's seeing the same doctor.
What happened to him?
I'd told you...
He thinks his brain's been french fried.
That's a problem with his English.
Otherwise, he's alright.
You're laughing, aren't you?
Wait,
I may just curse you!
Hey!
I'll say,
'May you be in my condition',
'Stumbling around restlessly',
'Living, but not alive',
'Mortified, but not quite dead'!
Oh...
So that's how you're feeling...
And
You didn't say a word.
I'm telling you now.
I'm cursing you, too.
Thank you, Farah.
You're thanking me now,
But you'll get your deserts later.
That's what they all say,
'You'll get your deserts when you fall in love'.
But this knave called 'love' never got me!
Who's talking about love?
You're dancing around as love itself,
And you're asking who's talking about love!
By the Lord, you lassie,
However do I tell you I don't love him!
I'm even feeling sad
Over why I didn't marry Mehtab.
I dragged principles in for no reason,
Otherwise, he was right -
Who goes to London to study after getting married?
Should I call him?
Mehtab?
Of course.
The poor lad would've gotten up.
He'd be shivering right now.
May the Lord keep him happy.
Hey!
Why are you throwing your responsibility onto the Lord?
If you've realised your mistake, just call for once.
Marry him, take him along to London, and keep him happy.
I'll meet him when I'd go to Karachi.
Oh...
So you're going to Karachi?
I might as well.
If I understood what Mehtab said,
I'd definitely go to Karachi.
Why are you laughing?
For God's sake, Farah,
You'd go to Rawalpindi, too, if only Afzal went there.
Just look at how
You've started respecting Mehtab for him.
Lubna!
You'd better leave.
Leave it be.
You'd be left afraid and alone here if I went away.
I won't be afraid.
Think over it, Farah Ibrahim,
You're taking a risk.
I know fully well
That lost love becomes a ghost
That presents itself here or there.
Who?
Afzal, of course.
C'mon,
Get out!
Okay, fine.
Close the doors and windows.
Although doors and windows do little to deter ghosts,
It just satisfies one's heart.
Okay?
Good night.
-[Call to the morning prayer]
[Call to the morning prayer]
-Oh, sorry...
-Good morning.
[Call to the morning prayer]
You've kept God busy, Ruqaiyya Begum.
He
Looks after everyone's children.
He will take care of your son, too.
Don't worry.
He'd better.
There's no power but God's!
This thing about 'He'd better' isn't exactly
Proper.
Your coming between the Lord and me is not proper either, Molvi Sahab.
Please be kind enough
As to leave the Lord with His woman,
Beyond the Molvi's control.
Whatever are you
Saying, Ruqaiyya Begum?
What could I do, Molvi Sahab?
A mother's courage is most unlike that of the Lord.
Nothing that is His ever gets lost,
But mothers' sons do get lost.
That's why I've been chanting requests -
'If You remember Your love for Your creation',
'Don't ever forget a mother's love for her son'.
-God forgive!
Does He ever forget?
That's it.
That's what I'm asking.
'Did You forget it when it was my turn'?
Your mother's saying words of disbelief!
There's never disbelief in a mother's words, Dad.
The one who gives birth to children is talking to the one who gave birth to all of creation.
She'd know how to talk.
Is it that the two of you leave me speechless now,
Or is it that the one who's left
Has taken my words with him?
But remember, Ruqaiyya Begum,
If there's so much as a speck on the honour of God's own,
Miracles happen.
Listen, Molvi Sahab,
Mothers pray for miracles in their helplessness.
It's an obligation on God's own to do something worth showing Him.
Then save your prayers.
Every day, to do something worth showing,
I go to watch cricket.
I spend the entire afternoon there,
At the playground where your Afzal
Used to play matches he'd gamble over.
If I got wind of his whereabouts,
I'd be at his doorstep one of these days.
And
Don't be so selfish in your sorrow
As for forget the pain of Afzal's father.
Just think
You're tormented in one way,
And I'm tormented in another.
Arifa!
Come and shut the door.
The Molvi
Is going to fulfil his fatherly duties.
What --
What's up with the people?
Why are they saluting me?
Why are they calling me 'Afzal Bhai'?
-The cowards are so helpless --
Peace be upon you, Afzal Bhai!
How are you, sir? Would you like to have some tea, sir? A cold drink?
-I'm fine.
No, thank you very much.
Okay, sir.
They refer to their oul fella as 'Bhai'.
Whatever does that mean?
Why are you so tensed? If they salute you, just greet them back.
-But --
Why are they greeting and saluting me now? They never used to.
And I didn't quite get this one about the oul fella and 'Bhai'.
Alright, come. I'll tell you.
How are you?
-I'm fine.
Greetings, sir! How are you?
Go on.
Tell me.
What do these sudden salutes mean?
Why were they calling me 'Afzal Bhai'?
Sit.
Cripes, mate...
Be done with this chapter of 'sit', 'stand up', 'I'll tell you at home'.
Just get to the point.
How tall are you?
You're asking about my height?
Just tell me how tall you are; I'll answer your question.
5' 11".
5' 11"...
Weight?
Again?
Tell me your weight.
81 kg.
Now, look around and tell me how many lads
Are above 5' 11"
And 81 kg.
You'd find more than a handful.
And when all of these lived here
Even before you came,
Why would girls have to fear for their honour
Before a 5' 11" hoodlum like yourself?
Because measuring one's height and weight does not tell anything about how much courage a man's got.
Hoodlums are not made by their capabilities,
But by the fear and cowardice in the hearts of people.
The one whom people fear
Becomes a hoodlum.
Tell me about the salutes.
Why were they saluting me?
The people have begun to fear you because they think you're a bigger hoodlum than Wali.
What?
One surprised 'What' isn't going to change the ways of the city.
-Here.
Here's your lunch.
So much?
It's not so much.
There's just many dishes.
What've you got?
Potato, meat, chicken ginger, and mixed vegetable.
Why are you looking at each other like that?
Sit and have some, and tell me how it is.
I've cooked the chicken ginger.
Yes, it's good. Good.
You're saying without even tasting!
No, it looks good.
When did you see it?
There's a lid on the top.
Looking at your face, one can tell that the chicken ginger you've cooked is delicious!
-There, now!
And what are you doing, looking at me like that?
Just a spot of lipstick's got you stunned!
Well,
That isn't something I could say myself.
Mam's told me not to.
How say you tell me -
How does this lipstick look?
It -- I -- It's good.
So you think
You've been sent
Here as part of a conspiracy against you,
And you're otherwise perfectly normal.
Of course.
Know what,
I'm the first girl in my family
Who's seeing a psychiatrist for her treatment.
Do you know why?
Why?
Because they think of psychiatrists as aliénistes in my family.
Aye?
'Aye' as in?
Is it right?
Naw at all!
So,
You were saying
That Lubna's your younger sister?
Yes.
And who's this Afzal?
Afzal?
I didn't even mention his name.
I get it!
You've been briefed before I came here.
Naw at all, you've named him five times in twenty minutes.
How could that be?
I shut up even so much as a thought of him.
Why do you think of him?
I mean, who is he to you?
Hold your horses, Monsieur le Docteur!
He's nobody to me!
Lubna's best friend is Arifa,
And he's her brother.
An ace loafer and wastrel.
Just last month
He gambled one last time
And ran away from the city.
Oh!
Where'd he go?
No idea.
But I've heard he's gone to Karachi.
I also know why he would've gone there.
Why would he have gone there?
Don't you think it's
Something I have nothing to do with?
Aye, right, you don't,
But...
I thought I might as well ask
Now that you've mentioned it.
He's having an affair with a girl.
He's eloped with her.
Do you want to know the girl's name?
Please.
You'd laugh.
Naw,
I promise.
Farah!
That blighter's name is Farah, too!
His parents are very sad...
It pains me to see them.
So, you pay them a visit now and then?
No, Monsieur le Docteur!
It's nothing like that.
I just felt, for once,
That I'm partly to blame for his leaving, too.
So, I went over to give them some comfort.
Why did you feel so?
I mean, if you shut up so much as a thought of him,
How could you be responsible for his leaving?
Leave it be, Monsieur le Docteur.
It's a long story...
I have no problems; I can listen to long stories.
I think
It's quite personal.
Look,
Nothing's personal when seeing a psychiatrist.
Everything the patient tells is strictly confidential.
'Patient'?
You're calling me your patient?
Uh -- Naw -- It was a slip of the tongue...
I meant,
We call those who consult us for advice our patients.
Oh...
But you won't call me your patient now.
Sure.
Right.
The story begins
With Mum getting me engaged to one Mehtab.
The lad's an ace bounder.
I'd agreed to it in the beginning,
But when I interviewed him after the engagement,
I realised
That --
His intentions aren't right!
What were his intentions?
Well,
I won't tell you everything.
Just think
That he had no intention to work even after getting married.
However would he get his two square meals if he didn't work?
He has no issues with that.
He's got millions lying in the bank,
And he gets his share from that.
But I
Curse a lad like that,
Who'd keep millions in a vault
And make a show of having a jolly good time before the poorer ones!
Seeing you, one can't possibly tell you're among the 'poorer ones'.
Monsieur le Docteur, what are you saying?
If only my Dad wanted to,
He could buy the likes of Mehtab in a moment.
Okay, okay.
Please, go on.
What happened next
Has brought me before you.
Just think
As if I've made one foolish mistake.
Peace be upon you, Dad.
And upon you, peace. Where are you?
At the psychiatrist's clinic.
So you actually went there!
I couldn't believe it when your Mum told me.
Where is she?
She's with the doctor. It's been an hour.
She was alright, wasn't she?
She was, Dad.
Seeing the patients at the clinic, she said,
'I can't see a single mad man here'.
Tell her to talk to me when she comes back.
I will, sure.
But...
But what?
She isn't going to get cured.
Are you alright?
She went there just casually; otherwise, whatever is wrong with her?
Nothing's wrong with her, Dad.
But she isn't ready to be cured yet.
What's this logic, mate?
Do you know what you're saying?
I'm telling the truth, Dad.
She's come to the psychiatrist because she, too, knows that she's --
-The psychiatrist will help her with her condition.
I've heard he's a very intelligent doctor.
He listens for hours to what the patient says, and solves it within moments.
Let's hope for the best.
Okay, Dad,
Bye.
Okay.
There was such a scene
When he brought his family along for the engagement.
And guess what,
They even had the engagement ring with them!
His Dad took it out from his pocket and showed it.
And, Monsieur le Docteur, it was the bleeding limit
That my Mum and Dad were chuffed, too!
They didn't even think
How a girl like Farah
Could ever even think about a wastrel like Afzal!
What happened, then?
What could've happened?
As if I'm meek as a lamb,
And I'd go along with him, bleating!
Right at the time of the engagement,
I exposed him!
I shoved the engagement ring in his face.
As in, right in his face?
No.
As in, refused to get engaged.
I showed him his place right there and then.
So, to speak,
'Shoved the ring in his face'.
Oh, so you were saying it just as an idiom...
Of course...
He'd be hiding his face in shame, then?
No, Monsieur le Docteur.
He left Hyderabad after that.
And honestly?
I did feel sorrow at his leaving.
Why did you feel sorrow?
I mean,
Why would you feel sorrow for such a man?
His family's missing him a lot.
Looking at them,
I torment in pain, too.
That's strange...
He's having a ball in Karachi,
And people are tormented here for him.
Please, Monsieur le Docteur,
Don't say that.
Don't say what?
That he's having a ball in Karachi.
That's not what Dad thinks.
Forget about Daddy, tell me what you think.
The thing is,
Seeing him, one doesn't really feel he'd be that type.
Besides his habit of gambling,
There isn't any other vice he has, really.
He'd even been acquitted in the case with Rosy.
Who's Rosy?
She was a blighter.
It came up later
That she was drooling over him.
Dad ousted her.
Oh...
So she worked for you.
Interesting story,
And funny as well...
Innit?
Alright, tell me,
Are you in the same condition now?
What condition?
The same - you shutting up even so much as a thought of him.
Do you shut it up even now?
No.
If he comes to my mind,
I think about him...
What, for example, do you think?
That he should come back to Hyderabad now.
It's better if he live here.
Why is it better for you?
I'm not talking about myself, Monsieur le Docteur.
If he stayed before his parents' eyes,
It'd give them peace.
How noble your thoughts are...
He ought to come back now.
But what if he didn't?
He'd have to, Monsieur le Docteur!
Molvi Subhanallah's prayers won't go to waste!
And with his Mum having the Ayat'e Karima [Prayer for Relief from All Difficulties] recited,
How much longer could he keep running away?
Plus, I've vowed to offer 100 additional prayers.
You don't know, Monsieur le Docteur,
My wish gets fulfilled
Just after I offer 12 of them.
At least tell me what the doctor said.
I will,
But promise me
That if you ever had such a problem,
You'd never go to a psychiatrist.
Why? What happened?
These psychiatrists are right wizards,
They even ask things one wouldn't even tell one's Mum and Dad.
So he asked you everything?
Yes...
And you told everything?
Quickly.
Then?
What did he tell you about the treatment?
Treatment?
So you think I'd gone there to get treated?
Do you know,
He called me a 'patient' by mistake.
He apologised for it.
So that means going there didn't help at all.
No, it did help.
He's told me not to silence any thought of him.
He said there's nothing wrong about it.
This reasoning is right, too.
He said you need to let his thoughts enter before getting them to exit.
How would they get out if you never let them in?
Whose thoughts?
Of Afzal, of course.
So you told him that you think about Afzal?
I don't think about him.
I just have an occasional thought of him.
Blimey...
Is there anything wrong with that?
No.
There's nothing wrong with it.
But tell me, what would you tell Mum and Dad?
What would I say to them?
Dad called me when I was there.
He asked me to call when leaving the clinic.
Mum's asked thrice, too,
'Why is it taking so long'?
I said, 'The treatment's taking time'.
'Treatment'?
Yes --
I said whatever came to my mind.
But be prepared with your answer.
Think of what you'd say when Mum and Dad would ask.
Would you tell the truth or lie?
What do I tell them if I tell them the truth?
Just say that
You think of Afzal.
I'd never tell that!
Well, you never told me about that either.
By the way, what kind of thoughts do you have?
Romantic, or
The bland desi type [South Asian, unsophisticated]?
As if I'd romance Afzal!
You wouldn't, sure, but thoughts come as they please.
Who knows, you may have had one one day, in a romantic mood?
Shut up!
Honestly, though, Farah,
It is about time you brought out the sly lass hiding behind your veil of innocence,
And say openly, 'I won't leave anyone in peace until I've found peace myself'.
What does this mean?
You crazy lass,
Why are you toying with yourself?
If you love Afzal, just say that you love him.
Nobody will say anything to you.
For God's sake, Lubna,
I don't love Afzal!
At least think before you say something!
Matching me with Afzal --
No!
Never!
What happened?
Can't you believe it?
Not one bit.
Am I lying?
You're not lying,
But you don't know the truth.
And it pains me to say
That the day you come to know the truth
Would be the day I'd say,
'You're lying'.
In that case, why don't you get this mirror out of here?
Here's your tea.
If my eyes fall on it while passing by, I take a look.
I'll say it straight, Mam,
Who doesn't like a pretty face?
Have your tea.
He's over 25 for sure.
At this age, a man with a fair face has already found a girl for himself.
What would you do if he told you that he's found one for himself?
He may have.
As if I bother!
Your bothered self
Would be visible in the mirror, then.
You wouldn't say, then,
'Get this mirror out, Mam'.
You'd say, 'Destroy this mirror'.
Have your tea.
Give me one, too.
A cigarette?
Yes.
Why?
Nothing, really.
Just feel like smoking.
Just get to the point and tell me what's in your heart.
The job as a security guard, you know...
I've agreed to do that.
As in,
We'd go to your friend tomorrow.
I'd apologise to him, and you can talk about the job.
But tell him I won't have my hair cut.
Are you enlisting in the army that you'd have your hair cut?
Don't worry; I'll talk to him.
May --
May I sleep?
Sure.
Go to sleep.
She won't come by herself,
You could've climbed up the stairs and asked her.
Well, she'd only lie to me.
Who taught her to lie?
Only girls who conceal their heart's secrets from their mothers
Go to see psychiatrists.
Brilliant. That was rather well put.
But even in this is an insult to you.
Just think
Why the daughter is concealing her heart's secrets from her mother.
There seems to be a communication gap.
I mean,
She fears
That you'd tell me whatever she told you.
Who else could I tell?
Why do you even need to tell anyone?
Listen to her, and tell me your decision.
Just what to do.
So would you do
As I say?
Of course, I will.
But think over your decision carefully before telling me.
May I compliment you?
Why, right now.
You're the watermelon that's red on the inside.
-Hey!
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
So you're sleeping in my room today?
No?
You aren't afraid, are you?
Not at all?
I'm in no mood to talk.
I'm very sleepy.
You'd have to listen to one thing.
Done.
You'd have to reply, too.
I'm always ready with my reply.
Just ask.
Tell me,
What do I have to do to show you
That would make you believe that I don't love Afzal?
What are your options?
You'd give me the options, right?
Even if you ask me to die,
I'd rather die.
Hey!
So you hate him so much!
I don't hate him.
But I don't love him.
You still don't believe it?
Pray tell,
Don't you have options either?
I do have an option.
It'd shock you if you heard it.
It's even possible that you may kill me, standing right here.
I promise you,
I'd do whatever you ask me to.
Put killing aside; I wouldn't even touch you.
May I say it?
Yes.
Say it.
It may kill you to hear it.
Put a sock in it!
My name's Farah Ibrahim.
I'm made of the same mettle as the mighty boulders.
Allow me, then,
I'd marry Afzal.
Good morning!
Oh!
Good morning.
I've brought bed tea for you.
You'd get it for free from now on.
Where's Babu Hamid?
Babu Hamid's
Gone to get
Some milk and tea leaves.
Isn't this
Too much of a formality?
I'd have to have the second cup now.
So, I thought I'd have it here.
It'd give you company, too.
Right...
Sit.
What's your wife's name?
Wife?
Haven't you gotten married yet?
No.
I got it.
What do you get?
You're having an affair.
Innit?
No, I don't.
Oh, shoot!
You're lying to Yasmin?
You're hiding it from me, right?
I don't lie.
Or, I lie to those I fear.
So you fear someone, too!
Splendid.
Who would that be?
Arifa.
My sister...
Molvi Subhanallah.
My Dad...
Why didn't you name your Mam?
I don't lie to Mum.
If I'm about to lie, I quieten.
What've you come to Karachi for?
No idea.
But why are you asking?
Nothing, really.
Just a pastime.
Do you know how to read palms?
I do.
I can find out one's love line quickly!
Show me your hand.
No --
I don't believe in these things.
Dad starts saying 'No power but God's' if he sees it.
Such childish talk!
Is Dad around, watching?
The thing is,
I don't like it either.
Is it that you don't like it, or do you feel that you'd get caught if you showed me your hand?
There's a line of love on my palm.
It's very long.
But I don't know where it leads.
Just show me the line.
I'll show it the way.
Good joke.
Nice tea.
Thank you.
Mam has her fanciful suspicions about you.
Oh?
What kind of suspicions?
She thinks you're married,
Or you've got a girl after you.
But it isn't quite possible, really...
You're educated,
You look lush, too.
Surely, a couple of lasses would be ready to die for you.
Someone's called me 'educated' for the first time!
You look like a hoodlum,
That's why everyone must think you're not.
But you just said I look lush?
It is, yes,
But it's one like a hoodlum's.
When you beat Wali, I thought you're an ace at it.
I beat Wali for you, and you're calling me a hoodlum?
Why did you beat him for me?
Who am I to you?
Say it straight, 'Yasmin, I'd lost my heart to you',
'So, I didn't like it that a hoodlum like Wali should boss over you'.
You're a Molvi's son,
At least be honest.
Well, now, it's better if you don't be honest.
A tenant falling in love with the landlord's daughter is a classic.
I don't even believe in such things.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital