Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
What are you doing?
Did you see his speed?
Then play accordingly!
Umpire Sir!
Call from my family!
Hello --
Misbah hit two sixes?
The wretch who couldn't hit a six on a hundred balls scored two sixes on two balls?
India will win this. India will win.
Raise the stakes.
I'm losing 7,000 elsewhere.
Alright, I'll pay you 7,000.
Bugger!
One minute!
Mate... Make it 8,000, will you?
It'll save you two and earn me one.
I'm facing a loss elsewhere.
I won't!
Come here! Here!
No, back -- go back -- there
Alright, I'll pay you 8,500.
But you're paying me 5,000 if we lose this one.
He's off the team after this.
The bugger blackmails on the crease!
Saw that?
Looks like we've lost it, Captain!
Shut up!
Saw that?
Go and get 10,000 from Babur.
The match closes with the next ball.
We've won, Captain!
No, it's that wretch who's won.
We're just getting 1,500 bucks.
God is the greatest
Farah!
Here she comes.
Peace be upon you
-God protect you from the evil eye. God be praised.
You don't know how long he's been gloomy
Look at him gladden at the very sight of you!
I'll -- be back.
Please don't leave without fixing the date.
Let your father come
I'll say it plainly:
I'll have dinner only when you fix the date.
And you better say something too.
Last time, you remained quiet, and dad said he'd think on it.
No, he's not a dosser
Having found no job after completing his BA
He spends some time with the lads.
One of them must be a loafer
Besmirching his reputation as well.
You know Molvi Sahab only too well
If he isn't back before dusk, he calls him a sinner.
Don't talk about Beenish
She'd said to me explicitly on the day of Eid,
'Aunt, I accept, but he does not'.
Uh -- no, Kulsoom --
Why won't he accept?
He must be teasing her for fun.
No, no, no -- Kulsoom, he's 25, not 28.
In fact, he's 25 just because Molvi Sahab wrote it a year older to get him admitted to school.
Here.
24,000 in all.
That makes for a total of
98,000.
Where do you get so much money from?
What do you mean?
I work hard; I earn it.
You're lying.
If you consider it a lie too, dad is going to rush to the police station with his rants about religious values!
He'll file a complaint against me.
You're into gambling, aren't you?
What?
Is it even possible?
Molvi Subhanallah's son is into gambling?
You're not a sister
You're a sworn enemy.
What if dad gets to know?
It's a matter of two days
I'll deposit it in a bank once I open an account.
Alright, I'll keep it.
But please
Tell me one day about your job.
You're doubting me again?
I'm not doubting you.
All I want is that if dad gives his judgement on this matter, I can say firmly,
'This is my brother's hard-earned money'.
Don't talk about him.
He even thinks it's unlawful to deposit money at a bank.
Keep it inside, quick.
If mum gets to know, she'll start on it.
This is your room.
Have a look and let me know if you need anything.
Last time, I had stayed in the room upstairs...
This is the best room in the house.
As the date is fixed, you rise in status.
But...
But what?
You don't like it?
The room's alright, but...
I would often catch a glimpse of her from the room upstairs.
Shall I arrange a meeting?
Is it possible?
She's said it herself this time
Before dad comes back, you are invited to meet her on the terrace.
When does he come back?
Ask when you're invited to meet her.
-When?
9 o'clock sharp.
Dad comes back at 10.
You've got 40 minutes.
Mind if I share a few precautional musings about the meeting?
Please.
Talk from afar.
And don't tell her how many cars and châteaux you have
Just tell her how much you love her.
That I will.
If she asks something, give a thoughtful answer.
Sure.
And even if she comes close, don't place your hand on her shoulder or hand!
I won't, but please tell me - this espousal has her acceptance, doesn't it?
Did you see her cheeks redden at the sight of you?
Redden --?
-I did!
This means she's very happy.
But the last time when I tried to talk to her
She had a go at me -- so to speak.
You were a stranger then
She only knew you were the son of a friend of her father's.
Father has many friends, and they have many sons.
She doesn't talk to all of them.
Now I got it.
When the date is decided upon
Place your hand on hers
Then she won't push you away.
Did you say it?
I did.
What did he say?
He said he'd not place his hand on your shoulder or hand.
What?
Did he intend to?
No.
I just forbade him as a precaution.
Mum says that nothing is written when it comes to the intentions of men.
Who knows - he might have reached for your hand the moment you started talking.
That's why I forbade him from committing this mistake.
That's fine.
I've told him to meet you at 9 o'clock.
I'd said 9.30.
Dad said he'd be back at 10.
If, perchance, he arrived at 9.30?
Fine.
Alright then.
Why do you want to meet him though?
Is there any good reason?
It may just help me someday.
I'll tell you everything once I come down from the terrace.
And I pray that all of them will be of use to you someday!
Alright. I'll be with mum and aunt, and you go up as soon as the clock strikes 9.
Okay?
Ahh... Let my past remain ensepulchred beneath dust.
For my past is but obloquy to me.
Great!
-Great!
Reified by yearning, meed for my endeavours
Is nothing but inglorious woe?
Don't chronicle my love before me
Instead, let me speak out the fortitude of my love.
Excellent!
-Well said!
And that ebrious gaze that abandoned me
I was never one to admire it;
The very tresses, gaze, cheeks, and form
I can find if so I desire -
Excellent!
-Great!
The lilies destined to blossom for them
Can blossom too where their gaze can't reach them.
Oh great!
-That's great!
Very well said!
-That's the real deal!
You sound like a man today!
Forget the harpy and marry someone better!
And rent a house in front of hers.
Show her you're a man!
Then watch her file for divorce within months!
It seems you've called her again.
Got scolded again?
No mate...
Disconnected at the sound of my voice,
Then answered when I tried again,
And said, 'Who is it'?
I said, 'I'm Sajid'.
And she said, 'Sajid who'?
Do you understand what it means?
It means skive off, chap.
'Leave me alone'!
That's what it means.
One of these days I'll curse you.
I'll say, 'May you be accursed with such adoration'!
It scares me the way you keep on laughing to yourself.
Why?
Just --
She writes to you twice a week, right?
What if she forgets to for one week?
As if that's possible!
She's not like your dear Chanda;
She'd die without me.
Do you know what she's written this time?
You received her letter?
You must have - today's Saturday, after all!
Read it out to us.
Hearing her words,
It feels as if one Chanda might've killed all affection
A second Chanda might as well resurrect it.
Her name's not Chanda.
So tell us her name today.
I have great respect for her.
I'll mention her honourably.
I will, someday.
Listen to her words first.
Man was born for his compassion towards the suffering
For there was no shortage of beings for subservience alone.
There was no shortage of divine spirits and angels to serve God.
Why was man born?
Man was born for the sake of the pains he goes through and his deeds of compassion.
That is why the rights of servants --
Oh --
God, I beg You to grant me the best of Your favours.
May you have a long life, son.
Dear Afzal,
She always addresses you as 'Dear Afzal'!
Shut up! Go on, mate.
How are you?
Everything good?
I see the best in you whenever I see you.
Always fresh!
Where do you meet?
That I will not tell.
Just keep on reading. Don't stop to answer his questions.
You stay with me for but a few minutes,
Eager every second of it to leave.
When will that time come when you will be before my eyes all night,
And I, like a devotee, shall relish every moment of my deity's presence?
When will it be, Afzal? And how?
Seeing you vivifies me
And when you vanish from my sight, it is as if the grim reaper has struck me.
I'd die without you.
That's it?
That's it.
For my sake, at least tell me her name.
Nope. That I won't tell.
You and your 'I won't tell'.
Mehtab?
Yes?
Let's sit down, shall we?
Where should I sit?
Why, right here, with me.
If you want to ask something
Or say something, please do.
All I want to say --
You're very beautiful.
That's it?
Uh -- No...
When you softly called out, 'Mehtab',
I swear I nearly died at that moment.
Your voice is fatal.
Fatal?
Uh -- I mean -- in a sweet manner...
It touches my heart.
Where in Karachi do you live?
Clifton, Block 2.
Wow...
Your house must be quite the chateau.
Ye -- No.
It's a small one.
How many cars do you own?
Just -- just the one parked here.
As in... You're going through hard times?
No -- It's nothing like that.
Nothing like 'hard times' in my life.
Then why aren't you telling me?
You have five cars.
You own four houses -
Two in Karachi, and two in Larkana.
The thing is -- Lubna had warned against talking about houses and cars with you.
You'd be angry.
Monseigneur's here.
Peace be upon you, Dad.
And upon you, peace.
Aunt Shugufta and Mehtab are here.
Oh?
Aunt said she'd leave only after the date is decided.
Alright, I will decide on it.
But tell me - is it acceptable to her?
I think so...
I want to study further.
Why not?
Even after I'm married.
I'm pursuing a Masters in Economics.
And will pursue my MPhil. in London.
Why?
What do you mean?
What's wrong?
And most importantly:
I want to get a job that's as glorious as it is grandiose!
My wife will work?
No way.
Everyone will insult me.
Who?
Friends -- relatives -- all of them...
And in all honesty, you'd hardly have the time.
You'll have to take care of me.
I'm so childlike.
I'll need you all the time.
So -- you won't work?
I don't need to work.
I have some 200 - 220 million in my account already.
I don't even know how much I spend per year,
But the balance just refuses to come down.
You know why?
Why?
Just the earnings from land revenues amount to 20 million.
What will we do after marriage, then?
Have a jolly good time, what else?
What happened?
Was it something I said?
You know, when I was young --
Leave my hand!
I despise people like you
Who are in this world just to 'have a jolly good time'.
Everything was fine until now.
Then she started talking about her education.
She said she'd be going to London to pursue her MPhil after marriage.
Stupid, isn't it?
London is best for honeymoon, isn't it?
Lu -- Lubna!
What time is it?
It's 10.
Call Safiya
And tell her the match is not fit.
What do you mean?
It means that Molvi Subhanallah won't allow
The wife to be cared for on money earned through gambling.
Gambling?
He's won 24,500 today,
And 16,000 of them the wretch had won in the match that Pakistan had lost.
Oh God!
I've heard he even smokes weed when he gets the chance.
And... Some girl writes letters to him.
I don't know who she is
But, sitting with his friends,
He reads her lettes out to them.
You're starting to question yourself, aren't you?
The same can be said of me.
When I teach little kids these days,
It feels as if
They're staring at me,
And asking, 'Whose father are you'?
'And look at what you talk about'.
Even the prayers lack that spirit
Every moment, a fear stings at me as I step out of the Mosque...
That the police
May be at the doorstep holding that scoundrel by the collar.
Tell him to leave this place!
For the righteous and the sinful cannot live together.
Is it only an accusation
Or do you have proof of it as well?
I'm not accepting it without evidence.
I have brought reliable information.
One of these days, you were struck with calamity at 'information'.
You'd even told me not to repeat it unless proven true.
Present evidence if you have,
Else in this matter of crime and punishment, your word cannot be taken for the truth.
And if you have evidence,
I swear by you
I would hit him with my shoes a hundred times.
I'll order him firmly to leave this place,
For the righteous and the sinful cannot live together.
I don't accept!
Tell dad I'm not marrying Mehtab Chawla.
You should've said this earlier.
Now they've gathered to decide the date.
It's not the end of the world!
Go and whisper into his ears; tell him --
-- That I don't accept.
He'll get up instantly.
You're strange.
You were one to enjoy the feast,
What has happened to you the moment you've swallowed what you bit?
I can't swallow this one, that's it!
Can't do anything now.
For my sake
Tell mum. I'll handle the rest.
Alright, I'll tell her.
Yes, please do.
What if he died when he heard it?
There's a possibility he might...
Go!
Don't lie to me.
You won 8000 in the local match, and 16000 when Pakistan lost.
What?
I swea--
Yes, I swear.
You're lying again.
Dad knows everything.
Mentioned all of it and said that the righteous and the sinful cannot live together.
Does Mum believe it?
Don't talk about her; I believe it.
And I know these 98000 you kept with me - all of it you made through gambling.
And who's this girl who writes letters to you?
Girl?
Did you say it?
Yes.
Tell me how it went. Whom did you speak to?
Mum.
Great! Then?
I know.
Mum would've said it flatly -
'Leave it, Ibrahim, she doesn't accept it'.
Isn't it?
It isn't.
Mum stuffed this sweet into my mouth the moment she heard it.
Gave me this plate of sweets, and said, 'These are for her'.
The 15th of December is the big day.
Who is it?
It's me, Afzal.
Had your dinner?
Yes.
Go and sleep then.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
May you live long.
Is someone coming, or will you go on your own?
Who's coming? I'll go myself.
Did he come?
Yes.
I figured as much.
I'll go and rouse him.
He can drop you.
Leave it be.
Shame on he who calls himself a believer,
Who drops another at the Mosque and leaves.
When he wakes up, tell him
I'd like to meet him before noon.
And remember, if you're listening
Today's meeting will be more important than your conventicles!
I love somebody else.
What?
Did you hear that?
Lightning will strike him when he'd hear this.
I've come to know
He'll be staying here to celebrate.
And if he'll stay,
I'll meet him again tonight.
And what do you intend to do?
What else would I do?
With two teardrops, I'll say,
'I'm sorry, Mehtab',
'But it's important'
'That you know the truth before our marriage'.
'Before our marriage'?
'If someone else told you later on, it'd hurt you far more'.
Honestly, what is it?
'I love somebody else'.
'Truly'.
'I've loved him since our schooldays'.
'We used to write letters to each other',
'But now, we talk over the phone for hours'.
'We'd sworn oaths',
'Made promises',
'To live and die together'.
'But what good is it now'?
'Now I'm getting married off to you'.
'I have to be yours'.
A fib.
-Might as well be!
But he will take it for the truth.
This time, he'd die for real
The moment he'd hear this.
He won't die.
He'd much rather kill his dreams
And say as he leaves,
'I'm not marrying this girl'.
Great.
As if it's that easy.
Is Dad going to stay quiet?
He'll hurl abuses at them?
-No.
He'll ask his Mum why he's rejected.
Then his Mum will ask him, 'What happened so suddenly'?
'You've changed after a second meeting'.
Don't worry.
He'll change.
Halt!
What are you doing?
Oh! It's you, Molvi Sahab.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
This man 'ere's a thief.
Stole a mobile and was trying to get away.
Round him up and get him in the car.
You're going to the Mosque?
Yes.
Shall I drop you?
No --
I'll go on my own. Please, do your duty.
With peace.
Have some tea.
Or you'll catch a cold.
Thanks.
Dad's left?
He's left.
Why are you following me?
Just a second.
You're into gambling, aren't you?
And hand over all the money you win to me.
[Call to prayer]
These pennies will, one day, become serpents and scorpions.
They sting Dad today; they might as well sting you tomorrow.
Leave it be.
It's my hard-earned money.
You smoke weed.
A lie!
God forgive!
Alright, give me the keys to your cupboard.
What's in the cupboard?
Her letters
That you read out to your friends.
Gambling, weed, her letters...
Dad knows about it all.
You should be ashamed of yourself, Afzal.
If she writes letters to you, you read them out to your friends?
Like a pallbearer of her honour.
Take this tea back,
And leave.
Don't accuse me like Dad does.
Say it now that it's all false. [Swear to me]
Who's she?
I won't tell you her name.
I've sworn to her.
And what about Beenish?
Beenish?
Aunt Sofya's daughter?
What's her problem now?
Mum's decided to get you married to her.
Ohh God --
What 'Ohh'? She's coming here in a few days.
Beenish is coming too?
Perhaps.
Let them come.
Let her come too?
I'll give her a befitting reply
She won't even turn to look at me again.
As if she was going to, anyhow.
You don't even need to give her a 'befitting reply'.
Shatter her dreams quietly.
Don't slam it into the ground, roaring,
'I've shattered them'!
Why not just say not to her?
Tell her
That she's only got wanton rampage waiting for her.
Anyway, who's she?
Don't tell me her name, just where she's from.
Not far away.
In fact, this city itself.
She must be beautiful.
Very.
Fairy-like.
She's happy with you?
Why not?
She must know that you
Smoke weed, gamble,
And read out her letters to friends?
See?
You're my sister for just a few moments,
Until Dad starts speaking from your mouth.
You should remember, too, Afzal,
You're Molvi Subhanallah's son.
Go to sleep early.
Dad wants to meet you before noon.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital