Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
You're not sleeping, Molvi Sahab.
You're just pretending.
I took the pill too.
But I couldn't fall asleep.
You took the pill a tad late,
Which is why you'd
Fall asleep a tad late.
The deal's no more now.
I'd even asked him
Not to bring his parents here.
But I don't know why
He brought you here
Without telling me or asking me about it!
I know
A moment's daftness brought me here.
But I'd never thought I'd call you here and decline.
And I swear by God, I don't even know your Afzal well enough!
No.
I'm not being demure.
It is with regret that I have to say this,
But no such engagement will take place here
That you are so euphoric about.
It's all because of him!
He's a first rate fraudster.
The move he's played
Even after everything was decided
Is one I'll never forgive him for!
Forget getting engaged to him,
I don't even want to see his face!
There!
Your Afzal is here!
Go and welcome him, then.
I'm feeling sleepy.
People look good when they speak the truth.
But you're one
I feel affection for even as you lie.
Get some sleep, Molvi Sahab.
It's better for his health.
By the way, the lassie's still awake.
She'll take care of everything.
He'd be a bit drenched, that's all.
Take off your coat.
Take off your shoes.
Go to bed if you've had your dinner.
Otherwise, take something from the fridge.
Has Dad retired?
It's 1.30 a.m.
Do you think he'd be awake?
Just --
Check for once.
Why?
If I go to bed without talking to him,
Neither of us would be able to fall asleep.
Talk to me!
Relieve yourself of the burden of whatever truth or lie you want to tell!
I'll only talk to Dad.
Then hold it until the morning.
You'd be kicked out of the house if you say something that makes things worse.
Can you see the downpour outside?
Alright.
I'll sit here until daybreak.
Have you no shame?
Is not one imbroglio enough for you?
You have no idea how you've wracked our hearts!
I do.
Then stay quiet until Dad says something,
Else, you'd get killed for sure!
I've been killed already...
Will Dad kill me again?
He's fine now.
His blood pressure is normal again.
He's taken his medicines and is about to go to bed.
You'd better be normal again.
Over here, everyone has a rather weak memory.
We forget today's news by tomorrow.
Tomorrow, even Dad would have forgotten what happened today.
Did he mention me when saying anything?
He mentioned God and said something.
Perhaps he was praying?
He didn't even get angry with me?
Not at all.
Mum would be cursing me.
She was just concerned about Dad.
Then why wasn't I allowed to see Dad?
Because of Dad.
I've heard
He used to get scared by ghosts when he was young.
He's affrighted.
His blood pressure didn't shoot up today,
It plummeted.
The doctor said this happens only
When one is utterly shocked.
He was asking what had happened.
What could Mum say?
After all, she can't say that the father's afraid of his daughter!
Stop it, Lubna.
Don't show yourself before Dad for a few days.
Why not?
Dad's going through a memory loss.
His memory may come back at the sight of you.
Okay?
Good night.
Wait, Lubna.
I can't wait.
Mum's said it firmly,
'Whoever stays with Farah shall be held responsible for his own words and deeds'!
Sit down.
Sit.
Orders,
Sir?
Please ask Arifa
To go to her room.
Go, my dear.
He's getting embarrassed in your presence.
What are your orders for your Mum?
She's eager to come here too.
There's nothing to conceal from Mum.
I just feel embarrassed before my sister.
Come here, Ruqaiyya!
You've been granted permission!
So it's been decided that he'd sit and talk,
And we'd listen.
Holding back would make no difference,
And if necessary, we'd speak too.
Isn't it
My dear,
May we
Speak sometimes, too, or
Is it that only you'd speak
And we'd listen?
I know I've wronged both of you.
It would've been more proper that you'd speak
And I'd listen.
But please -- listen to just one thing I have to say.
And say everything that you want to.
Go on.
I confess
That I'd known she'd refuse in front of everyone.
Regardless, I took you there.
Splendid, my son.
We're delighted to know you'd drag us
To drown where the waters are deep.
I've drowned too, Mum.
This is why I'm saying to you
That I want to come ashore.
Alright.
Continue.
I wanted the answer to a question.
Do I have the right to love a girl
Who doesn't even know me well?
Who, then, is the one who writes you letters?
Forget the one who writes letters, Dad.
Please, answer my question.
Hear the answer from me:
The perfidious have no right to fancy anyone here or there.
You've transgressed every limit of shame and morality.
I'm Molvi Subhanallah's son, Mum.
I can neither go back on my word, nor two-time anyone.
I'd just request you
To allow me to get my answer from Dad.
I think that to love such a girl is not comme il faut.
This
Would be like trespassing on her modesty.
What kind of a trespass, Dad?
Neither have I said anything to her nor asserted my right to love her.
Then why did you take us there?
Why do you go to the Mosque?
Do you go there out of love for Him,
Or do your job for the neighbourhood?
Oh God!
This blighter's become a blasphemer!
-Shut up, Ruqaiyya!
Let me talk.
No, my son.
I don't do a job.
I love Him.
Have you ever talked to Him?
Have you ever met Him?
-If only one person alone were dear to Him, one would meet...
And then,
He asks us to love Him.
And what if one does not?
He loves him regardless, doesn't he?
There are thousands in the world who neither believe in nor love Him.
Does He not love them all, regardless?
So?
I've started down God's path, Dad.
I will keep on loving
Whether she does or not.
Go on, my good man.
Keep on loving.
Let me know what I can do for you.
Allow me --
Allow as in,
Give it in writing that such invisible love of yours for any girl
Is justified?
Not at all.
I'm leaving Hyderabad.
Where to?
Karachi.
Has your spiritual guide asked that you should
Start this sermon of love there?
I'm going to try out my luck, Dad.
Then try your luck, my dear,
Don't try our endurance.
Set for us only such little trials as this,
And take us along to a girl's house,
We'd go with you,
Hear a refusal,
Come back,
And fall asleep after taking sleeping pills.
Today, too, we have taken sleeping pills.
But the two of us couldn't sleep.
Do you know why?
You'd not come home.
Now that you're here,
You'll see
How well the pill works!
Get up, Ruqaiyya.
Before he talks about parting again,
And wracks my heart with grief,
We should better leave.
I'm leaving, Dad.
You blighter!
You'd leave Hyderabad for the one who doesn't love you,
And you'd leave those who love you
In Hyderabad?
This habit of yours isn't good, Ruqaiyya.
You whack him the moment
Something rubs you the wrong way.
I had a few opportunities like this, too,
But I did not raise my hand.
And
What good is striking him, Ruqaiyya Begum,
Who'd strike a fatal blow to us with his separation?
Come.
Get some sleep.
Otherwise,
It'll prove the chemist wrong.
He was saying
The pill would
Get you drowsy within 15 minutes.
Come.
Are you going barmy?
You humiliate and give sorrow,
And shatter hearts,
And then stay awake?
I'm going to the University.
You have five minutes if you want to come.
Get your bag and come with me.
Give me the five minutes
That you have.
What do you mean?
Sit by me.
Here.
I did what was right, didn't I?
Yes, you did exactly what was right,
How dare he bring his parents here,
And think you'd get engaged to him?
Then why is Dad furious?
And why is Mum not talking to me?
It's hit them a bit hard.
They got to know the real story
When the engagement got cancelled.
You're telling the truth, aren't you?
I swear by you, I am.
Initially, I was a bit angry with you,
Then, I thought over it and felt
That that's what you should've done.
He shocked us all.
When we'd clearly stopped him,
Told him not to come,
He showed up regardless!
And why did he bring his parents and Arifa along?
The blighter would've thought
'The girl's parents have agreed'.
'How about attempting an engagement'?
And you thought all along he'd be virtuous and irreproachable, being a Molvi's son.
Well,
His previous reputation wasn't exactly good either.
I still thought
He's been ousted from his job and in need of one,
And he's Arifa's brother,
So,
He'd earn some being of help to us.
I will give him his money anyhow.
In all honesty, I'd shove it in his face!
But, Lubna,
I pity that girl
With whom he's got an exchange of letters going on.
The poor lass.
Her heart would be struck with woe if she found out!
If I ever came across her,
I'd narrate each of Monsieur Afzal's glorious adventures!
Girls are raving mad.
Look at the kind they fall for!
By the way,
Why haven't you slept all night?
I was delighted!
Even more so because I didn't do anything stupid this time!
Finished him off in a flash!
Let's go to the University, then, shall we?
Why are you sitting?
Get in the car.
I'm coming in two minutes!
God forgive, Molvi Sahab,
Last night's sleeping pill struck more like a pellet.
You even missed your morning prayers!
Why do tough times always make you miss your morning prayers?
Go and give it to him.
Give the blighter whatever he wants in his room.
I'd rather not glimpse him.
What was I saying?
You were talking about missing my morning prayers.
Right,
What am I remembering!
Her name was 'Fajr' [daybreak] too, wasn't it?
Your aunt's daughter.
You also 'missed' her!
Yes.
If I see her somewhere,
She calls me 'brother'.
What else can she do now?
And what else can you do now?
When the 'daybreak' is your beloved,
You don't compensate for 'missing' it!
Don't take refuge behind your son
And cast these aspersions on me, Ruqaiyya Begum!
The son no longer has a place in my heart, Molvi Sahab.
I've locked all motherly affection in a casket.
Didn't you see
How I didn't even call him for breakfast?
He must be saying, 'I'll have breakfast with Dad'.
Make it clear to him:
'You shall not have such good fortune'.
He's not in his room, Mum.
Where's he gone?
No idea.
It kills me to hear this!
He's left, Molvi Sahab!
Molvi Sahab, he's left us!
The blighter has taken after his father!
He does exactly as he says!
What are you looking at, sitting like this?
Go!
Bring him back, Molvi Sahab,
Bring him back!
Or else I'm gone.
Get a grip on yourself, Ruqaiyya.
He's not going anywhere.
Call him.
You can have me promise it, Molvi Sahab.
I won't slap him.
Would you look at that, Lubna!
He's standing in the way smoking cigarettes!
Know what, he'd be smoking cigarettes standing in the way like this everyday!
You don't know me, then.
If I saw him again,
You'll see what I make of him!
Hello?
Yes, where are you?
You're here, aren't you?
In Hyderabad?
Yes, Mum,
I'm here.
I'm with Timmy
Going to apply for a job.
Why didn't you have your breakfast, then?
I will have my breakfast.
When your anger wanes,
I'll have breakfast with Dad.
There!
Has your Dad forbidden you?
You have forbidden me.
I'd heard it.
Alright,
Now don't blabber on like that.
Disconnect now,
Come back quickly,
And have your lunch with Dad.
Yes, Mum.
The blighter's here
Stravaiging about with his dosser friends.
Right, now, what do you want to do?
Mate,
I want to become a great man.
You think I can make you a great man?
You bugger!
What are you talking about and with whom!
I'm honest, Timmy.
There's one way, mate.
Tell your Oul Fella and have your name changed
To 'Great Man'.
Sajid and I will have the entire neighbourhood remember it.
Everyone would say at your very sight,
'Great Man' is coming.
I'm talking about a real great man.
At the sight of whom, you'd say,
'That's Afzal',
And the people say, 'Behold'!
'He's a great man'!
Won't you go to the office today?
I won't for a few more days.
I'd called to ask.
Everything's going on fine.
It's better that you talk to her and ask her
Why she did this instead of suffering quietly like this.
I understand her problem.
She'd have an answer.
Then what's your problem?
Think about how much it would pain me to see you on the rack like this!
Honestly, Irsa,
Has such a moment ever befallen me that you felt
I cannot look someone in the eye and talk straight?
Never?
But why do I feel that
I wouldn't be able to meet his gaze if he ever showed up before me?
Why does my heart say that he's a virtuous man,
He is nothing in his status,
But he has the modest and honourable character of a gentleman.
If he's thought about Farah,
He's thought only about Farah.
Not for once has he thought about my mill or bank balance.
He's one of them, Irsa,
Who'd sell their hide to earn enough to feed their wife.
My father used to say
That to find a gentleman from among men
Is like finding from a heap of watermelons one
That's red on the inside.
Have some more.
Hey!
Leave that be.
Here.
Have a warm one.
That's enough. I won't have so much.
Why not?
You'll get a fever from the rains if you stay griefstricken like this!
Eat as much as you like.
Show, by eating, that you don't care the slightest
About one who doesn't care about you!
Get a grip on your grief.
Don't fear it.
What are you talking about?
I'm saying big words, isn't it?
Yes...
Do you know
What one wants to achieve by giving someone sorrow?
Ask what one wants!
What?
One wants you to be tormented,
Weep,
Wail and tell that you can't take so much grief.
But you are Molvi Subhanallah's son.
Neither will you be tormented,
Nor weep,
Nor wail to show anyone your grief.
Promise me.
Promise me, won't you?
I can't promise you.
The thing is
I don't quite come up to your expectations.
When grief torments me, I cry sometimes too.
Let it never be known that you are tormented
Even as the torment kills you.
I promise.
She's the one who wrote him the letters, Mum.
Farah Ibrahim.
He wasn't there in the morning.
So you want to see him there?
Yes.
I want that he should show up once more.
You'll see,
I'll give him a right thrashing!
Enough, Farah.
He's Arifa's brother.
What if he's Arifa's brother?
Every cad has an honourable sister.
The poor lass.
She's my friend, Farah.
And only I know how distressed she must be after that day.
I have all my sympathies for her,
But I can't help it.
What happened?
No idea. I'll go and check.
Look over there.
What's there?
This is the same ground, isn't it,
Where he'd sit with his lunch box?
So what?
Why are we talking about him?
We're not talking about him, Farah.
His mention's just coming up.
Will it get moving again or remain here?
Give me two minutes. There's a problem with the wiring; I'll fix it.
Offer your prayers
If there's someone's mausoleum here.
It does feel, indeed,
As if it's someone's mausoleum there.
Over there,
That's where the cricket ball had hit his lunch box,
And his piece of bread flung out of his hand.
There's a mausoleum over there,
Where he's interred his heart.
You've started smoking?
I'm telling Molvi Sahab!
Alladio!
Hey, Alladio!
Hey!
You --
Listen!
Stop!
C'mon, Rashid --
Wait, Rashid.
Do you have the slightest shame?
Farah, let's go --
Hey! Get off!
Let me see who's the boss!
Now that your engagement plan failed,
You stand in my way to get even?
You're playing the lover in front of everyone?
Want to besmirch my reputation?
You're Molvi Subhanallah's son,
So I thought you'd not step out of the house for days after all the insult that day.
You'd drown in shame,
Or leave Hyderabad to hide your disgraceful self!
But you turned out so brazen!
Roaming around in the streets like this!
You consider the humiliation your exploit?
Enough, Farah!
Le's go --
-Hey!
Put a sock in it!
Look at him!
Staring right back!
Come, Afzal.
-No.
Wait.
I'm saying this for the last time:
If I see you around one more time,
No one in Hyderabad will ever see you again!
-Farah!
I'm coming!
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital