Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
10,000 will be enough to provide both of them with food,
And we'd be making a profit of 10,000!
He was up to his trickery, offering the old 8,000.
I said, 'Watch who you're talking to'!
And he,
The one from Hyderabad,
I gave him a right scolding.
I even said, 'You have a bad reputation in Mam's eyes'!
'Shut your gob'!
Is he married?
Doesn't seem so, judging by his words,
Although someone his age should get married.
I'd seen him yesterday.
He does look lush.
What's it to us if he looks lush?
He's very insolent, by the way.
Took him two days to start a slanging match!
The way he addresses me with a simple 'you'!
How else should he address you?
Hey!
I'm his landlady,
At the very least he should say 'Madam' or 'Lady'!
It appears he's from a good family.
I'll ask him this one, too.
What will you ask?
The same - 'Do you come from a good family, or is it just Mam who thinks so'?
Don't you dare ask him anything like this!
Well, I can ask Babu Hamid about this too.
But what have we to do with his family?
As long as he quietly enjoys his food and pays us the money, and keeps fearing God!
Can one's face ever tell one about one's family?
It doesn't, does it?
Will they
Be serving us potatoes and lentils everyday?
No.
We'll be served chicken on Sundays.
Enough with it, Salim,
Enough with it!
Enough with what?
Sit down.
-How many times will you ask me?
It's Saturday today.
-You already know everything!
Tell me everything!
Tell me!
Be honest with me,
Did he ever touch you?
Never!
He used to say, 'Touching besmirches love'.
Oh?
Was he the son of a saint?
And you're praising him before me!
The blighter's here.
Tell her
That it's our personal affair.
She'd better not poke her nose in our affairs!
Yes, sir?
Why is your husband beating you?
Look, sir,
It is our personal affair.
No --
It no longer remains your personal affair when you scream so loudly.
Who are you?
I --
Live just across here
With Babu Hamid.
Please, leave,
And take it that the fault lies with me.
Listen, sir!
Yes?
Have you come from Hyderabad?
Is your name Afzal?
It is.
Hey!
What are you doing, Timmy?
Let go!
Where's he gone?
Who?
Afzal.
He played his last match with you.
Match, as in, gambling.
For 100,000, no less.
Where'd he go after that?
Karachi.
Where in Karachi?
I don't know.
Press harder!
-Timmy, mate, I seriously don't know what happened next!
I'd dropped him at the station, that's it!
I'd even said, 'Don't go'!
But he doesn't listen to anyone, now, does he?
Let him go.
He must call you sometimes.
His phone's switched off.
He must've gotten a new number.
Go and ask his family, will you?
He must be calling them sometime!
He doesn't.
Molvi Sahab came to me.
He was just asking how everything was going,
But, as he left, he said,
'Does Afzal talk to you'?
I said, 'Not at all'.
'His number's switched off'.
He was a bit dispirited to hear this
And said, 'Yes, his number's switched off'...
Go, now.
If you get in touch with him, if he calls... Just let us know, okay?
I will, surely.
I'll tell you that instant.
Why aren't you eating anything?
I will if I learn.
Learn what?
Please, go on.
I'm watching and learning
How one can swallow a bite like this.
Do you actually eat it, or do you just put up a pretence for me?
I'll try, too, today.
If you keep on trying,
I'll have to call the doctor.
And he charges additional fees for coming here.
The rest is up to you.
I'd gone to Karachi two years ago.
I don't even remember if that blasted sea is where it used to be,
Or has it, too, skedaddled...
So what's the big deal in going to Karachi?
We can go again.
But
Where will we look for him?
The city's as large as a country.
Is it too big for a mother's heart?
I can find my son with eyes both shut, Molvi Sahab.
Alright, then.
Make ready to leave.
We can depart
Any one of these days you pick.
But remember,
A defeated mother's son
Can never triumph himself.
Call Arifa and ask her
To send a picture of him.
Right,
What would you do with the picture?
Hey!
What would I do with it?
But we can ask for a picture and help them.
How?
We'll run an advertisement on TV.
That --
'A 32-year-old has run away from home, embarrassed'.
We'll have Arifa's voiceover with it.
She'll be saying with a melancholic voice,
'Come home, dear brother',
'Everyone's distressed',
'Dad's quietened up',
'Mum's not eating anything in her sorrow'.
You'll see,
He'll come back running!
What if he actually came?
So what?
He may come back with the Lord's blessings,
Stay at home,
And take care of his Mum and Dad.
Where will you be pursuing your MPhil from?
You can't from Hyderabad.
How does that even relate
To me pursuing my MPhil?
When I'd said
That I'm not going to London,
What does it mean?
That's what I'm asking.
Dad will talk to me tonight.
He'll ask, 'What is Farah up to'?
Why would Dad ask you?
Am I dead?
Well,
Even if he wants to ask you,
Then -- Just say,
That I'm firm in my intentions to go to Karachi.
Should I call now?
Call whom?
Arifa.
Oh, right.
I'll ask the driver to get the photograph from her.
Talk to her.
Get the picture.
But that blighter won't be coming back just like that.
You're right there.
He'd only come back if someone showed up at his doorstep,
Grabbed him by the collar, and said a few foul words to awaken his conscience.
No.
Just get a photograph.
One should keep all possible options in mind,
Right?
Hello?
How are you?
I'm fine.
And Mum and Dad?
They're better than me.
They're strutting about affectedly, looking at each other now and then.
Tell me,
Is everything alright over there?
Everything's fine, so to speak.
Farah was asking for his photograph.
Hey!
She'd run an advertisement on TV,
One of those 'missing persons' ads,
Complete with your voiceover.
Is she mad?
Tell her he's not missing!
She's lost him!
Alright --
Just give her his picture.
I know he's not missing, too.
May I request something?
Sure.
You'd better not call me.
I have no quarrel with you, but
It's only you or Afzal who calls me.
When you call, I get a feeling
Afzal's calling.
A ray of hope shines bright when the phone rings,
But gets extinguished at the sight of your name on the phone.
Look,
Please don't mind it.
You folks have everything, right?
We have only our Afzal.
We, his family, live in hopes of seeing his return.
Tell Farah, too,
That if she starts pitying people like this,
She'd try taking the Lord's affairs into her own hands.
There are many lads in Hyderabad who, embarrassed or vexed,
Have left their homes.
Ask her why she does not worry for any of them.
The reason to ask for a photograph is not to run a TV advertisement.
Then, that's --
Worse than running an advertisement on TV, innit, Lubna?
Remember,
She'd turned my brother down, pushed him away
At every opportunity she could get,
And all of us honoured her right to do so.
It's only fair that she, too, honour our right to refuse now.
I don't think she even deserves a photograph of Afzal.
Yes, Dad?
Come and sit here.
So what have you figured?
Have you tried getting at what's gotten into her heart?
What is she thinking of and why?
Please send her to Karachi.
What if I didn't?
The final decision will be yours to take,
But please, just let her complete.
But why is she vouching for her?
Because I'm with her all the time,
And I know her better than the two of you.
And I also know
That it'll take no more than four days for your order to crumble before her obstinacy.
So, it's better that you think about what she wants
Than getting angry with me.
What does she want?
The three of us must go...
To Farah?
No, Dad, to a psychiatrist.
You think I'm not the full shilling?
I would never go!
Why are you saying such things?
Just try to understand what I'm saying.
This girl will drive us mad.
That's right.
That's just what I'm saying --
Alright, I'll look for a good psychiatrist.
She must get treated, but will she go to him?
She'd say the moment she'd hear, 'You think I'm mad'?
Then, let her go to Karachi.
The same, again?
She's stumbling around in the dark within herself.
She wants to prove
That she just sympathises with him.
With whom?
Afzal.
However in the blazes is Afzal related to this conversation?
He's the only one who is related to this.
It's just that she's denying it.
Care to explain in simpler words?
Tell me.
Explain your point like you would to one who's unlettered and nescient!
She loves Afzal...
I don't feel the slightest of sorrow on hearing this.
But it'll grieve you to hear
That she doesn't know this herself.
What?
Whatever the dickens is she talking about, Irsa?
She's french fried my brain!
I'll take my leave.
That's what I don't like one bit about you.
You'd immerse your father in simmering hot oil, fry him into a croquette,
And then say, 'I'll take my leave'!
Dad, she'll think we're conniving against her.
What else are we doing?
Right...
I'm seeing a psychiatrist tomorrow morning.
I need a good psychiatrist!
Go.
Who shut the door to Dad's room?
Dad, of course.
Were you there?
I was coming back from there
When I saw you get out.
Then you've heard everything.
Ration my rum if I understood anything except 'french fried'.
But why did he bring french fries into such a serious conversation?
That's what I'm wondering.
Dad's lost his English, apparently.
He said, 'You've french fried my brain'!
I've never heard about 'french fried brain'.
You don't get it.
You know how they slice potatoes into french fries?
He must be alluding to that.
But why did he?
When I said, 'Let Farah go to Karachi',
That's what escaped his mouth.
This is nothing of the sort
That'd french fry one's brain.
I'd also said,
'She doesn't even know herself why she's going to Karachi'.
In other words,
You said,
'Farah's gone mad'?
I swear by God I didn't say that.
Your seeing a psychiatrist doesn't mean you've gone mad.
Lubna?
-Just see one for once.
At least it'll satisfy everyone.
Whom will it satisfy except you?
I have no such issue.
But Dad's officially lost it.
He facepalms the moment he hears what you say.
All of this is because of you.
You're trying to prove to Dad that I'm certifiable,
And telling him
That Farah's not the full shilling!
Good Lord!
You'd even have said
That I'm going to Karachi to look for that runagate.
There!
You've overheard the whole thing, haven't you?
Did you actually say all of this?
It was just in the flow of conversation that I said,
'Perhaps, it's possible'...
Oh God...
But he didn't feel the slightest of sorrow to hear this.
It's rather surprising, Farah,
He's usually merry as a grig at the mention of Afzal!
Get out.
What?
I said get out!
If you poked your prating trap in my affairs again,
Or gave any bright ideas to Mum and Dad,
I'd kill you for real!
Hold it, Farah.
You're taking everyone except yourself lightly.
People other than yourself
Are not marionettes;
They have never, and will never dance to your tune.
I'm your sister,
Which is why I double as a psychiatrist in times of need.
The truth is that your madness does not convince people!
Care to ask
What happened to Afzal's photograph,
And what Arifa said when I asked her for one?
What did she say?
She said you don't even deserve his photograph.
Tell me,
Do you?
No.
Not at all.
Let me give you a parting piece of advice.
Run an advertisement for yourself on TV,
One of those 'missing persons' advertisements,
Complete with my voiceover,
Tearfully saying,
'This girl is searching for herself'.
'Please help her',
'Or pray for her'.
His build looks fit.
Could you have your hair cut?
Hair?
Why would he have to have his hair cut?
Babu, boyo, he should look like a commando in his uniform.
Why should I look like a commando --
-I'm talking to Babu Hamid.
He's been scoring third division marks throughout.
With such excellent credentials, he won't be getting a job inside the office.
Then?
He can get one outside.
What's the job outside the office?
He can be a security guard.
I'm saying this because his uprightness works in his favour.
He looks like a security guard.
His salary will be 10,000.
Now and then,
He'd salute the toffs, and open the door for them;
He'd get some reward for that.
He'll easily make up to 15,000.
Isn't the salary a tad too low?
How much would you want, sir?
1.5 million a day.
Stop laughing.
You may note it down.
One day, you'd be working as a security guard under me.
You have a fit build too.
Yes, the stomach peeps out a bit, but...
It'll do.
Come, Babu Hamid.
By the way,
Here's the payment for the tea.
You may consider any overheads a benefaction.
Why did you say the thing about 1.5 million a day?
Are you thinking of becoming a politician?
Theirs is a trade that earns them so much...
1.5 million a day, perhaps even 150 million a day.
I used to make aeroplanes like that in my younger days.
Tad would be delighted to see, and say in a lively voice, 'You'll see, Arifa',
'My son will become a pilot one day'.
Arifa?
Arifa was my Mam's name.
Hey!
My sister's name is Arifa!
Surely, your Mam's name isn't Ruqaiyya?
Yes!
My Mum's name is Ruqaiyya.
How do you know?
Ruqaiyya was my younger sister's name.
Why
Do you say 'was'?
She's gone now.
My Mam, my Tad,
My sister, my brother...
All gone.
Where?
They're dead, boyo.
Gone, so to speak.
All at once?
Yes.
All at once,
One night,
One a minute earlier,
Another a minute later.
They had an accident?
No accident, mun, but murder.
Four murders over a feud over one-fourth an acre of land.
Acreage, boyo, has in its innate nature
A particular hunger for corpses.
Sometimes, when it's ravenous,
It may not settle for anything under eight for one-fourth of an acre.
Eight?
But you just said four.
Four of them died too.
I killed them.
Farah?
Please step aside.
Who is it, Arifa?
It's Farah, Mum.
Farah Ibrahim.
What has my son done this time?
My dear,
We are no longer responsible for his words and deeds now.
He's left our place.
When one leaves one country and settles in another,
The other country's law applies to him.
I'm not here to talk about him, Aunt,
Nor do I have any complaint.
Right...
So you've just come...
To meet us.
In the Lord's name [auspicious beginning].
Have Farah sit.
Ask her if she'll have tea or coffee.
Tea or coffee?
Do I deserve coffee?
If I don't deserve his photograph,
How do I deserve to have coffee at his place?
Tell me,
What brings you here?
What are you looking at down there?
He hasn't come yet.
So what if he hasn't?
Why are you worried only about him?
I'm not worried about him.
I've been thinking about lunch.
If he doesn't have lunch a few times, he'd say at the end of the month,
'I didn't have lunch on this and this day; I won't be paying for that'.
Why wouldn't he?
We'd cooked the food for him, hadn't we?
Alright, don't lean and look down there.
You might just fall face-first.
He's here, Mam!
Serve him food.
That one seems to be his room.
Yes.
It's his.
Why have you locked it?
Mum has a feeling he's in his room when it's not locked.
Oh...
He's earned a BA, hasn't he?
Scoring a third division throughout?
Whatever kind of job will he get with that?
There was still some scope in Hyderabad.
Quite a few bigwigs around here know Uncle, too.
Who in Karachi would hire him?
You'll see,
He'll end up in bad company.
God will help him.
God will,
But only if he does something too.
He could've pursued an MA.
Perhaps
He could've scored a better division?
He's done with his studies, Farah.
Anyway; That's his personal matter.
But there's no wisdom in it.
I figure he must've left a letter?
Yes.
He has one for theatrics, I'd give him that!
What's written in the letter?
The letter, too, is his personal matter, innit?
Oh...
Sorry...
Anyway,
He'd written,
'I'm not coming back until I've become something'.
What will he become?
I mean --
Surely, he must've thought of something?
He never got the opportunity to think.
He'd be thinking now.
Honestly,
You folks don't blame me, do you?
Molvi Uncle surely wouldn't,
But your Mum...
Perhaps she thinks he's left because of me?
No --
Whatever the answer is,
It won't hurt me at all.
I, too, feel that the fault also lies with me.
What's your fault?
When I'd --
Brought his letters
Before your Mum and Dad...
Why did I have to tell any of that?
I could've just called you
And said,
'I swear by God',
'I've not written those letters'.
Yes.
You could've.
But you!
You'd barged in to my house and started your own theatrics!
That's what had enraged me.
Everything happens for the better, Farah.
These are just hollow sayings.
When something bad happens,
It doesn't happen for the better.
What has happend that's bad for you?
Wouldn't I have felt sorrow?
Your Mum and Dad --
My heart sinks to think of them.
I feel as if I've committed a grave sin.
You have not sinned.
An honourable and virtuous girl should do exactly what you had.
Innit?
You shouldn't feel regret over this either.
Afzal's my brother, but
He wasn't being fair on you.
It has certainly wracked our hearts with grief that he's left,
But so has the fact that he's two-timing a girl.
Whom is he two-timing?
The one who writes him letters.
Ah, right!
The other Farah!
I'd forgotten her entirely!
Find out, Arifa,
Who she is,
What she does, and where she lives.
It won't do any good.
Why wouldn't it?
She can help us bring Afzal back.
What will the poor lass help us?
Her own love is at stake.
She'd have Afzal's new cell number!
Right!
He'd definitely be talking to her.
No?
He wouldn't be talking to her.
That's why she writes letters.
Afzal must be writing, too.
I mean, he must be replying to her in the least?
Perhaps.
Why are you saying, 'Perhaps'?
Obviously, he replies; That's why she writes to him!
She isn't mad,
To just keep on writing herself.
The most bizarre things can happen in love
That would never happen in sensibility.
Look, now,
At how you, in your senses, said it,
'The road ahead is yours alone, Monsieur',
'I have no ties with you'.
It ended there.
Now, if someone's ready to sacrifice his life for you,
But you have no ties with him,
What does it matter to you if he
Goes to Karachi or the wops?
Right...
You're right there.
But --
-When I'm right,
Why this 'but'?
Just pray that he comes back, having become something,
And tell us upon his return who it is who writes him letters,
What she does, where she lives;
Then, I can convince Mum and Dad.
'Convince', as in?
It's pretty simple.
I'll get the two of them married, of course.
Right...
They should get married...
It's almost evening, Arifa.
I'll take my leave.
You'd come again, wouldn't you?
Sure, why not?
I'll come again, if the Lord wills.
Why are you laughing?
Your brother's left home and gone,
And you're giggling gleefully!
No, Mum,
I'm tearing up to think of this poor Farah.
Which poor Farah?
The one who just left,
Or the one who never came?
However did she come in?
She would if she were ever there.
-What?
If she'd never been there, was it her father who wrote the letters?
Look,
I'm very restless to begin with,
Please don't give me new fears.
Fear the one who's just left.
Don't think about the one who never came here.
I dread her already.
She's come here twice,
And left us clobbered each time.
O God, have mercy.
Does this lad not work?
Which lad?
What's his name --?
Afzal?
Yes, Afzal.
He must.
What's it to us if he doesn't, though?
Where does he get the money from?
Now,
He's paid the rent for four months.
And,
On top of that, he's paid 10,000 in advance for his food.
How's he paying for everything?
Enjoy your mangoes, Mam,
Don't worry about the trees in the farm. [Mind your own business]
That's alright,
But we'd better know that the tree that produced these is indeed a mango tree.
Not gonna lie to you, though, he's good.
He's upright and doesn't look the wrong way.
He seems the mim and modest type.
He's just a tad lippy.
You're lippy too,
Ruffling everyone's feathers like you do!
If I'm not lippy, these men would eat me alive!
To add to it, I'm rather comely.
Am I not comely?
But of course, Yasmin, you are,
But please don't say it yourself!
Should I serve dinner?
Go.
But please don't start prattling.
Aren't you afraid?
The police will find you one day.
Have you ever thought what'd happen then?
What's the worst that can happen?
They'd throw me in the quod,
Send me to the gallows, perhaps?
Let them, boyo.
Let a fifth die when four have already.
Oh?
Then why are you in hiding?
Go and face them,
And tell them you're prepared to die.
I'm not ready to die just yet.
I'm not afraid of dying,
But I want to live on.
There.
Go and open the door.
The Reaper has come knocking.
Get out of the way.
And don't stare like that.
You could try asking for food yourself sometime, Babu Hamid,
Or is it that you folks don't feel hungry at all?
It doesn't come to that.
Here, we feel a bit of hunger,
And there you are.
The same potatoes and lentils?
Where's the potatoes?
Are you blind or do they call okras potatoes in Hyderabad?
Keep it there.
I will, sure.
You'd better know your limits.
Don't think of me as une femme frêle.
For the likes of you, I'm a ferocious wildcat.
I claw the faces of the insolent!
Hey!
It's good that you mentioned it.
I'd been thinking you're a girl for 20 days.
By the way,
What makes you leave after you've come?
What?
Will you leave if I meow you?
No way, that's --
What you say to call a cat.
Then,
What do you say to shoo a cat away?
Bleedin' dog!
C'mon, mate.
Have your dinner.
I'm starving.
This ain't right, Afzal.
What ain't right?
The punishment for breaking a heart is worse than gibbeting.
So, have some fear.
Come.
I've seen you.
Who is it?
-Afzal.
What are you doing here?
I'd
Come to return the utensils.
You came through this door?
Yes.
I think you don't know
But as per the rental agreement, you're not allowed to open this door.
Anyway,
We'll talk about it in the morning.
Listen.
The fault does not lie with Babu Hamid.
He retired immediately after having his dinner.
I --
Thought this door leads to your place, so...
I came here on the pretext of handing you the utensils.
Pretext, as in?
No, it's --
Babu Hamid thinks
I've broken your heart.
I couldn't fall asleep.
We don't have sleeping pills.
I haven't come to ask for a pill.
I've come here to ask forgiveness.
That's neat.
You're a right emotional man.
Does this apology come from your heart,
Or are you just apologising to impress me?
Why would I impress you?
It happens this way, too,
You lost your heart to a comely lady,
So acted rough at first,
Then impressed with an apology.
But I'm not going to be impressed.
I'd --
Just come to apologise.
I haven't come here to impress.
Alright, then.
It's okay.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital