Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Sitting here like this,
Staring at the roof and the walls,
Tell me,
Are you on the verge of a new discovery,
Or are you intent on destroying everything?
Sit tight.
Put this down before her.
What's this?
This is your gown for the engagement,
And here's the diamond ring
They'll put on you the day after tomorrow.
The day after tomorrow?
Don't argue over the day after tomorrow.
Just think it's the date of an exam -
Once it's been fixed, it's been fixed.
Why are you looking at Mum?
Look at the ring.
Isn't it lovely?
At least you could've asked me once before fixing the date.
Are you talking to Lubna, or to me?
To you, of course, Mum.
Then you're a right daring lass.
Just because I've come to show you the gown and the ring,
Don't think I'm asking you,
'Do you like the gown'?
'Do you like the ring'?
It's just that Sibtain's father wished that it be shown to you;
That's why the engagement gown is from him.
Come.
Take everything, Lubna,
And take it that she likes it.
If the engagement's on the day after tomorrow,
Tell them it won't be.
Tell whom?
Sibtain's father?
Should I tell him that daughters here
Order their parents around?
Hold your horses, you barmy lass,
Or every slap I've held back all my life
Will grace your face now.
Come.
At least ask me, Mum,
Why I'm saying the engagement can't be on the day after tomorrow?
Right, what is it the day after tomorrow?
Won't you invite Afzal's Mum?
I'm going over to her once I'm through with you.
How bad is it, Mum!
She's so ill she's bedridden,
And you'd go and tell her, 'My daughter's getting engaged the day after tomorrow'?
Even if Molvi Sahab alone is in attendance, it'll be enough.
Although I'll ask him
To bring Arifa along too.
How would she come?
She's not going to leave her sick mother --
And come.
Why are you suddenly feeling for her sick mother now?
First, you calumnied her son and ousted him from Hyderabad,
And because of you, he became a hoodlum over there,
And that is what has made her fall ill,
And you, sitting here, are playing her nurse?
His Mum's 'Mother Teresa'!
Don't you dare
Ruin the engagement on the pretext of his mother!
What was destined to happen to her
Has already happened.
Your intensive care isn't going to heal her.
Come.
Mum!
I don't like this ring, that's it!
Splendid.
You don't like a ring that costs 170,000 Rupees?
What would you like?
Tell them, will you,
That I'll get the ring I like.
It won't be too expensive.
If I agree to this demand,
You won't create a scene on the day of the engagement, would you?
I swear by you, I won't.
Not at all.
I'd even agree to the day after tomorrow.
Alright, then,
Get the ring you like.
May I ask about a problem, Molvi Sahab?
Begin in the Lord's name.
You've pronounced it forbidden
To meet him and be in his company,
But is it forbidden to look at him from afar, too?
I've gotten my answer.
How come you've gotten the answer
When I don't have one either?
Perhaps it's not forbidden,
But remember, Ruqaiyya Begum,
One look at him
Would forbid any calm from setting in in your life.
Then, this illusion of seeing the doctor,
These
Excuses of medicines,
None of this would work, either.
But I'm only talking about looking at him from afar, Molvi Sahab!
Just like --
I look at his photograph.
Does that torment me?
Why are you laughing?
I used to think
Who the blighter's taken after!
I've realised today
That he's taken after you.
Do you remember,
How he said one day,
'I've started down God's path, Dad'.
Would you see, now,
Where the path of God lies,
And where the wretch is!
And it's the same with you -
I check your pulse,
Give you medicines,
Give you courage,
So you can walk down the path of Molvi Subhanallah's wife.
But the moment you get a chance,
You start treading down the mother's path!
Don't let a single teardrop fall, Ruqaiyya Begum,
Or I'll leave you with him.
Why don't you get her married, Aunt?
She won't get married now.
She's started teaching the kids.
So, what's with teaching the kids?
She's devoted herself to it.
She says, 'Once you've devoted yourself to something',
'You remain steadfast in your devotion'.
That's not right at all, Aunt.
I mean --
What kind of a reply is this?
The question ain't right either, is it?
I mean,
Who are you to ask this?
Have I ever said that you should get married?
Or has Mam ever said so?
Don't look at my face,
Have your meal, and just think that teaching the kids
Is a far greater challenge than getting married,
And I always choose the more challenging job.
Is teaching children a job to you?
Put a sock in it!
Even a husband like Salim wouldn't pester one as much as the kids do!
One's got a finger inside his nose, another's got an itch in his underarm.
And when I asked one to recite his lesson, it turned out he was sleeping!
And one lad's a proper royal -
He asks, 'Miss',
'Why does 9 + 9 equal 18'?
'Why not 19'?
Pray tell,
Why not 19?
You tell me that.
I just know it's 18.
Arifa, my dear, would you see who's there?
Peace be upon you, Molvi Uncle.
And upon you, peace, my dear.
What are you doing?
I'm preparing a medicine
To give strength to the heart.
I'd mix it with some honey and take this,
And give some to her, too.
Peace be upon you!
Hey!
And upon you, peace.
It seems you'd not rest before I'm alright.
You come here everyday.
Sit.
-Alright.
Is this noise of grinding something coming from somewhere in our home?
Yes.
Molvi Uncle's preparing a medicine to give strength to the heart.
He'd give you some today!
That's what I feared.
He'd turn into a medic if he gave up his priesthood.
He'd given me an elixir after our marriage.
I used to have headaches in half my head.
That headache never affected just half my head ever again.
Are you waiting for my orders to get tea?
I won't have any tea.
I've not even come to look after you today.
I'd like to ask for a favour.
Pray tell.
I'm getting engaged on the day after tomorrow.
They'd sent a ring,
As in, they want me to see it and say that I like it.
But I didn't like it.
It must be a gold ring...
No,
It's a diamong ring.
But I didn't like it.
Why not?
Hey!
Sit down, will you?
If you keep standing like that, it feels
As if you'd refuse if I asked you for anything.
-Hey!
Who could ever refuse you anything here?
Ask for whatever you want without any hesitation.
I want the ring, Aunt,
That Molvi Uncle had had made for me.
Oh, that inexpensive ring -- what would you do with that?
And never wear that accursed ring on an auspicious day.
I'd have thrown it away
Had the wretched thing not been made of gold!
I'd only wear that ring, Aunt.
If I wore any other,
It'd gnaw at my finger every moment.
You're not getting that ring, Farah.
It's a memory of the day that led us to these.
And Mum's reasoning is true, too -
One doesn't wear such accursed things on an auspicious day.
I want the same ring, Aunt.
I beg you.
This isn't proper, Farah.
You're resolute to get something you'd so resolutely refused.
And whom are you asking?
Dad took it out of his pocket and threw it away the moment he entered,
And Mum never saw it again.
I have it with me.
I look at it whenever I feel sadness at my brother's fate.
So, forgive me,
But you're never going to get that ring.
Here, my dear, have your favourite coconut biscuits.
I'd promised you yesterday, hadn't I?
But she's left!
What happened to her?
She'd come to get the ring we'd had made for Afzal's engagement.
Why?
She's getting engaged the day after tomorrow.
She says she'd only wear that ring on her engagement.
Where's the ring?
Arifa has it safely with her.
Then, tell Arifa to give it to her.
She's left weeping at such a trifle!
Why don't you talk to Arifa?
She's left me speechless.
Hey!
What would you say the next time you come?
You didn't get it, did you?
You said when you met me yesterday, 'I don't love you',
Today, you said,
'I love someone else',
So, tell me as you're leaving,
What would you say when you come tomorrow?
Why not say everything at once,
And check
How much of it Yasmin can take?
I won't be coming now, Yasmin.
There!
You've learnt new ways to kill ever since you started murdering people.
Go and note it down, now,
That you killed one Yasmin, too, today.
This isn't proper, Farah.
You're resolute to get something you'd so resolutely refused.
And whom are you asking?
Dad took it out of his pocket and threw it away the moment he entered,
And Mum never saw it again.
I have it with me.
I look at it whenever I feel sadness at my brother's fate.
So, forgive me,
But you're never going to get that ring.
Show me where it is!
Show you what?
The ring you like, of course!
You didn't get it?
Didn't you like it?
No, it's not like that.
I liked that ring.
Why did you leave it, then?
They didn't give it to me.
Oh...
Arifa must've refused.
How do you know where I'd gone to get the ring?
Did Arifa call you?
Not at all.
I found out from my experience.
The thing is,
One girl in love
Knows another inside out!
I knew it the very moment
You'd kicked away a ring that cost 170,000 Rupees!
Mum had said it clearly,
'This isn't about liking',
'But about devotion'.
But why do you have such a devoted attachment to that ring?
Well,
Time's running out.
The day after tomorrow is just around the corner,
And you're bothered about a ring that isn't even yours!
How come it isn't mine?
Surely, it is mine.
Now, I can't say that the ring is yours...
But, surely,
It isn't an outsider's.
Why don't you go to her?
As in, to Arifa?
Yes.
She's your best friend.
She won't refuse if you ask her.
Why, mate?
Why should I get for you something that is rightfully mine?
It's obvious
They've still kept it with them for an auspicious purpose.
Why would they put it around someone else's bride?
Tell Mum, then,
This engagement can't go forward.
I'd already said so
When you dashed upstairs, stupefied,
I told Mum right then,
That she couldn't get the ring,
And I'd even told her that the engagement can't go forward now.
Then?
What, 'then'?
Mum said,
'In that case, she'd be getting married the day after tomorrow'.
Look, Farah,
Please, show that you're wise,
The circumstances are not in your favour.
And when Afzal's out of the picture for you anyhow,
What would you do, wearing his ring?
I'd say
That you don't test your would-be husband's sense of honour.
Look,
Get me the ring.
You may have Afzal if you want.
What?
Think carefully, Farah,
You're offering me more than you can dare to.
I think Molvi Sahab's sobs have struck me.
If I wore the same ring on my engagement,
It'd ease this burden on me.
If Afzal's taken a liking to you,
He's all yours from now on,
But even today, the ring is mine.
She's teaching the kids these days.
She says it's a far greater challenge than getting married.
One's got a finger inside his nose, another's got an itch in his underarm.
And when she asked one to recite his lesson, he was sleeping.
And one lad's a proper royal -
He asks, 'Miss',
'Why does 9 + 9'
'Equal 18'?
'Why not 19'?
The kid asked her that one?
Yes, he asked her.
You're mad.
She was asking you this one.
Look,
'9 + 9' means 'Afzal + the one who writes him letters',
Which would add up to 18.
But when you can never get the one who writes you letters,
Why can't 9 + 9
Equal 19?
And 19 means
'Afzal + Yasmin'.
You've been failing Maths all your life,
And now, you're telling me that 9 + 9 equals 19?
So does that mean that because I don't love her,
9 + 9 can't equal 19?
More than half the marriages in our country follow this formula.
Only in textbooks does 9 + 9 equal 18.
Practically,
It's always either 19 or 17.
Anyway,
Tell me,
Why did you go there?
Why did you go there when you'd told her yesterday that you don't love her?
Just went there.
I thought I'd just as well tell her that I love someone else.
Why are you laughing?
You could start sitting with the kids she teaches,
With your finger in your nose one moment, itching your underarm another; and when asked to recite the lesson, just sleeping peacefully.
But please don't tell such a blatant lie.
It's not a lie, Babloo.
I have proof.
I've told her that I'm never coming back.
I agree that she's very nice,
And loves me a lot.
It must've really hurt her to hear that I love someone else,
But what could I do, Babloo?
She's treading down the same path as I am,
And she, too, would find nothing down it.
You sound wicked when you say that, Afzal.
It sounds like the owner of a river pitying the thirsty but not giving him a drop.
May God forgive you for being such a miser.
I'd told you
She'd be sitting on the swing.
You're here again?
Why do you drop in so suddenly?
At least leave me alone for two days.
Finished yet?
Sit on the swing and listen to me calmly.
There's insolence in my profession, but not disgraceful shamelessness!
What do you mean?
I've heard everything about your drama.
I wasn't even willing to come,
But then I thought I'd see for myself what you're made of!
Watch your words there!
How dare you!
Hey!
Get him out of my sights!
Look at how he's bossing over me!
I haven't even started bossing over you!
I'll tell you when you get to my place!
And don't you dare talk about me so rudely.
I'm not the kind
Who'd mistake such discourtesies as affection!
It is pure insolence to me.
Lubna!
Why are you calling Lubna? Talk to me.
What's this
Engagement ring drama you've started?
I didn't like your ring.
You didn't like a ring worth 170,000 Rupees.
So,
Please show me the one you like.
I will
When I get it.
Where'd you get it from?
I know about that, too.
So such rings would be used on the occasion of the wedding of a psychiatrist like myself as those whose sanctity is dubious!
Pray tell, also, how much that ring costs.
More than the price,
Think about how much I like that ring.
You're rather dubious, too, when it comes to what you like.
Shut up!
Then listen carefully -
An engagement isn't destined for that ring.
Put it clearly.
What do you mean?
What do I tell you what it means?
The thing is,
You don't deserve me.
I don't deserve you?
Nobody's told you, apparently,
Many psychiatrists have sacrificed their love for the sake of their honour.
I'm your doctor,
I know it very well that you're a bit round the twist.
You're remembering your old ring today; you might remember your old lover tomorrow.
No.
No chance. Never.
This engagement isn't possible.
My foot!
You'll know about 'foot' when your Paw gets the news.
Say, then,
'My foot'!
If the Lord wills it, your feet would've been chopped off the next time we meet!
Hey!
Why are you so furious?
I've just sacrificed my love for the sake of my honour!
Please tell me in simpler terms - what have you just done?
I've called the engagement off.
What?
I've put it plainly -
If that accursed ring is used on the engagement,
I'm not getting engaged.
Lubna!
What is it?
Why are you so worked up?
The engagement's broken...
He's found out about everything, hasn't he?
He was shivering out of disgrace.
But however did he find out?
Who could've told him but you?
You?
Hadn't you told him?
Don't you remember when you'd gone to him for your treatment?
You'd narrated the entire story about Afzal over the three hours you sat with him.
That's right...
You must've told him then about the incident with the ring, too.
It's possible...
But who told him that I'm going to wear the same ring on the engagement?
I did.
I just uttered it...
What it is is I don't like to lie to someone so close.
There!
You're not a sister, Lubna Ibrahim,
You're a snake
That's been biting me ever since!
You're such a thankless girl!
You forgot in one moment
Everything I've sacrificed for you!
I've told the truth and lied for you,
Taken slaps and scolding,
And you're saying today that I'm a snake?
Alright.
If I'm a snake to you,
Stay away from me!
Call him!
I asked you to call him right now!
And tell him
That I've agreed.
'Agreed', as in?
Tell him I'd wear his diamond ring on my engagement.
He shouldn't break the engagement,
Or Dad would kill me for real.
Do you know what he'd said?
He said I'm 'a bit round the twist'!
'You're remembering your old ring today; you might remember your old lover tomorrow'.
Go and tell him
I'm not the type.
You said when you met me yesterday, 'I don't love you',
Today, you told,
'I love someone else',
So, tell me as you're leaving,
What would you say when you come tomorrow?
Why not say everything at once,
And check
How much of it Yasmin can take?
I won't be coming now, Yasmin.
There!
You've learnt new ways to kill ever since you started murdering people.
Go and note it down, now,
That you killed one Yasmin, too, today.
Yasmin!
Wake up! It's almost the afternoon!
Didn't the kids come?
They won't be coming today.
It's Sunday.
You'd said it yourself that Sunday's a holiday.
There.
Why had I said that?
Is this a school that'd have an off on Sundays?
I don't love you, Yasmin,
And I'm not worthy of being loved, now, either.
Drop me at my place.
The kid asked her that one?
Yes, he asked her.
You're mad.
She was asking you this one.
Look,
'9 + 9' means 'Afzal + the one who writes him letters',
Which would add up to 18.
But when you can never get the one who writes you letters,
Why can't 9 + 9
Equal 19?
And 19 means
'Afzal + Yasmin'.
Hey, Alladio!
Where are you off to?
Hyderabad.
Have these four days been enough to satisfy you?
No.
It's not been enough.
I've got to go for the engagement.
I'll be back in a few days.
You're getting engaged?
I'm not getting engaged, mate.
Good old Mlle Farah,
The daughter of Monseigneur Ibrahim, the mill owner,
She's getting engaged.
Mum asked me to come.
'Attend the engagement',
'And meet me, too'.
May I go, now?
S -- Sure,
Go...
Will you get engaged to me?
Why are you laughing?
You asked me, 'Will you get engaged to me'?
Why didn't you ask, 'Will you marry me'?
Or is it that you intend to shoo me away at the engagement?
-No way!
I accidentally said 'engaged' instead of 'married'.
Mam!
Why are you calling your Mum?
You're proposing me for marriage.
I have to discuss with Mam.
Just pray that she accepts it.
You accept it, don't you?
Now,
I get proposals like this every now and then.
But girls don't decide in a moment.
It takes about a week or so
To arrive at a decision.
I don't have a week or so.
If you accept, we're getting engaged tomorrow.
What if I don't agree to tomorrow?
If you agree to get engaged, why not agree to the date as well?
Just think as if
I'm adamant over it.
So you're adamant over it!
You haven't fallen in love with me.
Come with me.
I'm taking him upstairs.
It's a case of memory loss.
Sit down.
Tell me, now,
Whom are you obdurate against?
Won't you share what lies in your heart with the one you'd get engaged to?
She's getting engaged tomorrow.
You're exacting your revenge?
She doesn't love you, does she?
You don't love me, either.
How would I get even with you?
By getting engaged to you?
You thought you'd toy with her with this game of engagements,
And please Yasmin, too!
You could've just said, 'I need a favour, Yasmin'.
You shouldn't have said, 'Will you get engaged to me'?
Girls are very sensitive, Afzal,
They'd lose their heart in games such as yours.
Thank goodness I didn't think you'd fallen in love with me.
I'm serious, Yasmin.
I've come here with a proposal.
I'm serious, too, Afzal.
I reject your proposal.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital