Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Oh God!
She's suddenly taken to praying!
Pray quickly and tell me what's wrong this time!
God knows what she's praying for!
I was praying that this Sunday not fall on the 27th.
Or that the 27th not be a Sunday.
Are you touched in the head?
I'm getting married this Sunday, you blighter!
You'll not get married.
I've wished for this in my prayers!
You're envying your own sister?
Do you remember
How you said that you are making this marriage possible?
I'd said that I made this engagement possible.
But you've taken a shortcut from the engagement to the marriage!
What can be done now?
When Farah thinks of something, her decision is final.
You don't need to think anything.
What you thought to be an engagement was no engagement!
That was a part of your treatment!
What?
You mean --
That bleeding psychiatrist was treating me?
We were both of the opinion that you'd need a different kind of shock therapy.
You love someone else
And you're not ready to admit it.
And that blighter was saying with complete confidence,
That the moment it'd come to marrying him,
You'd shriek,
'No way, I can't marry Sibtain'!
So he wasn't in love?
He was conniving!
You weren't in love either.
You, too, were conniving!
You were exacting your revenge over Afzal's engagement.
Afzal again?
Tell me, who is he?
Whose is this Afzal?
First with that Farah who wrote him letters,
Then with you,
And then with that blighter Yasmin --
Well,
Yasmin is my friend now;
I won't call her a blighter.
I was never with him, Farah.
I was lying.
Lying?
I mean I was just putting up a show.
Because of this doltish Sibtain.
The blighter read a bunch of his books
And said, 'When Afzal's name comes next to yours, she'll say with evident agony -'
''Shut up, Lubna'!'
''Don't even think about Afzal'!'
He was right in saying that.
Don't you remember I'd slapped you and said,
'Don't even think about Afzal'!
But you didn't say anything beyond that!
What should've I said beyond that?
The same thing you are unable to utter;
The same thing that unfortunate bloke couldn't muster the courage to say.
You've killed each other,
Too reluctant to accept that you love each other.
I've said it a hundred times over and will say it a thousand times more,
I don't love Afzal!
Sit down.
Here are all those letters
Besides the one in your possession.
These are not letters, Yasmin.
These are an unsung chronicle of love.
This chronicle ended when
I got engaged to you.
Take this
And torch these with your own hands.
Just think as if
Afzal had a dream since his childhood days;
His dream unfulfilled, he felt too ashamed to even disclose what his dream was.
Don't look at me;
I'll never mention who wrote these letters.
Will you torch these, or should I?
No one will torch them, Afzal.
Letters written in love are not to be burnt.
One kisses and lifts them to the eyes,
And holds on to them like a book of Divine Revelation that touches the heart.
You are under my oath, Afzal -
Burn all you want in the flames of her searing remembrance,
But never burn these.
Arifa, I want to meet Farah.
Right now?
Right now.
Have you asked him?
I won't ask him.
I'll tell him when I'm back.
Does she retire by 11?
I don't know.
Then call her
Tell her
That it's important that I meet her.
Tell me
What will you say to her when you meet her?
Nothing, really.
I've got a few questions in my heart.
It'll satisfy me when I've asked her.
I'll talk to Lubna.
Hello, Arifa!
How are you?
I don't know.
Hey?
What happened?
To be honest, I'm furious!
I feel like murdering that chuffing Farah!
She's getting married this Sunday.
Why do you need to murder her now?
She hasn't rejected the marriage, has she?
No.
She's not rejecting it this time!
She's firm on Sunday.
Alright; by the way
Yasmin wants to meet her.
Everything alright?
I don't know.
She said that she wants to meet right now.
Tell her to come over.
But how will she come?
Tell her to get ready.
I'll send a car.
Thank you.
Shut up, mate.
The car will be there in ten minutes.
Okay.
-Bye.
Would you look at that, Ruqaiyya Begum?
He's massaging my feet to sweeten me up!
I'm also looking at how you're not sweetening up!
You could say
That there's not that old warmth now...
There's this knot in my heart now.
Keep on massaging.
It'll untie this knot.
Do you remember, when I'd had the heart attack, you'd said,
'The Molvi has been overcome by the father'?
You were right.
If a Molvi is more fatherly,
He may succumb to a weakness of honour.
I mean, it's not as if I've been dishonoured,
But, still,
I am in no position to avouch.
Why are you laughing?
I'm feeling sleepy,
And
It's without having to take any sleeping pills!
Is everything alright?
Nothing's alright.
It's something or the other since the day I've come here.
Where is she?
She's sleeping.
You'll see. She'll wake up today.
Upstairs?
Yes.
Stay here.
Just tell me where her room is.
Hers is the first room on the left when you climb upstairs and turn right.
Open your eyes!
I'm actually by your side!
I don't believe this.
Is everything alright?
Wake up and we'll talk.
I'm awake.
What is it?
I've got a few questions, Farah.
Will you answer them?
Ask away.
Do you know Miss Mary?
Miss Marry, who?
No, I don't know her.
The year was 2007.
Where were you studying back then?
I was doing my O-Levels back then...
Oh, yes -- Just a minute.
Miss Mary D'Souza was a teacher at my school.
She was so stern!
She used to get angry a lot; perhaps it's because she was a divorcee...
How did you find out about her?
I don't think even Lubna remembers her name.
You'd written it in a letter to him.
You'd warned him,
'If you stood in wait in front of the school or looked at me here or there, I'll have you caught'.
To whom did I write this?
Afzal.
I've got the letter in my bag if you want to read it.
I don't need to read it.
I know that a girl writes him letters.
Her name is Farah.
And I'm getting a bad name because of her.
There's just one way now, Yasmin.
Grab Afzal by the collar and ask him,
'Tell me'
'Who is this Farah'?
Why shouldn't one ask you before asking Afzal?
Why is the name of that Farah's teacher Mary D'Souza?
Perhaps this is why you're marrying a psychiatrist.
You know, deep inside, that you're ailing.
If he's not willing to tell me,
You're not willing to admit it either.
You wrote these letter, Farah.
It's possible
That you fell in love with him sometime
And afflicted with that love, you wrote those letters.
But you realised later on
That he's not your class!
This is why you hide your face in shame,
Lie to everyone,
And tell everyone that the Farah who wrote him letters is someone else.
You're getting married this Sunday, aren't you?
That's it.
It's just a problem until your marriage.
You'll be cured,
As will he be.
He holds on to your letters even now.
He's forgotten everything else he should've held on to.
Wake up, Farah.
Don't ever sleep in peace
With the knowledge that you've given many others sleepless nights.
Ask the driver to leave me home.
Come.
I've given her such a slosh she'll be left wondering.
What'll she be left wondering?
Just
What this Yasmin is made of!
Tell me,
What are you made of?
I've said it clearly to her,
'You used to write letters to Afzal'.
Why did you say that?
This Miss Mary D'Souza
Was a teacher at her school.
Tell me, then,
If it's her teacher who's mentioned,
She's the one who wrote those letters, isn't she?
She's not admitted it yet.
But now, she's within my grasp.
I couldn't dare imagine!
For the love of God,
How much my brother has been humiliated because of those letters!
I'm here now,
And I'll leave only after I've extracted the truth from her.
Didn't Mum ask you where you had gone?
She didn't ask but she was staring at me quietly.
What's this?
Afzal's diary.
He used to write it everyday up to his FA [A-Level] days.
There's another one from after he'd completed his FA [A-Levels].
I've read both of them
But found no clue.
May I read this?
Let me see what he used to write.
Go on.
'If love were a cricket match, I would've won'.
'I gambled for the first time today'.
'Won 500 Rupees'.
'I gave them all to Arifa',
'And Arifa is the kind who gave me a right scolding, asking where I'd got them from'.
'What could I do'?
'I lied to her, seeing her anger'.
What's the matter?
Just a second.
What is it in that letter?
She's got wind of who wrote those letters.
And the clue lies in the very letter she's got in her bag.
Why is she doing this, Ruqaiyya?
Searching and probing like this, she
Will lose something which is hers.
Where is she?
Call her here.
I will talk to her.
Come in, my dear.
She was outside, waiting for you to call her.
What is all of this, my dear?
You're remembering the one
Who should've been forgotten?
And you're reminding him, too?
No way.
Give me that letter.
In fact, bring me the rest of them too.
We'll consider it a sacrificial offering
To mark your engagement when we burn those letters.
Whom will you serve those coconut biscuits?
Whom will you see and say, 'When she comes, it feels as if Afzal has come'?
I do not need such consolations, my dear.
Afzal is here.
If she gets married this Sunday,
Afzal will be gone again.
Was she the one who used to write those letters?
Yes.
No.
That's completely wrong.
That can't be.
She didn't write those letters -- She --
She was ready to swear on the Holy Qur'an.
She was telling the truth.
She wasn't lying one bit!
She wasn't lying one bit, yes.
But she'll admit it today
That she wrote the letters.
You should admit it too. Please.
The car's here.
Car?
I'm going to meet Farah.
Allow me, please.
You've met her last night too.
You didn't ask for my permission last night.
I thought you'd stop me because it was late.
And I feared that I'd go regardless.
I didn't ask for permission so that I don't show disrespect.
What'll you do today?
I won't allow you today either.
Today, too, I'll go regardless.
For now, I'm obligated to disrespect this command.
What did she just say, Ruqaiyya?
How respectfully has she said
That she'd disrespect my command!
She's pronounced her judgement as she left, Molvi Sahab.
She's decided she won't live under the same roof as Afzal.
What happened?
Who was there in the car?
Yasmin.
Try as much as you like, Yasmin, she'll not admit it.
She will, today.
The circumstances and evidence have changed.
She'll be saying to you in a while that she's written the letters.
Where is she?
In her room as usual.
She's suddenly started offering additional prayers.
Go up, turn right, first room on the left, right?
Yes.
Don't come upstairs today.
Seriously.
Don't.
Hold it there!
Offer the rest of your prayers after I've left.
I dropped in again, didn't I?
Sorry, Farah, but I had no option.
I've sworn I'd leave only after having you admit it.
Admit what?
Sit.
Say that you're the Farah who wrote those letters.
I swear by God --
-Don't swear!
Just say it for someone's sake.
Why should I say it, mate?
Because the Farah who wrote those letters isn't anyone else.
What?
What do you mean?
Alright, remember:
You'd see him outside school sometimes,
And sometimes, at the gates of your college.
Yes, I used to see him.
In fact, I used to see him outside the college very often.
Because Arifa used to study there.
He used to come to pick her up.
He came to see you, Farah.
He used to glimpse you, secretly.
You, the daughter of the owner of Ibrahim Cottons,
And he, the son of a poor Molvi.
That is why he never mustered the courage to say anything or talk to you.
So?
And when he felt
That he'd never be able to talk to you,
To tell you that he loves you,
So, he took the other route to his love.
What has he done?
He started writing letters from you to Afzal.
That which he had wanted to tell you,
He believed he had,
And that which he wanted to hear from you
He wrote in his letters which he'd read to his friends.
He believed in his mind
That you loved him,
But also accepted
That you can never be his.
I feel sorry for him...
Yes.
I feel sorry for him too.
He's admitted it?
Obviously,
He'd have admitted it now that he's been caught.
He's been caught, Farah.
But he's not admitted it
Because I never asked him to admit it.
That's your fault, then.
He's your fiancé.
You should've grabbed his collar and said,
'Hey Mister'!
'What's this business'?
Did this start today?
And will this end with tomorrow?
This will go on until he dies, Farah,
Or love itself dies.
Interesting...
So, now you want
That I forgive him.
No, Farah.
Now, I want that you confess it.
Admit it that you love Afzal
And admit it
That you had written all those letters.
Very funny.
I don't think I'm crazy like you!
Honestly,
Are you actually his fiancée
Or just say it to terrorise us?
You could think it's just like that...
I just say it to terrorise you.
The blighter had terrorised me when he first met me.
Said, 'I'll throw you out'!
No!
He didn't throw me out.
Just
Said it for the sake of saying.
He doesn't know how to talk to girls.
He'll learn when he talks to you.
But now that he's been with me for a few days,
He's learnt something.
Said it very politely when he came for the engagement,
'Will you get engaged to me'?
It felt as if --
As if --
He'd cursed me!
Cursed?
Who says, 'Will you get engaged to me'?
If he loved me, he'd have said,
'Will you marry me'?
I swear by you,
I would never have thought who writes him letters then!
Whether you're the Farah or someone else,
I would've trampled her underfoot!
He deserved a girl like you
Who'd break others to pieces for his love.
He only wanted you
Who'd broken him to pieces.
He'd come from Hyderabad a broken man.
One who comes broken from Hyderabad
Cannot be patched in Karachi.
He said to me a day before the engagement, 'Yasmin',
'I don't love you'.
And I'd known he'd say that
Because he never knew love
Except for his love.
When he came to talk about the engagement, it felt
Like he'd come to amuse me.
You were getting engaged on that day,
So he'd come to give a befitting reply.
I, too, thought, 'Get on with the engagement'.
'What's an engagement'?
'The moment he'd turn to look back',
'It'd break'.
I'm getting married this Sunday.
It'll all be clear this Sunday.
You'll see,
He'll marry you this Sunday.
He'll give the same befitting reply again.
Why, Farah?
Why must it only be the two of you who play this game of befitting replies?
How say I play my move this time?
And when I do, you'll realise,
That one who comes broken from Karachi
Cannot be patched in Hyderabad.
Don't break off your engagement!
-Not at all!
I would never.
But what do I do about him?
When he startles at the sound of your name,
The engagement breaks.
No -- He's nobody to me;
I know he's Arifa's brother,
Molvi Sahab's son,
And now also that he writes letters to himself under my name...
The blighter!
You love this blighter.
No?
You'd die without him.
Very funny.
You look for him when you can't find him around,
And look for him so that nobody else can ever get him.
Oh -- No, it's nothing like that!
I don't love him!
I don't even think about him!
Y -- You can
Have me swear on it!
-Alright.
Swear on it.
Swear by God you don't love Afzal.
He's watching you right here,
Show Him;
Tell Him you don't love Afzal.
She's found out that this Farah had written the letters.
How?
How did she find out?
Miss Mary D'Souza was a teacher at Farah's school.
She mentioned her name in a letter.
The same letter which Yasmin has in her bag.
There's just one way left for you.
Swear to God and say
That you don't love Farah Ibrahim.
You're Molvi Subhanallah's son.
You wouldn't swear to God over a falsehood, would you?
Stop.
What about Yasmin?
She'll be coming back after having her admit it for real.
And what if she actually admitted to it?
What about your engagement?
It'll break, won't it?
Answer me!
-She'll never admit it.
She'll swear over it and say she'd not written the letters.
And it is indeed true, Arifa, that she's not written the letters.
Then Miss Mary D'Souza -- Her handwriting --?
I told you
That's not her handwriting.
Don't you feel ashamed to think
That she loves you, and she's searching for the one
Whom you love?
Come.
Come on, mate.
You'd started going down the path of God, so where have you ended up?
Nowhere.
You'd just left Hyderabad and ended up in Karachi.
And here you are, thinking whether
You've never left Hyderabad,
Or never returned from Karachi.
How are you, Mr Fiancé?
Come inside.
I saw you playing cricket.
You're such an ace, mate!
Don't say 'mate;' Dad may hear it!
These are mere parting discourtesies, my dear;
Then, who knows what may become of me
And you?
Tell him to not look at me with such fury!
Don't look at her with such fury!
Why did you go there?
Eh?
For the sake of Molvi Uncle's coconut biscuits.
Please agree to what I'm saying!
And for your Mum's sake.
She sees your image in Farah.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital