Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Listen!
Where to?
-To Samina's.
Today's her wedding anniversary.
As in, it's been another year.
Is hers the kind of wedding one would commemorate?
Her husband does every year.
After all, it's her husband's 'love marriage' to her.
In two years of this 'love marriage', she's been beaten by her 'lover' some 200 times!
Only God will ask about this.
What will you give her as a gift?
Why would she need one?
She has a far greater need for cash.
I'm thinking I'd give her a thousand.
And who will get the security guard his food?
I'll be back before he is.
And who'll tell you he's back?
Well,
I get to know
The moment he sets foot in the alley!
May I go now?
Yes.
Go.
But please do tell me when you're back
How you get to know the moment he sets foot in the alley.
Peace, Aunt.
Babu Hamid!
Babu Hamid's not here.
I've come back because of you.
Tell me you're awestruck to look at me!
Yes.
I sure am awestruck.
That's why I don't deck up too much!
The thing is,
It's Samina's wedding anniversary.
I'm going to attend that.
Oh.
Good.
If you stare at me like that, the evil eye would curse me.
Say that it's as the Lord has willed [compliment]!
As the Lord has willed.
Do you guard
Empty-handed,
Or do you carry a gun, too?
No,
I have a gun with me.
Where is it if it's with you?
Of course,
I leave it there.
Bring it along someday.
Why?
What'd you do with it?
Fire it, of course.
Wali would be scared if he found out!
You don't need to scare him; he's already scared.
He's scared of you.
If, one of these days, you left, or got married,
What would I do?
I'd be left alone.
Then, you get married too!
Leave that be!
Which lad would marry me while Wali's around?
I'll take care of Wali.
Just prepare for the wedding.
Is that a proposal?
Proposal?
Would you look at your own condition?
Earning 10,000 a month and talking about Yasmin!
When did I ever talk about Yasmin?
And whenever did I propose?
There!
That's it with all the lads!
If a girl rejects them, they'd promptly say, 'Sorry'!
'That's not what I meant; you're mistaken'.
I swear to God I didn't mean that!
You don't need to swear.
I'm 21 now, so I can understand in a moment what such things mean.
What are your plans for the future?
Plans for the future?
One should know when this blue uniform will be taken off and you'll become a great man.
What makes a great man?
The one who has a respectable job or the one who has a lot of money?
I have neither.
-Your name's out.
Out of?
I'd kept you as an option.
Proposals will line up once Wali's out of the picture, you'll see!
I thought once you got a respectable job,
I could think about you, too!
She
Must be waiting for you.
Who?
Samina. It's her wedding anniversary, innit?
Good Lord, it's so late!
And you!
You have such a habit of keeping one talking whenever one says two words to you!
Alright, I'll get going.
And
If you need any tea, or even water,
Just ask Mam.
Alright.
And don't stare like that.
Have you ever seen modesty in my eyes?
I can see that.
Your eyes should have just as much modesty, alright?
See,
To be comely is no flaw; please, do look.
But not in a way that it seems
You're looking at me the wrong way.
Fine.
I'll get going.
Happy wedding anniversary!
What is it?
Nothing.
Nothing, really. Sit.
Where is he?
He's not come.
You've kept a cake with candles here as if he's on the way. Call him!
His phone's switched off.
So that's what you're so sad about.
Sit tight,
I'll be back.
-Wait.
Tell me,
If someone asked you what kind of a girl Samina is,
What would you tell him?
Why are you asking that?
Just asking.
I want to see myself through your eyes.
I swear by your modesty and loyalty.
Don't swear by my loyalty.
I'm incapable of being loyal now.
What do you mean?
If you don't like it, just say,
'You have no right to live, Samina'.
Who said you have no right to live?
And why are you saying this today?
I'm leaving today.
I was just waiting for you.
If he comes back, ask him
To forgive me,
And set me free.
It's you, Aunt!
Would you like to have dinner right now?
No,
But when Babu Hamid's here,
I'll have dinner.
He'll be here shortly.
Alright.
Come here and sit. I want to talk to you about something.
Did you have a house of your own in Hyderabad?
I mean, you didn't rent a flat, did you?
No.
Why, then, have you come here to work for 10,000 a month?
It's just...
That destiny brought me here.
Surely, your marriage is not being planned?
Not at all?
And you seriously don't have an affair with anyone?
I can't believe it, though,
That a lad like you couldn't find a girl.
I swear to God I haven't.
But you have, now, right?
You've put her under such a spell that she tries to keep you happy day and night!
Who?
You're being demure?
No, I'm a bit worried.
Why?
Why are you worried?
You just said,
She tries day and night to keep me happy.
I thought you're actually talking about someone.
I'm talking about Yasmin.
She's very nice,
Yes, she does look a tad like the angry type,
But
She isn't really that type.
So, what do you think about her?
Or do I have to tell you what she thinks about you?
Yasmin?
-Samina's leaving, Mam!
She won't live with him anymore.
She's packing her things and saying,
'Forgive me',
'But I won't live with Salim any longer'.
Come with me. This way.
Samina?
Where are you going at this hour?
He's fallen from a moving bus!
His phone's lost, too!
He's got injuries on his head and face.
But he's fine now.
He was using someone else's phone,
And said, 'I'd have to stay at the hospital'.
'It'd be better if you come'.
In that case, take Afzal along.
-No.
He suspects Afzal, too.
Afzal scolded him one day,
And he quietened.
He came home drunk yesterday, saying, 'Tell me everything',
'What's going on between the two of you'?
He's never going to change.
But don't worry.
I'm not going anywhere.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Very good morning.
Tell me, now,
Do you remember me?
Mehtab.
Mehtab Chawla.
Don't you remember?
Farah Ibrahim's fiancé.
The engagement may have been temporarily broken, but that does not mean I'd forget you.
Whatever are you, mate?
Working as a security guard, dreaming of marrying Farah Ibrahim?
I don't, anymore.
In plainer words, she's found out about your situation.
Yes, sir.
Can you see this office?
Which office, sir?
Why, the same you're standing outside as a security guard.
I can, sir.
I'm having an office just as big as this one built.
If you want, you can leave this job and come to me for work.
I'll even give you a raise.
Thank you, sir.
How much do you earn?
10,000 a month.
Good Lord!
10,000 a month, and
Loving Farah Ibrahim!
Leave love out of this, sir.
When love came into this world,
It didn't bring wealth to this world.
Good one.
Stay with it.
We'll meet again
After the break.
Have you bought the cake?
Bought the cake, and some sweets, too.
Monseigneur had said that it's not proper to just bring a cake.
That's right, but for those whose son's missing...
How could I give them sweets?
Anyway,
He'll be found if he's gone missing.
I'll say it's for searching for him. Let's go.
Come.
Get the glass fitted nice and quick.
Mademoiselle, it seems like someone's thrown a stone at this!
A flower vase, not a stone.
But don't keep on talking; get the glass fixed.
The work's going on.
The vase is alright, innit?
Nobody's downstairs except the servants.
Where's Mum?
She's gone over to Afzal's.
Who is it?
Peace be upon you. It's you, Aunt!
And upon you, peace.
Mum, would you look at who's here!
Come.
In the name of the Lord [auspicious beginning].
What are the sweets and cake for?
I'll tell you in a moment.
But first, give me a hug.
I've come to your place for the first time.
That's what this is for.
Thank you.
Please, come.
I thought you'd come to tell me about Farah's wedding,
And that's what the sweets are for.
That day shall come, too, if the Lord so wills.
For now, I just thought I'd meet you and ask how you are.
You're very brave.
When God gives one Afzal ['the most excellent one'],
He gives one the most formidable ['Afzal'] courage.
Tea, or coffee?
Coffee.
Would you have coffee, too, Mum?
It's enough for me that she has a cup.
How are your daughters?
By the Lord's grace, they're both fine.
Farah had come to meet you.
I was scared to see her.
I even asked her, 'What has my Afzal done this time'?
But Afzal had left by then.
Yes...
It was only when she reminded me
That I remembered that he'd left...
But what's it with these lads?
They'd even tease one in one's thoughts!
Touché on that one.
Monseigneur
Came back from the Mosque rather distressed one of these days.
He told me that Molvi Sahab was only praying for the good name
And righteous conduct of children.
My Afzal's conduct is righteous.
It's just that he has a bad name.
People have great expectations from a Molvi's son.
They say that angels are born to the family of a Molvi.
One's good name is quite naturally at stake.
Monseigneur thinks the same.
He thinks one can't find someone like Afzal anywhere in Hyderabad.
Look at the Lord's doing!
He isn't anywhere in Hyderabad himself.
Please give me his picture.
Picture?
What'd you do with it?
Monseigneur has asked for one.
He said he'd send one to Karachi.
It'd take just four or six days to find him.
Don't worry,
When Monseigneur's determined to do something,
He doesn't rest until he's accomplished it.
How old is he?
Old?
Yes, how old is he?
By the Lord's grace, he's completed 56 years.
-May God will
That he complete another 56!
Arifa!
Bring the coffee already!
And while you're at it,
Get me a cup as well.
Please, sit.
I'll get the picture.
Hello?
Farah?
Yes?
Didn't you recognise me?
It's Mehtab.
But your voice doesn't sound like Mehtab's.
Your voice doesn't sound like Farah's either.
Well,
Let's be brief.
Why have you called?
Who's fuelling that arrogance?
The man with a gun doing his job for 10,000 a month?
Who are you talking about?
Your lover, of course!
Afzal?
Yes.
Your Afzal.
Where'd you see him?
I saw him twice,
And
I've just seen him now.
Is he in Karachi?
As if you don't know at all!
I do know,
But I thought he may've lied to me...
He's been telling the truth so far...
So, tell me, where in Karachi is he?
He's a security guard at my friend's office, the bugger!
Don't insult him!
Alright,
Insult him if you like...
No problem.
'No problem'?
Tell me the address.
It's Farah, right?
Do I have to repeat it every now and then?
No.
The thing is
Your voice sounds just like Lubna's.
Anyway,
Give me his address.
So he hasn't given you his address?
Would you talk a load of rubbish or tell me the address?
I'd tell you on one condition.
Condition?
Go on.
Tell me that you'd reconsider me.
'Reconsider'?
By the Lord, he isn't your type!
He looks like a hooligan,
And sounds unlettered.
After all, status matters!
Yes...
Sometimes, I think about all of this, too.
Tell me the address,
I'd catch him red-handed.
The blighter
Had told me
He's got an office in Karachi!
Hey!
Such a white lie!
That's it!
Alright, I'll text you his address.
No, just tell me the address.
No need to text me.
I've got a pen and paper with me.
I'll write it down.
Then, write down.
Go on...
Okay,
Thank you.
The pleasure's all mine.
Okay, bye.
-Bye, but tell me, you'd reconsider me, right?
I'd have to, now!
Have a good day.
I will.
You too.
Bye.
What were you doing in my room?
Looking for you.
Why?
It's --
I'd come to tell you
That he'd called.
Who?
Afzal.
He was saying, 'Congratulations',
'I've got a job'.
He's enlisted as a security guard for 10,000 a month.
So you'd come to tell me this.
No.
I'd come to tell you that there's no chance of a rejection now.
He's got a job now!
What's his number?
Whatever it may be,
I'm not telling you that!
Monseigneur's said 4 to 6 days.
One can't tell whether it'll be 4 or 6.
Either way,
Tell him that one's gone by.
Didn't I tell you,
Now that Monseigneur's decided on it, he'd bring Afzal back.
That's alright, but
I don't have the courage for any more than 4 to 6 days.
May it not be that his ride stop
Only when my pall is borne.
God forbid!
May the Lord bless you with a long life.
You have to see your son's happiness now.
Whether or nor I see his happiness,
It'd delight me
If I saw him.
Just tell Monseigneur about my condition as you've seen me,
If the Lord wills so, he'd be so merciful...
In the Lord's protection [farewell].
God be with ye.
Do you ask people to have mercy, Mum?
When have I ever asked people, my dear?
I'm crying out to Him
So that He may listen somehow.
Open the door!
There.
Give me his number.
I can't give you his number.
He's sworn by his head.
I'm having you swear by my head!
A sister's head is no more than a watermelon in front of the beloved's head!
Remember, then,
There'll be such a scene today
That you'd remember till your last breath!
Another scene?
Let Dad come.
You say that everyday,
But one can see clearly that you've not even talked to Mum!
One 'I've tasted blood',
And you said that I was singing!
Give me his number.
Don't even think about his number.
Have you no shame?
Exactly! That's the thing about love -
First, you feel shy and ashamed to admit it...
Then,
You're left with everything but shame!
So things have gotten so far?
That's my grief...
Before things could go anywhere,
That wretch went to Karachi.
Alright, brace yourself.
Why?
I'm going to talk to Mum and Dad today.
I swear by you,
I will, today!
What happens next is your fate!
Wait!
I have his address.
I can give you that.
Mum's here.
What happened, Mum?
Don't ask me anything.
This lass has been a tyrant.
She's earned the curses of a mother and a sister.
What's that in your hand?
His picture.
I've brought one for your Dad.
He's said he'd be able to find him in a few days.
You don't need to search now, Mum.
His address has been found.
In fact, his new cellphone number's been found out, too.
What's his address?
And what's his phone number?
The number's in Lubna's cellphone,
And the address in her hand.
Get it from her, will you?
And please don't tell me later
That someone's cursing me,
Because it's my turn to curse now.
One incantation from me
May very well burn your sweet Lubna to death.
Why do you have his address and phone number?
Why isn't it with Farah?
Why would Farah have it?
Whatever is she to him?
She'd invited his family over and left them humiliated.
And what had she said about him?
'He's a first rate fraudster'?
'A lover for hire'?
Now, if he's sent me his address,
Why is she up in flames?
I don't fear her incantations either.
The prayers of those who slander love like that don't work,
Let alone curses!
Where's his address?
Here.
And phone number?
I don't have his number.
I'd lied to her.
May I go?
I'll take my leave.
Hello, Lubna?
'Lubna' again?
I'd told you I'm not Lubna.
I'd said it then,
But today, the number is Lubna's, too!
Mehtab,
Everything's upside-down in love.
If an honourable man can steal your heart,
Can't I steal Lubna's cellphone?
Yes...
Touché.
So, even if you get a call from Dad's phone,
Just think that Farah's calling.
Okay, I get it.
But promise me, too,
That you won't talk in Dad's voice when calling from his number.
Don't be silly, Mehtab.
If I call from Dad's number, just think that Dad's talking.
I'm not that silly either.
Alright,
Did you meet Afzal again?
Am I a pleb who'd meet a security guard like Afzal again and again?
You don't understand the dignity of work at all!
That's why I could never love you!
Please don't say that.
I've wept over you a lot...
You daft dimbo! You can weep, but can't respect someone working honestly?
This --
You're saying 'daft dimbo' in good humour, right?
I wish you would've just kissed Afzal's face on seeing him,
Held his hand like a faithful devotee, saying,
'You're such a great man, Afzal'.
'While at this job, you didn't think at all'
'That your salary is just 10,000 and designation nothing'!
How could I kiss Afzal's face?
Seeing him makes my blood boil!
I feel like breaking his face!
But then,
I stop because of you.
Because of me?
You're impressed by him, right?
He may do any lowly work, and you call it 'dignity', right?
Alright,
Keep an eye on him.
Eye?
I mean, don't let him go anywhere.
I want to catch the blighter red-handed.
Why do you want to catch him, Farah?
Why don't you let go?
You don't understand a girl's problem.
She breaks a hundred times over before her trust breaks.
Just think that if I saw him in a security guard's uniform,
My trust would be blown to bits.
The bugger!
He would shatter into a thousand pieces within me.
You're insulting him?
When the tormented can't curse,
They utter insults!
You'd be right in saying that.
Just tell me
How he looked in the uniform.
Oh!
He's fair,
And with a blue uniform!
The bilghter would show such a contrast!
The sissy looks hideous!
He has a gun, too?
Obviously! A security guard has a gun.
Good Lord!
Why are you saying 'Good Lord'?
He's the first soldier in love's legion!
He's not a soldier; the bugger's a servant!
He gets up to salute the toffs.
It's a habit with him.
He's Molvi Subhanallah's son,
He must've taught him
To greet even enemies and wish them peace.
Did he wish you peace?
Wouldn't Daniyal have fired him if he'd not done so?
Who's this bugger Daniyal?
Please don't call Daniyal a bugger.
He's my friend.
Where are you right now?
At my office?
Go to M. Daniyal's office right now.
Why?
I've told you to keep an eye, haven't I?
Don't let the blighter go anywhere.
He won't go anywhere.
Cads like him may desert a girl,
But never a job.
You're right there...
That's why he's left me...
You're in regret, right?
A lot.
But you don't quite understand girls' problem.
Hey!
What's the problem now?
I want to see the blighter in a blue uniform for the last time!
It kills me to think
What the bugger would be looking like!
I like it when you insult him.
Just wait and see,
Watch out for every four-letter-word I'd say to him when I've got hold of him!
Then, I promise you, Farah Ibrahim,
I won't let him go anywhere.
He'd be there until you've got your hands on him.
Swear by me.
I swear by your head.
So sweet of you.
I'll disconnect.
Hold on!
Don't disconnect just yet.
Do you want to say something?
Just tell me
Whose number would you call from the next time?
I swear by you,
I'd call using my own number the next time.
Bye.
The engagement may have been temporarily broken, but that does not mean I'd forget you.
Whatever are you, mate?
Working as a security guard, dreaming of marrying Farah Ibrahim?
I'm having an office just as big as this one built.
If you want, you can leave this job and come to me for work.
I'll even give you a raise.
Thank you, sir.
How much do you earn?
10,000 a month.
You're a Molvi's son, aren't you?
So, I give you this chance -
Say your prayers.
Time's running out.
You can't say your prayers while I count to ten.
Don't count to ten.
I've said my prayers.
Your time's running out, now.
Shoot the bugger!
He's got something going on!
He'd kill me if he got out! What are you waiting for? Shoot the bugger!
Afzal!
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital