Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
What's up?
I'm watching a film.
Which one?
'Vaastav' ('The Reality').
'Vaastav' ('The Reality')?
Hey!
You'd said that it's one about hooligans.
Yuck! What a subject.
I'd heard so about it back then.
I'd not watched it.
Now that I'm watching,
I get a feeling it's a rather remarkable subject.
You're a rather remarkable subject too, Farah!
And I think Dad's right.
You should be married to a psychiatrist.
What?
An ordinary husband would commit suicide on the wedding night.
Shut up!
He's given you his heart.
Who?
The same.
Your psychiatrist.
The one you'd consulted to be cured.
Good joke.
It's no joke, Farah.
He's coming tonight.
He'd meet and talk to Dad, and take you along.
What?
I'd said too, when Dad asked me,
'Hmm'...
'Not a bad idea'.
Dad asked you?
He doesn't trust you one bit.
He said, 'I'd decide everything'
'And give her the news when the date of the marriage is fixed'.
'Her' as in, 'me'?
Yes.
Where's Dad?
Sit tight, Farah.
To have a daughter is no farce,
So you'd rather not teach Dad
That he'd be punished repeatedly for the sin of being delighted to have two,
Nor mither him by telling him
That you've started liking 'Vaastav'.
He's coming tonight.
If Dad says yes, be a good daughter and say,
'As it pleases Dad'.
Lubna!
Lubna has outlived her usefulness.
When Dads start praying for their daughters' marriage,
Take it they stay awake for 4 hours and sleep for 2.
And this psychiatrist,
He's not a wastrel like Mehtab.
His reputation precedes him in the city.
He's got three clinics.
What else do you want?
That's the sticky limit!
Peace be upon you. I hope I'm on time.
-Peace be upon you.
Just in time, yes.
Peace be upon you.
-And upon you, peace. May you live long.
Come, Monsieur le Docteur.
Peace be upon you.
-And upon you, peace.
Sir,
Please don't address me as 'Monsieur le Docteur'; I get the feeling I'm visiting a chronic patient.
Come.
-Right.
Farah!
Farah, the chap's here!
I mean, the good man's here.
Farah?
Where are you, Farah?
Hey!
You're so predictable.
I knew it,
You'd be here if not in your room!
He's here
And looking so handsome!
Just the thought of a psychiatrist
Gives me the chills!
I'm sure it gives him the chills, too,
Marrying one's patient is no trifle either.
But some people are just naturally a tad adventurous!
What be my orders?
Do I change
And go before him?
Should I say, 'Yes'?
But have Dad promise, then,
That he'd sleep for all 6 hours.
You agreed!
Wait, Lubna!
I'm not as predictable as you folks think I am.
That's it.
That's why they're marrying you off to a psychiatrist!
Psychiatrists aren't spectacularly predictable either!
Your parents are in Yorkshire, aren't they?
-That's right.
When would they be coming?
In a week or so?
Did you send them a picture?
I did back then itself.
They just keep looking at it.
Maw was saying,
'However did you get such a bonnie lass'?
What did you say, then?
However did you get her?
I said, 'It's because I'm a psychiatrist'.
In the beginning, both of them
Were against my decision to become a psychiatrist.
'In Pakistan', says Dad,
'A psychiatrist is considered no more worthy than an aliéniste'.
Farah says the same!
Except that she says it to my face.
May I come in?
Yes.
We're done talking.
She's...
Left her room and is sitting on the swing.
Would you allow me to meet her?
Sure, my dear. Go.
Where's the swing?
On the terrace.
It must be blustery up there.
Yes.
It is.
Fresh air, and a lot of it does the trick for such patients.
Now --
Look, my dear,
Don't even call her a patient by mistake.
I'm saying this before you,
I can't even think of saying this before her.
Shall we go up to the terrace?
Sure.
Excuse me.
Listen, my dear.
If she says something foul,
Don't get angry.
Psychiatrists never
Get angry,
Aunt.
May I come in?
Who is it?
Sibtain.
Sibtain who?
Your psychiatrist.
I mean, the one who's a psychiatrist by profession.
They've sent the blighter upstairs!
Lubna!
She left me here and went.
Come.
You're the type to babble your heart out loud.
What do you mean?
I heard it hen you said 'blighter'.
Oops...
I -- I'm sorry...
No, no -- It's okay.
It happens often in my profession.
Once,
In fact,
A patient abused my mother and my sister,
But I said,
'No problem'.
'It's okay'.
Accursed be such a profession!
Initially, my parents used to say the same.
But when they saw
The same patients, after being cured, bless my mother and sister from the depths of their hearts, they were happy with it, too.
You're still thinking of me as your patient?
No, no -- Not at all.
The thing is,
I spend so much time at my clinic
That it's become a habit, so to speak.
In fact, even when one of the mannies says something like a gowk,
I say,
'Mate',
'You look right like a patient'.
Why have you come up here?
I mean --
When Mum and Dad approve of this match,
Why this formality?
That's an intelligent question.
Wait!
Answer her later.
The thing is,
There's no place to sit on the terrace except the swing, so I thought I'd give you this chair.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Please, carry on.
She is so sweet!
Then marry her, will you?
Why are you thinking about me?
The thing is,
Once you've thought about someone in love,
You've thought just about the one.
-Oh?
So psychiatrists love too?
Hey!
Why are you making a trifle of a psychiatrist?
We're the only ones who love genuinely.
The others just have affairs!
Ohh...
Oh, as in?
Pray tell,
I mean, when a girl says 'Ohh' to words of love,
What does it mean?
May I?
Please.
It means
'As it pleases Maw and Paw'.
Get up.
I said get up!
Come with me!
Look down there!
I can't look down.
I --
I have acrophobia.
I have acrophobia too!
But I'd rather jump from here and die
Than marry you!
I'm sorry.
Perhaps my words hurt you too much.
But I can't help it.
It's okay.
Then go downstairs this instant,
And -- Say to Dad,
'I can't marry a girl so depraved as Farah'!
No.
Under no circumstance am I rejecting this marriage.
Why can't you?
It'd kill my parents' emotions.
With such difficulty, they've found a daughter-in-law who's liked by both the parties.
Both the parties?
My parents and I are two separate parties.
Usually, it's that the girl they like is one I don't lik --
-And the one you like is one they don't.
Not at all.
Earlier, I had no interest in girls at all.
I thought of them as patients.
Every girl
Loves one and gets married off to another.
And the greatest irony is that they live life happily after marriage.
But this time,
It's different.
I've found one
Who gets unhinged
At the very thought of a different lad.
It's
Time for me to go to my clinic; my patients would be waiting.
See you.
If only one would look, begging for mercy,
If love is true,
It can make the mountains melt!
It'll work if you come everyday for seven days.
I will, Father.
I'll come here all my life if it works for me.
Show such devotion to Him, too.
Offer your prayers,
Bow to Him.
Just so much would delight him.
I will, Father.
Wipe your tears, then.
One weeps and begs from Him,
And not begs and weeps.
Go.
Right, Afzal, matey,
The area from here to here is yours.
And the one from here to here,
Except this 10 kilometre stretch in-between,
The next 10 kilometre stretch is yours.
Why have you left the 10 kilometre stretch in the middle?
That's my area, matey.
Oh...
And beyond that?
Beyond that reign the others.
Fanne Khan, Rehmat Baloch, Gullu Qainchi and the others.
By the way,
Najju,
How many murders have you committed?
16.
The one just now, though,
That lucky wretch escaped alive.
And how many out of these 16
Did you feel pity for, as you killed them?
There ain't room for pity in this profession, matey.
Alright; you must know how many of them were innocent?
4 of them were completely innocent.
Why are you asking this, matey?
Just asking.
The thing is,
I think a tad differently.
I think
One should not kill the innocent.
In this profession, matey,
If you show so much as an ounce of pity, you'd regret it the next day.
There ain't a next day in our lives, Najju, matey!
To sleep is to die,
To wake up again is to live another day.
That's right, matey.
My father used to say
That an outlaw's life is only up to his thirties.
Either he no longer remains an outlaw after his thirties,
Or he no longer remains alive.
It's two.
I'll get going, matey.
Bye.
Speaking of which, Najju, matey,
Yes, matey?
How old are you?
In or past your thirties?
Past, matey.
Say goodbye, then.
Goodbye.
Najju would've served us well.
So he would've, mate,
But he only served his evil intentions.
And then,
He'd killed four people who were innocent.
Why are you distressed?
There is cause for me to be distressed.
I saw the map of the city today.
Not a corner of the city is under the Government's writ.
It's been cut up into pieces, a hoodlum reigning over each.
Another hoodlum takes over the moment one's reign ends.
This traffic signal
Is a traffic signal only for the public.
It's a border for the ruffians.
Kingdoms change from one signal to another,
As does the ruffian's name.
I can't talk to Dad,
Or I'd show him the map and tell him that the faithful are losing,
And the sinners are reigning supreme.
I've ordered sleeping pills for you.
There's one by the jug of water in your room.
5 mg?
5 mg.
I long to go to Hyderabad, mate.
I miss those alleys a lot
That I, complete with trousers, shirt and tie,
With a lunch box from Arifa in my hands, would walk through on my way to the bus stop.
That kind of walking had its own kind of romance, Babloo.
Look, Afzal,
It's not too late yet.
Hyderabad awaits you to this day.
Just decide on it and get out of here.
I can't get out of here even if I decided on it.
I feel
I'm here for this purpose.
What purpose?
To murder those who kill 16 something.
I swear by God, until I'm past my thirties,
I'll hunt down and kill each of these buggers.
Farah?
I was yearning to meet you since last night,
So came here first thing in the morning.
Come in.
Mum and Dad are alright, aren't they?
Yes.
Molvi Uncle must be at home?
These days, he is at home.
Well, at least there's the satisfaction
That he's happy
Wherever he is.
Come here.
Let me greet Aunt first.
Mum!
Farah sends her greetings.
And upon you, peace.
There's nothing to be shocked, really.
Seeing Mum, one feels like solacing her...
But she says,
'Beware'!
'Nobody shall comfort or solace me'!
How's Lubna?
She keeps sorrow at an arm's length,
And is thus happy.
She doesn't even know that I've come here to meet you.
Got any wind about him, any news?
Got word from someone about what he's been doing?
One needn't listen or search for news about him.
One gets to see his photograph in one newspaper or another,
And with it, a chronicle of his craft.
Yesterday,
He's killed a hoodlum by the name of Najju.
Hey!
You're affrighted!
Dad's affrighted, too.
But he's affrighted that people would start fearing him.
Didn't I always say
That he'd end up in bad company if he went to Karachi?
That's what happened, innit?
Leave him.
Tell me,
What'll you have?
Tea or coffee?
He may still be reformed, Arifa.
No...
It's no good reforming those who commit murders.
They either go to jail, or to the gallows.
Dad closed his eyes tightly when he heard about his first murder.
Then, regaining control, he said,
'We won't be getting him back, Arifa',
'We'd only get the news about him one day'.
You didn't tell me -
Would you rather have tea or coffee?
How easily you say
Such fatal words!
I'm the sister of a fabled Bhai [= brother, hoodlum];
His fame resounds throughout Karachi.
Now, I'd say such things with fearless audacity.
Have some tea.
N -- No.
I won't be able to drink it.
Try and find the Farah who used to write him letters somehow.
She can stop him.
You think I'm kidding?
No.
I'm saying it myself,
If I chance upon that lassie!
What would you say to her if you chanced upon her?
What is there to say, really?
I'd explain it to her and say, 'Go',
'You're better off marrying someone better'!
'Start a new life, you wee lassie'.
No heartfelt words can reach where he stands now.
How would her letters reach him?
And may God will that she'd have been married off when I next see her,
Going somewhere with her husband...
I wouldn't be able to recognise her even if I did.
I'm getting married.
To whom?
Dad's
Found a psychiatrist.
He used to think I needed to see one,
So I went to him.
I found out
It was he who needed to see me.
Blessed be you.
At least show some of that delight.
If he's Dad's choice, he must be a good man.
Yes...
I've seen it, too.
You always end up choosing a dreadful one yourself.
When are you getting married?
I don't know.
Judging by Dad's intentions, though,
It won't be too long.
Don't invite Mum and Dad.
Call me and I'll come.
Shall I take my leave, then?
You'd come just to tell me about your marriage?
Yes.
This way.
Right, this way.
I'm leaving, Aunt.
She must have fallen asleep.
She takes a pill at night,
And dozes off in the morning.
I think that's right, what you said.
If you chance upon the Farah who wrote him letters,
Tell her to get married, too.
Settle with her husband and start a merry life.
He's not coming back.
Peace be upon you.
-And upon you, peace.
Where's Afzal Bhai?
-Please, sit.
He's coming.
Tea or coffee?
Coffee.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
How are you?
Fine.
Please, sit.
Thank you.
Thank you, Monsieur.
I've been supporting the police for two months,
But I don't trust you.
-Look, Monsieur,
The police won't sign any agreement with you
To show their trust.
You've supported the police,
Which is why, in these two months,
Not one of the bobbies
Has so much as glanced his eye at you.
But I've not been told who gives me the money,
And why are my tantrums being borne up with?
You will never find out about the money,
But let me tell you why your tantrums are being borne up with.
The target it costs
The police
And the Government
Millions to get to,
And yet earns them the courts' barbs,
You get to that target in a few hundreds of thousands.
So actually,
Less is being spent,
And more is being saved.
So the Government is paying the money.
I'd said you'd never find out about that.
Alright, then, you'd have to answer my second question.
Ask away.
How long are you keeping me alive?
As long as you want to.
A lie.
If you won't enter politics,
At the end of the road, you'll be presented with two options.
And in the second option, you'll be asked
To take your money,
And leave the country.
And what will they ask of me in the first option?
They'll say, 'Say your prayers'.
I'm the son of Molvi Subhanallah.
I routinely say my prayers.
What'll they do if I enter politics?
They won't even give you so much respite as to say your prayers.
The thing is, you're new in this trade,
And you're half a Molvi yourself, at that,
Thus, it'll take you a while to find out
That everyone's a hoodlum in politics.
Politics has changed greatly, Monsieur.
Politicians don't kill each other now;
They kill each other's henchmen.
Although it makes the job easy for the police,
It doesn't benefit the Government.
If the riches of the Treasury
Fall into the hands of hoodlums,
New hooligans are brought up
To snatch them back.
So, if one hooligan dies,
You get news that two have replaced him.
Do you take bribes?
One's got to, Monsieur.
Otherwise, for so much as sitting the wrong way on my chair,
Saluting a few moments late,
Or firing two additional bullets,
I could be inculpated.
But I swear, Monsieur,
I don't disgrace the uniform.
Have you brought the money?
Yes.
It's in the car.
Alright, I'll not ask for too much information.
But the next time you send me a dossier on a ruffian,
Please do write in the footnote the name of the one who's been nurturing him.
I'm sorry, Afzal Bhai,
The other hoodlums are being nurtured
In much the same way someone's nurturing you.
Should you get furious,
This city will forever remain a hostage held by hooligans.
And should you refuse,
You'd be asked to say your prayers.
I know
That you routinely say your prayers.
But when they say, 'Say your prayers',
It means you'll be saying your prayers for the last time.
Ask someone
To get the bag from the car.
We'll meet again.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital