Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
He's talking about running away!
Although I scolded him the moment I heard it,
His words have stuck with me.
It's no problem to you,
Whether he stays here or runs away,
And runs away to Yasmin or someone else,
It won't change anything for you.
I do have a problem.
I was thinking about
What'd happen to you.
What'd happen to me?
He's running away from you, too.
As in, he doesn't love you, either.
He is in love,
But he's afraid to speak up.
He's not expressive.
Go and talk to him,
Have him swear on you...
Say that,
'May he leave this place'
'Over my dead body'!
Hey!
That'll sort everything out.
If he swore on you and left,
Just think
That he's very expressive.
That he says the truth to someone's face.
No way!
If I have him swear with such audacity,
He'd think I'm head over heels for him.
Then tell him you're head over heels for him.
What's the shame now?
It isn't about shame...
A girl's got to have some ego, Farah.
Should I talk?
I'll talk,
And have him swear.
Hold on, Farah! What are you doing?
-Let go of my hand!
I won't let the blighter run away from everywhere!
Look at how much Mum and Dad are running around for him!
He should understand what that means, shouldn't he?
And
How much longer will you keep singing 'I've tasted blood'?
Your voice is bad, sure,
But your feeling surely isn't, right?
Wait, Farah! What are you doing?
Listen to me!
By the Lord!
Did you see that?
It's happened, hasn't it?
What has happened?
Afzal's run away!
What?
He told the doctor, 'I've started walking now',
'I'd run away by the evening'.
That's very unfortunate, Irsa...
What would I tell Molvi Sahab, now?
Why should you tell anything?
He'd have to answer himself!
Why are we responsible for his doing?
Hold it, Farah!
Just think of where he'd go in the condition he ran away in!
To Yasmin's?
Well, you can't think of anything else!
So, where'd he go?
Looking for Wali.
The one who'd murdered Babu Hamid.
And remember, all of you,
Everyone would hear very bad news by the evening if he found Wali.
Who knows what'd befall Molvi Sahab...
The next bit of news might as well kill him.
Can you see that?
This way leads to Sea View.
That means
The sea is right where it once was.
Alright, now...
Ask how far their place is.
How far is it, good man?
We'd be there in 15 minutes.
Please, Ruqaiyya Begum,
Hold on to yourself today.
Don't slap him in your fury.
Right...
Many people hear the whack of a slap,
And if Farah and Lubna
Happen to be there,
You could safely say that all of Karachi is listening.
Good evening, Modryb.
Good evening.
Come in.
I can't believe it, Modryb.
You'd believe it when the two of you have met.
What's this, Wali?
You've brought your cronies along today, too?
No, Modryb, they're not cronies.
I've got a wedding procession with me.
-Oh?
So you've fully prepared, too?
Come in.
C'mon.
Good evening.
Very very good evening.
Sit.
How --
How much I've fought for this one moment.
I'd even been so discourteous to my Modryb...
Please, forgive me, Modryb.
What's this apology for, Wali?
One gets discourteous in love and war...
Tea, or coffee?
Coffee today.
Just a moment.
Seriously, though, Wali,
You killed Babu Hamid for nothing.
The poor lad was a nice man.
She still cries in his memory.
Tell her not to, Modryb.
One doesn't cry for any other man.
Besides,
Murders happen in love and war.
Do you see how lively she is, Modryb?
I'll take you along tomorrow!
Tomorrow?
The day after, if not tomorrow.
As you say.
Now, I'd only do as you say, Modryb.
Then, take her today.
There won't be a tomorrow.
Why, Modryb?
Do you fear anyone?
Yes, that's right.
Afzal, you know...
He's fine now.
He's started walking.
So?
So what?
I'm afraid.
She was drawn to him in the beginning.
What do you mean? She'd fallen in love?
-No.
Not love; just fondness.
Fondness, though, as in,
Fondness today, love tomorrow.
Easy there, don't worry.
Have your coffee.
Sit tight, Wali,
Or I'll fill you with lead.
Do you know how much thoughtful labour it takes to brew a cup of coffee?
The poor lass has put a lot of effort making it.
You'd have spilt it if you'd run away, wouldn't you?
Alright,
Drink it.
Drink it sip by sip.
I'll sit here and watch you drink coffee until then.
The two of you have conspired against me, haven't you?
You've handed me over to the enemy.
I've recovered you through them.
I didn't have the time to look for someone like you.
How could I do everything else if I'd kept looking for you, eh, bugger?
Why are you looking at the window?
Your four minions
Won't come to help you one bit.
Ask why.
Why?
The four of them are all dead.
Alright,
Have your coffee.
Here.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
Now, before asking
How we are, quickly tell me
Where the blighter is!
I feel like exchanging blows with him first!
This way, isn't it?
Yes.
Come.
Afzal!
You blighter! You've been caught!
I'm here now!
I've brought your Mum and Arifa along!
Afzal!
Where is he?
Please, sit down and have some tea.
We'll talk.
There, now.
We haven't come here to talk, Monseigneur.
We've come here to meet him.
Please, allow us to meet him.
This meeting is not possible, Madame.
He's left.
Where's the key?
In my pocket.
Take it out.
No, my dear --
I didn't ask for water...
Give it to her,
She's crying a lot.
Aunt, why don't you have this?
It'll ease you a little.
No, my dear.
I've been eased.
I've shed a few tears when the moment came,
So, I've been eased, so to speak.
Why don't you have it, my dear?
You haven't even shed a single tear.
There!
She's been eased, too.
Get up, Molvi Sahab.
We should turn back and leave,
Or the night will be a long one.
How can that be, Madame?
If we have to go back, we'd leave together tomorrow morning.
We'd have to go back, Monseigneur.
He's gone,
And so are we, you could say.
Look, he didn't tell me anything before leaving.
It's possible that he'd come back.
That's something I like about you, Monseigneur,
You put a dying soul on a ventilator.
You never let one's hope die out.
He's left his things here.
That means he'd come back.
The guard told me that he said he's going to get a cigarette.
He's started smoking, too?
He'd smoke a few now and then there, too...
He doesn't have any such habit, really...
Would you happen to have sleeping pills?
No problem if you don't have any.
She'd stay awake
Even after taking one,
And when she stays awake,
She doesn't let me sleep.
Where are his things?
In that room.
Where are you off to, Ruqaiyya Begum?
The rapscallion leaves his scent behind even after he's left.
He's left us,
Let me see if he's given up that habit, too.
Afzal...
My Afzal...
I used to make aeroplanes like that in my younger days.
Tad would be delighted to see, and say in a lively voice, 'You'll see, Arifa',
'My son will become a pilot one day'.
Arifa?
Arifa was my Mam's name.
Hey!
My sister's name is Arifa!
Surely, your Mam's name isn't Ruqaiyya?
Yes!
My Mum's name is Ruqaiyya.
How do you know?
Ruqaiyya was my younger sister's name.
So you'd kill me?
I don't want to kill you either.
It would pain my Dad a lot to hear
That a faithful one has killed another.
It'd pain me, too.
But, you bugger,
You took the life of a faithful man,
And killed another deep inside?
Forgive me.
That's it...
I've been thinking about that, too.
But how can I forgive you?
Alright.
Tell me something positive,
Hearing which
I could have mercy.
Afzal, I can be very useful.
I'm Najju's right hand man.
I've seen that you're made of the right stuff.
Come with me, I can introduce you to matey.
You can do his work
And earn millions.
What
Is this matey's name?
Najju.
He's committed 16 murders.
He marches about the city,
But the police don't dare raise an eye at Najju.
Call your 'matey'.
-What's the need to call?
Come with me,
I'll seat you right before him.
Call him.
A -- Alright -- Phone...
Aye, matey, it's me, Wali.
Go on.
Why are you so scared?
No, matey --
I'm not scared --
I'm negotiating with Afzal.
I'm having a deal with him.
Who's Afzal?
I'm Afzal.
Afzal Subhanallah.
Who are you?
Just like there's a 'matey' backing every hoodlum,
Every 'matey' out there's got his oul fella.
I've asked you who you are.
I'm your oul fella, Najju.
I've just gotten this post.
Give the phone to Wali.
Wali, --
-Listen, Najju!
Talk to your oul fella.
Later on, you'd think that it'd have been better if you had.
Alright,
Make a deal with me.
What deal?
Give me a good mansion,
Two cars,
And 5 million.
It'll prolong your life.
Or else?
What'd you do?
It's simple, Najju,
I'd kill you.
You bleedin' --
-No, no...
Don't abuse me.
I won't take the money after such abuses.
I'd take your life.
Alright, disconnect now.
And when you offer prayers for Wali tomorrow, pause and think
Why no one's given the call to this prayer,
Because, Najju, matey,
Death doesn't knock before coming in.
So you'd kill me?
That's what I've been thinking about.
It's my first murder,
And that scares me.
Please.
Sit.
Everything's alright, isn't it, Monseigneur?
Yes, everything's fine so far,
But if this night passes off fine,
You'll get good news in the morning.
So,
Why, then, are you worried, Monseigneur?
Look,
I --
Otherwise have a lot of courage,
But, seeing you in this perplexed state,
My courage has begun to break.
That is precisely why I'm talking to you in solitude.
If Madame
Heard it, she'd start wailing.
Wailing?
Look...
Your son...
He's alright, isn't he?
Yes, he's fine, but...
He'd taken two bullets to his leg a few days ago.
That was nothing serious, really,
He was fine in a few days, but...
B -- b -- but?
The same people murdered his friend, Babu Hamid.
Just a few days ago.
You're listening, aren't you, Molvi Sahab?
Yes?
He's gone looking for them,
Especially the lad who'd murdered Babu Hamid.
What'd he do
When he's found them?
You tell me what he'd do.
You know him better.
Ruqaiyya!
Come, Ruqaiyya Begum!
Pack your things.
'Tis the reckoning.
Afzal isn't coming back.
Afzal isn't coming back...
-Afzal!
He's not coming back...
There's no turning back from where I stand now,
And you're going back
From where you've come.
Listen to me, Afzal,
5 million, 2 cars, a nice mansion -- I can give you.
Just spare me.
I won't even walk down Yasmin's alley again. If you see me, you can shoot me dead.
Surely, you won't, Wali.
But what would I do?
How would I walk past the cemetery where there's a new grave of one Babu Hamid?
Isn't it a question
You don't have the answer to?
I've been seeing Babu Hamid in my dreams for four days without a break.
He says, 'You'd mocked the Lahoris, eh'?
'Tell me, now',
'Are Hyderabadis weaklings'?
You're unknown in this city.
Here dwell the kind that'd swallow you whole without opening their mouths!
Join hands with me,
And you'll see
Where I take you.
Your words enrage my friends.
Come here, Babloo.
Take his phone.
Najju's number is saved in it.
Forgive me, Wali,
But I can't remember Dad's words at this moment;
All I can see is Babu Hamid's face.
Give my regards to Babu Hamid.
I said call him here.
He's coming in a few minutes. He's afraid.
Strange.
He's fearing me
And I him...
Dad!
Forgive me for all my sins!
For God's sake, forgive me!
You blighter!
You'd leave Hyderabad for the one who doesn't love you,
And you'd leave those who love you
In Hyderabad?
Why didn't you wake me up?
No one needs any waking up in this house now, my dear.
I knew that you were awake.
She is, too.
Take care of her.
In the Lord's protection [Goodbye].
It's raining heavily outside.
Ah, yes --
I can see that.
What happened?
I've been slapped hard in the face.
I've been told not to go out.
Henceforth,
Someone else will lead the prayers.
Who's told you, Dad?
Who could it be except Him?
How would He accept, now,
That a hoodlum's father
Should go about his priestly duties at the Mosque?
He's forcefully retired me.
Get up, Ruqaiyya Begum!
The prayer and time are both slipping from our hands.
You may leave.
I'll prepare it.
You get up at daybreak everyday.
I thought you'd pray today.
Visit Hyderabad for once.
It'll ease you if you meet Mum and Dad for once.
I can't go there.
Why can't you?
Dad would've thundered his judgement on me,
Proclaimed me a sinner and spat on me.
He doesn't pronounce judgements anymore.
He's stopped going
To the Mosque for the last one month.
He says, 'Priesthood is not proper for me'.
Who told you?
Alladio.
Where is he?
He's sleeping.
He'd die in agony if he doesn't go to the Mosque.
I know my virtuous Dad very well.
That's why I'm saying that you should go for once.
One look at the sinner's face would resurrect his honour.
He'd insult me,
He'd say, 'Don't you dare set your foot at my doorstep'!
Or, he'd say, 'Ruqaiyya',
'Stop him'.
'Do not let him desecrate any part of my house beyond the doorstep'.
When it's a matter of virtuousness and sin,
Mum always supports him.
She'd say,
'Who are you, my good man'?
'Whom do you want to meet'?
It'd kill me to hear that, mate.
Then sleep through daybreak.
Be done with this telepathy.
Every one of your family is awake at this hour.
Then, give me sleeping pills.
5 mg.
I'll sleep through daybreak.
Yes?
Who are you?
Whom do you want to meet?
I'm Sajid, Samina.
So what if you're Sajid?
Whom do you want to meet?
You're deliberately not recognising me, innit?
Your name sounds familiar, you look familiar.
Look,
An enemy of my husband's is named Sajid.
Please, leave
If you're the same.
Please, leave.
That makes you
My enemy as well.
... And there are distances now,
Someone was close to me,
And there are distances now...
Destined for man
Is such helplessness...
So what,
If he has altered course,
I'd stay quiet
Without aspersing and disgracing him...
How many are alive without their lov --
The estate agent had come in the morning.
He said he's found a new tenant.
He'd pay 12,000 a month,
And he was willing to pay a year's advance.
I don't want the 12,000 a month or a year's advance.
What do you mean?
No tenant will live in this house now.
The ones that came and left have been enough.
How would things go on?
The money saved up for my wedding
Are enough for four years.
Won't you get married?
Why wouldn't I?
As long as that blighter is a 'Bhai' [hoodlum],
Marriage to him isn't possible.
The day he's no longer one
Would be the day he'd come to me.
I wouldn't need so much money for the wedding then.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital