Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
May I come in, Dad?
Two minutes; that's all you have.
And, for these two minutes,
Stay at an arm's length from me.
Go away!
Away!
Don't touch me.
Your mother
Had named you.
I'd said back then, 'Ruqaiyya Begum',
'The name's august'.
'It won't be easy'
'To live up to and honour it'.
Why don't you tell me
What kind of an 'Great Person' [Afzal] are you?
Change my name.
I don't know who's the greater one around here -
Those who die in their innocence, or the ones whom I've killed,
Who kill 16-something others,
And parade around the city fearlessly.
I would've become a great man [Afzal], Dad,
If only someone showed me what greatness ought to be like.
You're either at the Mosque, or at home.
With the Lord there, and the Lord's faithful people here.
You don't know what's going on here, Dad.
A thief who stole 2 billion is bargained with,
And another who steals 2,000 is sentenced to two years in prison.
It's just that the petty thief is not respected.
The greatest of thieves are hailed as the greatest of men.
I can't fit in with all of these, Dad,
Which is why I request you to change my name.
Have you convinced your mother?
With my head in her lap,
She was running her fingers through my hair.
She's affrighted
That
You may go back.
Tell me, did she say anything?
Did she talk to you --
Any complaint --
Did she carp about you?
No.
Go to her, then,
And ask her
To give you a tight slap on your face.
Slapping you
Will build her confidence.
What are you looking at?
Go and give her reason to believe
That, even after being slapped, you wouldn't
Dare set foot outside the house!
Then, she'd
Talk to you confidently.
Otherwise, she'd just keep fearing you.
And you'd do well
To fear a mother who's scared, my child.
Arifa!
What are you cooking?
I think --
We can prepare chicken pulao; he enjoys it thoroughly.
And some thin green gram lentil along with it.
But no,
I don't know if he'll have that...
Get to work already, what are you looking at? Now --
Get some bread and braised meat ready; I'll prepare whatever he'd like to have.
What would you like, Afzal?
I've not been slapped by Mum for so long.
I'd like to have that for starters.
May you live long.
You've become a great man,
But haven't forgotten your mother's silly pastimes.
May you be prosperous, my dear.
I'd sworn as I came here
To never go back.
There, now.
What are you talking about?
This is your home.
Stay here as long as you like,
And leave whenever you want to.
You've got a car, now, too.
You need no ticket now,
Nor is there the fuss of going to the station.
You just have to get in your car and leave.
You're staying here tonight, aren't you?
I'm asking you because if you're staying,
I'll prepare some rice and lentils for you.
You used to enjoy it so much.
Won't you forgive me?
You'll have to, Ruqaiyya Begum.
Give him a nice slap and
Settle all scores,
Or I'll be pronouncing a final judgement
And throw him out of the house.
I'll go and see --
-Why would you?
If someone rings the bell,
Would your sister go and see, you blighter?
Get going!
Go!
I've come to meet your wife.
To congratulate her.
In fact,
Congratulations to you, too!
You've brought a right comely lassie along from Karachi.
Step aside.
Hey, Arifa!
Where are you, mate?
Farah!
Hey!
You've brought flowers!
Would you look at that!
I've brought these for her.
I'd made friends with her in Karachi.
Here.
You do remember, don't you?
Yes.
Then embrace me.
I've come to congratulate you about your engagement.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
Molvi Uncle!
Just one prayer has got you hale and hearty!
Do you know what's gotten me hale and hearty?
What?
I've gotten used to hearing 'Uncle Molvi'.
I thought
Who'd call me that over there?
Peace be upon you, Aunt.
And upon you, peace.
May you live long.
Please, sit.
I'll sit with my friends.
Alright.
Yes.
Go.
What are you looking at?
She's started a murder spree like you.
She kills
By her mere words.
Alright now, tell me the story.
Who said 'I love you' first?
Nobody did.
He came to me one day,
And said, 'Get engaged to me tomorrow'.
Coffee?
Yes.
Right,
You'd have said yes immediately?
I'd seen it, Yasmin,
I could glimpse him in your eyes.
And I could glimpse him in your eyes.
Well,
I didn't say yes immediately either.
I said, 'Why tomorrow'?
'Why don't you talk about the day after'?
As in, you must've just said it as a nicety, so to speak,
As in,
Just to feed your own ego.
He didn't let any ego remain.
He said, 'Tomorrow means tomorrow'.
'Neither today, nor the day after'.
Why, mate?
May I tell that?
Would you rather conceal it even now?
The Farah who wrote the letters was getting engaged that day.
He wanted to give her a befitting reply.
No --
I was getting engaged that day.
Molvi Uncle had a heart attack at my engagement.
What's the matter?
So you write letters to him?
By the Lord, no!
Yes --
Her name's Farah, too.
Initially, everyone here suspected it too,
But I cleared everything up.
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
That's a right coincidence,
Three engagements on the same day.
Wow...
The two of you weren't even acquainted?
The two of us, as in?
You and Afzal.
We were acquainted.
He's Arifa's brother,
Molvi Uncle's son,
And lives in the neighbourhood,
So we were naturally very well acquainted.
Then, who's the one who used to write those letters?
If she was getting engaged that night, why were you getting engaged that night?
What do you mean?
I mean, the real coincidence is that both the girls, except for me,
Getting engaged that night are named Farah.
Would you think about that!
Why were both of them named Farah?
Why should I think about that?
You should.
He's your fiancé, after all!
I'm his fiancée, Farah,
Not his love.
I'd just
Stepped in to give a befitting reply.
There's nothing to worry about.
These lads have loved at least once or twice before they're married.
They might have.
But he's only loved once,
And as long as he lives, he'll only love her.
But then,
Why did you get engaged to him?
I'd fallen for him, Farah.
The allure of his proposal enticed me.
I thought that I deserved at least an engagement to him.
You sound raving mad to me!
You're saying it as if it's not an engagement,
But a temporary arrangement.
The blighter's very handsome.
One would lose one's heart to him easily.
I'm surprised to wonder why you let him come to Karachi in the first place.
I let him?
Never mind,
Let's talk about you.
Don't you think he's handsome?
I do.
But he doesn't belong to my class.
He fits in with you nicely.
Why are you laughing?
I'm laughing at how you brought class in.
I'm remembering the day
When you'd come to our place, looking for him.
Right.
With Dad, right?
'With Dad', so just to speak.
It was you who was looking for him.
I was just having a look at my cupboard.
You were looking through her letters.
Take these and throw them away.
You don't need proofs of your previous love to start anew.
If you burnt these,
It'd ease the poor lassie's searing pain.
You're here until Sunday, aren't you?
Yes, perhaps.
Alright, then.
We'll have a ball on Sunday.
What's on Sunday?
I'm getting married.
Hey!
You've not even been engaged yet.
How can you get married?
Ask Molvi Uncle and tell me,
Is it necessary to get engaged before marriage?
No.
I didn't mean that.
I'm just a bit shocked.
So suddenly, so quickly...
I can't believe it.
But I can believe now;
You, too, have decided to give him a befitting reply!
To whom?
That's what nobody can know.
Everyone's giving a befitting reply to someone,
But doesn't tell his name.
I'll take my leave.
You'd come just to tell that?
No --
I'd come to congratulate you.
Would you see that!
I forgot it entirely!
Promise me
That you'll stay here until Sunday.
I promise.
I won't go even if someone took me away.
I'll take you along when I go shopping.
Sure.
Mum!
Are you listening?
Farah's getting married this Sunday!
Alright.
God be with ye.
Farah's left?
Yes.
What did you say? Who's getting married?
Farah's getting married, Mum.
She's getting married this Sunday.
There's no need to smile so broadly.
Where's Uncle?
He's watching the news.
And where's your sister?
What's her name --?
Farah Ibrahim?
She's in her room.
Then take me straight to her room.
What?
I'll show her today that Sibtain Akhtar Ali is not going to fear any wee lassie out there!
That angry face will be getting a slap.
I'll take it, but will speak my heart out to her face.
Put a sock in it!
As if you've got the guts!
You --
Just tell me where her room is.
The wedding date's been finalised, innit?
I know all of it.
What would you say, then?
I've thought of ten different ways to decline.
But your Mum and Dad are overjoyed.
To the dickens with Maw and Paw!
Good Lord!
You're furious!
Nobody's seen my fury yet!
You're under my oath,
Show your fury before you leave.
Well, shan, whatever do you want?
There was no danger until the engagement; should I marry her, now?
Have you studied science?
Then understand it clearly -
Marriage is a chemical change.
No inducements can bring the substances back to their original states.
Run!
Get going.
Now that he's here,
He'll be up to more of the same.
He's deliberately aimed his shot.
It's me.
Where are you, Monsieur?
It's been three days and we haven't the foggiest!
I'm in Hyderabad.
But as per the terms of the deal,
You cannot leave the town without permission.
I just left.
What did you leave?
You and your town.
Are you alright?
I'm alright, sir.
I'm on the streets of my neighbourhood, playing cricket.
Surely,
You're kidding?
I don't know what you understand by 'kidding'.
Look, M. Afzal,
You are needed here.
I'm being asked where you are and when you'll be coming.
Tell them I'm not coming.
I'll be playing cricket on the streets of my neighbourhood,
And live my life with Mum and Dad.
Where are the letters, Arifa?
Which letters?
The same
That Farah used to write to him.
They're in Afzal's cupboard.
He's kept them safely with him?
Have you read them?
Yes...
Three or four of them.
I will, too.
Don't.
It is not proper of you to read them.
Why isn't it?
They're not letters, Yasmin,
They're chronicles of love.
Someone else has written them.
So?
Their words will come back to mock you tomorrow if you read them today.
And I will regret it tomorrow, Arifa, if I didn't read them today.
I'll never know how much she loves him.
I just want to see
If she loves him more than I do.
Ask Afzal,
He'd let you read them.
He'd never let me read them.
He'd think that I'd feel sad to read them.
Swear to me, then,
You won't feel sad.
I'm a girl, Arifa.
And girls are the kind who'd beckon to sorrow just like that!
How can I swear to you?
Alright,
I'll test my courage.
Girls should not test their courage.
Don't fear.
Show me the letters.
Over here.
What's the matter?
What is it? Why are you so anxious?
She's in Afzal's room, reading the letters.
'She',
As in Yasmin?
Yes.
She's read them?
My heart says she's reading them.
Oh, so it's your heart that's said it.
The news isn't true, so to speak.
Ruqaiyya Subhanallah is my name.
I can read intentions, Molvi Sahab.
Alright, you can read intentions...
Then,
Pray tell, what is that
Your Afzal is up to?
What is he up to?
Is he talking about going back?
When did I say he's talking about going back?
You just claimed,
'I can read intentions',
So I thought I'd just as well ask you
What
He would do now.
You're --
You give such a fright, Molvi Sahab.
Speaking of which,
Truly, you should fear.
He's only been engaged,
And he's sitting with his fiancée before your eyes in his room.
This
Is not proper.
Which part of it is not proper?
And who's ran into his room with his fiancée?
Fear God, Molvi Sahab,
Arifa's with her in the room.
Afzal's gone to meet his friends.
There's no power but God's!
Don't exclaim that,
Go and knock the door,
And
Dissuade her from reading the letters.
By the Lord, lady,
Let her read them.
What's the worst that can happen?
Oh,
You're asking me!
I'd gotten my hands one letter of Fajr's!
I remember it line by line to this day,
Just -- what was that song? What were its lyrics --?
'Uhh -- O you who met my gaze and turned away',
-'I have no complaints from you'.
I have told you a hundred times,
She'd written this rather sheepishly!
Otherwise, unlike your son,
I'm no longer involved in such exchanges of letters! Right?
Who's this Miss Mary?
Miss Mary?
This letter speaks of a certain Miss Mary.
She'd seen Afzal.
Seen, as in?
Outside the school.
Wow!
This is love from good old childhood days, Arifa.
It's been going on since schooldays.
That's enough, put these letters away.
Don't read any further.
Take all the letters except this one.
I'll keep this one with me.
Why?
What'd you do with it?
Just --
It feels as if there's something in this letter.
Don't worry.
I'm not keeping it forever.
I'll give it back to you in a couple of days.
Where are you going?
To your room.
I'll read it a few times,
Research over it,
And you'll see,
I'll dig up something interesting!
It's not about the elephant, Monseigneur,
But about the scallywag.
He's afraid of sitting on an elephant.
Gone are the days, Monsieur, when grooms would ride an elephant.
Just have him ride a horse.
I said the same to him,
But he flared up at the mention of a horse.
He says,
'I don't trust it'!
'Who knows what it could do if it decided to gallop'!
Let me talk to Madame.
Sure, I will.
Here. Talk to him.
Hello?
Where's our daughter-in-law?
She's just come back, Monsieur,
She'd gone to give her friends
From the University cards for her wedding.
Yes.
That's alright.
Saturday
9 p.m.
After the news?
Alright, bring the henna.
God be with ye.
What's up with you?
What's up?
It appears you've been traumatised.
You're suddenly all worked up!
Not at all --
No way.
I just -- Thought when I heard of the elephant,
That if he rode an elephant,
Won't it stall all the traffic?
Ah, right.
I'd never thought of that.
Leave it be.
Don't think of it.
Let him ride an elephant if he wishes to.
Whoever cares about the traffic here?
But
Why am I anxious, Farah?
What are you anxious about?
Everything's been decided now.
I've agreed, too,
And I'm as firm as a boulder on my intentions.
Why are you anxious, then?
Please, don't be.
I won't step back.
That's the problem!
Problem, as in?
I mean, you won't step back.
What if he stepped back, though?
I have a hunch, Farah,
He'll not be coming.
He'll vanish on the wedding day.
I'm feeling the same.
It must've burnt right through him, this news.
That's what I want, too.
He should burn in agony for one day.
He may vanish, then, if he wants!
Grab his sweet Yasmin's hand quietly,
And leave for Karachi.
You're talking about Afzal?
Obviously.
I'm talking about Sibtain Akhtar Ali, Sherlock!
What?
So you think he'll vanish on the wedding day?
Yes.
That's what I feel.
Dad will throw him under the elephant's foot and kill him!
Look,
I can't exactly tell you, Farah,
But he doesn't want to marry you.
He doesn't want to marry me?
That blighter, the twopenny-halfpenny psychiatrist?
No.
I don't believe this.
He loves me!
He doesn't love you, Farah.
You're saying that
As if you've gotten your hands on his diary,
Or you've caught him red-handed.
Alright, tell me,
If he doesn't love me,
Whom does he love?
Do you, by any chance, fear God at all?
Sibtain's Mum and Dad will be downstairs any moment,
And you're up with this quiz game up here.
Pray tell,
Who loves whom?
Are you talking about Salman Khan?
Or Aamir Khan?
Irrfan Khan.
There!
Now is that too big for his boots!
That twit's into these affaires de cœur!
Anyway,
You can tell me with whom later.
For now, come downstairs.
This Irrfan Khan is the same, isn't he,
Spindly,
Dark-complexioned,
Puffy-eyed?
Afzal, just tell me one thing, mate,
Does she no longer write you letters?
I mean,
You haven't read out a new one for seven months.
I've gotten engaged, mate.
She won't write me anything now.
You got engaged just a few days ago.
I'm talking about the time before the engagement.
Leave it, mate.
I've gotten engaged, intentions changed,
Just think that the girl who used to write letters has changed, too.
-The bugger's lying.
You're afraid of Yasmin, aren't you?
Yes.
I'm afraid of everyone who loves me, Babloo.
Very afraid.
This fear has brought me back to Hyderabad.
She loved you too.
Weren't you afraid when getting engaged?
I didn't.
Ask why.
Why?
All fear of her had vanished.
She was getting engaged on the same day.
And now, I've heard she's getting married, too.
I'll get going, mate.
The call to the night prayer will be heard any moment.
Everything's alright, innit?
Yes.
Ev --
Everything's alright.
Nothing's alright.
And if something's still alright,
It won't be now.
What happened?
She's reading your letters.
Letters?
Don't ask who gave her.
Can Arifa turn down an order of our daughter-in-law's?
Don't look at her.
Focus your eyes
On what's to come.
She thought she'd just glance over them and put them back in the cupboard,
But I've heard she's reading them as if
Preparing for an exam.
And she's taken such a liking to one of those letters
That she clenched it in her hand and ran away.
She says she'd 'research' over it.
Where is she?
In my room.
Hey!
You don't have the right to go into her room.
She's still an outsider to you.
I won't go into her room, Mum.
I'll knock on the door and say, 'Give the letter back'.
Yes.
That's fine.
But still, take Arifa along.
Come.
And listen,
Request her.
Don't show your anger, okay?
Alright.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital