Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
No.
I won't Dad at your work's.
I mean, I --
Won't work at your Dad's.
Who has asked you to?
Work for us till December.
For you?
You'll get such a salary you'd be left counting it all!
And a designation that will leave you awestruck!
H -- How much?
As much as you say!
I mean as much as you can think of!
And
Designation?
We can decide your designation if you agree.
Where's your office?
We don't have an office.
What?
Lubna,
I don't want a poltroon for this job.
No --
I'm not a poltroon.
Then say yes!
Why are you asking our office address?
It's all legal, isn't it?
No,
I mean I've promised Dad I'd not do anything dodgy.
I'm sorry.
I just said 'dodgy' spontaneously.
Then say it with firmness that you're ready!
What's with the firmness?
I mean,
Does it involve a threat to my life?
Yes, it may.
So say it plainly that you won't do it.
How can that be?
I'll do it even if it means putting my life at risk.
-Good.
That's the spirit!
What's the job?
I'll tell you. Have something first.
How will I have something?
I'm not hungry.
You're lying.
You were opening your lunch box before my eyes!
No --
That was because Arifa had said...
Actually,
Arifa orders me like a mother;
So I thought I'd eat.
I was really not hungry.
Lubna,
Let's talk business.
Alright, we'll pay you 200,000 a month.
200,000?
Farah will pay you from her personal account,
That is why you won't get more than that.
And we'll give you additional allowance
For your dresses and all.
You --
You're must be kidding!
You're kidding.
You're pretending as if you've never seen 200,000.
I haven't.
I've only seen the 98,000
That I won playing the matches.
Playing matches or gambling?
Can you stand firm and talk to our father ?
I can.
But I have great respect for him.
He called me today and said, 'Take your place at our office'.
Are you out of your mind?
You'd leave a job that gets you 200,000 and take one that earns you 10,000?
I won't.
But --
Must I stand firm before him?
Is he into this business too?
The entire business lies in his hands.
You just have to snatch it from him for four months.
What are you looking for?
A handkerchief.
Thank you.
To snatch the business from a father's hands is sinful.
Listen to the whole thing.
Yes?
Pray tell, I'm listening...
The thing is, Farah is getting married to Mehtab Chawla on the 15th of December.
Look at me!
Right, so where was I?
Glass -- water.
Did you hear what I just said?
Yes.
The truth is that Farah does not want to marry him.
Now that the date's been fixed, the situation's gotten a tad bit hairy.
But Farah has found a way out of this.
She's mustered the courage to tell Dad
That she does not want to marry Mehtab
Because she loves someone else.
In all truthfulness, this isn't quite true either.
She doesn't love anyone.
She just wants the marriage put on ice.
And
That's where you come in to help.
Help?
Your help and the job are one and the same.
What do I have to do?
Love Farah for four months --
-What's this balderdash!
I -- I mean, act as if you love her.
If necessary, you'd stand firm before Dad in saying,
'I love Farah so much that I'd die without her'!
You'll take it quietly if he wants to whack you over it.
If he aims his gun, you'll say resolutely,
'Shoot me'!
But I can assure you
It won't come to that.
And if it does come to that,
His aim's nawful!
My aunt made it out alive, too!
Excuse me...
Why did he black out like that?
I've told you,
He's taken a shock.
What shock?
Besides a salary of 200,000,
I'm allowing him to love me for four months!
How could this ever shock
A clerk earning 10,000?
Try to understand, Farah.
His heart's woeful right now.
How is that?
Try to remember
Whose son he is.
Why do I need to try to remember?
If you do remember, I hope you'd understand
That he thinks like Molvi Sahab.
Meaning?
What does he think?
He's thinking
About what a girl from an honourable family is doing to one-up her father!
Put a sock in it!
It's merely been days since he turned so faithful!
When one has newly turned faithful,
He sticks to his principles faithfully!
Anyway,
You don't need to get worried.
We can find someone else.
What?
You want to besmirch my name everywhere!
That blighter will tell his sister,
And what will she think about me?
She'll not think of anything but call me
And ask me about what Afzal is saying.
I'll say it plainly,
'He's lying'.
You'd better.
And say it in a way
That if Molvi Sahab heard it, he'd break his face!
May I go now?
Go where?
Sit.
And don't you dare budge from here until this smirch is washed off me!
Smirch?
Oh God...
Who is it?
Dad?
It's me.
It's you!
How come you're here so early?
-Let me get in.
Why are you shivering?
I can't figure out myself.
Where's Mum?
She's gone to Aunt Kausar's to lustrate her child.
She'll be back soon.
Get me a quilt.
A quilt?
This cold is killing me...
Go to your room.
Take me, will you?
You have a fever too...
It's just a fever...
It may be malaria.
No.
I don't have malaria.
I say
Go and see a doctor.
What do I tell him?
For God's sake,
Get yourself checked up.
Why are you feeling so cold in the summer?
Could it actually be malaria?
Just give me a quilt.
I'll start sweating in a moment.
You would, sure.
Alright, I'll get you one.
What do I have to do?
Love Farah for four months --
-What's this balderdash!
I -- I mean, act as if you love her.
If necessary, you'd stand firm before Dad in saying,
'I love Farah so much that I'd die without her'!
Here.
Quickly, now...
I think you're fine!
Show me your hand.
The temperature's worn off...
Shall I turn on the fan?
-Beware!
What's this way of talking?
Why 'beware'?
I just uttered --
I mean, don't turn on the fan.
I'll start shivering again.
You've got malaria, then.
That's what makes you hot and cold.
To be honest,
I don't have malaria.
I swear.
Would you please tell me what has happened?
Stay quiet, Mum!
Walk so that your footfalls cannot be heard!
Alright...
Come.
What happened?
-Malaria.
What?
It doesn't seem so...
Not me, Dad, he's got it. Afzal!
He's in his room wrapped in a quilt.
With a quilt?
-Yes.
Came home early from office.
-Oh?
I swear, Dad, he was shivering so much!
Come and see!
Look at him.
He's all drenched with sweat.
Why didn't he see a doctor?
I'd asked him to,
But he didn't agree to.
What's there to agree or disagree over here?
Wake him up.
Everything seems to be alright here...
Wake up, my good man!
Dad?
It's you...
What happened?
Nothing.
Arifa here
Told me you were shivering when you came back from the office?
It was just about then...
I'm fine now.
You won't see a doctor?
What would I do?
I neither have a fever nor am I shivering.
I hope everything is alright at your office?
No --
There's no problem there.
It's been two days since Monseigneur last came for his morning prayers.
He doesn't usually do so when he's in town.
You must be meeting him sometimes?
Some --
Sometimes, yes.
Alright, I say
You get some rest.
Prepare some yahni for him.
If he starts shivering again,
Drag him to the doctor's.
Call him later.
Yes, Dad.
And when will your mother be back?
Before sunset.
Alright.
Close the door.
Get me some yahni, will you?
And yes,
Where's the key to the cupboard?
If I'm not mistaken,
Monseigneur's daughter
Is your friend, isn't she?
What's her name --?
Lubna.
What happened?
Nothing, really.
I'm sure she calls you once in a while?
Yes, sometimes.
She always asks about you.
Meh.
Sit down for a while, so that I, too, get a feeling that I'm preparing yahni for someone who's ill.
Such ornate sets, Madame, that would bedazzle Farah!
Not a single bangle is without diamonds.
Have you purchased everything?
Why not?
Purchased them and had them kept in the locker.
We're now thinking about the dresses.
I'm looking at gold embroidery samples.
It'll take at least 50 biscuits.
Biscuits?
You know, bars of pure gold.
We call them 'biscuits'.
Oh...
And Mehtab here was saying that he'd gift her a Ferrari when he'd come to see her.
Ferrari?
Yes, it's a bit dear, but
Not more than our Farah, certainly!
Tell me,
How go your preparations?
We're just deciding...
Deciding?
Monseigneur will call you in the evening when he's back.
That's new.
New?
The men of your family talk about the wedding preparations?
He's
Been preparing for a few days.
He'll tell you everything today.
Okay.
I would request you, Madame...
Yes?
Ask Farah
To talk to Mehtab sometimes.
What's with all the shyness in her conduct?
Shyness is but natural in her conduct --
I mean,
This, too, will be decided tonight.
Right...
How could I say this to Monseigneur?
God willing, it will not have to come to that.
He'll tell everything.
Alright,
I'll talk to him about this too.
Give my love to Farah.
Bye.
Ohh...
You agreed to everything she said.
Don't be too hasty.
It's just a matter of a few hours.
It'll all get started
As soon as Monseigneur calls.
Hey!
You're out here, studying peacefully,
While your future is being decided over there!
Tonight, at last, you'll have to tell
Who he is.
What can I do?
Think about it and tell me his name!
Whom do I name?
You'd suggested that blighter,
But he blacked out as soon as he heard it!
Purify yourself.
Purify?
It isn't time for praying yet.
It's time for an additional prayer.
Resolve to offer 100 of them,
And sit on the prayer mat right now.
What are you saying?
By God, girl!
When you can't find a way out yourself,
You ask for God's help!
Quickly; Mum's coming.
And Dad's coming in an hour too.
Which prayer is she offering right now?
It's time for neither the sunset one, nor the dusk one.
Care to tell
Which prayer is she offering right now?
Additional prayers.
She'd made a vow
To offer a hundred additional prayers if her special job is done.
A hundred?
And what was this vow about?
The same, Mum, about Mehtab.
She's even taken to praying regularly that she's not married off to him.
Here, she's offering additional prayers to fulfil her vow,
And there, Shugufta has had jewellery worth hundreds of thousands made.
And she was telling me that every kind of ornament
Has diamonds studded in it.
So how is this cause for worry?
They'll be of use to some other girl.
They'll be of use
When your father declines them.
So why don't you say it?
'Please decline'!
Call that boy first.
She's not even telling me his name.
She'll tell you after her prayers.
Stop her halfway.
Tell her that her job's not done yet.
She'll be complaining to God for nothing later on.
And tell her yourself
To be downstairs with all the lad's details before your father arrives.
Otherwise, it's none of my responsibility.
By the Lord, she didn't feel any shame when falling in love with him,
But now she's feeling shame in mentioning his name!
How many are you done with?
Just 12.
-Enough.
Ask for blessings, and continue with the remaining 88 after the news bulletin.
Why?
Ask for blessings,
Bolt the door,
Sit and think who he is!
You'll be facing Dad in an hour!
Dad will call to decline
Only if you can argue your case before him.
Or else
Neither your destiny,
Nor the date of your marriage will change.
Where are you going?
Excuse me, please!
Your narking has fried my brains!
You could say I'd die the moment Dad would thunder.
No more help, sweetheart.
It's over!
Oui, Monsieur Mehtab?
Not Mehtab...
Afzal.
Hey!
You called?
I thought you'd never come to once you were out.
No.
I'm fully conscious.
So, why did you call me?
To say yes.
Yes, as in?
The job and designation you were talking about
So, I was saying
I accept.
Really?
Would I have called to lie?
You've thought about it, haven't you?
This job means putting your life on the line.
Dad can do anything when he's furious.
Please
Talk about Farah.
Farah?
Don't you remember
What she'd said at the restaurant.
What?
'It may involve a threat to your life'.
Yes?
Do you think your father will kill me?
Quite possible.
Alright, then.
It ends there.
I will sacrifice myself.
But please tell me...
Yes?
This love will go on for four months?
You'll have to keep it going on.
Will we meet, too?
Obviously, you'll get to meet us.
But what will happen after four months?
Do you know how much you'd earn in four months?
800,000.
That'd be enough.
Start a business with the 800,000, and keep on blessing Farah.
The love ends there?
Love?
I mean -- the job...
The job ends the day Farah likes a boy
And Dad says, 'He's the one'!
What about me?
What could happen?
Dad will never agree on you.
By God, he'll create such a scene at the mention of your name --
Dad will create a scene, and the two of you will act your parts.
Farah will weep before Dad, naming you,
And you will fall at his feet, saying,
'Uncle, I can't live without Farah'.
'I'd die without her; I'd take poison'!
Then?
What, then?
Farah will threaten him similarly.
He'd be scared at hers, for sure.
Won't he agree if he got scared?
He may if his daughter threatened...
But don't worry,
We've thought of a way out of this too.
What's the way out of that?
You'd two-time Farah.
Two-time?
That's what the onlookers will think
First, love her with all your heart,
And then run away a two-timer!
What do you mean, 'Run away'?
You --
Can't you understand what I'm saying?
What do the perfidious do?
What do they do?
Leave for Karachi for a few days, my good man...
Change your phone number,
Farah will weep before Dad and say,
'Afzal's left me, Dad'!
'He's smitten with another girl'!
I swear by God, I'm not smitten with any other girl!
Did anyone ask you?
And that girl who writes you letters,
Is she your Mum?
Anyway,
Just think
Your relationship ends
The moment you two-time her.
That's it.
That's what she wants you to do and that's what she's paying you 800,000 for.
Is it too little for you?
It's too much.
The perfidious deserves not a penny.
Alright, I'll disconnect.
Tell her the deal's done.
I'll do exactly what she says.
Farah!
If you're afraid that I may get angry on hearing his name,
You're wrong in thinking so.
I listened to it that you love someone,
And said
That I'd reject Mehtab after meeting him,
Why are you getting worried?
Don't you think
I'm a liberal father?
I consider it natural to love,
As long as it does not smirch the girl's honour.
I --
I swear, Dad...
You don't need to swear.
I trust you.
Just tell me his name.
Give me his number.
I want to talk to him.
And I promise you that once I've talked to him, I'd call to decline Mehtab.
What's the problem with you now?
Say something; answer him!
Ease her a bit.
Even if he's a tad lower in status or rank,
Accept him.
That's a thing for later, Irsa.
First, let her say something!
Just a minute!
I'm sorry, Dad.
But if you give me a minute, she'll say everything.
Alright. Come and sit here.
No, Dad, I won't sit here.
I'll take her along for a minute.
Okay.
Take her.
He's neither turned tail,
Nor declined.
He's agreed.
He's even agreed
To sacrifice himself
If Dad wants to take his life.
But today, you will only mention his name.
You will not say he's Molvi Subhanallah's son.
Did he say that?
I'm saying this.
Start off with the sparklers
Before igniting the bigger bombs.
But Mum will suspect immediately.
She'll ask, 'Are you talking about Molvi Subhanallah's son'?
What should I do, then?
You've been performing well enough so far,
So keep it up!
Mention his name, and come out of the room demurely.
Mum would swoon.
Dad would swoon, too.
But you'd better remain in your senses.
Get up the moment you name him,
And before they come to,
Come out of the room.
What's the matter now?
Will he come if you call him?
Why should I call him?
You call him now.
He'll open up when you talk to him.
Open up, as in?
He'll have to open up so he can speak openly before Dad!
Haven't you seen
He starts stammering when talking to you!
Monseigneur says that it's been a minute.
Go
And tell him quickly
That his name's Afzal.
May we talk right now?
Yes.
What's his name?
I'll only tell you his name today.
Alright.
Just his name today.
Afzal.
Afzal isn't his name --
That was a remark about his character.
That is his name.
It wasn't a remark about his character.
May I go?
Who's this Afzal?
Molvi Subhanallah's son?
Is he the same?
Tell me!
Answer me!
Tell me it's the same if he is!
Yes.
He's the same Afzal...
How is it that you are swooning over a lad from the neighbourhood,
And my angelic sixth sense hasn't the foggiest?
This means
That I have failed in my duties as a mother.
I told you, Mum...
It was just childhood feelings.
I realised when we grew up
That I love him.
I don't meet him.
Don't leave this stone unturned!
The thing is
Given the time of a year or a half,
I can correct my mistake.
How will you correct your childhood love?
Touché.
Didn't it ever occur to you,
The mention of his name could kill!
I made a mistake...
A mistake is one that's committed once,
And never repeated again.
Now, you tell me what I should do...
That's why I was quiet all along --
Hesitant to mention his name.
His name says it all.
Call him tomorrow.
And ask him to meet me first.
What'll you do when you meet him?
Let Dad meet...
You want that he should say something before your Dad
That overwhelms his heart.
Traditionally, it's the mother who meets the boy first.
Alright. Call him
And ask him when he'll come.
Also, tell me
What he likes to eat.
Leave that be, Mum.
Just -- serve him some tea.
As you wish.
A --
Ask Dad
To call Mehtab.
Don't worry; he will.
Now that you're determined, everything will end up in your favour.
May I go now?
My phone's upstairs in my room...
Go.
Done earwigging?
Shut up!
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital