Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Here's your tea.
Listen!
Yes?
Did he pray at daybreak?
I went to wake him up. Smiled in his sleep as he glimpsed me.
I thought he was dreaming, so I thought I'd let him.
I'll wake him up at daybreak tomorrow.
I'll get you admitted to the University this time.
Ask him when admissions open when he's back from office.
But what about
Co-education?
So what if it's co-education?
Maintaining one's decency is in one's own hands.
You come across men even in the markets.
Thinking like that,
That's co-education too.
Dad!
I know when admissions open.
When?
The 25th of the next month.
Right.
Would you serve some food? I'm starving.
Where's Mum?
Sleeping in her room. Shall I rouse her?
No.
Let her sleep.
Who's calling you repeatedly?
No idea.
It's an unknown number.
Calls again if I disconnect. He's called me some 10 times since the morning.
Talk to him.
I will for real.
So what?
Do you feel like insulting someone?
Hello?
Where's Farah?
Why isn't she answering the phone?
Who's on the line?
You forgot me? Didn't even recognise my voice...
Will you keep on with this blather or tell who you are?
It's Mehtab, Lubna...
Oh, Mehtab...
Where's Farah?
I've been trying her number. She's not answering.
She keeps her phone on silent mode at the University.
Want to talk to her?
-Yes, please.
I thought she'd have called me by the time I reached Karachi.
Right here, Farah. Mehtab wants to talk.
Hello.
It's Mehtab here, Farah.
I've come to know.
You didn't remember me?
I did remember you.
But I couldn't figure how I'd talk to Dad.
Talk?
To Dad?
What?
You'll know within minutes when I've talked to him.
You're the one Dad will call first.
So tell me,
How go the preparations for the wedding?
Whose wedding?
Very funny.
I like this one.
Ain't no joke.
I'm seriously asking you -
Whose wedding are you talking about?
Ours, dear, of course!
I find it awkward to answer such a question.
Ohh...
The one planned for the 15th of December...
You're talking about it, right?
Again, very funny.
You're angry because I didn't call you when I got here?
Ask, for once, why I didn't.
I was waiting that you would --
-Look, Mehtab.
It would hurt you to know,
But let me be very honest with you -
This marriage is unacceptable!
The 15th of December you're talking about,
That December will never come!
Or that December won't have a 15th!
Such fury!
Forgive me.
I was wrong.
What mistake?
I made a mistake!
I should've told you before you'd left.
But it's alright. I'll tell you now.
Our second meeting on the terrace
Was our last meeting.
L -- Last meeting?
La finale!
Did Mehtab say something [wrong]?
No.
I said something.
-Go on.
I told him I'm not marrying him.
That this marriage is unacceptable!
No matter the cost!
Then suffer the consequences.
What consequences?
An earful from Dad,
And you won't be able to bring yourself to watch Mum's ululation!
I don't worry so much about Mum...
But Dad --
-Dad may even slap you!
Oh God!
What have I done?
What if he draws his gun?
Gun?
Don't you remember?
He'd drawn his gun when Aunt...
And fired too.
That's another thing it didn't hit anyone.
But it can't be every single time
That a bullet is fired but does not hit anyone.
Where are you going?
To my room.
Stay hidden in my room.
What'll hiding do?
Going before them is dangerous.
A bullet can strike
Where a second hit won't be necessary.
Afzal!
Come here. Get in.
Whose car is this?
My brother's.
Get in, quick.
Don't go on asking questions.
No.
I'm fine.
I'll walk. Thank you.
Why are you saying 'Thank you'?
C'mon, get in!
I've decided to ride a car home
Only when I've purchased my own.
How will you purchase one?
Clerks don't get to own cars.
[Call to prayer]
Farah
Don't you think you're taking it for granted?
As, say, with a wedding.
When you're invited to one,
You accept it with delight.
And then think,
'I'll attend if I can spare time',
'Otherwise, I'll call and say, 'Sorry, mate, I had some work to do'.'
And, as it happens,
You're done for.
Don't remind me my mistakes!
I'm no Mehtab Chawla
To think we have an understanding if you scold me.
Please, Lubna,
I've realised my mistakes.
I should've rejected the proposal before they left.
And if I could not,
Then I shouldn't have phoned Mehtab and said,
'This marriage is unacceptable'!
You're regretting what you did?
Obviously.
I should've talked to Mum instead of Mehtab Chawla.
No, Madame, you should've talked to Dad.
What?
Talking to Mum will get you nowhere.
She'll just say,
'Monseigneur, this girl will drag you through the mire'!
If I talk to Dad, he'll actually drag me through a mire!
No way. Dad's not like that.
He'll be a little furious when he hears it.
But then ask stenly,
Is that your final decision?
Sure?
Be positive!
Just think as if that's going to happen.
Show some sensibility,
And when he asks
If this is your final decision,
Say firmly:
'Yes, Dad. It's my final decision'.
He won't slap me?
Good fathers don't slap their young daughters.
Surely he'll ask the reason?
Reason?
-He'll surely ask what Mehtab's fault had been.
And if there was a fault,
Why I'd not mentioned it before the date was decided upon or before he left?
That's right...
He'll ask that for sure.
What'll you say?
You tell me.
I'm totally blank. I don't know.
Oh yes!
Say the same you did to Mehtab!
What did I say to Mehtab?
'I love someone else for so long',
'We used to write letters to each other and now talk for hours over the phone'.
I'd say this to Dad?
No. Say this to Mum.
What about the mire, then?
Not at all!
You'd be deep in the mire by then.
I mean
You'd have said to Dad that you don't want to marry Mehtab.
He'll ask why.
Tell him you'd only tell that to Mum.
Yes. That's possible.
But when do I say this?
Before he watches the news.
Is there any logical reason?
Of course.
Dad will get to hear all sorts of bad news on the TV,
With your news as the icing on the cake.
God, he'll think you're Kamikaze attacking him.
Mademoiselle Farah,
Yes?
Monseigneur wants you downstairs.
Yes, Dad?
Sit.
You talked to Mehtab today?
Yes, Dad.
He called.
What did you say when he mentioned the marriage?
Tell me. What did you say?
I -- said
That this marriage is unacceptable.
Did he say something wrong?
Not at all -- he just wanted to talk.
If you'd much rather that he not call you before the marriage,
I can ask him not to.
It's not that, Dad...
What is it, then?
The fact is --
The fault -- was mine.
I should've --
Told you earlier.
What is it that you
Should've told me earlier?
That I --
I don't want to marry Mehtab.
-Couldn't you remember to say it before the date was decided?
Are you bent upon dragging us through the mire?
Don't worry about that.
Just tell me the reason.
I'll tell Mum the reason...
Come with me, then.
What did she say?
She will not marry Mehtab.
Call Mehtab and convey this rejection.
Say that it's not possible now.
Why is it not possible?
Because she loves someone else.
Who is he?
Should I ask her this too?
Yes.
This isn't something I can ask.
Get all the details from her.
Who he is, what he does,
Where does he live,
What his family background is.
What do you mean?
Try to understand, Irsa Begum.
This isn't 1992
That I could try to impose my decision at gunpoint.
If she does not want to marry Mehtab,
Alright.
I will decline the proposal.
But first, get to know very well from her who he is.
What's his status, family background, and character like?
A tad here or there in rank and status is fine by me.
But I shall not compromise
On family background and character.
Go to sleep.
How do I fall asleep?
Then get ready
For you'll be asked in a while
Who it is you love.
Who's the boy,
What's his status and rank,
What does he do,
What's his character like?
Bolt the door.
Bolt the door, please.
And if anyone asks about me,
Say, 'She died the moment the entered'!
It's time for dinner.
Have yours.
I mean -- Serve everyone.
Farah's not hungry.
You're not hungry either?
Why are you asking questions?
Go and say that Lubna's not having dinner either.
Why don't you go?
Go and see how everything is going on!
Don't be crazy,
Sleep on quietly.
I'll say you took sleeping pills if anyone asks.
What'll that do?
Buy some time!
Think about his name, address, family, and character.
If there's no one,
Imagine there is.
Name him,
Think about his family
And take it for a given
That his character's applauded in all of Hyderabad.
If I keep on lying like this,
What'll happen to my character?
Then there's just one way.
Tell me.
Tell the truth and marry Mehtab.
No way!
Then let untruth be your master and say anything you like.
It'll ruin your life to worry about your character.
Shall we go to the terrace?
What's on the terrace?
You just have to lie.
Sit here and prepare yourself.
If you gad about everywhere, you'd be caught before you're prepared.
I'll face whatever comes my way.
Do you know how happy Dad was today?
I know.
You don't know.
He said, 'Apply to a University'.
What?
No way --
I swear by you.
It's a golden opportunity, Afzal.
Yes.
Surely, apply.
I'll pay your fees.
I'm not talking about admissions and fees.
Then?
Tell me about her.
Who?
The girl who writes letters to you.
Just mention her name and address.
I'll talk to Dad.
What'll you talk about?
Won't you marry her?
I'll ask Dad to go and talk to her family.
Ask, first
Will she marry me?
Does she write letters to you just for fun?
Just think she does.
My marriage to her isn't possible.
So,
Promise me
You'll never mention her again
Nor will you ask her name.
Just think as if
There is no girl.
There's no name.
Just a dream...
That delights me when I imagine it.
And if this isn't acceptable either,
Go and ask for Dad's opinion on it.
Ask him
If delighting myself with a dream is sinful,
I will henceforth not.
Are you friends with anyone from your University?
Shut up!
Do I ever make friends with anyone?
Any class fellow
Who could be taken into confidence and asked for help?
Don't even think about it!
Farhad!
Aunt Mahjabeen's son?
-Yes!
He'll agree in an instant!
That's what we want!
Are you touched in the head?
If I name someone from the family,
I'd have to get married to him.
God forgive
But he's worse than Mehtab!
Don't put up a blank face, missy, find a way out!
Who's talking about his face?
Here I name him,
And there Aunt sets up camp at our place!
He should be the type
Who stands firm for four months,
And vanishes within minutes as the moment of the marriage approaches.
Oh God, very filmy!
So what if it is filmy?
I'm not marrying Mehtab.
No.
My heart doesn't agree to it.
In fact, it isn't just about the heart.
My mind asks me to be wary!
Alright, think about Aunt Mehru's Jamil Akhtar!
You're officially gone barmy!
Don't even talk about anyone from the family.
What, then?
You're not on speaking terms with anyone outside,
You've not got eyes for anyone in the family,
Then you've got no option except Barack Obama.
What can that poor fellow do?
Launch a drone attack on Mehtab's house and resolve the entire matter in a flash.
Where are you off to now?
Where would I go?
I'm just checking why Aunt hasn't come yet.
Why would she come?
Splendid.
She's going to come and tell you that Dad's calling you.
Over there.
Here he comes.
The Molvi's son.
The bugger's turned into a Molvi himself!
You bugger!
What am I hearing?
I'm getting late for work,
We'll talk when we meet later.
When will we meet?
You're giving the thumbs down to your friends
For some twopenny-halfpenny job?
It's not like that,
I promise we'll meet tonight.
He's lying!
He's not coming!
His Dad's had him swear that he'll never meet Timmy and Sajid!
Innit?
That's the matter, right?
No. That's not what it's like.
You've got to change yourself to do a job.
I've heard you've stopped playing matches.
I'll play.
But I'll not gamble on it.
Why don't you just say you've been ensnared in your Dad's sermons!
I've been ensnared in Dad's sermons!
Seeing what I do brought tears to his eyes!
I can't bear to see his tears.
I'm wicked,
But not flagitious.
The sun's come up!
It's 9 already!
Oh my God...
Thank God!
You'll be thrown out of the University!
Get ready quick, Farah! Double time!
I'm thankful it ended there!
Mum must've explained everything.
And Dad must've decided, too
'Even if she loves someone',
'We'll talk some other day'.
I'll offer two additional prayers when I'm back
In fact, I'll offer all my prayers!
What are you looking at?
Go to your room and get ready, quick!
I'm going!
I know I'm late!
Good morning!
I've called to apologise.
Mum called and told me
I was left screaming in horror; after all, it's between us; we'll resolve it together.
Where's your Mum?
No --
I swear, it's not Mum's fault either.
It's just she talked to a friend, and --
She suggested it.
Where's your Mum's friend?
Hey!
You don't even know her.
Besides,
What will you say to her?
I'll thank her.
Say a big 'Thank you' to her.
And
Thank you very much too!
I was growing anxious how I could talk about it to Mum and Dad.
So sweet of you!
Alright, disconnect now.
I'm getting late for my classes!
Peace be upon you.
Please sign this photocopy
And confirm the receipt of this letter.
Letter?
It's a memo.
What's a memo?
You'll find out when you read it.
Read it after you've signed this.
Please don't talk to me about anything!
Talk to me!
I've signed the memo.
What's this you've written?
That I t -- tease Miss Rosy, I --
Pester her, harrass her?
Can you see this?
Miss Rosy has complained against you.
Look at me, mate!
I've been easy on you when writing that.
Miss Rosy had also mentioned
That she fears for her honour in your presence!
In my presence?
Over here!
I've even come to know the thing about the injury.
Be thankful
I did not write this Fescennine story in the memo!
Fescennine story?
The thing about the injury --
What about the injury?
Have some shame.
You thumb a lift from a girl,
And try to assault her?
I'm ashamed to think of it!
You're the son of a priest.
Look at your father's dignity and honour, and fear for yourself!
Yes?
Yes sir.
Coming, sir.
Come.
Where?
Monseigneur has called you.
And beware!
Don't try to lie before him!
Come.
Listen, Farah.
Come here.
Yes, Mum?
Tell him to come and meet your father.
Who?
What's his name?
Name?
Don't be afraid.
Your father has said that if he's from a good family and of good character, he has no problem.
A tad here or there in rank and status is fine by him.
I told you, you've nothing to fear.
Call him here.
You don't believe me?
Alright,
Go to the University for now; call me when you believe me and tell me when he'll be coming.
It
Would be better if he came in the evening.
Get a move on!
What is all of this?
It's all a lie, sir.
Get the girl here, Mr Chengezi.
Please wait, sir...
Why are you calling her here?
So that she can say all of this to my face?
I accept that she'd have said it.
And I accept that Mr Chengezi reported it to you because she'd said it.
But I want to ask one thing, sir.
If what that girl has said is given to be true, why is what I say necessarily a lie?
I saw you get in the car with her with my own eyes.
And that bandage on her head - she's shown me the wound.
A wound half an inch wide!
Is this proof that I'm lying, sir?
Do you know where you're standing?
And whom you're blabbing before?
I've come to realise today where I stand, sir.
I have nothing to say but that I'm not the culprit.
You may pronounce whatever decision you see fit.
I have great respect for your father.
He leads my prayers.
I'd given you this job on his request.
And do you know what he'd said when he recommended you?
He'd have said, 'My son is not virtuous, sir'.
'He gambles on matches, smokes weed with his vagabond friends'.
But he wouldn't have said, 'My son does not respect the dignity and honour of women'.
That's the one vice I don't have, sir.
Perhaps, trusting my inculpability from this transgression, my father used to forgive every trespass of mine.
I hereby resign from this job, sir.
For the first time, I am not the offender.
But I've got a feeling I am.
Please do mention this crime of mine when you meet Dad.
I, too, want to see, sir,
How much Dad distrusts me.
With peace, sir.
He's just being dramatic, sir.
Did you
Wake him up at daybreak?
I didn't need to!
He was praying when I entered his room.
He's awakened now, Dad.
There's no need to knock and wake him up now.
Do you
Remember Hazrat Sahib?
Of course.
When he was young,
He used to seat him in his lap.
He loved him so much.
He would turn his gaze to me and say,
'Remember, Subhanallah',
'He'll grow to become a great man one day'.
Take him to his grave someday
And say to him, 'Bless you'.
'What you said has come true'.
With blessings, your son has become a clerk.
What do you say, Ruqaiyya Begum?
That's how everything starts.
A tree does not grow tall in one day.
Take me, for example.
When I got married to you,
What was I?
And what are you now?
You just became a Molvi, Molvi Sahab.
You couldn't become a great man.
There is no other power [but God's]!
Hello?
Hello!
How are you, sire?
How goes your job?
Good!
Very good!
Ohh...
You're speaking English to proclaim your majesty!
My dear, show your majesty through your work. Many can speak English 'round here.
I'm doing a lot of work...
What's that noise?
Noise --?
The TV's on.
Mr Chengezi has a thing for the matches.
So he's like you!
Yes.
When's the break?
Break?
I mean when do you have your lunch?
Why don't you ask straight away?
I have my lunch when I'm hungry.
Hey? It's 2 p.m!
You're not feeling hungry?
Oh?
It's 2?
Alright. Quickly now, have your lunch.
I know you've got a lot of work. Keep on doing it.
But take care of your health.
I'll eat in a while.
And remember to offer your middle prayers.
Dad feels good to hear about it.
I will.
Alright.
I'll disconnect then.
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital