Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
'Everything'?
I'm sorry.
Yes,
So what's 'everything'?
I wanted to say that
It is not meet, considering my status, that I love Farah,
But I have a right to love Farah.
Oh?
Who bestowed this right upon you?
No...
Nobody bestows this right,
Nor does anyone ask for it.
Or else, one would have to take permission before falling in love.
This would make a complete haymes of it all.
A complete haymes, as in?
As in, asking permission
Of the one you love first.
Mention your status,
And ask,
'May I love you'?
What would you take to just love her?
Another good question.
I've asked you something.
How much money would you take to spare her life?
The thing is, I've promised on oath to Dad I'd never gamble again.
I'm not talking about gambling.
You are talking about gambling.
But it seems you do not understand gambling.
My friend, Babloo,
He says, 'Win this match, and the money's all yours'.
And you're saying, 'Lose this match, and the money's all yours'.
There is no room for such match-fixing in love.
Love is all about striving all your life and dying for its sake.
You play to win
Even if it gets heavy on the pocket.
It seems your mind doesn't quite work.
You're talking like Dad!
Whenever I used to score third division marks on my exams,
Dad would say,
'Look at this, Ruqaiyya'!
'It seems your son has not a brain in his skull'!
Ruqaiyya is my Mum's name.
Your family must be chuffed.
You've trapped such a good and wealthy girl.
Isn't it so?
This line is not worthy of my reply.
If you have any other questions, please do ask. Otherwise, I would take my leave.
To be honest, I'm rather furious at this.
Thank you very much.
You gave me a chance to speak my heart out.
But your last question wasn't nice.
Regardless,
I'd like to tell you as I leave
Nobody in my family knows that I love Farah.
With peace.
He came and left?
Yes.
But
I'd said he should leave only after meeting me.
You met with so much jewellery on?
He must've been frightened.
No.
The wretch doesn't fear anything.
Answered me back rather artfully on everything!
It is today that I realised how torturous it is to be the mother of a girl
Who's fallen for a right dosser from the neighbourhood.
Did you call him a dosser too?
I didn't.
But it occurred to me every now and then - whom am I talking to, and about what!
What happened?
Did he not agree to a million?
He left, calling me a gambler!
How dare he!
He said you're a gambler?
When I asked him how much he'd take to spare Farah's life, he said he'd promised his father.
'I'll never gamble again'.
When did he call you a gambler?
When I said, 'I'm not talking about gambling'.
He said, 'You are talking about gambling'.
'But it seems you do not understand gambling'.
He said, 'My friend, Babloo',
'He says',
''Win the match','
''And the money's all yours'.'
'And you're saying',
''Lose the match','
''And the money's all yours'.'
He's actually called you a gambler!
Don't be angry over it.
I'll see to it.
And where are both the girls?
Upstairs.
I'd asked them not to come downstairs
Until he's left.
Good.
And yes,
That line about Babloo was perfect!
Mum would've had a canary at that moment!
Canary?
In Eire,
You 'have a canary' when you get all worked up!
To be quite honest,
Afzal's won the first match.
Mum has lost by ten wickets!
Ten wickets!
Wickets or lines,
One or the same.
His ten lines, to Mum,
Are like ten wickets lost.
He bowled Mum out on every line of hers!
No need to get so excited.
Dad will decide to call Mehtab
Only after he meets Dad.
Why didn't he meet Dad, though?
We'd told him he'd be meeting Dad after meeting Mum.
The same
That I said in Irish!
Irish?
He's had Mum have a canary!
Then he'll be as vulnerable as a canary before Dad!
I have nothing to fear now.
I trust him.
And I trust him too!
No problem.
Tomorrow, he'll be meeting Dad.
You'll see.
Tomorrow, Dad will call bleeding Mehtab and say,
'Scurry away, you whippersnapper'!
Tell me where you're coming from.
Did you go on a date?
You're coming after meeting her, right?
Wearing a new suit, eh, you bugger?
Seems it's more than a 'meeting'.
Innit? Tell me.
I won't tell.
You guard the honour of those
Whom you love, mate.
This bugger's trying to dupe us!
Here.
Your clothes have been ironed.
Put this on and get going!
You're not our type anymore.
Thank you, Timmy.
Leave it be, Afzal.
I'm not Sajid
Who'd be ensnared in your sweet talk.
You only use friends for your own ends.
I love the three of you so much.
I don't use you for my ends.
I swear by her.
Take his word for it, mate.
He doesn't lie when he swears by her.
Innit?
Praise the Lord.
O God, the most excellent one! Have mercy.
May my greetings reach your ears too!
They have reached.
And upon you, peace.
Wash your hands and rinse your mouth; I'll be serving dinner.
I'm a Molvi, Ruqaiyya Begum.
My hands and my mouth are always clean.
And
Where is your most excellent one [Afzal]?
Do you remember when I'd asked you to give him a humbler name
For you may have to pay for it otherwise?
Stay quiet, Molvi Sahab!
If names made any difference, you wouldn't be 'Subhanallah' ['God's perfected Creation'] either!
My father named me.
When I was born, he saw me and exclaimed, 'Subhanallah' [Praise the Lord]!
And my mother said,
'That's the perfect name'!
If
Mum were alive today,
She'd ask you,
'Who's the greater one [Afzal] -'
'The one named Afzal',
'Or my Subhanallah'?
Who's that?
Your Subhanallah!
Oh...
God is the Greatest...
Peace, Dad.
And upon you, peace.
Peace, dear Mum.
And upon you, peace. May you live long.
Where are you coming from
At 9.30 p.m.?
By the Lord, Molvi Sahab,
Let him catch his breath.
Yes, do catch your breath.
Take in a gulp of air,
And then tell me where you're coming from.
You -- didn't tell Dad?
I was about to when you came.
I was meeting the boss.
Took quite some time.
Alright.
I hope he's satisfied with you?
Yes.
He's begun to give a lot of attention to you.
Otherwise,
These
Mill owners
Don't usually talk to office clerks.
I mean,
He's seen your talent clearly.
Monseigneur is
Quite adept at
Seeing through people
My dear,
Please don't listen to what your Dad is saying.
He was just recounting how, when he was born,
His father exclaimed on seeing him, 'Praise the Lord' [Subhanallah]!
Why are you so hesitant?
Give her a befitting reply!
I've been embarrassed because of what I've said,
What do I say now?
If, before me
Stood my wife,
I would've replied to her,
But Afzal's mother stands before me right now.
Forgive me, Madame.
I accidentally uttered 'clerk'.
Here, have this.
Eat properly.
Or is it that you've decided to die without him?
What are you doing, Irsa?
I think -- I'm --
I'm having a nightmare.
I can see
That blighter coming here with a wedding procession.
No --
I won't be able to see this, Monseigneur!
What will we tell people?
What will we say when questioned by our own family?
I don't have any reply.
And I'm sure it's the same with you.
Or --
Or will you proudly say
That your daughter has married the one she loves?
Neither seeing his status or family background,
Nor seeing where and how he'd keep her,
When he'll earn and what he'll be able to feed her --
We'll think, Irsa.
Let's talk about it later.
-What do you mean, talk later?
We'll have to agree to it now, Monseigneur!
It's just like I've seen in countless films and dramas!
When girls want to impose their desires,
This is how they quieten!
They eat slowly, and
And eat little.
There!
Look at her cohort!
She'll tell her now
That I was saying something against her
While her Dad was quiet.
Mum, I'm going because I've had my dinner...
Oh, please!
Even if she wanted this badge of unseemliness,
She could've drooled over someone who's not from the neighbourhood!
-Mind your tongue, Irsa. Please.
Go, my dear.
That's not how you talk to daughters, Irsa.
Granted, she's made a mistake
She doesn't eat enough, stays quiet...
Perhaps she, too, thinks,
'What am I doing'?
Give her some time.
Don't start insulting her.
Afzal?
Dad's calling you for dinner.
Are you sleeping or just pretending to?
Afzal!
Mum! Dad!
Afzal's got a scorching fever!
Oh God...
Go right now
And tell Mum you were lying.
And tell her that I was in on it too!
Tell her that you don't love Afzal,
And nor does he love you!
Just -- We'd hired him to 'love',
But don't tell her about the money.
Or else, she'd say,
'200,000 a month'
'To a third division BA'?
Have a glass of water,
Ease yourself,
And then we'll talk.
To the dickens with easing!
Mum was hurling such insults
That would embarrass even sworn enemies!
And save this glass of water for yourself
For you'll be needing it in a while!
Tell me,
What did Mum say?
Fear God, Farah!
You'd die when you hear it!
Alright, I'll die.
But please tell me the whole thing first!
You'll shriek so loud...
Let me shriek!
Don't worry.
Okay.
Shall we sit?
Why sit?
For the love of God, just sit!
You may plummet when you hear it!
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
What happened, Monseigneur?
I've got a feeling
My blood pressure's high.
I'll check right away.
Sorry, but
It took me a while.
Molvi Sahab showed up
As I stepped out.
Who?
Molvi Subhanallah?
Yes.
His son's got a 103 fever.
And he was even afraid to tell that he'd gotten drenched in the rain!
These lads these days!
Alright, please don't speak now.
In the name of God.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you, peace.
O Lord, the healer of all illnesses...
What's his temperature?
-103.
103?
-It's two degrees lower now.
Don't worry.
The doctor didn't let him come home until the temperature started falling.
And
The doctor's advised him to have some tea with rusks.
So,
Get some tea,
-Yes, go.
I'll get some rusks.
-I'll go, Dad.
Sit down.
-No, my son.
Sit down and relax.
Get some rest.
And tell your mother
Where you got drenched in the rain!
Where did you get drenched?
Your clothes were all dry.
That -- I -- The doctor
Was asking many questions.
'What did you eat, drink; how did you get this fever',
So I just said that I got drenched in the rain.
You lied to the doctor?
I didn't lie, Mum.
I did get a bit wet...
It was quite the downpour!
But you were inside your office.
No, Mum, I'm not inside the office at all times.
There's no roof overhead
When you go from Accounts to Production.
Besides,
What's the worst that can happen if you get drenched in the season's rains?
You can have a fever!
103!
You --
Get me some tea.
I'm hungry.
Go!
It would've been better if you'd bought a thermometer too.
I'll keep on having doubts
When the wretched fever will wear off...
It'll wear off as soon as I've had some of Arifa's tea.
Lie down.
Just for a while. Here.
Wait while she gets you some tea.
Would you tell me what happened?
It may have hurt you,
But at least it didn't hurt our reputation.
I don't have the slightest sorrow.
If Mum started talking like this,
You won't find a place to bury your head with shame.
She said it before Dad...
God forgive...
Alright,
I accept it's our fault,
But we should be granted at least a shred of clemency.
Please, go on.
She must've been delighted to hear it.
I didn't talk to her.
Hey!
You'd marched from here as if
You'd create quite the racket there.
What happened?
Dad's unwell.
His blood pressure's shot up!
The doctor just left after examining him.
I turned back the moment I heard it...
Imagine what would happen if Dad heard it.
Don't worry.
I'll tell her in the morning --
-Don't wait until the morning.
Tell me whatever you want to right now.
Mum...
I was furious at that blighter,
And I vented all my anger on you.
I've heard it somewhere
That a mother's insult is not an insult.
If you still think
That I insulted you, please forgive me.
What's this you're saying?
It's far more insulting
That you're asking forgiveness of me.
Get me through to him.
Whom?
That blighter, obviously!
I'd deliberately had him stand
In the rain.
I thought he'd look dishevelled
Drenched like that.
But I never thought
He could get a 103 fever.
He's gotten a 103 fever?
As if you don't know!
I swear I don't.
Would you look at that?
He's trounced me again!
He didn't even complain to you about how I treated him!
This is Molvi Subhanallah's upbringing!
The poor lad's a 3rd division BA,
But a 1st division in the elegance of his manners.
When you ask about his health,
Please do ask him to come and meet your father when he's well.
Good morning!
It's 'Peace be upon you', not 'Good morning'!
Well, peace be upon you, but where are you off to?
You didn't wake me up? It's 8 already!
Where do you have to go?
Good question, where do I go everyday?
Take a leave, then.
Tell them you got drenched going to the Production wing from Accounts
And got a fever. Ask them to grant you a day's leave.
And if you think the mill will close down if you don't go,
You may go right now.
I've ironed another pair of trousers and shirt and kept them in the cupboard.
I'm thinking, too, that I'd rather not go...
A 103 fever's no trifle.
What could I do now?
Great.
Why 'great'?
I'm happy to hear your decision.
It has saved you a pointless perplexity.
What kind of perplexity?
A job's a job after all!
Please, go now.
I'll get you breakfast in a few minutes.
This is also the first time you've said 'Please, go now'!
It didn't exactly please me.
Don't you intend to go to the University?
Is it morning already?
What?
The sun's come up...
So you've been awake all night?
No...
I'm growing dozy now...
Mind if I doze off?
Not at all...
Could've at least called him.
Mum would never forgive herself if he died...
Why don't you call him?
He'll talk to you if he's alive.
He'll stay quiet if I call him,
And I'll think
He's no more.
Where are you? I've brought breakfast.
I'm in the bathroom. Brushing.
I'll keep it on the table.
Alright; keep my medicine on the table too.
Where's your medicine?
Right under the pillow.
Hello.
I've heard you've gotten a 103 fever?
I've gotten you all drenched in the rain, haven't I?
I'm so sorry...
You're taking the medicine along!
I thought
I'd take it.
Such a medicine will be invented some day, won't it,
That the sister takes,
And the brother gets cured,
Completely cured?
Alright. Have your breakfast, take your medicine.
Forget your job and get some rest.
In fact,
Give me your office phone number.
I'll call and tell them that Afzal's unwell and won't be coming today.
No -- Not at all.
I'll call.
I'll tell them.
Don't worry.
The two of you didn't go to the University today?
How could I go alone?
She's lying flat out in the arms of Morpheus.
She's been awake all night.
Because of me.
In fact, because of you.
Even if I'd said something, why did you have to tell her?
When did she fall asleep?
Just some 15 minutes ago.
How's Afzal now?
How do I know?
You could've called and asked!
Whatever he's like, he's sick.
Because of me.
Why have you started blaming yourself?
I asked the poor lad twice to have some tea.
But I don't know what had gotten into him; he said, 'I won't'.
Or perhaps
It was just something I'd said...
By the way,
To be quite honest
Yes?
He doesn't know how to show anger.
He shows the same old expression all the time.
I don't think he watches any films or dramas.
Actually,
I think he must be into films.
So what if he's a Molvi's son?
After all, he's a lad from the neighbourhood!
Do you know,
The rapscallion smiled even as I said things
That would make one's face redden with rage!
Hello?
Right.
Afzal speaking.
I know.
Has your fever worn off?
It has.
But who told you?
We keep tabs on our office staff.
Hey!
Farah is very satisfied with you!
Oh?
What a performance!
It felt like a scene from 'Romeo and Juliet'!
Which scene?
Oh?
So you do watch films after all!
You would remember that balcony scene.
What perfect lines by Juliet!
Did I say it like that?
That had been said rather rebelliously,
You said it all with a smile!
But --
She --
Does she think I said it well enough too?
She's raving mad about you!
She was saying before the meeting, 'Our punter will surely win this round'!
Punter?
She didn't exactly say 'punter',
That's just something I uttered...
When do I meet Monseigneur?
Get better first.
Let the fever wear off for good
And then we'll fix a date for that.
No, please do fix a date.
The fever's worn off.
Don't worry.
I'll win again.
You're real clever, you punter!
You want to finish 4 months of work in 4 days and take your 800,000?
No!
If I did that, I'd be charged with a grave sin!
When we'd negotiated it for four months,
My four months are hers.
Besides,
I needed a job.
My family's delighted too.
I've started down the path of righteousness.
Alright.
We'll fix a meeting for tomorrow when she wakes up.
She's sleeping?
She's just fallen asleep.
Got furious last night over something,
And stayed awake in her anger all night.
Oh...
Mind if I ask you something?
Please, ask away.
What you say doesn't quite match your reputation.
Tell me,
Are you like this, or have you just become like this?
Good question.
Alright. I got it.
I'll disconnect.
I'll call in the evening when I've talked to Farah. Bye.
Bye.
Shall I take the dishes if you've had your breakfast?
Yes, I have. Take them away.
Would you look at this phone?
It's new.
It cost 40,000.
Where'd you get 40,000?
Where would I get it from?
The office fellows bought me this.
Wow...
A phone worth 40,000 for a clerk?
You've hit a jackpot!
Jackpot?
What's this you're saying?
That is what one would say to your type.
You're green with envy...
Don't show it to Dad.
If he gets envious,
It'd paint the world green.
Ruqaiyya!
Pray tell, sire.
Praise the Lord [Subhanallah]!
You're talking with such respect!
I respect you so much.
I have to.
It's an old order to me.
Pray tell. What is it?
The two of you are all so occupied looking after Afzal today
That nobody served me breakfast!
Sit down.
I'll serve you breakfast.
Thank you so much!
Otherwise
I was beginning to think
I'd have to get drenched in the rain
Get a 103 fever
To earn such respect!
They say you should say something nice
Even if you don't look so good.
You're saying this a bit browned off...
Otherwise
You used to say before Mr Afzal came of age,
'There is no other'
'Like you, Molvi Sahab'.
I say it to this day.
By the grace of God, there is none like you.
But try to understand what that means.
May I go and meet some of my friends?
Are you asking me?
Yes.
No!
Ask your mother about
Such ill-fated zeal!
So, Ruqaiyya Begum, please tell him if he may go and visit his friends.
Go, my dear.
But come back quickly.
There!
That's how you should be asking!
Go; it's a great day to be you!
But please tell me before you leave
If you've taken your medicine.
I have.
Then, I'd request you
To come home before it's time for your next dose.
Yes.
God be with ye.
Alright now, get me some breakfast.
God is the Greatest...
98...
But that's all there was!
Where did that 40,000 come from?
So he gets things instead of cash now!
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital