Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were those people
Who won their love?
Don't you feel ashamed to think
That she loves you, and she's searching for the one
Whom you love?
Come.
Come on, mate.
You'd started going down the path of God, so where have you ended up?
Nowhere.
You'd just left Hyderabad and ended up in Karachi.
And here you are, thinking whether
You've never left Hyderabad,
Or never returned from Karachi.
How are you, Mr Fiancé?
Come inside.
I saw you playing cricket.
You're such an ace, mate!
Don't say 'mate;' Dad may hear it!
These are mere parting discourtesies, my dear;
Then, who knows what may become of me
And you?
Tell him to not look at me with such fury!
Don't look at her with such fury!
Why did you go there?
Eh?
For the sake of Molvi Uncle's coconut biscuits.
Please agree to what I'm saying!
And for your Mum's sake.
She sees your image in Farah.
And for your sake, Afzal Sir,
For I see her in your eyes.
It occurred to me that you'd gotten engaged for my happiness,
For your happiness, then, I thought I'd break this engagement.
Uncle, tell him
To return my ring.
You're under my oath!
What are you saying?
Please, Yasmin.
Don't say such things...
I've made a promise to Molvi Sahab,
And you're so one-sided -
You agree to everything the Coconut Girl says;
Won't you agree to one thing I said?
Dad's crying...
He loves you so much.
I love him so much too!
I, too, will tear up when I'll remember him.
C'mon!
Return my ring.
Mam was saying to me on that day itself, 'What kind of engagement is this'?
'Which the boy's parents didn't attend'?
I said, 'Thank God he's come'.
'I would've agreed to the blighter's proposal had he asked to get engaged over the phone'.
Every compeer
Every compeer abandoned me
After ephemeral moments of companionship
Who has the leisure to stand by
One so crazed in love
I'm not returning your ring.
I'm keeping it to show it off before Mam!
I'll tell her it's a long term engagement,
That I'm waiting a lifetime for the marriage...
C'mon now.
Drop me at my place.
I'd written all those letters, Lubna...
Which letters?
The same
That Afzal has.
A lie.
You're lying.
Don't say 'You're lying' now that I've accepted it.
I've been caught because of Miss Mary D'Souza.
I wouldn't have admitted it otherwise.
And when you'd gone to Afzal's place after ritual purification,
And said to his mother that you can swear on the Qur'an,
Why did you say that?
You were ready to commit such a grave sin?
I knew she wouldn't let me.
Oh God!
I'm so ashamed already...
Forgive me... Please...
Try to make a list
Check out how many people you'll need to apologise to, and how many will forgive you.
Dad will punch you right in the jaw!
I'm determined now, Lubna...
I'll take it.
And when God asks you,
What will you do about that?
Yasmin's taken care of it,
She said, 'Confess the sins of lying and breaking him'.
'I'll weep for you and ask forgiveness for you'.
She was weeping?
A lot.
She loves Afzal so much...
One-sided.
And that blighter loves me.
So she sacrificed herself to you.
I'd tried to dissuade her,
I said,
'Marry him'.
You're so simple...
But she said, 'Be uncharitable in love'.
'Had I been in your place',
'I'd have trampled everyone underfoot'!
And that's something you must've learnt instantly.
For you trampled Yasmin underfoot momentarily!
I love Afzal, Lubna...
Tell me, then,
What do I do?
Call Sibtain,
Say to him, 'I'm not marrying you'.
Why don't you --?
Poor chap's a good man.
I guess I'll have to now...
Else, everyone's going to say,
'These girls just like to get things started',
'They never get things moving forward'.
It's my sacrifice for you!
Call her here.
Tell her her dresses are ready.
Tell her to have a look, get ready; we're leaving.
Where's Mum?
At the jeweller's; she told me to come with her.
She's selecting the jewellery?
Of course!
Come with me.
Get these upstairs.
D -- Dad...
Please endure this final bulletin --
Final bulletin?
Slap me if you get angry.
But tell Mum that it's my decision.
I mean -- yours.
Don't say a word about Farah.
I don't want to hear any news about her.
I promise, Dad.
I won't say anything from Farah.
Have no fear, then.
Tell me - what is it?
Uh --
Dad -- It's --
You know -- Sibtain?
What happened to Sibtain?
Nothing's happened to him.
Please listen patiently.
Alright, go on...
It's --
Sibtain actually --
Was for me.
I mean -- he --
The proposal --
Was intended for me.
What?
I swear, Dad.
But I said, 'There's one condition'.
What condition?
You're getting angry, aren't you?
I'm not getting angry!
Get over with it.
The condition was that
He'd cure Farah completely.
Cure her?
What do you mean?
Dad, she's cured!
She's admitted that she used to write those letters to Afzal!
Nobody will mention Afzal in this house now!
Let me finish, Dad!
Isra will die if she heard anything like this!
She's in on it, Dad!
I've french fried your brain, haven't I, Dad?
But this time, the mistake wasn't Farah's.
I've fried it this time.
For God's sake, what will Sibtain's parents think?
Nothing at all!
They're in on it too!
Why did you have to conceal it from me, then?
You can't act, Dad!
We thought it'd be better if you performed naturally!
So she's 'cured'!
Completely, Dad!
Don't you all think it's a bit too late now?
Be honest with me -
Have I been more of a father to you or a friend?
A friend, of course.
Tell Farah, then, that no friend would ever give this advice
To even think about Afzal.
You're saying this because of Yasmin, right?
She's no more --
I mean, she's breaking the engagement.
She's the one who explained everything to Farah.
She said that the engagement was just like Sibtain and Farah's 'marriage'.
Only that she'd been a tad bit serious.
But Afzal was just exacting his vengeance from Farah.
Vengeance -- as in, Farah got engaged the other day,
So he got envious and got engaged on the same day.
He's come after committing 12 murders in Karachi, Lubna.
He'll have to pay for them all.
She'll have him pay for it.
She'll ask him why he did it.
He must be having an answer too.
Otherwise, he'll just say sorry --
Come on, Lubna...
Let me think like this, Dad...
He's come now.
He's playing cricket here in Hyderabad.
Let him play.
Don't talk about murder.
How far is Karachi?
Here you go and there you arrive!
Don't cry, Aunt.
We'll talk over the phone.
I'd never talk to you.
Tell me,
Who am I to talk to you?
You're family.
The one-sided engagement's still there.
Given that, you're my mother-in-law.
50-50.
Where's Uncle?
He'd be in his room, crying...
I thought I'd meet him.
It's me, Uncle... Yasmin.
May I come in?
Don't you dare set foot in the room!
I don't want to meet you!
Not at all!
Please allow me...
I'll be there in your heart even after I'm gone...
Every time you'd look at the Coconut Girl, you'd bless me.
Scold me if it's a lie.
Otherwise, let me go.
I have to go.
Whether you grant me leave,
Or not.
God be with you...
You're leaving because Farah used to write letters to me, right?
To be honest,
She did not write those letters to me.
I used to write those letters myself under her name.
No.
That's not why I'm going.
I'm going because
That blighter loves you.
So much that she cannot bring herself to say it.
She started crying buckets and buckets when she was about to say it.
Who is it?
Sibtain and his father.
Why are they here?
And why are they laughing?
They're happy
That Sibtain's not getting married to you.
Oh seriously!
As if I'd marry that ignoble psychiatrist!
What were you looking at over there?
Afzal was going somewhere with Yasmin.
Look at how she turned away!
She didn't even meet me as she left!
Don't be so happy about it.
She's left this place with tears in her eyes.
Bless her in your prayers now that you're getting married to Afzal.
Did you talk to Afzal?
Not even now?
Tell him to talk to me.
You're both trapped in these issues.
He couldn't say it, and nor could you.
I'm never saying it.
Alright.
Wait until the marriage.
You'll start saying it all then.
Where are you going?
Downstairs.
The date of your marriage is being decided.
Dad's saying you'll get married this Sunday and the next Sunday will mark the celebrations.
But -- Molvi Uncle didn't even talk about it...
The two of them don't have such issues as you two!
There was one Yasmin,
Who loved my brother,
But my brother
Loved Farah.
Seeing it, one would believe that if love is one sided, it is often more than mere love,
But one never knows
That if love becomes something more than mere love,
What does it turn into?
It's midnight, isn't it?
Yes.
Why did you set an alarm for midnight?
I figured
He'd have arrived by midnight.
He must've arrived there.
We're going to Monseigneur Ibrahim's tomorrow.
Are we invited?
What are you asking, Ruqaiyya Begum?
It's the girl's family.
Why should they invite us?
We'd go to them!
We'd beseech them humbly,
'Please'
'Be so generous'
'As enrapture us by giving us Farah'.
Yasmin?
Yasmin, wake up. We're at your place.
Thank you.
Listen.
Won't you ask me to come in?
No.
I'll start to grow on you if you come inside.
Will you forgive me?
Did you call Farah?
Call her.
Tell her how much you love her.
I'll forgive you that instant.
Take care.
Listen.
If you ever visit Karachi...
Do not pay me a visit.
Did you call Farah?
Call her.
Tell her how much you love her.
I'll forgive you that instant.
Dear Afzal,
Do you know the most undeniable truth in the world?
Don't guess.
Hear it from me:
The most undeniable truth in the world is that
Farah Ibrahim
Loves you.
Hello?
Afzal --
Yes, Afzal?
Go on; why are did you stop?
Afzal?
Do you have the slightest shame?
Farah, let's go --
Hey! Get off!
Let me see who's the boss!
Now that your engagement plan failed,
You stand in my way to get even?
You're playing the lover in front of everyone?
Want to besmirch my reputation?
You're Molvi Subhanallah's son,
So I thought you'd not step out of the house for days after all the insult that day.
You'd drown in shame,
Or leave Hyderabad to hide your disgraceful self!
Hello?
Farah here.
I know --
The call got disconnected?
Yes --
Disconnected.
So what was it you were saying?
I was saying --
That's what you always do.
It's either that you can't say,
Or can't say the whole thing.
Go on.
I'm listening.
Farah,
Yes...
Once you say something after 'Farah', you'll see
How you start speaking everything!
Speak up...
Tell me...
Why did you call me?
I wanted to talk to you about the letters.
Yes, go on?
Go ahead from the letters.
But, I --
Alright.
I'll start.
But -- You finish it.
I wrote all those letters.
For you.
To you.
A fib...
All the letters, I --
I wrote them myself.
To you...
Sorry --
Why are you saying sorry?
You were right.
It's alright if you'd written them.
Go on.
These long pauses of yours, Afzal,
Something's not right.
It's cost a lot before.
C'mon, be a man!
Tell me clearly that --
You love me.
That's it --
What's it?
I love you...
So much...
But Farah,
Don't say 'Farah' like that...
I might die when I hear it.
There you go silent again!
Listen,
I've written a letter to you.
For real this time,
I'll post it tomorrow, and you'll receive it the day after.
'Don't ask me what I've written,
Just...
It opens with 'Dear Afzal'.
You're so shameless.
Said it to my face that you love me so much!
Now, I'm a girl;
I have to think.
I've written this after a lot of thinking.
I'm not telling you anything else.
You're on the way, aren't you?
When will you be back here?
Tell me...?
Please tell me...
Speak up
Please?
How many times to I have to tell you, Afzal,
Your silence costs all of us so much.
Who were those people
Who won their love?
When obsecrating for rosebuds
I was presented with a garland of thorns...
Who were
Those people
Who won their love?
When looking for the garth of happiness
The sands of sorrow engulfed me
When desired an ode to love
Cold sobs rewarded me
Every compeer I found doubled my heart's grief
Translation: Aditya Misra © ARY Digital