foo
Not so fast...
D'you think this is a blimmin' inn... A hotel that you can leave and come back to anytime you want? Eh?
What've you been up to all night?
What d'you mean? I was at work.
I told Kanwal...
Yeah, she told me...
-I'm not talking to you.
I'm asking her.
Feel free to blame me all you want... But not now. I'm honestly knackered. Can't take another earful.
Blimey... You're rude, I give you that!
If my daughter dared say that, I would've cut her tongue out!
Done?
This is my place, young lady. Never forget that.
No one dares come and go without my will.
If you've got a problem, be my guest and find somewhere else.
Mhm hmm... Anything else?
I'm dead on my feet... Need to get some rest. Could you please wrap it up a bit quicker?
Blimey, you're bigly balky!
Thank you.
Good Heavens! So insolent and uncouth! The blimmin' savage!
Well, what do I care... It's gonna be the end of you!
She's gone, Mum! It's okay, Mum!
-Like, seriously, d'you think I'd care?
Shut up!
Back to work! C'mon!
What next? Clean the whole place?
I don't see why not!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky