foo
Welcome home, dear.
Here. Come in.
Make yourself at home.
Dad...
Wait, Dad!
Dad! Dad!
ADD
Here.
I've got this for you.
A dress just like this one. I'm sure you'd love it.
How do you know us so well?
I mean... First time we've met...
I don't know much about you...
But I've heard Mum and Dad talk about you.
Dad always talked about you...
Missed you...
All of you...
ADD
For you...
Keep it...
We don't need your gifts.
I'd brought it with love...
I would've been happy if...
You accepted it...
Well, if you care about our happiness, why don't you just leave? Why'd you even come here at all?
ADD
I don't even think she's a Muslim! Just look at the book she's got...
Who?
Abdullah's daughter, of course!
What book? I don't get it.
Whatzit... 'Babel'?
Bible?
Yeah. That.
I've been restless since I saw it! Something's not right!
What's the big deal?
The Bible is the holy book revealed to Jesus Christ...
She probably got it from her mother.
But why does she have to keep it?
Why do you have to keep your mother's jewellery?
They're all that's left of her!
Well, maybe that's all that's left of her mother...
You don't get it...
She's not one of us!
Just look at her name!
This... Ignorance is not really your fault, Sajida...
ADD
What?
Scared?
So it's you!
Maria... The one they've all been talking about...
Gotta say... Until I saw you, I almost didn't believe you'd be so...
Gee, mate, I'm your cousin!
Sumair.
Ring a bell?
No.
Not even remotely.
I'm sure we can fix that...
You're staying here...
No way we won't see each other 'round here!
Well, guess what, I don't care about random lads on the street.
Which is where you're wrong... All the chicks do.
That's how you think... Who knows what they may be thinking...
As lovely and captivating as yourself...
I like the way you talk.
Makes coming here... Worthwhile... Thank you...
Thank you for giving me a reason to stay here...
See ya...
Real soon...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky