We pray to our Lord, Jesus Christ...
Thank You for all the years we shared with her...
Your father was a good man.
He respected beliefs.
He loved his family.
He couldn't live without them...
But he was willing to leave everything to stand by me.
He gave you the name I liked - Maria.
Maria... The daughter of Abdullah...
ADD
Everything was alright...
Yeah...
That's how it felt...
Before...
It wasn't...
You must promise me...
You will do as I say.
This is our promise...
And the Lord God Himself bears witness...
Sometimes, you got to leave everything...
For those you hold dear...
Even if they were never yours...
Sometimes, you just have to accept things as they unfold...
Whether as the sliver of light cutting through the endless night...
Or the nightmare that comes back to haunt you...
I'm going because I've accepted everything...
I'm treading this long and tiring road...
Weary...
But holding on to every bit of courage left in me...
Strange, how they...
Leave this world in peace...
Leaving you in a web of promises...
Sometimes, you have to take a step...
To find yourself...
That's what you're doing today.
Taking a step.
Going where you should've been...
But were never...
Keep it with you...
And if you ever feel lonely...
Know that I'm with you...
You'll find me right by your side when you need me.
ADD
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky