foo
Gonna see Nisha!
She's not taking my call, her phone's off! I want to talk to her!
It's 2 a.m.! She'd be sleeping right now! You want to go now?
-Chuffin' right now! Lemme see who's got the bloody guts to stop me!
You're off your head! Always up to something! That's the blasted limit!
-My love knows NO limits!
I'm keeping that.
-Gimme the keys, Ammar!
-For God's sake, Danish...
Please don't go there... You'll lose Nisha forever...
ADD
He alone is Lord thine
He alone is Lord mine...
He alone is Lord mine
'Tis for another day
That our paths ne'er entwine
Why dostn't thou see through the blur
Creation in its endless beauty
He that looked on Him found succour
But 'tis for another day...
O Lord...
ADD
Know what... I always wanted to have a daughter...
But the Lord gave me two sons...
He did what was best...
If I had a daughter, she'd by my best friend.
Of course...
A mother can be her daughter's best friend.
My Mum was mine...
But now...
I'm all alone...
So...
How say we be friends?
ADD
Please don't grieve yourself over what they say... They can only give you grief...
Care about them, but not about everything they say...
We can't change the world...
But only... How we see it...
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky