foo
Hello? Who is it?
Someone very special...
Or, at least...
Someone very close...
Sorry, who?
I live so close...
Get it?
Sumair...
It's Sumair.
Yeah, what is it?
There's a lot...
For starters, you could recognise my voice...
Anyway...
It's no big deal...
You'll get there soon...
I'm at work. Don't disturb me again.
ADD
Surprise, sweetheart...
Never thought your coming here could feel so magical...
You...
And me...
Just the two of us...
And the sweet redolence of our love...
That...
Only we can feel...
Shh...!
There's a lot you're thinking... A lot you want to say...
But please... Not just yet...
Let me say it...
You love these flowers, don't you?
Redolent with our love...
Bearing witness to our love...
I love you, Nish --
You?
ADD
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky