foo
Hey!
How 'bout a selfie with the soon-to-depart?
-Aye!
-Now you're suckin' diesel, mate!
Wait for the Reaper... And sue me from in here...
Lemme see if your bite is worse than your bark. See ya!
I say we ungag 'im, mate!
He deserves the last scream before his death.
Lovely! Do it!
I'll show you! Get me outta here or I'll scream so loud that --
-Yeah? Do it. Scream your guts out all you want.
No one comes here in ages.
That's why we dug your grave here.
To the devil with you! Get me outta here!
C'mon!
Hey!
What d'you think you're doin'?
Get me out of here!
Hello!
Hey!
Not fair!
Anyone!
Get me out!
Anyone?
Help!
Anyone out here? Help...
Please... Anyone...
Anyone?
Hello...?
Hey! Anyone hear me?
Anyon --
Out here?
Please... Help...
God is the Greatest...
There's no god but God...
-Reverend...
Your love calls you...
ADD
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky