OST
'Kaiser Villa'
Jeez...
It's 7 already...
And I've got an exam today... The teacher's gonna eat me alive if I failed again...
Look alive, Meenu!
Aye, I heard you!
'Kaiser House'
Me fella... Me dear lad... Me sweet wee young paddy!
All that sweetness is gonna give me diabetes...
But yer are me sweet wee lad!
-Don't call me 'sweet'.
Gie me a break! Oi canny fib!
Anyway, what is it?
Don't let that old hag know we're going to meet a potential match for you tomorrow.
But she's our Mam-gu too!
-She's my co-wife! That's all you should know!
Grandpa's no more! It'd be better if you two got over this blood feud!
-Gie me a break! I'll get you some tea, sweetie...
Blimey, Granny, be done with it already... You'll push everything I've learnt out of my head!
Oh I'm gonna have proper fun today. Come 'ere. I'm gonna slice and rats and mice your Granny Bakhto before I skewer 'er and char 'er proper! If you got a job today, my lad, I tell you!
Please don't say that. She's our Granny too!
Like the devil she is! That cow became my co-wife a month after my marriage!
Well, Grandpa's fault! He lost his heart to her!
God bless your Grandpa... Although I doubt he deserves it one bit...
Kaiser thought he was some blasted king for real, who could get away with two marriages!
Gotta say he treated you equally though. Equally majestic villas, equal number of kids, equal shares in the business... How very... Saintly of him!
Oh, put a sock in it... Daan't get me started! Just focus on your interview.
It's tomorrow.
Whatever. Na get aahhht of 'ere quietly before your ovver Granny sees ya. That Gooseberry Puddin' can clock through walls, she can!
Okay... That's enough oiling for one day!
Scapa Fla wake aw them loungers up! We ain't gonna wait until Jim Skinner for them!
-Okay...
Here!
Yes! Here it is!
Yeah!
-Shh!
That's mine!
Gimme my share quietly or there will be blood!
-Ya daan't say!
We'll divide it on the way.
-Hurry up, Walid! Before someone sees you!
Quit mumbling, Mumbo!
-Double time!
Jesus... Hadi's here!
Quick!
Wonder what our Three Idiots are doing in Uncle's room...
-Asking for our pocket money...?
Except Uncle's waiting for you at breakfast.
-Really? Let's not keep him waiting for Godot, then, Meenu!
'Waiting for Godot'? And I thought someone was failing in English...
Out!
See ya!
Like anyone, sweetie?
I've got no choice.
Forget about your sisters. Tell me the kind you like.
A bookworm. A lover of literature...
As nice and cultured as they get!
Calm, composed, sober, and graceful.
Guess I'll have to look in a NASA library...
OST
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe