You know, Ruby, I want someone simple, mature, and modest who can take care of me... The household... And Faris!
Of course... Yeah, I know there's many in the family... But you know about all their 'issues'!
Anyway, I'll get back to you. Bye.
I was wondering what's going on here... I heard everything.
So it's Mission: Find a dream daughter-in-law these days!
What do you mean, dream daughter-in-law?
If the one I like is gonna be my dream girl, the one you like is gonna be your dream daughter-in-law, of course.
It'll be good for you. I want the best for you.
Remember Mrs Chauhdry? The lady you met the other day?
She's introducing us to someone tomorrow. She was praising her family so much!
But you've got such a vast social circle. Why don't you look there? You're trusting a complete stranger!
Because I'm not gonna pick someone who's so busy with herself she hasn't got a moment for you!
What are you looking for in her?
-Respect, simplicity, modesty... In other words, a family-girl.
Wow... Good luck with that...
Anyway, what's for dinner?
Sunday roast.
-Blimey...
I'll go change...
It is so... Breathtaking... I could spend my whole life this way.
I wish...
Live all your dreams with me...
Promise?
How 'bout we start right away?
How?
Just a sec...
Whoa! Easy there!
Jaysus, mate... What is it?
Who is it, more like. Who are you dreaming of?
Lemme sleep, Yusra...
Get up. I'm getting late for work because of you. You want to be late for college?
Just a minute...
Rabi!
Get up, Rabi...
The sun's come up!
Oh, it's such a beautiful thing!
Please, don't bother...
Forget it, Mum... Seems she just wants to skive off...
Just -- Why?
The sun doesn't wait to come up when you want. Quickly, now... I'll be waiting at breakfast.
Don't forget to have breakfast before you leave!
Yusra...
-Yeah?
Could you come to the shop with me in the evening?
No... You know I'm knackered after office... I'll get what you want on the way back.
It's about... A friend's birthday... Gotta get her a gift... Would you happen to have some money? I'll go with Mum.
Hmm... I don't think I've got any...
C'mon, mate... I'm going to the bank. I'll transfer some to you. Get it from the ATM.
Thank you so much. I know you started working just for me!
Of course.
Because you're my queen!
Thank you so much!
-Eww! Get off me! Go brush your teeth!
Go!
Hey...
Hello... Ready to go to work?
Of course. I'll get your medicines on the way back, but! Don't forget to check your blood pressure.
Of course, Doc.
You know I think of you as my sons...
I trust the two of you more than myself. That's why I let you work as you wanted.
Anyway, how are you going to the office?
Same as everyday? I've ordered a taxi and it's almost here... Okay, bye!
Bye, take care!
-Take care.
Here's your cuppa!
-Thank you!
What's our young lad Rabi up to?
Your lad's off her head. Still busy getting ready, I guess...
Yeah, I'm waiting for you.
Okay, come to the pinned location and call me.
Rabi...
Yes?
Aren't you too busy dressing up of late?
So?
So mind yourself. You're grown up now!
Grown-ups busy themselves with dressing up. Not kids!
Lippy as always! You don't have to answer back every time!
Of course... You only answer questions!
Jaysus... When'll you grow up?
All I'm saying...
Nah, forget it... You'll say I'm being immature again!
You could learn a thing or two from your sister.
You think everyone who earns money is mature?
Who said anything about money?
Yusra's very practical. She's working because she wants to.
You know just as well your Dad's pension is all we need.
Aww, turn the frown upside-down, Mum... Cheer up!
There, now... You can stop buttering me up... And come have bread and butter!
You know I don't feel like having anything in the morning.
I hate it how these films and dramas are making unfed skeletons of girls! Have something before going to college!
I'm not dieting or something, Mum... Just don't feel like having anything.
Good Lord... I pray we find a match for Yusra so I can get you married off as well!
Don't worry. I've sorted that out myself.
What've you done?
I contacted Fish Aplenty.
They'll be here anyday...
What's Fish Aplenty?
They'll tell you everything you need to know. Don't worry.
Anyway... Yusra tells me everything when she's back from work... Why don't you tell me anything when you get back?
What do I tell you about college? It's all classes, classes, and ah, yes, boredom that kills you!
Anyway, come have breakfast...
Nah, not this one... Pack this.
Please pack this one. Thank you!
What d'you mean, 'Pack this one'?
I'm buying this one. Please pack it.
-Excuse me, but I told them to keep it for me...
What do you mean 'keep it for you'? I've picked this one after so much time!
I was here before you. I told them to keep it for me. I don't know why it was even on display... Tell her, will you?
Sorry, ma'am, but he's already paid for it. Someone must've put it on display by mistake...
Excuse me! What d'you mean he paid for it? I'm paying for it right now. Pack it for me!
Just in case you didn't notice, it's for men.
Who are you to tell me that?
If you kept on bothering me, I'll raise a crowd right here!
No, it's okay.
Please pack this one.
Yeah, please...
Thank you so much.
-You'll have to pay for it over there.
You better not expect me to say thank you or something!
It's okay...
Good afternoon. Saba Chauhdry. Mobile marriage bureau at your doorstep. Here with the best matches made in Heaven!
(No money back guarantee in case of divorces, estrangement, or cheating.)
May I come in?
Thank you!
Hi!
Ain't it a bit too hot in here?
Scorching, yeah.
And look at me... Waiting for you in this heat...
Everyone's got brains, but few bother to use them! Who told you to wait right outside the door, Yasir? You could've waited in the car!
Why? Worried someone may see you?
You know I don't get worried.
Aye, but I do... So worried my heart skips a beat!
Aww... No need to get so romantic!
Shall we?
Let's.
Please.
I saw you in my dream last night.
No surprise... You don't see me much when awake.
Guess what, you tripped and fell!
I fell for you long ago...
Just pray someone comes with a proposal real quick!
Congratulations to you in advance...
Shut up! I'm talking about Yusra.
It'll be my turn once she's been married off.
Blimey, you're smart!
Innit?
Mum doesn't think so. She thinks I'm immature.
Because no one knows you better than me.
How 'bout we have some ice cream today?
I thought you'd have lunch...
No, I'd have to have whatever Mum's cooked... She won't let me go.
Anyway, before I forget again... Whose car is it?
Mine, of course?
Don't you have that white car?
I had to send it to the garage for repairs, you know... This one's mine - ours - too. Get it, smart girl?
If you don't like, I'm sure I can get another --
-No way, I love it.
Thank you. Shall we?
Good afternoon!
-Good afternoon.
Saba Chauhdry. I've got the perfect match for your daughter.
Alright... Please, take a seat!
Thank you!
Actually, I -- Sorry, gotta take this one...
Aye, what's up, Shabana?
Nah way! Ya kna 'e doesn't loike ter 'ave it wahn bit!
Daan't ya dare touch the meat! Yeah, 'e'd golden dove sum calabash!
Aahhht ya can find! I'm busy wite na, daan't call me again!
Sorry.
Your younger daughter Rabi got in touch with us. Sent us her sister's pictures too. For her marriage, you know...
Yeah, we're looking for a match for her.
Don't worry.
I understand girls' parents have their hands full with worries, and I believe in lending a hand where I can.
I mean, it doesn't look proper if they go about or come to our office to find a match for their daughters... That's why I provide this door-to-door service.
I appreciate your effort. It's so convenient for parents!
No one thinks that way these days... Not for families with daughters, at least!
Except me!
Sorry, I forgot to ask you... Would you like to have some tea?
No, thank you! Not in this heat! But yeah, I'd love it if you could get me a cold drink...
Okay.
-Thank you!
So... What d'you do? Of course if you don't mind telling me...
Why would I?
I'm retired so... Not much these days...
Besides, it's my health...
I hope it's nothing serious, I mean, like... Heart diseases... Kidney disorders... Or something?
Goodness, no. Just... Allergies and the flu!
I don't see your daughters around. Where are they?
Yusra would be at her office and Rabi at college.
Very good... She's got a job... That's very nice...
Here.
-Thank you so much!
Don't worry. Your daughters are my responsibility now.
I'll find the best matches for them and get back to you!
Mind if I said something, Mrs Chauhdry?
Please come around when they're both home, so you can meet them yourself.
Their pictures won't nearly tell you well enough.
-Absolutely. I'll be back. Gotta pick my kids from school. I thought I'd drop by and see you first.
I'll be back. Thank you so much!
You're welcome.
Bye!
-Bye.
The Lord has been very kind...
Okay, Yasir, bye!
Hi!
Hi... You're?
Saba Chauhdry. Mobile marriage bureau.
It's you! How are you?
Did you meet them?
Yeah, just met your parents.
And... You're Rabi? The one who got in touch with us and sent us your sister's pictures?
Yeah.
Who's he?
A friend from college...
He's real handsome... Gimme his number. I've got many lovely matches for him!
No, thank you, he's committed.
Oh, you don't know how it is these days! Gimme his number.
Aren't you getting late, Yasir?
See you!
The thing is, they don't marry outside the family, so, you know...
Cousin marriages, eh?
-Yeah.
His number plate's gonna tell me his number!
Anyway, give me yours?
My number? Come back and I'll give you.
Please, find someone good for my sister real quick!
Don't worry, I'll do my best!
I'll get going. Bye.
-Okay, bye.
In'cha so clever, lil' wahn!
Wotcha?
Yeah, where's the bleedin' Jam Jar?
I'm at the front gate!
Quickly!
Jeez...
Translation: J. Mir © HUM TV Europe, HUM TV USA