OST
Breakfast is ready, Miss Annie.
Just a moment, Asia...
'Morning, Mum... Dad...
'Morning.
-'Morning. Have your breakfast.
I've had my breakfast, Aunt. Besides, I'm getting late.
Hey, everyone!
-Hello!
Aren't you getting late for class?
Calm down, Kashif... Have your breakfast...
No time, Mum. Getting late...
Aye... Your scruffy hair say as much!
You don't know it, but this style's in vogue these days.
Hashim! You know my girl doesn't like anyone poking fun at her hair.
I don't want to say anything about her hair...
But sometimes, looking at something, you can't resist...
Nice try, Hashim. Anyway, I'm getting late.
Okay, bye Mum. Bye Dad...
Okay, bye!
-Bye!
-Okay, bye!
So late today... Gonna miss my first class...
You should really work on getting up early, Kashif...
I was busy with this assignment all night...
Kashif...
Just look at Annie... She studies all night too...
But she can get up early... She knows how to manage her time...
She can... But I'm not Annie! Anyway, I'm getting late...
Okay, bye!
Bye!
-Bye.
Bye...
Would Madame Quratulain allow me to put some music on?
No way.
I've got an exam today. Gotta study.
What's wrong, Annie? Always buried in a book! You're gonna ace it anyway!
Gotta study to ace it. Focus on driving...
Have it your way. I ain't coming to pick you up again.
We'll see about that...
Wow, you're clever... You know I can't do that... You win this one...
Mind if I said something?
No.
Please don't compare Kashif and Annie...
Why?
Annie's her older sister. She could learn a thing or two from her.
Aye, but every kid is different...
I mean, can you imagine Kashif dressing up like Annie, like, ever?
Annie's always been good at her studies.
Kashif's satisfied with scoring just enough to --
-Okay... I get it.
And yeah...
Please try to accept Annie's new look.
Stop lecturing her on it all the time.
I've accepted her.
I don't say anything.
Except... Paying a little attention to herself?
Aye. I know you inside out...
You almost didn't let her cover up!
And you started bugging my late Mum ever since she started veiling!
But when did I say anything to her?
Don't you remember?
At Ahmed's wedding anniversary, you said that Annie's been possessed by Mum... Which is why she's started covering up!
Blimey, Amjad... That was just a lighthearted remark...
I didn't know it was her friend Ayesha's fault back then...
And what's my fault? I'm getting late for office... Now where'd I keep the keys?
Here.
-Thank you.
See you.
-Take care.
Ayesha!
Hey!
-Hey.
How are you?
-Good, you.
About yesterday's assignment...
Come in.
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © HUM Europe