Hmm...
'Ty ar rent'? Nah...
'Ty i'w rentu'!
T-Y   I-'-W   R-E-N-T-U.
Actually, no... Write in English. 'House for rent'!
English?
I've spent so much to get you educated! Can't you write it in English?
H-O-U-S-E   F-O-R   R-E-N-T! Get to it!
Bedar Khan's here to ruin yah lives!
Get up y'alls! Bedar Khan's here!
Hey!
Locked?
Lovely...
I knew it...
That's why I came prepared...
I'll have me lunch here... Pray here... And sleep here...
Let the waiting begin!
Lemme see who's got the guts to stop me!
Because NO ONE can stop Bedar Khan!
What are you doing, man? Hello?
You gettin' eggs or layin' eggs?
Got to lay in wait up on the top floor!
They curfewed the city or something?
-I got yah!
I've had me eyes on you for so long!
Dead...
Just wait 'til I get me hands on ya!
-What's Bedar Khan doing here?
He'd kill us for real!
Don't underestimate him! And -- Thank goodness you locked the door from outside!
-Alright, listen...
Stay quiet.
-Don't try anything smart! Okay?
Motor vehicles underwent changes in the 1980s and 90s... Just pray I ace this exam, Annie!
What, you got an exam? When? Today?
My second-last paper, remember?
On Sunday?
-It's Sunday?
Aye... You had your paper on Monday... Tuesday... -ish?
Blimey... This psychology paper's makin' me a blimmin' PSYCHO!
Can't disagree there, Eve...
And... What are you wearing?
-What?
Shut up!
You may not know it but -- It's in vogue!
Get me some breakfast!
I'll sort you out later... Your Puny Majesty!
C'mon, write it!
And if you can't, pull your ears and stand over there all day!
'Allo?
Ie?
Eh?
Fell down?
Down the mynydd?
To the dickens with you! Book a ticket for me, I'm headed for Beddgelert right away!
Book a flight! I don't care how much it costs!
Caewch i fyny! I'm comin' right away!
Curse my luck! I'm comin', son...
Put it up straight... Nah, it's too much to the right!
You sure this won't help us get the right sorta tenants, Naina?
-Annie! Annie!
What's this?
Putting up this poster for the annex...
Wasn't it enough to put it up on the internet?
-Not enough to get a tenant, apparently!
Well, it's me your clients are bugging! And -- Mrs Randhawa would be here any moment!
-Goodness... What makes these women so...!
By the way, that's my marker and tape you're using!
How'd I put it up?
-Why don't you ask your sweet Annie?
'House for rent'
God, I'm gonna die... My BP's dropping...
Just kick Bedar Khan out!
Get up!
-What is it?
I can't take it anymore... We need to move out.
-Aye... For the love of God... Let's just leave this place...
Gimme that... I'm honestly starving...
-Bedar Khan!
Mam! Mam! Okay, stop... You can just sit across the pond and talk! But Annie's not interested in this proposal! All she cares about is her annex... Or her gym classes!
Yeah why don't you say that to Mam-gu? I'm here to study, okay? So keep me out of it. Bye.
Aye, I'll have my lunch... Bye...
Iesu Grist...
Hello? Aye, Crime Master Koko here!
Yeah, it's her assistant.
How many? We're renting the annex, not a village! No way.
What was that?
Naina ma'am's clear we don't want to rent the place to many people.
-Well, why don't you let her do what she wants?
As the man in the house - and the servant - it's my duty too...
-Your Tad sent you here to study, young man! Why don't you open your books for a change?
Not books... It's the exams I dread, Milord!
Ehh?
Just turn around...
Watch out!
Stop!
-Wait here.
Ow...
Heavens, mate... Can't you see where you're going?
Annie!
What happened?
Mrs Randhawa's fine! Just -- her nail chipped, okay?
All the clients left me!
For?
They left the gym, smarty!
They're scared they may break something like Mrs Randhawa.
Get her a tissue, Koko! Right now! From the car.
Easy there, Annie... It's okay... They were burdening the earth anyway...
Easy for you to say. My gym's empty. No one's renting the annex. My business is failing. How d'you expect me to take it easy?
Oh, forget this place... Think of where you're going... The people around you... And the match Mam picked for you?
-Never! Get it?
I can't think of anyone but Alastair Brook!
He was your fiancé! Not your husband! You'll find someone!
No, there's nobody like him! There will be nobody like him! Alastair Brook... A babbling brook brimming with perfection...
Lovely eyes... Enchanting style... Wonderful personality... That melodious voice singing poetry in every word...
The man in the tuxedo looking at me from under that hat...
There's nobody like him in the world! There can be nobody!
Okay, but... Just... Get some rest...
'To Let'
I've got an exam tomorrow, I gotta study. Checking on Mrs Randhawa's wasted enough time already...
Your Mam's ravin' mad! 67th time she's calling me! Looks like she got nothin' else to do there on the other side of the pond! You better sort it out with her, okay? Come!
This one?
Yeah?
You outta your mind? Who d'you think you are?
-Aye, so what?
My Dad's got a bigger mansion in Devon!
You mean the one you got kicked out of for this love of acting?
-As if your Dad booked you a flight to LA.
I ain't staying anywhere else. Willy-nilly.
You'd get us killed.
Never underestimate what Shobi can do!
I got this one...
C'mon...
You know my business is failing! And all you care about is my marriage?
Oh, I've heard this before... You're the older sister, you love and care for your little sister...
Eve's leaving for your place in a month, I'll be left alone, and you'll be left worrying... I know all of that but I don't care!
I'm not going to Tad in Toronto. In case you don't remember, Alastair Brook died because of him! He had an accident after meeting Tad!
You know how sensitive he was! I can't forget it for a moment!
Goodness --
You --
I'm so disturbed... I'll talk to you later...
Just -- Why... Why do you have to bring him up every time?
Yes, sir?
Could you call the man of the house?
-What do I look like?
A kiddo?
-It's Crime Master Koko, okay?
-Of course...
We're here to talk about this notice, sir... Could you call someone who'd...?
Just a minute. Lemme throw this out.
The kid's the real deal, mate...
Aye.
-Come in...
C'mon...
Whoa!
Always the embarrassment, eh?
-Who is it?
-Whoa!
-Hey!
You dropped all my papers!
-Good Lord...
Who are they?
-Our new tenants. Here to see Naina ma'am...
Take them to her... What are they doing here?
Shahabuddin Shobi and Böri.
Please...
Don't cover those sightly eyes...
Take them in.
-Ma'am.
Come.
-Kiddo?
Aye...
Theatre or film... Hollywood or BBC...
You ain't getting this annex until I've met your family.
As if we're here with a proposal...
-What? What was that?
Get up! What was that just now?
He means -- Our families don't live here...
-Then how'd you think you could live here?
We're new here...
We're looking for a place to stay until we've bought a mansion ourselves...
-I can totally see that...
What?
That you're here to buy a mansion...
What's your problem?
-We don't let men stay here without their families.
I'm sure we can get along... Like a family?
-Ehh? What?
-What d'you think you're doing?
I can have the cops vouch for me right now if that's what you --
-Oh, can it...
Go and get your parents to vouch for you instead.
Clear? Now get goin'!
Which, in case you don't get it, means get out!
Ma'am...
Our parents... Aren't with us anymore...
-Aww... You've got no one? Well, then...
Why don't you go to an orphanage instead?
C'mon, now! Get out!
-...Except -- That one Uncle...
Yeah! Of course! In Swansea, remember?
-Yeah? Okay -- Ah, yes, him! Yeah! Swansea!
Got a name?
-A big name! Tell her! Very famous -- A writer... An intellectual...
-He's very famous! Very intellectual!
A man held in the highest regard and --
-Just give us a name, we can Google the rest.
Of course...
-Yeah, what's his name? Where does he live?
Alastair Brook.
Come again?
-Alastair Brook.
Don't you like it?
No.
In fact, it's lovely.
I guess, on that note...
-NO!
The only thing I'm gonna note is what your Uncle says about you.
Koko! Man in the house!
Ma'am?
-Throw 'em out. O-U-T!
Aye, get out! Out!
-Hey -- Just a sec...
C'mon...
C'mon!
-See you.
I said throw 'em out! Make sure they're outta your sights! And lock the gate!
-He's coming after us!
Annie...
Annie...?
I don't think I can find a place for us...
By the way, I've been thinking all night... How are you gonna bring your late Uncle back from the grave?
-You don't know what Shobi can do!
Oh, please... Save it for that wretch Bedar Bukht! How long are you gonna take anyway?
Ta da!
What am I looking at?
Lenses? Doesn't it hurt?
A bit, but it's okay!
But -- Wh -- Just -- Why?
Could you... Tell it's me?
No... But... You're outta your mind! Now if you'll excuse me, I gotta go take a shower!
I'm gonna kill him!
Oi! Caught ya!
'Ere!
'Scuse me, who?
It's me!
-Listen, guv, I only know two blokes 'round 'ere. Two blokes who stay but don't pay. Saw them?
Listen, guv, I only know two blokes 'round 'ere. Two blokes who stay but don't pay. Saw them?
Gone.
-Eh?
Gone, Mr Khan!
-Really?
Böri... My nephew... Had an accident...
May his soul rest in peace...
Wasn't you with 'im?
Real bad news indeed...
Last time I came here, I saw this big lock...
Anyway, who're you?
His Uncle...
-For real?
Yeah... Just here to... Get his things... Clothes and all, you know... His mother's just... Crying buckets...
Most unfortunate... She poor?
Very.
Alrigh', easy there, guv... It pains to see you cryin'...
'Ere...
This is --
Back off, it ain't all yours! Get it?
Just -- Pray for me, okay?
So sad... There goes all my rent...
Why d'you leech our money if you've got so much?
Grist... Why do I have to do everything here?
Who is it this time?
Let's just say someone...
Who takes the road...
Less travelled by...
The name's Brook...
Alastair Brook.
But please, call me Amadeus... All the other poets do.
Unbelievable...
To believe, or not to believe... That is the question. But it is nobler to believe. By the way, who'd you be?
Naina.
Naina...
Such heavenly touches ne'er touched earthly eyes.
Your name... Personality... And style...
They remind me of someone very close...
Be careful who you hold close... Too close and they bring you to tears...
How d'you know?
Elementary, my dear Naina...
I can read everything...
On your face.
Your eyes as deep as the oceans... I'd rather drown --
-Please...
Yeah, let's talk business.
I hear the boys were here yesterday.
Shahab and Böri.
There's only one name I remember...
Shahabuddin Shobi!
Your nephew, is he?
Of course...
More like a son, really.
That's what they all say.
Anyway, Madame... How much would you want in advance?
Forget it --
-Oh, lots!
Just send them... We'll sort it out with them.
Sort what out with them?
The deal for the annex.
Of course... I'll take my leave.
-I'm sure you'd be back soon?
I'm leaving a piece of myself here...
My nephew, get it? Almost like my son?
Good day.
Uncle!
Your phone.
Please... Call me Alastair Brook.
Lovely name.
Take care.
Thank you.
What are you doing? Go after him, man!
Make sure he doesn't come back!
The same look, the same style, the same personality...
The same eyes...
And the same love for poetry.
It's...
Outta this world!
Unbelievable!
-Annie!
He looked like a poor counterfeit Alastair Brook to me, the codger!
No...
There was something about him...
My heart tells me there's something about him...
My Spidey-sense tells me there's something about him too...
What?
Well...
I guess we're about to find out!
♪ My crew's all fired up! ♪
Whoa!
What the devil?
-It's -- Just a flowerpot!
Was a flowerpot!
Sorry, we didn't see it...
-Go get your eyes checked!
Well, Miss Evensong... Why don't you just pray the Lord heals our eyes?
Why'd you say her name?
D'you want me to call her Koko?
-All of that later... I want this month's rent!
God knows where your Uncle disappeared after casting his poetic spells!
Ma'am! Glad to see you!
I've got something for you from Uncle Brook.
-Yeah?
He said he's gonna talk about the rent and all with you... In private.
Of course, if that's what he wants... But no worries... Who cares about the rent anyway?
Let me take care of it, byt. Okay?
Where's he, by the way?
Right here.
Huh?
As in... Us... Or Uncle... What does it matter?
-Aye, what's it matter?
He'd be here tomorrow -- for lunch?
-Sure. On us.
Bless you!
Just your Uncle.
Not you two!
Okay. No problem.
-Okay.
Aww...
I'll send something for you.
-Thank you.
We'll get going then?
1 p.m.?
-12.45.
Yeah. Tell him, okay?
Koko! Show them the annex.
Okay, ma'am... Okay, Miss Eve...
See you!
-Of course!
What's for lunch?
-Bloody poison!
And who broke this?
-What do I -- THEY DID, of course!
Psst!
Listen to this one, Koko...
You're the man here.
-I know, Eve...
So, naturally, you're watching the two suspicious men here. Especially their Uncle!
Don't worry. Crime Master Koko won't disappoint you.
Great! On your feet, soldier! Your mission impossible commences now! Good luck and Godspeed!
Go, Koko, Go! Whoa!
Whoa!
Lovely place...
Not bad, Naina...
Fully-furnished...
Did you see how Naina looked at you? What a cute snake!
You'd be found dead on the street if you let her bite you!
Watch it mate... Getting this place wasn't easy!
Just pray your mate's career kickstarts! I'll build something better for you!
Quit daydreaming!
Lying on this bed, I ain't dreaming of anything short of Cinderella!
Hey there, laddie!
Koko!
Come in.
-Come here, mate...
How d'you like the room?
What were you doing here?
Listening in on us?
Who d'you work for? Miss Eve?
Well, then, let's go see her...
So, Crime Master Koko... The unsuccessful Sherlock Holmes!
Let's meet your Watson, shall we?
Naina ma'am wants to see me...
Hey! Ko --
You got him to spy on us!
Why would I?
I can see it on your face.
-What other theories can you discover on it?
Quite a few, to be honest. The plain, and the mysterious, the --
-Hold it... No one wants to hear it.
Please, don't...
This look suits you.
Behave yourself!
My hair, my choice!
Sir! Your roadie's here.
What a lovely feeling...
That's the tenth time you said that...
I guess 10's my lucky number... And this time, it's for real!
'Far as I remember, it was for real the seventh time too!
C'mon, mate! Get off! Let's go have something... It's cheat night!
What's up?
Just singing an Evensong... Praying...
-For?
For something...
That could change a man's life...
I'm really sorry... I was too rude back then...
Really...
What if I didn't say it's okay?
You have to...
It ain't okay, it ain't okay, it ain't okay!
Shobi!
Not okay...
-Shobi! Hey!
Shobi! Hey!
Get up! Naina's calling your other number!
-Put a sock in it!
Here! Talk to her!
-You had to ruin my dream, didn't you? Get me some tea...
Sir, yes sir. Anything else, sir? Don't forget to talk to her, sir!
-Go!
Jesus...
What the actual --
Now we mix this...
No, not this... Whoops...
What next?
What's up, top chef?
Gee... Why'd you have to interrupt me? I was following this recipe!
But why?
We've got special guests for lunch... Could you help me dice this nice and small?
No way I'm doin' anything!
Okay, go ask Koko to clean the drawing room. I want it shining bright!
They don't deserve it!
-Hey!
Go and ask him to clean the room. I'll be checking!
Grist... I lost track of everything...
Annie!
-Ie?
You burnt the coq au vin!
-Good Heavens!
The advance. Right here. Right now.
Hello? Where's the advance?
You've got some fine manners, girl...
Not finer than yours.
Look at how you stare!
When do we get the advance? No freebies for anyone here. I need it right now -- Annie needs it! Just put the blimmin' flowers away!
Ow!
Wait until I'm through with you!
What's with all this salt?
-Just pray I don't poison him!
Everything ready? Aye.
C'mon, now, quickly. I'm sure he's starving!
-Just a minute!
Here!
Specially for you.
The pleasure is all mine...
Please, try some...
-Sure.
Coq au vin... Always a favourite...
I always thought you'd rather like fried brains...
Plaît-il, Madame?
By the way... What d'you produce at your factories?
I'd tell you if I could count...
I think I'll try the afters, Miss Naina...
Not just yet... You got to finish that first!
Or is it you don't like it?
No, it's fantastic... Made with love, evidently...
I won't know that until you've finished it...!
Before we forget... What about the rent?
You better not say anything, Annie... I've got no money and I need to go shopping!
Well, in that case... You can take my card... Get whatever you want... Anything...
Why are you giving me your card? I'd rather have some cash, you know.
The times have changed... Haven't they, Miss Naina? Who uses cash today?
Ie.
Password?
What d'you think you're doing? Give him his card back.
Give it back!
Fine!
Here. Don't worry about the rent... And don't worry about her... Heaven knows what's wrong with her!
-It's okay...
I'm sure we can work something out...
Uh...
Looks like she didn't like that!
Forget her... She's always a bit round the twist... Please, enjoy the meal...
Annie's blinded by love...
I'll have to deal with him myself... By the way, what the devil is the old devil doing in there for so long?
I'll have to deal with him myself... By the way, what the devil is the old devil doing in there for so long? There you are!
You're dead for real!
Where's he off to?
That blighter Vikram!
No luck?
He only casts his own fellas. We're strapped for cash. Gotta leave this place.
-Calm down, mate!
Lady Luck's on our side!
Where is he?
Where the devil is Alastair 'Amadeus' Brook? Yeah?
Hey!
-Yeah -- Where's Uncle Amadeus? -- Gone...
-Gone?
I just saw him come here!
Where's he hiding?
-What's wrong with you?
I've got a problem with your Uncle! He's acting Romeo to my sister's Juliet, that blimming --
I'm gonna be the end of him!
Ever fell in love?
Eww!
Had a crush?
No.
-Bet you've got someone in your heart!
Bet you've got someone in your heart!
-I'm not off my head yet!
I'm not off my head yet!
-What makes you think you can understand what my Uncle and your Annie feel for each other?
What makes you think you can understand what my Uncle and your Annie feel for each other?
Wait a minute --
Don't touch me!
Okay... But... The name's Shahabuddin Shobi.
Shobi or a showman... You're our tenant.
Don't dream of taking over this place... Or our hearts!
Which reminds me...
The
The rent.
The rent. Right
The rent. Right now.
Don't you dare, smarty-pants!
What are you thinking?
Uncle's discussed everything with Miss Naina...
I mean -- Why are you so worried? It's not good for your health?
When?
Yeah -- Discussed -- Everything...
My blood's boiling --
My blood's boiling -- Calm down --
My blood's boiling -- Calm down -- Calm down, Eve --
My blood's boiling -- Calm down -- Calm down, Eve -- No way, I can't! Just --
My blood's boiling -- Calm down -- Calm down, Eve -- No way, I can't! Just -- SHUT UP!!!
Outta my way!
-Good Lord...
That 'shut up' ignited something in my heart...
She'll cut you up and feed you to the dogs!
-Don't worry, you'll be safe.
-Much appreciated.
What are you so worried about, Mr Brook? I'll take care of everything. Don't worry at all, okay?
Alright, if you're going to Swansea... Be careful, okay? Don't drive too fast... The thought of it scares me...
Promise me...
Don't worry, I'll take care of them. They're having the coq au vin too... Take care.
Are we turning into Hungry House for the hungry blokes in the house?
What's your problem? He was so kind... I mean, who'd give his MAC card like that? He even told you his password!
I thought he nearly died that moment.
-Gotta go serve them the coq au vin...
Gotta go serve them the coq au vin...
-You ain't going anywhere, Annie...
You ain't going anywhere, Annie...
-What's wrong with you? I'm sure they're starving! The least we can do is be kind...
They're hungry?
-Yeah, I'm sure the poor souls are starving. Lemme go...
Poor souls?
-Yeah, I mea -- Just lemme go!
Annie!
I'm dying to taste the coq au vin! And, couldn't you ask for the bouillabaisse too?
That all you care about?
I've got no idea how I can tell Eve how much I love her...
If that weren't enough, there's this blasted Naina!
Right here...!
From Alastair Brook... With love!
I thought he left for Swansea?
He has a place in our hearts.
Uhh... Just the coq au vin? I mean -- bread or, anything?
Oh, yeah, sorry... I'll ask Koko to get you what you want...
I called Mr Brook to tell him you're trying it... But his phone's switched off...
He'll check it any second...
-Hem hem!
I mean -- I'm sure he's just having issues with the signal -- On the way...?
Exactly. That's what I was thinking. You'll get what you want, don't worry.
-Thank you.
She'll make you pay for every bite if she found out, you twit!
No time. Lemme enjoy this!
Jesus...
No way... I can't do it. C'mon, we're leaving...
Lemme try the coq au vin... And -- What about all the times you said, 'You don't know what Shahab can do'? I know you can do it!
You won't get it, mate --
-Just... Talk to her.
Tell her we got it... We'll sort it out later, mate... I'll go get some bread... Okay?
Please, don't...
This look suits you.
I know how you feel, Mr Brook...
I understand everything...
I understand your hesitation...
But, if it helps... I feel the same way...
And...
You know I'm happy with it...
I'm -- I'm texting you my sister's number... Could you send the proposal to her?
I can't live without you...
I understand... Uhh... I'll get back to you, Miss Naina...
Thank you.
Gotta say, the coq au vin was lovely.
-I'm tired of living this lie!
What's she saying?
-Oh, nothing...
She just wants me - that is, Alastair Brook - to send a proposal to her sister!
Way to go, mate!
Looks like we just enjoyed her wedding feast... In advance!
Shut up, I'm out of ideas!
I don't know why it's always me --
-What happened? Where are you off to?
I'm gonna throw this laptop out!
-Throw the charger too... Someone may still be able to use it!
Thank you. Shut up, Koko!
-What happened?
I was in the middle of this presentation when this piece of junk decided to die!
Just ask tech support or something... Why are you throwing it out? It's so expensive!
I can try that... Though I don't really want to... But if it didn't work, I'm not sparing this pile of junk!
Bye!
-Hey!
What're you doing? Go after her! Quick!
This blasted piece of junk...
-Okay...
Can't you see?
-Were you not so angry all the time, I swear, I'd only have eyes for you...!
She's throwing her laptop out.
-It caught COVID-19 or something?
It caught COVID-19 or something?
-No, it caught your kind of ScallyVirus! It's useless now!
Well, I may just have the cure...
-Are you a doctor?
Maybe?
-No way.
And if I got it working?
-I'll give you whatever you want!
I'll give you whatever you want!
-Promise?
Promise?
-Promise.
Promise.
-Good.
Charger?
Make sure he doesn't hack it or something!
Koko!
Get my charger from my room.
-Never knew you needed one too!
My laptop charger...!
Why d'you make it sound so hard?
Ooh, gotta say that's a dangerous virus...
Our hero battles it valiantly... Who's gonna win this?
The virus...
The virus... Or me?
What's going on?
Hi, Miss Naina!
He's fixing it...
Why's your Uncle not taking my calls? Been trying for ages.
-He's busy somewhere else...
What?
-I mean -- He'll be here tomorrow...
Sure?
200%!
Don't forget to tell me!
Sure... You can try calling using your landline... Just in case it's something with the signal.
Ie, why didn't I think of that? Just a sec!
Gotta say...
Someone misses him too much!
Back to work.
Okay.
Took you long enough!
-Here.
Okay...
Plug it in, will you?
-Okay.
Come here...
5...
-5...
4...
-4...
3...
-3...
2...
-2...
You lose! It's working!
Sorry!
Koko...
Take it to my room.
Get ready to fulfil your end of the bargain!
You heard me. Take it to my room.
Thanks shobi for the help :)
There.
'My pleasure'
What do you want from me???????
A blessing... An Evensong
'Evensong'?
'Could you dedicate one to me?'
Think again
Ain't you asking for too much?
Who's this?
'As stunning'...
'As you're smart'...
'I like you'?
Who is it? And how dare he? I'll teach him a lesson...
You 'like' me, eh?
-This call cannot be completed due to insufficient balance.
This call cannot be completed due to insufficient balance.
Jeez!
I'm entrusting her to you...
Take care of her, okay?
-No, Hadi...
Annie!
I've got no balance but I gotta call someone...
♪ At every turn doth sorrow await... ♪
♪ Such is my cruel fate... ♪
♪ Every golden dream lies shattered... ♪
♪ I cry out, haggard and pale... ♪
♪ A memory from the distant past, ♪
♪ A tear that may be my last... ♪
♪ Why punish me with this cruel fate, my Lord? ♪
You know you're the only one who can tell Dad how much I enjoy acting...
I promise you, I'll make you proud one day... Or come back the same old...
I'll call you in a sec, Mum...
Gotta say, you're quite the actor.
Those looks could kill, I swear...
Been missing me? I didn't text back...
-Call him.
Call your Uncle. Right now.
Uncle?
Yeah.
Are you serious? It's so late. I'm sure he turned in, I don't want to --
No, he's up, and he just texted me something... Wanna hear it?
'You're as stunning as you're smart. I like you.'
Turns out, we'd been sleeping. Annie and I... In ignorance... Just -- What is this?
Lemme show you...
C'mon, take the call...
Yeah? And don't you dare lie again.
I checked Annie's phone myself. That's Alastair Brook's number.
You're Alastair Brook, aren't you?
Aren't you? D'you feel, like, ashamed of yourself, like, ever?
D'you have any idea how much it'd hurt her? How much you've hurt her feelings? You vile snake!
Listen to me, Eve -- I had my reasons --
-Oh, you did?
No! Don't say anything. Ever thought how she feels for this Alastair Brook? We had enough worries without you doing any of this!
What could we do? You wouldn't rent the house to us --
-So you can try your acting skills on us? Lie to us?
Do you have any idea she's actually fallen for this Alastair Brook?
-I --
I --
-Shut up! Just shut up!
I'm gonna tell Annie everything, and she's gonna kick you out!
You're a goner...
Just try to understand, I have no interest in him. Never was, never will be.
One thing's for sure... I can't leave Alastair Brook -- Gee, what's wrong with you? God forbid...
The living Alastair Brook! Don't ever say that again!
Our engagement... Wedding... Honeymoon... I've planned for everything!
Just tell Dad in Toronto... I'm not gonna budge this time.
Where are you off to? Just -- Get our things, we gotta slip away sharpish!
Where can we go? And for how long?
You came here from Kildress. My Dad kicked me out of the house... That's when I left Devon. What're we gonna tell our families?
You told 'em you work at a bank...
There comes a day when you live a lie, but night falls and you gotta tell the truth. And, like it or not, the night's fallen on our lives.
So please... Don't stop me today... If I didn't tell them the truth... I don't think I will ever be able to face them.
I know you're worried. But it was my plan, and I'll fix it. Just -- Leave this place... Don't stay around here. I'll take care of everything.
What are you thinking? I say -- Forget the things, let's just slip away --
-Just go! I got this...
Whatever did you say to him? He says he'll kill himself -- Hang himself -- Jump from the roof -- Or something...
I mean -- Yeah, we shouldn't have done it -- And we're sorry --
But d'you even know how much he --
I'm sure you've told Miss Naina everything?
Okay. Fair 'nuff. Could you ask her to come here? He'll tell her everything. Because he's got the courage to face his lies.
Tell her everything so we get kicked out again, okay?
-I didn't say anything...
I didn't say anything...
It's no good...
She's --
She's head over heels for your 'Alastair Brook'... Engagement, wedding, honeymoon... She's planned everything!
I came here to study so we could help her forget her Alastair Brook.
Then you came in with a second Alastair Brook and ruined everything!
Like, seriously? You didn't say anything?
I can tell her if that's what you want!
-No, wait...
Don't worry... We'll fix this.
-Just -- How?
Look at your lives! You're struggling to fix your own lives, what can you fix ours?
Don't worry. We'll work something out.
Oh, please, can it.
I promise we'll -- Why don't you say something? -- We'll work something out...
We came up with this idea... We'll come up with something else...
-What, Alastair Brook the Third?
No idea... But something...
What? And why should I trust liars like you two?
We may not have earned it... But you got to trust us this one time...
C'mon, fire up your grey cells! There must be something...
Shobi?
You're the only one who can come up with these kinds of things.
Idea!
She's got something! C'mon!
I know someone who can get us out of this...
Who?
The one and only...
The one and only... The super-rich...
The one and only... The super-rich... Uncle Rufus!
Good day, sir!
Good day, sir. A very good day to you...
'Course...
Admit it already...
You've lost to Alastair 'Amadeus' Brook.
Touché...
Rufus?
When did you get here?
Romeo.
Rufus Romeo.
No one dares lay a finger on Naina with Rufus Romeo around.
Although, to be honest, I'm so disappointed.
He's no match for you. Can't believe you're playing him. What's wrong with you?
Ever heard anyone mention -- Whatzit? Your name?
-Alastair --
Alastair --
-Allô?
Oui, je sais que ces fichiers sont importants.
(Yeah, I know they're important.)
Oui, ils sont prêts.
(Yeah, they're ready.)
Look, I'm a bit busy right now...
So you'll have to wait...
Could you deal with them?
I don't care if their company's goin' bankrupt! Bye!
Yeah, go on.
The name's Alastai --
-Jiminy Cricket, these emails...
Females?
Emails.
You didn't even tell me!
-Uncle Rufus?
Blimey, you're actually here! I'm so happy!
-Yeah! Blimey, I'm actually here! So am I!
And what were you playing?
Who's this old chap, by the way? I must've missed his name -- What's up with him?
He bowled me over the moment he entered, that imitation swashbuckler!
I say, let's pack our things and get going... Our days here are numbered anyhow.
We can't... Not when... Eve's given me some hope...
Forget your Evensong... Forever!
And to think you almost had Naina... Until now.
Oh, please... Just leave me alone...
Done...
There.
Not so fast!
Would you look at that?
These losers can't even start their bike... And you want to start a new life with their Uncle! Seriously, what's wrong with you?
As if my life's a bike... By the way, you here to say anything nice?
-Huh?
'Course not, but -- You know --
There!
Big deal. Took 'em 12 kicks. I've been counting.
How many would it take you?
Full steam ahead!
-Just look at these losers! You seriously comparing them to me? What's wrong with you?
Just look at these losers! You seriously comparing them to me? What's wrong with you?
Right...
But you ever thought how low I'd have to stoop for you?
-How?
For instance... I hate how everything's got a price for you! You blimmin' huckster!
Hey! W --
What's wrong with you, mate?
What happened?
Hey!
Can't you win her heart and live up to your name, Romeo? Wonder how you win over your customers!
-What's wrong with you? That's what I'm here to learn!
Just... Forget you're Rufus...
From now on... You're just Romeo... And she's your Juliet!
How's that sound?
-Fascinating... Worth a shot!
-Yes!
I ain't Rufus... Just... Romeo... And she's... Juliet! Just Romeo! Not Rufus!
-Romeo, aye! Juliet! Just Romeo! Not Rufus!
Rufus Romeo...
I'm sure Alastair Brook sent it...
I see your eyes smile...
And forget my sorrows for a while...
Water.
Who sent this here?
Can't be anyone but your Romeo!
-Huh?
Hmm...
Alastair Brook better exit stage right today!
To the dickens with 'im... What d'you -- What does Uncle Rufus think of me?
How do I know?
Okay, what d'you think of me?
You're reall --
Don't distract me! Go! Double time! Get ready for your last scene as Alastair Brook!
Blimey... WhAT d'YoU ThINk oF mE...
Ie, that --
Don't you think the good chap here...
Has a thing for pulling our legs?
Jesus, what now?
'Allo?
Not again! Daan't ask me why I daan't loike ter be wif ya...
As your 'usband, Beca... I order ya ter sha sum respect for your co-wife!
I'll explain it ter me girl Catrin when I'm 'ome...
Bye!
Cheese and Rice...
So, Uncle... You've got two wives?
No...
Three, actually...
-Three!?
Aye... Had to kick poor Mari out... She broke me love Beca's leg in a fit of rage...
What it is is...
I'm looking for someone...
To replace Mari...
Alastair -- You've got -- Two wives -- Two - and you didn't even tell me!
Sorry, I think he said three... Yes?
Y -- You never asked...
Big mistake. Get up. Out!
Annie! How 'bout we sort this out after lunch?
-Shut up!
-Yeah, get out!
Out! Kick him out already!
-No one takes my Naina for a ride!
-But -- Lunch?
You blasted cheat! You dare romance me when you've got two or three wives?
Aren't you ashamed of yourself? Get out!
-Don't let the door hit you where the good Lord split you!
And you dare come here for lunch?
-Bu -- Miss Naina!
-Throw him out!
See you not, Uncle!
Are you okay, Annie?
You think I'm okay? Do I look okay?
I'm sorry!
-Well, as they say...
Like a ghost from the days past...
Lovely!
-That wretched man --
Left me --
-Ie, that wretch! That wicked wretch!
-That treacherous wretch...
-Annie!
How could you do that?
I've heard girls need a shoulder in moments like these...
And Romeos never miss the chance!
So -- I think I should get going... By the way... I look alright, don't I? Thank you!
-Yes! Of course! The best! All the best!
Dyw, what a mess...
Tad didn't like the first Alastair Brook... And the second turned out to be second-rate!
Dreadful luck...
Why d'you always dial the wrong number?
-No idea...
Look at me...
-And?
Not like that... It's a bit embarrassing... I just mean --
You've...
Always got me...
I'm all yours.
There!
Your phone... Something about your business... Innit?
-Aye. Aye.
Meetings, business deals, tours... You're always chasing money! You've got no time for anything else, have you?
What about that deal? That meeting you just missed?
Look, I ain't to blame if you lost something just now!
You are --
-There! Knew it!
There! Knew it!
-You're not!
Of course you're not...
And -- I ain't just chasing money... I've been chasing this lady -- My lady... For ages...
-Of course!
But I don't know why you don't even look at me...
I've waited for you all my life...
I've loved you...
Every moment of my life...
Just you...
I've got everything, but the only thing I ever prayed for...
Is you...
You're the only thing I can't lose.
You can ask Eve...
How I felt...
When she told me about this cheat Alastair Brook...
That's why I left everything...
And came here...
I'm not going anywhere...
Not this time...
Not until I've got you...
Naina...
Behind Rufus...
Awaits your Romeo.
He pleades you...
To be his Juliet...
Please?
Really?
Really.
One less mess in the world...
Juliet...
And her Romeo...
Get their happy ending this time...
Alastair Brook's gone for good! Good riddance, I say!
Mr Rufus Romeo's arranging the funeral...
By the way, this -- Whatzit -- Rufus -- Romeo -- Whatever...
He's a tough one, for real... He better not be the end of my love story...
Don't you always say, 'You don't know what I can do'? Well, show me, Shobi!
Now you're suckin' diesel.
Stand up!
Hands up!
Actually -- Hands down...
So... Which one of you is Shahab, a.k.a. Shobi?
It's him!
-Me?
Aye.
-Aye... It's me...
Knew it. And who's Siggeir, a.k.a. Böri?
It's him, obviously... I mean, who else've got here?
You're Siggeir... And Böri?
Yeah.
-Ooh, impressive.
Knew it. But you know the drill...
CitizenCards! I wanna see yours!
What's wrong with you, guys?
This is only the beginning...
7 p.m....
I want 50k rent...
And 50k advance... Which makes...
50... 50... 100k...
Aye, knew it. I was just testin' you. I want 100k, okay?
He's paying. Yeah, he is...
Aye, because...
Aye, because... W --
Aye, because... W -- Why not?
But I'd need some time --
-Not much, really...
Yeah, gotta go to the ATM and get the money...
How cute!
I give your cute and calamitous selves...
Until 7 p.m. today... And your time starts...
Until 7 p.m. today... And your time starts... NOW!
Why'd you have to call that blasted Romeo?
-As if I knew he's gonna be our doom!
Here's a tip. Sell your kidney. Problem solved!
Shut up!
I swear, I'd curse this place and leave... If I didn't love Eve so much!
They're gonna curse us and kick us out if we don't pay the rent!
Eve sent this for you...
Okay...
What's this?
-How cute...
Can't be a love letter... Not in this day and age...
What is so urgent that you...
Ie... You needed some money... I thought I'd lend a hand...
Pitying me now, eh?
Thought you could buy me with this...?
Look, Annie's gonna kick you out for real if she didn't get the rent...
I'm sorry, but I can't take this...
And I'm sorry, but you've got to take it!
I love you...
C'mon... I got everything...
Get up, boyo!
By the way, when'd you become so upright? Returned 50k in a second!
I...
Couldn't take it...
I felt...
I should give it back...
On the bright side, I scored some brownie points for being upright...
And? Eve can't be yours now. Congratulations.
C'mon, get your things, and let's get going... Just forget her...
I can't, mate...
I just can't forget her...
The final act played out like a proper tragedy...
I even thought...
I'd give up on acting and take up a job at Dad's factory for her...
What's wrong with you?
Couldn't you find anyone other than this blimmin' actor?
As if she could find anyone other than a second-rate counterfeit copy of her fiancé!
Look where it got me. You wanna end up like me?
He didn't really deserve you though...
Aye... No one deserves Naina...
More... Than her Romeo...
But he's a good lad.
I mean --
So upright...
As in?
As in...
I could see right through his disguise...
I told Naina right away... But we thought we'd wait... Enjoy the show until the curtain fell...
What? You?
-Yeah, just like you... I mean -- You were interested in him and you didn't even tell me!
Yeah, just like you... I mean -- You were interested in him and you didn't even tell me!
And -- It ain't your fault... I mean, he's a nice lad... From a decent family... He's done an MBA too... It's just -- This thing he's got for acting that's in his way --
I can work on that! You just gotta convince Tad-cu and Mam!
Don't worry. I can work on it too.
I know what you're so excited about...
Grist, can we talk about me first?
Can't hurt if we got married the same day as you, can it?
Lovely...
Gotta say... That was one lovely performance!
I'm impressed!
Shows the lengths you can go to for Eve.
Huh?
Don't try something smart... I wanna see your parents - your real parents - for real this time... If you want to make her yours!
And...
You can stay here as long as you like... Without caring about the rent...
But if I heard you're bothering her... Or I see her crying because of you... You know it ain't gonna be good for you!
Of course... I promise...
You'll have no complaints... Don't worry...
-Aye, no complaints!
Anyway, mate... I'm knackered... Gotta go get some rest...
Nighty night!
Uhh...
Uhh?
I'll get going...
-Aye... Okay...
By the way...
-Ie?
Nothing... Nothing, really!
Okay...
-Umm...
'Night!
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb © 7th Sky Entertainment