Lemme work at Ayesha's firm. She's paying so well!
And I stay home? No way.
Our charity's been spending 25 gee on you every month for the last six months... I'm comin' over to your place tomorrow!
You're introducing Curtis to your wife... And he won't have a clue!
The name's Curtis. Top tyke in town! I know a rotter when I see one!
Your name, please?
Yes, please.
I asked you who that is.
-Ka -- Kashif's friend...
Corona or no corona... You're dead for real, mate.
-Yeah?
Why do I get a feeling your wife's down here?
Stay away from her! She's a witch, I tell you!
Don't worry, laddie, I've got one at home too.
Aren't we bros?
-Doesn't quite look like it...
He's lame and that's his wife!
-He's blind and that's his wife!
To the dickens with you!
-Hey!
-I -- Ow!
Wives always get beaten about... Break my heart but not my bones!
'Blind Love'
Good morning!
'Morning...
Your breakfast, Madame.
I would've made something for myself -- Why'd you -- ?
You do everything six days a week. You deserve a day off.
You go to work six days a week too. Take care of my needs... Comforts... You deserve a day off too.
Hold on...
Comforts? Here?
Please, Zoya... You left your comforts behind...
I mean... The daughter of the owner of Siddiqui and Co., choosing to marry a middle-class man like myself... Angering her father... Leaving her luxuries behind...
Love demands sacrifices, Mr Marlin Munro.
So, no regrets.
Thank you.
Breakfast? It's getting cold!
And aye... How 'bout going out for lunch?
No way you're wasting another penny!
Using the AC's cost us so much already.
For God's sake, Zoya... These words don't suit you.
(They suit me.) For now, though, I've got the money!
Just save it for later!
Besides, all the diners are closed. Thanks to the Coronavirus.
Guess what, I've got this friend who knows the right palms to grease. We're going to his diner!
You gonna finish your breakfast or want me to...?
Kashif!
Get up! C'mon!
2 Gee. I want it right now.
Where's your gun?
Gun?
I thought all the robbers carried one.
No -- It's just -- Zoya wants to go out for lunch... And I haven't got my salary yet...
Make her a nice big omelette for now and be done with it. Simple.
A nice big omelette, eh?
Seriously, Kashif? You've been staying here for weeks. Have I asked you for a penny? Like, ever?
The same old line you say at least ten times a month to rob me of 2 gee every time, which you never return!
Well --
-Would've been better if I paid you a rent instead!
Forget the rent... Just 2 gee? Your mate's honour's on the line!
Yeah?
Maybe next time you'd want to check your wallet before taking her out for lunch...
-Could you just check yours for now?
It's all I've got for now --
-Aye...
Aye... It'll do!
Marlin!
A 'thank you' couldn't hurt all that much, could it?
Not now!
Marlin!
I gotta thank you?
Osman's wounded her...
She's broken... Completely...
Why don't you rid yourself of this burden?
Mum says once a girl's married --
Jesus...
It's been a year since Zoya's marriage... Marlin would've demanded money if he was after it!
You don't know how patient these middle-class folks can be...
The day the lights go out of my eyes... Everything that's mine... Will be his...
I don't know it? Seriously?
In case you've forgotten, Mr Siddiqui... Before hitting the jackpot, you were no more than a middle-class folk yourself...
Don't tell me you haven't mixed some water in your shampoo to squeeze every last drop out of it!
Hey! Keep your voice down!
Big deal!
You shouldn't forget your past like that...
You shouldn't forget how hard I've worked all these years... It ain't just about a jackpot or something!
Big deal, Mr Siddiqui!
You won the money but lost your daughter's love.
Fathers sacrifice everything for their daughters.
Okay...
I'll forget everything if Zoya leaves that Marlin bloke...
Blimey, he's her husband!
Not to me!
-Okay...
Guess I gotta sort a few things out too...
I want no complaints.
Hey!
Not cricket!
That will be all...
Blimey...
After you!
Told you no one's gonna be around!
Aye, but I would've liked it better at home... But you wanted to go out for lunch...
No, Zoya... I really want to see you happy... Don't spoil my mood now...
You really want to see me happy, right?
Yes!
Then -- Just lemme work at Ayesha's firm! She's paying so nicely! I'd love to help you!
Shh!
We've talked about it and you know my decision.
What's your problem?
-Zoya...
It's about my self-respect!
Like, d'you expect me to stay home? No way!
Guess what your Dad's gonna say? 'He'S LiViNG oFf HiS WiFe'. No way I'm gonna take it quietly!
Your phone's ringing.
Who is it?
-Uhh...
My boss... I'll be right back!
Hello?
-Aye...
Martin Munro? Sorry -- Marlin Munro...
Aye...
It's...
Curtis from NBFUK...
Good day, sir...
You're the Bacon Rind Heap Of Coke, in'cha?
Our charity's been spending 25 gee on you every month for the last six months... Aye?
You've been...
You've been... Most kind,
You've been... Most kind, sir...
I'm comin' over tomorra!
Sir?
Why?
Did ya seriously fin' we'd never goose's Gregory Peck on ya?
There's nah shortage of pretenders 'ere... We just wanna make Bobby... Save this country's name, maybe...
Okay...
When are you coming?
Loike I need an appointment!
I'll drop by chicken pen I wanna!
See you!
Okay...
Bye...
WhEN aRe yOU CoMiNg?
Get me sum Ten Furlongs!
Wow...
What is it?
Nothing... Why?
You look worried... Since your boss called, you know?
Do I?
No?
It's nothing, really...
I was just thinking...
Yeah?
How...
Backward I am!
I mean, you want to work... What's my self-respect got to do with it?
Who am I to stop you? If that's what makes you happy, by all means!
Yeah?
-Hmm...
Your friend who runs that firm --
-Ayesha.
Ayesha.
-Aye, Ayesha!
Why don't you call her? You can start tomorrow. Fine by me.
What happened so suddenly?
Nothing... I just really want to see you happy, Zoya. And you're happy, right?
Of course.
-So am I.
Enjoy!
Tried this?
What's up?
What I should've done long ago...
What?
I'm going...
To Karachi...
To my daughter's...
I can't live away from her anymore.
You'd go against me?
No... Only against your bull-headedness.
I got a ticket for you too...
In case you have second thoughts tonight...
And yeah...
If you didn't come with me, don't expect me to come back.
You can live the life you want in this palace, all by yourself...
Our charity's been spending 25 gee on you every month for the last six months... Aye?
Did ya seriously fin' we'd never goose's Gregory Peck on ya?
Then -- Just lemme work at Ayesha's firm! She's paying so nicely! I'd love to help you!
Shh!
I was just thinking...
Yeah?
How...
Backward I am!
I mean, you want to work... What's my self-respect got to do with it?
Who am I to stop you? If that's what makes you happy, by all means!
I'm comin' over tomorra!
There's nah shortage of pretenders 'ere... We just wanna make Bobby... Save this country's name, maybe...
This one'd fit three of me! What were you high on?
-No way?
What?
Someone else's size?
No way... No woman can be this big!
I've spent five months' savings on it!
No way I'm getting another. You're gonna fix this one.
Who could be this big?
Zoya!
C'mon, mate! Get up! Get ready!
C'mon!
-What is it?
Don't you have to go to work?
I'm starting next week...
What? Next week?
What's wrong with you? Stop shouting!
-What's wrong with you? You've got this job and you're putting it off!
Do you have any idea how many people struggle to get a decent job?
Never thought you'd be so thankless!
Actually, no... My bad...
You're used to having servants!
How can you handle the pressures of a 9-to-5 job, a boss, and yeah, office politics?
This ain't for you, mate?
Seriously? That what you think?
You're forcing me...
Well then, I'm about to prove you wrong!
Really?
Aye!
-Get ready then! Double time!
Make me proud!
Thank goodness...
Zoya!
What now?
Sanitiser...
Mask...
And...
Good luck...
Bye!
Alright, Marlin...
Time to put up your best act!
I was hidin' in plain sight,
Chasin' all my wildest dreams,
When life caught up, gave me a fright,
And pushed me to extremes!
I got in a bit of a tizzy,
Fate made me a bit dizzy...
Until it blew my mind!
That's what happens when love turns blind!
Just a second!
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
This blind man's gonna need a moment!
Nah way you're gettin' away! I'll expose ya for the world ter clock! You're busted for real this nickle and dime!
So sorry, but I take a whi --
I ain't talkin' ter ya -- Yeah I'm talkin' ter ya! Aye, ya!
Yeah...
They call me Scarface Jr.
The name's Curtis. Top tyke in town! I know a rotter when I see one!
What'd you think? Like for real? Aye, I'm askin' ya!
Thought ya could Duck And Dive your hand in your Dicky Dirt and act loike ya were born wifaht it? Nah, ya twit!
I daan't even need me mince pies ter spot a fraud!
Nah...
Nah way dipstick,
You're garn in the Shovel and Pick!
And payin' the bloody Calvin Klein!
Na shut up!
Fillet Of Cod Frank Bough!
Aye...
Marilyn Monroe? No -- Whatsit...
Marlin Munro.
-Aye, that...
Shall we?
So...
Where to?
Come with me... Over here...
This way.
Grab a pew...
Wanna have a cold drink?
You're introducing Curtis to your wife...
And he won't have a clue!
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
'Blind Love'
Please, come in, sir.
This way.
Wanna have something?
A cold cuppa... Or hot water?
Cold cuppa? That sounds awfully cold!
Your place looks fine.
Aye, sir...
Thanks to me Mum and Dad who left me this place.
Or a blind man like me
Wouldn't have a roof over his head.
Too bad I can't live on the curtains... The windows, the doors here...
Did -- Did you drop something?
Nah, nothin'...
Roof over yer 'ead, eh?
Hardly the first time I've heard that one, kid.
This emotional blackmail ain't gonna Kathy Burke on me.
So, I meant to say...
Sir?
Why don't you sell this place,
Get an apartment
And invest whatever's left?
Better than living off charity, innit?
This place
Is my last hope...
You know
My type have got no one in the world.
Besides --
The times, they're rotten!
What if I bumped into a fraud?
I'd have nowhere left to go.
Nowhere left ter go, aye.
If you're done with the questions, could I hear the good news?
News that your charity's gonna gi -- I mean... Support me?
We ain't done yet, laddie. I wanna clock your trouble and strife.
Sir?
Hmm?
B -- Bu -- But why?
What d'you mean why? Just wanna ask some questions.
Sh -- She ain't here...
What?
Thought ya wrote you're cash and carried! Didn't ya?
Aye -- I -- Am, aye...
B -- But... She ain't here right now...
Where's she?
O -- Over to... Her cousin's?
She's just a bit under the weather...
(Just ask me...)
Okay, I guess --
Shall we?
Where to, m'lad?
I'd like to wait a while.
'Course -- Not --
Not?
Young man,
I'm not used ter repeatin' myself. I said I'm not leavin' before I've seen 'er!
Yes --
Sir...
You won't happen to have a nice little comfy room?
I'd rather get some much-needed rest while I wait...
'Course, sir... This way...
Where?
Here...
Lead the way.
Come with me...
(What a headache!)
What was that?
-Nothin', sir...
(He better not see Zoya!)
Marlin!
Could you give me some of your aftershave? Badly need some.
Badly what?
Badly need some. No idea why it feels so weird...
What is it?
Need some... One!
What's the matter with you?
C'mon.
Come here, mate!
-What's wrong with you?
What d'you think you're going?
-Gimme a moment to explain, mate! Could you put this on?
C'mon!
That's why I never shave around you!
It's not what you think!
Fair 'nuff. Then why in the blasted world d'you want me to put on your wife's clothes?
What the devil's goin' on in that dirty mind of yours?
-Just shut up!
I just want you to put this on and see Curtis.
Me -- As your wi --
Wife -- Who's Curtis?
You know -- From NBFUK?
NBFUK...
As in the charity?
Aye.
I ask here and you answer over there. Another question and I fear you'd be out on the street!
Why's he here to see you, and why do I have to be your wife before him?
Say something, boyo!
Say something, boyo! SAAAYYYY
Say something, boyo! SAAAYYYY SOMMMETHINNNG!
For the last six months, I've been...
Living off the 25 gee allowance they give the blind...
WHAT?
That's what happens when love turns blind!
Aye.
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
You...
Livin' off charity?
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
AYE!
But why?
Just -- WHY?
I mean -- Why?
It'd been a year since I completed my Masters with a first...
A year of unsuccessful attempts to get a job...
A year of stepping out of the house everyday, hoping to get what I'd toiled for all these years... Hoping to get my right...
A year of hoping not to come back disappointed...
A year of losing hope
With each passing day...
A year of having no blasted idea what was going on...
A year of being the most qualified of them all...
A year of being the best on the interview...
A year of being crushed under the weight of positive action...
A year of being trampled by those with 'recommendations'...
A year of having what I deserved snatched away by blimmin' bribers...
A year in which I realised that all I had was merit...
A knick-knack no one really needed in the modern world...
A year in which I'd begun to loathe myself...
All the more whenever I'd look at Zoya...
Who'd rather starve herself to stand by me
Than complain...
Zoya, who'd taken up arms against her family for me...
Me, who couldn't even provide her three square meals a day...
It was just another day hoppin' between offices
When, consumed in fury, self-loathing, and anguish all together...
'NBFUK'
'Monthly allowance for the needful and disabled - 25 thousand Rupees'
Sir...
Could you tell me the address?
I decided...
To end my life...
But my eyes fell on a banner...
'25 thousand Rupees'
I was tired of asking for what was rightfully mine...
It was finally time to get my hands on it!
I told Zoya I got a job...
But the truth is, for the last six months...
I'd leave for 'work'
And spend the day in the park...
I'd give my allowance to Zoya, telling her it's my salary...
Until today, when Curtis came knocking...
Saying he wants to see my wife!
I'm looking my ruin in the eye...
Please, luvvie...
Don't make me tear up...
Kashif?
Don't worry... You're introducing Curtis to your wife...
And he won't have a clue! So...
I was hidin' in plain sight,
Don't... Don't you worry, m'love!
Chasin' all my wildest dreams,
When life caught up, gave me a fright,
And pushed me to extremes!
I got in a bit of a tizzy,
Fate made me a bit dizzy...
Until it blew my mind!
Kashif...
You better do this right...
Don't worry, Marlin, you've got quite the player on your team!
Don't get caught!
-I won't, boyo! Don't worry!
Wait here. I'll tell Curtis you're back.
Here's a tip.
Light a cigarette too.
You told Curtis your wife smokes?
I don't remember telling him my wife sits like that either!
Marlin!
Zoya?
Who's -- That?
That --
Well, that's --
I asked you who that is.
Ka -- Kashif, you know?
She's his friend...
I told you, he's upstairs, okay?
How come you're back so early, darling?
I saw Ayesha, and guess what?
She told me to start next week.
Guess someone's a bludger...
You sent me for nothing. Anyway, gotta get some rest...
No way!
You can't go in there.
Why?
You know --
I'm having this awful headache, mate...
Could you get me a cuppa?
Sure thing. Just lemme change?
Blimey, man!
You want to change first? I'll make some myself! Don't bother!
-What's wrong with you?
What's with the anger? Gimme a moment...
Fair 'nuff...
Hmph...
I'm gonna barge in and kill ya!
You owe me 534,515.
I'm gonna make Bobby it goes ter someone 'oo deserves it! I'm not scared of ya!
No one, get it?
We clear?
Bog off!
Hmm...
The lady's here, Mr Curt!
-M'lady -- What?
How'd she get here? I thought I --
Not your lady... Mine! Come...
Can't you bark calmly?
-Ehh?
Actually -- You don't see it... Keep at it... Keep blabberin'!
Can't stay awake when I'm not chewin' some betel... You almost gave me a heart attack, laddie! Which way?
Here. Come with me.
-Gimme a moment...
This way, sir...
Fate, it seems, had me outdone,
Why are we back where we begun?
Aye, where's she?
Upstairs, sir.
Call her down here.
She'd rather not come here.
Why?
You know...
She stays upstairs today.
Cut the codswallop!
It's nothing, really, sir...
Just -- Her 'me time', you know?
She stays in her room one day. I stay the next.
That's one way we can say we're happily married without lying through our teeth.
(And they told me the happy part came from being together --) I mean -- When d'you have your 'we time'?
Sundays?
Every Sunday.
Just -- Come with me...
Marlin!
Marlin! Open the door!
Jeez...
I'll show you the way...
What's that noise?
It's all black to me, sir... What noise?
Your brain's blacked out too...
You hear with your ears, see with your eyes, aye?
-Aye, sir... 'Course...
Why do I get a feeling your wife's down here?
No, sir, that's not my wife -- Stay away from her! She's a witch, I tell you!
Don't worry, laddie, I've got one at home too.
-You don't get it, sir!
A real one, sir! That witch comes 'round here sometimes...
And -- I've heard she never spares strangers!
Wh -- What now?
J -- Just go upstairs sharpish! I'll deal with her! Go! Before it's too late!
-Upstairs? Yeah?
Thank goodness...
Hi...
-Why'd you bolt the door?
No -- I -- Don't think I did?
Who've we got in here except the two of us?
How do I know? I can't see, you know...
What?
Just kidding, mate...
Tea?
What's with the sunglasses and stick?
That?
Well, just -- Preparing for when I'm blind.
What?
Aye.
Why?
Uhh...
Just -- Getting some practice, you know? Who knows what the future holds?
I thought I'd prepare for the worst case scenario... Get it?
What the devil is wrong with you? You all right upstairs?
Aye, never been better...
Is it ready? My cuppa? This awful headache's killin' me... Nothing your tea can't cure though! Gimme...
Thank you.
Don't you think you should -- You know -- Change now?
Good girl.
I'm losin' it...
Your name, please?
Yes, please.
Blimey, I asked for your name!
Kashif...
Ehh?
Zoya Kashif.
Zoya...
Kashif...?
Zoya Kashif...
Zoya Kashif?
But... Aren't you married to Marlin? Aye? How d'you explain that?
Very high IQ, I must say!
But, regrettably,
This society
Cannot conceive a woman's identity as distinct from her husband's...
Regrettably,
She doesn't have a name she can call her own...
She's always chained in one surname or another...
Why?
Her old man's name before her marriage...
And her husband's aft -- Old man's -- Ka -- K -- Kashif's me ol -- Father's name...
When'd he lose his sight?
God bless him...
He's 70 but with a perfect 6/6 vision!
I meant your husband!
(I never asked him!)
Aye? I asked something!
Uh -- Well -- Gimme a few options and I'll pick...
We playin' Millionaire 'ere? I'm askin' about your husband, young lady!
What's it matter?
Our life's been pitch-black ever since...
Every day moonless,
Every night starless...
Easy...
-No!
You need to get a grip on yourself...
-NO!
Excuse me...
'Keep him busy until I say it's clear down here'
I guess I'll take my leave...
No --
You can't leave just yet...
I'm done here. Why'd I --
-Curtis...
You're so selfish...
You'd slip away sharpish the moment you're done?
I mean --
I ain't gonna let you go... Until you've had some of my finest tea!
No, thanks, that won't be necessary...
-Uhh...
I say it is. Please, take a seat...
Please... Take a seat...
I'll get us both a cuppa.
No way, I'm done here. I shouldn't be stayin' here too long...
-CURTIS!
You wanna slip away when you're done?
I won't let you go until you've had a nice cuppa!
No, thank you, I'd rather not --
But I would!
I need some right now.
Please...
I beg you.
Just -- Some water...
And some tea after that. I insist.
Now you sit here like a really good kitten, and I'll be right back!
Meow!
Meow???
Me giddy Aunt that's...!
You sent me to Ayesha's office so you could enjoy your little date with her!
-Date?
You said she's Kashif's friend when I got back...
And locked me in the kitchen!
You are so caught in the act now!
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
'Blind Love'
Marlin!
Double time!
What is it?
Curtis wanted to leave but I've managed to stop him for tea.
I'll get some fritters and sweets too.
-Okay.
Blimey, mate! Just let him go already!
I thought you texted me to keep him busy!
Change o' plans. Zoya's in her room. Now's the chance. Get him outta here ASAP!
Okay.
Kashif...
Aye?
You ain't just a friend... You're my life!
I'm gettin' all dewy-eyed!
-I love you! Here!
That's what happens when love turns blind!
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
MARLIN!
(Oopsie!)
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
Z -- Zoya?
That chuffin' chippy!
-(Gotta disappear!)
I'm gonna kill her!
-Calm down! What's wrong with you?
What's wrong with me? You -- You blasted cheat! That hag called you at the restaurant yesterday, didn't she? That cow!
That's when you planned it, innit?
You sent me to Ayesha's office so you could enjoy your little date with her!
Date?
-Aye!
No way, mate!
Holy Mary! You said she's Kashif's friend when I got back...
And locked me in the kitchen!
You are so caught in the act now!
I'll deal with you later! She is so dead!
-Hey! Mate! Gimme a moment to explain! Lemme tell yo --
She is so dead, and SO ARE YOU!
-Hey! Zoya! Zoya! It's me! Kashif!
Kashif?
What's wrong with you? Look at yourself!
Why don't you ask Marlin?
Kashif!
That's my dress he's --
Don't worry.
I'll tell you everything.
Zoya! What's wrong with you? Lemme explain!
Explain what?
What are you gonna say? What's left for you to say, Marlin?
We've been living off charity?
There was a time I'd take pride in your uprightness!
You've crumpled that image!
I ain't stayin' with you another moment!
Please, Zoya!
Please listen to me!
Who is it?
Good day.
Good day, sir.
Jiya Effendi.
From the Royal Trust.
I've got some questions for you.
Ah... Aye...
I get it...
Come in. Please...
After you.
Please...
You didn't have to come all the way...
You could've just asked me to come...
I'd like to see your wife, Mr Marlin.
Just want to ask her some questions.
Nothing much... Just a few minutes...
A few minutes?
That's all?
Of course.
Please, take a seat. I'll send her here.
Okay.
Kashif!
Okay...
Definitely not okay.
Do I look okay? I've been starvin' --
I almost died just now, and you think it's okay?
Just -- Put on your scarf and come with me.
-I ain't goin' anywhere. It's no use now.
Zoya knows everything!
Jiya's here, you know...
Who's Jiya?
You know, uh... From the Royal Trust?
The Royal what?
Another trust?
Can I trust you to tell me all the parts of your body you've damaged or lost to win their trust?
Just one last time, mate...
See her so she leaves pronto!
No.
No blasted way!
I ain't helpin' you in any of your scams, like, ever!
Kashif...
Boyo... Aren't we bros?
Doesn't quite look like it to me... No way, we ain't no bros or something. Find someone else.
Wonder who you would be?
We're pals, mate.
Just once?
Good day, ma'am.
I'm from the Royal Trust.
This 'help' is a crime!
And I ain't helping you in another crime! No way!
Mr Marlin may have a broken leg, but it is so heartwarming to see he's got your shoulder to lean on...
It's not like I'm enjoyin' it.
I've got no choice!
But I promise you...
Once they're gone, I'm gonna cancel my registration myself!
I promise you.
But please...
Help me out one last time?
Just once?
We've got no shortage of people who'd lie to us...
That's why we're asking these questions... We're working to weed out the leeches...
Fine them, and send where they belong - in the nick!
Looks like you don't need me anymore.
Break a leg, tough guy!
-Kashif!
What do I tell you...
Uhh...
Mr Marlin! Please, take a seat.
That's Zoya...
My wife.
Yeah, we just met.
We've been talking 'bout you, you know.
-Ohh...
Excuse me, where's the loo?
Over there.
Thank you.
Seems someone forgot to tell me he's got a broken leg too.
Don't worry, I didn't tell her anything.
Thank you so much.
'ThANk yOu sO MUcH'! Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Zoya... I can explain...
Once Jiya and Curtis are outta here...
If they found out,
I'll be thrown in the nick,
Not to mention the fines I'd have to pay!
Y -- You! To the dickens with you!
-Hey!
-I -- Ow!
Oww...
Argh!
Ow!
Kashif!
Kashif! You alright?
Kashif?
Kashif!
Mum?
Dad? Here --
Zoya! M'girl!
How are you?
Kashif!
Get up!
What happened, boyo?
Kashif!
Get up!
-Mrs Munro!
Mrs Zoya Kashif Munro!
Been a while since you left to make me a cuppa...
Hey! What happened here? How'd she fall down? And why?
Don't you see?
-Ehh?
I mean -- I don't, but -- Don't you?
-Aye...
I dunno... She tripped maybe?
-Oh...
Why don't you take her upstairs?
I'll -- Get some hot turmeric --
Hot milk with turmeric...
Take my hand.
-Hey!
-Take my hand.
Okay.
Get up, hun.
Careful...
Bless you...
Here.
I'll take you upstairs.
Careful, okay?
-Of course!
Be careful, okay?
What the devil is going on?
Sorry, it took me a while...
Aye...
No...
It's perfectly okay...
Where's your wife?
Uhh...
Well, she --
Why don't you take a seat?
Mum...
Dad... Come in...
Mum and Dad...
Uhh...
Mrs Jiya... From the office... Nothing much... Just got a few things to ask...
I was hidin' in plain sight,
Why don't you come see my room?
Chasin' all my wildest dreams,
This way!
When life caught up, gave me a fright,
And pushed me to extremes!
I got in a bit of a tizzy,
Fate made me a bit dizzy...
Until it blew my mind!
That's what happens when love turns blind!
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
(Jaysus...)
(Couldn't you pick another day?)
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
Would you like to have something? A cuppa? A cold drink, maybe?
God, it kills me... Mum!
What happened?
He beat me!
Ehh?
That blind bloke?
Couldn't he see -- ?
How's it any different if her husband's blind, lame, or not...
Wives always get beaten about...
Break my heart but not my bones!
No way...
No way Curtis is forgivin' domestic abuse! I'm gonna fix that blind wretch!
Please, Courtesy...
Courtesy?
Don't leave me alone in here...
Please, I... OW!
Please... Lie down... Easy...
Ow...
Easy there... It's nothing...
No... I can't take it anymore...
Here?
-Yes, sir.
Here.
And here.
Another?
Here?
Aye.
Here.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
-Thank you so much!
Hope you're... Satisfied?
Of course. Thank you so much.
Pay attention to this important announcement!
Due to rising COVID-19 cases...
16th Street and 17th Street are quarantined!
No one is allowed in or out!
The Government announces a complete lockdown until everyone in the area is tested!
Your cooperation is requested. Thank you.
No...
M'love...
You're Curtis's life! And Curtis, but the dust under your feet!
I swear, I was just investigating someone when --
They quarantined the whole street!
I can't stay here!
Of course you can't!
You need to leave right away. Double time!
-Aye. I'll get going.
Thank you so much. Take care!
-Aye. Take care!
Don't forget to close the door!
-Sure.
Thank goodness...
Good half-riddance.
Told you not to force me to go to Karachi.
If I died of COVID-19 in here, you're responsible for it!
What are you saying?
Life and death are in the Lord's hands, and His hands alone.
Besides...
The virus is spreading all over the country...
Mum...
Please, relax...
Everything's gonna be alright.
Hammer some sense into your Dad.
Thank goodness Jiya's gone.
Where's Zoya?
In her room.
Her Mum and Dad are here.
Whe -- Here?
That just means --
-Aye?
Corona or no corona... You're dead for real, mate.
You gonna curse your mate like that?
Aye aye, Your Highness.
Don't worry. Your man's gonna update you every hour.
I won't let you or your faith in me down.
Of course!
Take care, hun.
Gordon Bennett!
You're lucky
That Mum and Dad got here.
I can't tell them about the real you because I don't want to embarrass myself!
I chose you over them.
And you!
Honestly, Zoya?
You got a point there.
Can it.
And could you please take my gown off, clean it, and give it back?
I -- I'd give it back right away -- But -- Curtis is upstairs and -- I haven't got a replacement, so...
Aye.
She's right...
I mean -- He's right...
Sorry...
Not so fast!
Where are you off to?
-Don't you know these streets have been locked down?
Please let me go...
I was just here for an inquiry...
I've got my mask on! Lemme go back --
Sorry, ma'am. Orders from the top. No one goes in or out.
Go back.
That --
Isn't my place!
Mum's gonna be so worried if I didn't go back!
Please lemme go...
-I hope you know that if, God forbid, you got infected, you're gonna take the virus straight to her doorstep!
No way we're riskin' it, ma'am.
What d'you think you're doing?
-What d'you think you're doing?
Tryin' to bribe a cop?
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Why? Don't you folks normally take it?
Not really.
Not this time, at least.
-Aye.
Go back.
-Aye, back where you came from.
Please let me go, sir...
I was just doing my duty.
Just here to inquire...
Last warning! Go back where you came from!
-Can't you hear me? Go back right now!
But -- Mum's all alone...
It's best for you to go back.
-Right now!
Back!
-You hear me? BACK!
Aye...
-RIGHT NOW!
Get a move on!
That's how your lovely son-in-law honours us!
Half an hour since we got here, and he hasn't even bothered to greet us!
Big deal.
That's how you honoured your son-in-law. For an entire year!
Please, Mr Siddiqui... Don't expect respect when you didn't give any.
What? You want me to fall at his feet?
I came here because you told me to.
And now that you're here, why don't you be a bit more generous?
Perhaps even say sorry for how you treated him?
What?
Say sorry? Like, for real?
No way.
Fair 'nuff.
Feel free to book a ticket back home.
Blimey, are you blackmailing me?
I might be.
You blackmailed me for an entire year.
I've missed my girl for an entire year.
I ain't begging for his forgiveness or something.
Who asked you to beg forgiveness?
Just pull him into a warm embrace... Burn the cold bitterness with the warmth!
Hmm?
Mrs Marlin!
Just a sec!
Zoya!
Just a sec, Dad!
Guess no one needs me...
Good Lord...
You heard me in a moment!
Guess I should've asked for something else...
Alright, Marlin...
Don't stop me now, Zoya!
How dare that blind bugger touch you? I'll never forgive him!
-B -- But --
I already forgave him...
When the most courteous forgive someone, the others should follow suit too.
Why'd you say sorry to him? No way!
Just... For your happiness...
And to put everything that's happened behind us...
Zoya!
Can't you see he's got a broken leg?
-The name's Curtis! Top tyke in town! That's his wife there, ask her!
But -- His wife's right here! Zoya!
-Ehh?
What's your problem with me, you Chinese knockoff Judi Dench?
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
'Blind Love'
(Who is it this time?)
You?
What happened?
The cops won't let me go!
I literally begged them!
But they're like, 'No one goes in or out'!
It's okay, easy there... Come in...
How will I go back?
I'm sure we can work something out.
Make yourself at home here. Don't leave this room. What if -- I'm infected and you caught COVID-19 from me?
Please...
Prevention...
Is always better...
Than cure!
Hmph!
Calm down, ma'am... Please... Get a grip on yourself!
You know the virus is spreading so fast!
Who knows...
One of us... Me... Or my wife... May be infected!
Aye.
So...
Here's a tip...
Don't leave this room.
Okay? I don't want anything happening to you.
Get it?
No leavin' this room.
Very good. I'll be back...
Just a moment, okay?
I realise I've been so wrong about Marlin all this time...
I just want to embrace him, and in that warmth, put all this coldness behind us...
No way!
No way you're embracing him or something!
But why?
Because --
Social distancing, you know?
You heard the announcement, didn't you? It's spreading!
You're staying a good 2 metres from him!
And... It's best if you stay in here... Don't leave this room, okay?
Okay...
Fair enough...
The cops sent Jiya back. She's in the drawing room.
Dad wants to give you a warm embrace and put all the coldness behind.
And Curtis wants to make you pay for every bit of cruelty you've subjected me to.
Why are you crying?
It ain't gonna take you home or something.
Just missing me Mum...
I've never been away from her this long.
I can't sleep without her...
Why? Does she sing you a nice little lullaby every night?
Whoa... How'd you -- Read my mind? You're so nice...
-Please -- Social distancing, you know?
Could you sing a lullaby for me?
What?
Or --
I'll be up all night... Please?
Mum...
I really wanted to embrace you...
But I guess... Cruel fate stops me...
It'd be a choking embrace if you knew a thing about cruel fate...
I'm impressed by your honesty, uprightness, and self-respect.
(Don't worry...)
(You ain't gonna be for too long.)
What?
Uhh...
No -- I mean... Never forget that...
Just...
One thing I'd ask of you.
Aye?
Don't keep anything to yourself.
You've always got us, m'boy.
You're more our son than son-in-law.
Of course. Just what I wanted to say... Before I lost my words back there.
Guess we're both losing something today...
What?
I mean -- It's such a blessed day!
I've found Mum and Dad again... In you...
Bless you.
I'm sure you need some rest.
Lemme know if you need anything.
Bless you with a long and happy life.
Zoya...
Please...
I have no explanation that can satisfy you...
Nor the courage to beg forgiveness...
So... Punish me any way you like...
You've got a long list of people to beg forgiveness of.
If they all forgive you, I'll tell you my decision.
I was hidin' in plain sight,
Chasin' all my wildest dreams,
When life caught up, gave me a fright,
And pushed me to extremes!
I got in a bit of a tizzy,
Fate made me a bit dizzy...
Until it blew my mind!
That's what happens when love turns blind!
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
You blasted tyrant!
Wanna see how you brutalise your English hoe -- Rose?
What's the matter? Calm down!
How dare you leave her poor, frail self to sleep on the floor outside the room?
She -- what?
Guess I didn't see it... I can't see, you see...
'Can't see'? I thought you had a broken leg!
Uh...
Aye...
Hey! Who's askin'?
Can't you see he's blind?
Forget about me. Who in the world are you?
I think you're the blind one here! Can't you see he's got a limp?
Can't you see he's got a broken leg?
-The name's Curtis! Top tyke in town! That's his wife there, ask her!
B -- But -- His wife's right here! Zoya!
Ehh?
What's your problem with me, you Chinese knockoff Judi Dench?
First, you tell me he's not blind. Then, you tell me this is not his wife... What the devil is wrong with you?
I'm just shutting up your lies!
He's lame and she's his wife!
No ma'am, he's blind and Ishe's his wife!
-He's blind and she's his wife!
ENOUGH!
I'm not blind...
Or lame...
I'm just another liar...
And... I'm not his wife...
I'm his friend, Kashif...
-Blimey...
What's going on, Zoya?
So, you flimflammer...
You've been living off our allowance for the last six months, pretending to be blind?
Not just yours, he's been living off our allowance for the lame for the last six months too!
You cheat! You've been living off charity? What'd my daughter do to deserve this?
Can't believe I was awed by your uprightness!
Mhm!
After I'm through with you...
Generations to come will remember what you --
Shut up!
Your name's Curtis...
But all I see is the most discourteous man I've ever met!
I'm the top tyke in town!
-Can it!
What d'you want?
Want to send me to the nick?
C'mon, call the cops. Arrest me.
That's the blasted limit!
I've done my Masters!
With a first... Straight As all the way...
But... Medals, grades, certificates... I might as well burn 'em all...
Because I find they're useless to me...
There's no place in the city I haven't applied to...
But you know what they want?
A sweetener.
A 'recommendation' from the toffs...
I've got neither...
No one - including me - loves to live off charity.
But the status quo, the system...
Forces a wise and capable man...
To use his wisdom in all the wrong ways...
Hunger...
Numbs the mind... The conscience...
Until... It doesn't feel wrong at all...
I could bear the hunger...
As long as it was just my own...
But someone else depended on me...
She had everything in life, every luxury...
She chose me over it all...
Because she believed in me...
She could see my potential...
Don't think...
I don't have any regret...
I deserve to be punished for all I did...
So please... Arrest me...
Sell this house...
And take back every penny I took from your NGOs...
Consider whatever's left my donation to you...
Because it's never gonna be home again...
Aye, looks like a zoo to me. You done yet?
Lovely speech... Give him a huge hand, will ya?
That was bang-on brilliant, me lad...
Lemme tell ya wot 'appened. Ya thought ya could brin' Curtis ter tears.
But Curtis 'as got a heart of stone! Get it? Stone!
Lemme call 999. Get sum cavalry in...
-Wait.
Not so fast.
I'll pay back every penny he's taken from your charities.
Too late, sir. Ya daan't kna me.
They say I'm loike Sylvester Stallone... Quite accurately, I say.
'E drew first blood, and I'm gonna give 'im a bloody end 'e won't believe!
... And I'm donating 1.5 million to each of your charities. How's that sound?
Ya didn't 'ear the whole fin'...
Blood for blood's gonna bleed the whole world ter deaf...
Wise words... Wise words indeed!
-'Course...
You don't need to do this.
I do, my dear.
Because, in a way,
I'm guilty of what's happened too...
If I had the same faith in you as Zoya... If I could give you a chance...
None of this would've happened...
I'm sorry...
I've apologised to everyone.
What's your decision?
I can forgive everything...
Except...
One cardinal sin...
If the tailor ruining my favourite dress weren't enough, you gave it to Kashif who absolutely Idevastated it!
Way to go, Zoya! He devasted my gender identity, but all you care about is your dress!
Not to mention this dreadful armache thanks to the flowerpot you threw --
Actually... Never mind...
By the way, Uncle... Marlin owes me a small amount too... Just about 20 gee or so... It's no big deal, really...
But I thought if I got a little cheque too, we'd Iall have a happy ending...
Now you're suckin' diesel!
Alright, you'll get it back.
(Sorry!)
Translation: Fajr Aurangzeb  ARY TV
That's what happens when love turns blind!
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!
'Blind Love'
I was hidin' in plain sight,
Chasin' all my wildest dreams,
When life caught up, gave me a fright,
And pushed me to extremes!
I got in a bit of a tizzy,
Fate made me a bit dizzy...
Until it blew my mind!
That's what happens when love turns blind!
Yeah, love, my love's turned blind!