I've been longing for this moment...
Come.
Palwasha! Get something for them. Here.
They're here.
Already? Wee hee!
-Not so fast!
Where are you off to?
Gonna see them, of course!
-Did you hear Aunt call you?
Jeez... I gotta wait for her now...
Don't worry.
I'm sure you'll get to see them now that they're here.
Mirha...
You have no idea how happy I am, Mirha!
I've waited so long for this one moment!
Mirha!
Go and take a look! Tell me how he looks!
-No way! Aunt's eyes would shoot me dead if I went there.
Please, Mirha! I beg you! Please, Mirha! Please, please please...
Stop it!
Stop it already, you drama queen!
Okay... I'll go take a look...
But... What if Aunt called you Rushna before him?
Don't worry, I've told Mum everything!
Blimey, you're so...!
Anyway... You're supposed to be the ideal oriental girl. So keep your head covered and eyes lowered, okay? Don't start ogling him!
Arham's all yours!
Okay, now! Get going and tell me they want to see me!
I should check my lipstick.
Go and get some spoons and plates.
Translation: J. Mir © Hum Network