ADD
Boo!
Jeez! You know you're ruining your own work, don't you?
So, done yet?
Ain't even close...
By the way, looking at you, no one can tell you've got an exam tomorrow.
I swear I've got an exam tomorrow! I'm stepping out after ages, gotta look no less than my best!
And if Mum saw you...
-Yeah? So? Mum's gonna kick me out or something?
Oh, sure... Kick you out and send you home.
... Which is exactly what I want!
I'm just waiting for my Prince Charming to set me free!
Does he have to be charming?
Of course!
No way I'm settling for any less!
I mean, just look at how beautiful I look!
Do you think I deserve any but the most charming of them all?
You're never gonna change, are you?
Anyway... Do you like the bangles?
They're lovely... Sent with love, so quite naturally...
Ooh, love is in the air!
But I want everything!
The riches of Paradise, a palace...
And my Prince on his steed!
Dream all you want in your sleep, Rushna... You've got a long night ahead of you.
And what are you doing, Palwasha?
Madame Rushna's got an exam tomorrow, and I'm working on her crib sheets!
Not cricket, Rushna!
What's the big deal? Who's gonna help me if not my sister?
Can't you study?
As if I'm gonna work...
God forgive you...
ADD
You're still here?
-Just another moment!
I hope you've prepared well.
-Of course. I'm sure I'll ace my A-Levels this time!
Tell me something I haven't heard in three years.
I'm sure I will this time! Don't worry.
I'm very worried.
You won't get a good match if you don't pass your A-Levels.
Then again, who am I arguing with?
Here.
What? This is barely enough to get there!
That's all I have. Your dearest Mirha took everything else. Can't even get some grains before Wahaj sends some money... We've got nothing left...
ADD
Translation: J. Mir © Hum Network