Again?
Listen to one thing, Mum -
You'd reap only what you'd sow.
Don't expect roses when you've planted cacti!
Give me the pills.
I'm having a bad headache.
-No, Madame, I can't give you those pills.
You'd only get worse if you took those...
Give me those blimming pills, Sabira!
But remember, Mehrab,
Don't expect anything from me,
For you won't get anything except misery.
Good Lord...
What now...
Take your medicines, Madame.
Madame...
Madame, your pills...
What would you like, sir?
One bun kebab.
Anything else?
That's all.
Cold drinks?
-No, thank you.
This place is rather famous for its bun kebabs.
You want to have a bun kebab?
I'd enjoy these with my friends after college.
Would you like to try?
What would you like to have, sir?
2 bun kebabs, with a lot of chutney!
I'd like...
The chicken and double egg one.
Anything else?
Drinks?
That will be all.
Here's your bun kebab, sir.
Why must you create a scene here everyday?
Why must you let me create a scene?
Why not just listen to me for once
And come with me?
Why should I go with you, Mehrab?
Who are you to me?
Our sorrows are shared, Mirha.
The least you could do is shed a few tears with me.
I'm very lonely...
Why?
What happened to Rushna?
I don't know anything about her.
And frankly, I don't even bother.
What do you mean, Mehrab?
Why did you marry her if you don't even bother?
Sometimes, passions push people into taking unimaginable decisions.
One's forced to act on them...
I don't get it.
I wish I could explain it.
Perhaps...
Losing Arham
Had shattered me so much
That I decided to pluck the smile from Rushna's face.
Mehrab...
I didn't expect this from you.
I shouldn't have done this, bu --
-But you did.
How is Mehrab any different from Rushna?
They've both ruined lives out of love for their selves.
It pains me.
Very much.
Monsieur! Madame's very ill, please see her.
Please see her, Monsieur, she's seriously ill.
Come.
Rushna!
Rushna...
Get up, Rushna!
Rushna?
What happened to her?
She had a bad headache.
Which pills have you given her?
The one Madame la Maîtresse used to take.
-Show me.
Rushna!
Rushna?
What've you been giving her?
Who told you it's a painkiller?
Sometimes, passions push people into taking unimaginable decisions.
One's forced to act on them...
Losing Arham
Had shattered me so much
That I decided to pluck the smile from Rushna's face.
Our sorrows are shared, Mirha.
The least you could do is shed a few tears with me.
O my Moon, where have you been all night?
I'm very lonely...
My heart has been making excuses for you
O my Moon, where've you been?
Hello?
What?
What happened to Rushna?
Alright, don't worry, we'll be there shortly.
Why are you worrying? Dubai isn't that far away.
Your son will be back in a few days.
Quickly, Mum!
Rushna's seriously ill!
What's with all the noise at this hour?
I got a call from Rushna's. She's very sick!
So?
We should be going to see how she is, shouldn't we?
No need for that. Her husband's there to look after her.
She needs us, Mum!
I said no one's going there!
She's your daughter, Mum. At least don't say that for her!
-She's dead for me!
Why should I care about anyone when no one cares about me?
Alright.
Don't go. But I'm going.
What are you saying, Aqila?
Call her even if you're not going.
You know very well, Khala Amman, she must be putting up an act!
Remember how she used to act sick to bunk off school?
She must acting this time around, too.
Why'd she do that now, Mum?
So I forget everything and pay her a visit!
What's wrong with that? Why not just go for her sake?
You always knew she was putting up an act,
But you'd have her take the day off.
Have some mercy, Aqila!
She's your daughter! Your blood!
She'd be fine, Khala Amman!
Catch some sleep and let me catch some, too!
She never bothered about us, but I should bother about her!
Goodness, Aqila...
Only the Lord can give you better sense... You don't know --
-Shut up, Khala Amman!
My love for Arham had driven me mad.
I have no right to toy with anyone's life like this.
Rushna did what she did
Unknowingly...
But I've done no better...
Rushna!
What'd I say to Mehrab at this hour?
No.
He'd think I'm too emotional.
I shouldn't call Mehrab at this hour...
Yes, I'd like to order a pizza.
Chicken tikka.
Cold drink... White.
Yes, the same.
How long will it take?
Okay.
What are we cooking for lunch?
Nothing.
I've ordered pizza.
Oh?
That's good.
Which reminds me...
Ice cream tastes so good with pizza!
I'll ask Iqbal to get some.
Hey!
What're you eating? Leave that be.
What are you doing?
I'm very hungry. Let me heat it.
Forget that!
Right here! Ta-da!
Pizza and ice cream!
You love it, don't you?
Are you ever afraid?
Hey!
It's the fear that thrills!
Ain't my life so movielike?
He lost his heart to me at first sight.
Don't you think a miracle's about to happen in my life?
Why do you keep annoying her?
Let her be annoyed.
I can't bear your absence
At such an important point of my life.
Alright, I'm not going anywhere. Come, let's get ready.
Mirha!
There's no difference between us. What's mine is yours. Show me your hand.
We'll get our ice cream in a while.
What happened?
Why are you crying?
Tell me, will you?
Don't cry...
What is it, Mirha?
Rushna...
I'm missing Rushna...
Well, then, call her.
There, now. Let's call her.
Easy there.
Arham?
It's you...
Rushna, it's --
Not Arham. I'm Mehrab.
Look at me.
Wh --
What are you doing, Rushna?
Rushna...
Put it back on, you'll have trouble breathing.
Put it on.
Let me say what --
I've always wanted to...
I always knew --
You'd be here...
You're the only one who ever cared...
I've hurt you so much...
And look...
Where it got me...
I'm dying for a drop of love...
Punish me, Arham...
For breaking --
Your heart...
Everyone's left me...
I'm all alone...
Even Mirha...
Take me along...
Promise me
Promise me that you'll never leave me
My sweetheart,
Never break my trust...
Rushna!
Rushna?
Rus --
Rushna!?
Rushna!
R --
Doctor!
Anyone!
Mirha!
O my Moon, where have you been all night?
Rushna!
Jeez, mate, calm down!
O my Moon, where have you been all night?
My heart has been making excuses for you
Have some tea. I've made it myself!
O my Moon, where have you been all night?
I want to dream on!
-Hey! Give it back!
-Careful!
O my Moon, where have you been all night?
Please!
You'd better not fall down on me!
My heart has been making excuses for you
O my Moon, where've you been?
You live in my heart
You captivate my eyes
I am now yours, my beloved...
No need to thank me, mate.
Doing such little favours has become a habit with me.
Who's calling at this early hour?
Aqila?
I'll go see.
Hello?
What?
No --
Mum!
What happened?
Palwasha?
Palwasha...
What happened?
-What is it?
Mum -- Rushna --
-What happened to Rushna? Tell me!
What happened?
Rushna's gone, Mum!
What?
Rushna's gone, Mum...
That can't be!
Mum!
Careful!
No...
No, Khala Amman, I didn't mean that she --
Actually -- Die!
No...
Rushna!
Rushna! My dear...
Aqila...
Rushna!
Mum...
'A few days later'
Look at yourself, Aqila...
Rushna's death grieves all of us,
But you've got others to worry about.
I'd cursed that Rushna die...
Little did I know
That she'd actually die...
It was just her time to go...
Be brave...
I should've been the one to go...
But Rushna...
Khala Amman,
You, of all, should be brave.
Instead of comforting all of them,
You're losing your courage, too...
No, Kulsoom, I'm fine.
Deep down,
I'm very strong...
Wahaj was right...
I've --
Become stone-hearted.
I'm --
I'm infinitely capable
Of hating
And tormenting...
Infinitely...
Wahaj is right.
We're trying to contact Wahaj.
He'll be back.
Don't worry.
Kulsoom,
Do me a favour.
Don't punish my daughter for my mistakes.
Accept her as your own.
I --
I don't deserve forgiveness --
But I pray you, save my daughter from my atrocious decisions!
Save her...
Aqila...
What are you saying?
I should be the one to apologise. I've hurt you so much...
I promise you,
I'll accept Palwasha as Ghufran's bride.
It'd be an honour.
May the Lord will thus...
Something to begin with...
The kids can now be happy...
Palwasha...
Forgive me...
Forgive me, my dear...
Khala Amman... Forgive me, everyone...
Please, Mum, No...
Mum...
I'm sorry...
Come in.
Here, my dear.
Would you see who's here, Khala Amman?
Mirha!
My sweet Mirha...
Where were you, my dear?
You left all of us...
We've missed you a lot...
Mirha...
I know I --
I don't deserve it, but --
You're too kind...
If you can... Forgive me...
Aunt...
What are you doing?
You're like my mother.
I have no complaints
And if I ever had,
They are gone with Rushna.
Khala Amman...
My --
Wahaj was the same, but...
But my hatred
Shattered his heart...
And --
Now, he's so cross that he didn't even come here for Rushna's funeral...
Aunt...
I'm like your son.
I'll try to fill his space.
May you live long.
May you be happy.
May you have a good life.
May you always be happy and live a good life...
Hey!
Get them something to eat.
Drop me at the hostel.
So, what's next?
I
Haven't really planned anything...
Okay,
Then...
I love you.
Pardon?
Me -- ?
No.
Sorry.
You live in my heart
You captivate my eyes
I am now yours...
You live in my heart
You captivate my eyes
I am now yours...
I walk down the road
I walk down the road to your heart,
Looking at you every now and then
As if there's a bond between us...
Would you like to say something?
Yes.
Will you marry me?
W -- Wha -- ?
Just a minute.
Promise me...
But, Mehrab --
It's the best I can manage right now.
Promise me that you'll never leave me
My sweetheart,
Never break my trust...
O my Moon, where have you been all night?
You live in my heart
You captivate my eyes
I am now yours, my beloved...
O my Moon, where have you been all night?
My heart has been making excuses for you
O my Moon, where've you been?
You live in my heart
You captivate my eyes
I am now yours, my beloved...
Translation: J. Mir © Hum Network