Why don't you answer my call?
Hello?
Die of shame already!
I haven't seen a lowlife like you!
What's this guff?
I haven't even started my guff.
Meena?
Not Meena. Rushna.
I'm Rushna!
I'll regret it all my life that I couldn't see through a man like you!
I didn't know you could fall so low that you had my sister abducted to get even!
She's -- Your sister?
Mum didn't even let her in!
Who knows where she went in the rain...
What? What are you saying?
You were angry with me, right?
You should've vented it out on me!
What was her fault?
You've left her a drifter!
Meena --
I swear --
I didn't have the foggiest --
-I don't care, Arham.
Give my sister her life back.
But Mehrab had gone to drop her?
-She isn't here.
All I want to know is where she is!
Meena... Listen to m --
O Lord...
Keep Mirha safe.
Please don't punish her for my mistake.
She's innocent.
It was my fault, and she's getting punished for it.
Bro!
Bro?
ADD HERE
Meena used to talk about you a lot.
I mean, Rushna...
But I'd never thought
That we'd be meeting like this.
And...
I'd never thought that my life would turn into an endless night
And I'd be out of my house like this.
Believe me,
You'd get the dignity and respect
That you deserve over here.
Doesn't talking of respect after such humiliation sound a bit strange, Arham?
It does.
But believe me, there's no plan.
None of us wanted this to happen.
Perhaps it was just destined to happen...
That's it with the two of you.
You'd rather blame destiny than accept your fault.
We do realise our fault,
And we're trying to make up for it.
Your brother's done all of this to get out of his sense of guilt,
But, even if I want to,
I can't wash this blemish off me.
I'm sure my brother won't let any harm come to you.
You're still backing your brother after everything that's happened?
No.
I'm assuring my sister that trying times are upon us,
But these, too, shall pass...
Please, have your breakfast.
Translation: J. Mir © Hum Network