Reham!
Why did you stop there?
I've been in here talking to you.
Your head's wet. You'll have a fever.
Quickly, now, come in.
Come.
Make sure your head's dry.
Here's a towel.
What's up with you? Come.
Here.
Hey!
Why have you come upstairs? Reham's coming downstairs to teach you.
I --
Forgot my notebook.
I've come to get it.
Okay.
I saw your picture...
You look nice.
Really? Do I actually look nice?
Very.
Do I look nice only in pictures?
Don't I look nice otherwise?
No.
You look very nice otherwise.
I like you a lot.
You may test me.
I've prepared thoroughly today.
Oh?
That's very nice.
C'mon.
Let's.
Done.
I bet I haven't made a single mistake.
Oh?
Now,
Attempt your paper the same way tomorrow.
Oh...
Appa Bi was right. You shouldn't have come.
You've fallen ill.
No.
It's just flu.
It'll get better.
Besides,
Economics is still left --
Where is it?
Your book?
Go home and get some rest.
I'd study on my own.
I'd study on my own. I promise.
In fact,
I'd come with the driver to drop you home.
No,
I'd go by rickshaw.
Adan,
Are you sure you can do it?
Haven't I just promised?
Promise me, too, that you'd take your medicines when you get back.
I promise.
Okay.
Alright then, take care.
Likewise.
Bye.
What?
You've been teaching Adan for a month, and you don't know he's Ashir's brother?
How could I find out?
I teach him in the drawing room,
And I wouldn't have found out if I hadn't gone upstairs today.
Alright, even if it is Ashir's house, why are you so worried?
Suboor,
I'm worried precisely because it's Ashir's house.
Silly lass, you should be delighted.
Who knows, you and Ashir may meet again on this pretext!
Alright, tell me,
How's Aunt Sofia's behaviour towards you?
She's very happy with me.
And Adan?
Adan's become so attached to me.
What could possibly be better?
Are you mad, Suboor?
Fate has separated Ashir and me,
And the class and family I come from
Decides on the basis of familial honour and prestige.
Besides, I don't want any drama.
What'd you do?
Adan's got four papers left.
I'd stop teaching him
As soon as he's done with them.
Reham, think over it again.
Don't you think you're deciding it all too quickl --
-No, Suboor.
There's no better way out.
I saw your picture...
You look nice.
Do I look nice only in pictures?
Don't I look nice otherwise?
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
I've sent you a separate email with the approved samples, Mum.
We'll start production on that quickly.
I'll email you the rest by next week.
Okay.
How's the response from the clients?
Very good.
We've gotten orders for almost every article.
That's great.
Come here for a few days if you can.
Sure, Mum, I would,
But I've got a ton of work.
I'm missing all of you a lot.
Especially His Royal Highness.
We miss you a lot, too.
And His Royal Highness has lost all his royalty now.
Really?
He's completely focused on his studies now. Can you believe that?
I'll call you in a while, Mum, I'm getting an important call.
Alright.
Take care.
Bye.
Hello?
Yes, speaking.
Happy birthday to you...
Happy birthday dear Reham...
-Seriously?
Happy birthday!
-Thank you so much.
Here.
You didn't have to do this...
Why not?
Alright, cut the cake.
Okay.
Light the candles.
Sure.
Thank you so much.
It's all thanks to him!
What you've done for Adan, Reham,
Matters so much to me that you can't even imagine.
It's nothing like that.
It was my duty.
No.
It was
It was the duty of his class teachers too.
But they only complained about Adan.
They never tried to teach him and change him for the better.
To be honest,
Adan's worked hard.
He's studied hard, devotedly.
Of course.
But you're the one who has taught him to work hard.
Not just in his studies,
This Adan is not the old Adan.
He's changed so much.
He used to be so insolent and adamant that whenever something happened against his will,
He'd create a proper scene.
Actually,
Adan just wanted attention.
Since
You're so busy with the business,
And there's nobody else...
Perhaps that's why he used to react like that.
I think you're right.
I wanted to talk about something important.
Please, go on.
Actually...
I won't be able to continue teaching Adan after his exams.
No, Reham --
Please don't do that -- It's because of you --
-But --
It won't be possible for me. I'm --
It won't be possible for me. I'm -- I'm really sorry.
Besides, you'll have
Besides, you'll have a lot of days after the exams... You can find a good tutor.
As if I'd find another tutor like you!
Look,
If it's about the money, I can pay you more.
-No.
It's not like that.
I'm getting married.
And I'm shifting to Lahore.
So -- How's it possible...
Ah...
Right.
I can understand.
It won't be possible.
Congratulations, by the way.
Thank you.
But please don't tell anything to Adan.
I fear that he may...
React.
-No.
I haven't told anything to him.
I won't talk to him about this
Until he's done with his exams.
Thank you.
You'd asked me to write my heart out in my diary.
This would help me improve my English handwriting.
While writing, I figured
That my heart only thinks of you.
It brings you up every time, in everything.
Your smile,
Scolding lovingly,
Your delight at everything about me,
Your
Your looking at my picture and saying that I look very good,
But now,
My heart has grown weary of thinking of you,
Which is why my heart is speaking out to you today.
Speaking about something that you ought to hear.
My heart says
That you'd be chuffed to hear it.
I love you.
I can't live without you.
O Lord! You know my predicament
My life has become an affliction
Every gasp weighs at me
Why don't these doleful nights come to pass?
How do I recount what has befallen me?
I don't want to talk to you. Don't call me again!
Reham?
Are you okay?
Why are you so furious?
Suboor --
Suboor, come here, quickly.
What happened, Reham?
Why are you crying?
Just come here quickly.
Alright --
Alright, I'm coming.
Relax. Girls do huff and act coy. At least you poured your heart out.
Right, mate...
But at least she should talk to me.
She's not even answering my call.
Patience. It takes a while.
I can't be patient.
I've already waited so long.
I want my answer now.
I've stayed awake all night,
At least she should think of that.
Take this. It'll help you.
I've already finished a packet.
It doesn't help.
As you wish.
I'm coming.
Hello, Aunt!
Hello.
You're here after so long!
I thought you'd left.
No, Aunt. I'll be leaving in a few days.
How are you?
I'm fine.
But your friend doesn't seem well.
She's locked herself in her room. Hasn't even had her breakfast.
I say, get us some tea. I'll take a look at her.
Alright, go. I'll get you tea.
Mum -- I --
Reham?
Whatever the dickens has happened, Reham?
Disgusting!
This Adan!
I'll talk to Aunt Sofia.
She ought to know that Adan --
In fact, I'll -- Call Ashir.
-No.
You're not telling anything to Ashir.
But Reham!
Please.
She's angry with me, mate.
It's 4.30 and she's not here yet.
Didn't I say,
She'll not talk to you for a few days, and everything will be fine after that.
And if not?
What if she's angry with me, like, forever?
Look,
Call and message her,
But you don't need to start with 'Sorry' and all.
I wish I'd known her address.
I'd have gone there myself.
Here's an idea. Come to the club.
It'll distract you a little.
No, I don't want to.
No.
Yes, I'll tell you.
Yes, I'll tell you. Okay, bye.
This isn't a trifle.
We have to tell Ashir.
It'd go out of hand.
And...
What'd Ashir think about me?
I can't even tell Mrs Sofia.
But --
Just think about it, Suboor.
What exactly
Has Adan done?
With this, he's not broken not just his own, but my trust as well.
I used to think of him as my brother.
He took my love
In such a wrong way...
You don't need to explain yourself.
It's Adan's fault, and it's not something so insignificant that --
I can't even believe it
That he's claiming to be in love with you.
He's just a kid!
Who's this Adan?
Adan!
Where are you going?
Reham would be here anytime now. It's time for your tuition.
She's usually here by now.
Have you called her?
I did.
She's not answering.
Not answering?
She's never done this before.
She's usually here on time.
Adan?
You haven't misbehaved with her, have you?
Why would I do anything, Appa Bi?
Bu -- W --
Adan!
But Aunt, it's not like it's Reham's fault, is it?
She always thought of Adan like a bro --
-'Thinking' of someone as a brother doesn't make him one.
What I'm angry about
Is why she didn't tell me
That she's going to teach a young lad!
Adan's a kid!
This --
-'Kid'!
15-something. This is the age of such naïveté!
Emotions go out of control of the mind,
And this is the age when the Devil leads people astray.
And she's there for hours on end, teaching him!
We're in an absolute mire!
One, because of that Ashir,
And two, because of his younger brother.
Couldn't you find anyone else to tutor?
Mum, I swear I didn't know that it wa --
Mum, I swear I didn't know that it was Ash --
-You can swear all you want,
Say anything you want,
Whatever your intentions have been,
People will only speak ill about you.
And if word about this got to your Dad,
He'd die of disgrace!
What have you done, Reham?
Aunt,
Nobody will find out anything.
Who'd tell that imbecile?
What about his family?
And what if his mother found out?
I'd not go there now, Mum.
Yes.
And --
In a few days,
Adan will grow tired and understand.
Please don't worry.
A load of worry has been written in my destiny!
Listen, Reham,
You'd better sit at home now.
There's no need for you to work.
This is the day I've always warned you about.
Tasted the consequences yourself?
Now, suffer!
There must be something.
Reham's otherwise quite responsible in this regard.
You're right.
Appa,
I'd be busy at the office for the next few days.
I'd be back by 11.
A delegation's here,
And it's important that we make a deal with them.
Why are you tiring yourself so much with your hard work?
By the Lord's grace, Ashir's managing the entire business.
I'd tire myself if I didn't work.
Besides, it's not just a business. It's become a part of my life.
Either way,
Take care of your health.
-What happened to my health?
I'm perfectly alright.
Alright.
As you like it. Do as you please.
I'll meet Adan after dinner.
I have to leave early in the morning. Won't be able to meet him then.
What happened?
So busy now that you haven't even got time for Mum?
No, Mum...
Just... Exams...
I've got to score good marks for you.
I'm so proud of you, my dear.
Your current dedication
Is enough to satisfy me.
In fact, you and I are going on a vacation after the exams.
Wherever you want to.
A gift to you.
From me.
And
What if I wanted something else as a gift?
Ask for anything you want.
Anything, for your happiness.
Promise?
Promise.
And yes, Appa told me that Reham didn't come today.
Give me her number, I should call her to ask wh --
-I talked to her, Mum. She's not well; she'd be here tomorrow.
Okay.
Fine.
Get some rest.
Alright.
Good night.
Hello, Moiz?
Found out anything yet?
Jeez, mate.
It ain't no rocket science to trace a number to an address.
I got it.
I'll text it to you.
Thank you, mate.
You don't have to go there, bro.
Just let her know you have her address.
She'd call you herself.
Okay.
Okay, bye.
What happened, my dear?
Are you unwell?
Nothing really, Dad. Just a headache.
Come, then, you ought to see a doctor.
I'm taking you to a doctor right now.
No.
That won't be necessary.
I'm better. I've taken a pill.
Satisfied?
Didn't I tell you it's nothing to be worried about?
Shakira,
How could I be at peace when my daughter's in pain?
My peace of mind and happiness is in my daughter's peace.
Innit?
It's really nothing to get worried about, Dad.
I'll get better with some rest.
Alright, then.
Get some rest.
And let me know if it doesn't get better.
We'll go to the doctor quickly.
Yes, Dad.
If you didn't talk to me, I'm coming to your place.
Hello?
Threatening me, eh?
Why aren't you talking to me?
-Shut up!
What you've done
Is so low and cheap!
Do you think I'd talk to you now?
Whatever load of rubbish you have in your heart and mind,
Dump it out.
And from now on, never call or message me again.
I'm not even coming to teach you.
-You can't do that.
Because if you did, I'd do exactly
As I said.
It's not a threat.
I knew you'd come --
-Enough!
I'm not here for this cod,
Nor have I given in to your threats,
Nor here to hear the filth that your mind is full of.
I've come here to make you understand.
-I'm far beyond the point where I'd 'understand'.
It'd be better if you understood my feelings --
-'Feelings'?
This is pure naïveté, not 'feelings'!
How can you even think like this, Adan?
-Love never thinks.
Put a sock in it!
Ours was a relationship of honour, respect and admiration,
That you've blown to smithereens.
The fault is mine.
I thought
That I could expect you to honour this relationship,
And maintain its dignity!
Listen to this clearly -
Forget all of this,
And focus on your studies.
It's not possible for me to forget!
Besides, it's not as if it's a crime to love!
Be done with it!
Be done with it already, Adan!
Don't say another word!
And --
From now on,
You're not calling me,
Not texting me.
And we're not meeting either.
And --
Keep this with you!
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV