Hello!
Yes, Appa Bi?
Is everything alright?
Ah, mate, it isn't alright!
His Royal Highness has locked himself in his room,
And I'm afraid breakfast may be soured if Sofia got up.
Don't worry, I'll talk to him.
Fair enough, ask him. He only listens to you.
My love is no good. It isn't even held in any regard!
I'll talk to him right away.
-Alright, bye.
I knew it!
Appa Bi would complain to you about me.
Complain?
Complain about what?
She's worried for you.
Nobody around here worries for me.
Otherwise, they'd have understood what worries me.
Tell me, what worries you?
Oh...
Oh... Yeah, I got it.
The Hunza trip!
Exactly.
You'd promised.
But why'd you bother?
You're going to Australia,
Leaving me to rot here.
I'm not going to Australia on holiday, ol' chap.
I'm going to manage the business over there.
Honestly, I don't really want to go to Australia either, but I didn't turn Mum down.
Why?
Why don't you want to go?
A story for another day...
Fix your mood for now.
You'll get your permission for the Hunza trip today.
Sure?
100%.
Alright, see you at breakfast, okay?
Okay, deal!
Come to me, my dear
Don't keep me waiting...
Come to me, beautiful one
Come to me, my dear
Don't keep me waiting...
Come to me, beautiful one
Come to me, my dear
Don't keep me waiting...
Taufiq, I've refused many times before.
I won't agree if you kept on asking me.
Whatever is 1 million to you?
Look, Taufiq, it isn't about the money.
I'd lent you some just a few days ago.
What about that?
Oh...
So you'd have me account for those...
No.
But I'd like to know what you need this money for.
I'd like to start my own business.
It's just a small investment,
The profit will be far greater.
As for what I'd borrowed before, if you really want a full account of it...
It's obvious. Mum used to live with me.
Her medicines and treatment, her illness,
Her plight...
I had to bear everything.
If you had to bothe --
-Mum was never a bother for me.
She would've been living with me had she not been so adamant.
I think you misunderstood me, I didn't mean it that way.
Whatever.
I can't give you the money.
Goodbye.
Halva poori!
Dad,
How did you know I felt like having halva poori today?
Because you do at least twice a week.
Besides, he's used to misspending his money.
Go and get some tea.
-Oh, Shakira!
This isn't misspending,
Shakira Begum!
It's
It's the most charitable use of my earnings.
Fair enough!
For the first time, I'm hearing that one's giving food in charity to one's child.
Mum,
If parents provide their children with food out of love,
It is recompensed.
People now have changed the meaning of 'charity' completely!
-Ah, yes.
Team up, dad and daughter.
I'm the one who's wrong.
-Speaking of wrong,
Where's your royal duke?
Won't he have breakfast?
He's sleeping. He came back late last night.
Change his habits, Shakira.
Otherwise, you'll regret it later.
God forbid
That I have to regret.
He'll be alright once he takes up some responsibility.
Dad.
May I go to Suboor's tonight?
Why? Is everything alright?
Fesl will be leaving for the US.
And Suboor will be gone very soon, too...
She's hosting a grand soirée at her place.
She's invited all her friends.
I --
I -- tried to excuse myself --
I -- tried to excuse myself -- but she didn't listen...
Why did you have to excuse yourself, my dear?
Why, surely, if you ask me, you may go.
Splendid.
You're just emboldening her.
Look,
It'd be proper if you kept your friendship to the University.
Mum...
I'm not going if you don't allow me.
When I've allowed her, it ends there.
You may go.
Thank you, Dad!
Shakira,
I have confidence in my daughter
Because she's earned that confidence,
And, God willing, she'd never let me down.
She's my pride. My pride.
Who's going with you on this trip?
Talha, Sami, Moiz, Kashif...
They're all going.
Adan,
I don't like any of your friends except Talha.
Please, Mum, they're my friends.
Besides, what do you know them?
Well, that's the problem. Whatever do I know them?
Alright, Mum, if you've given him permission,
Please let him go.
Just let him go like that?
His exams are round the corner.
And as usual, you wouldn't have prepared.
He'll prepare when he gets back. Get good grades.
Consider it my last favour.
You'd better not do a favour on him!
Why not?
He's my only brother.
And he's so cute...
Okay.
But you have to assure me about your grades.
Thank you so much, Mum.
Hello? A bit of thanking is due here, too.
-Thank you so much, bro!
You'll get good grades, won't you?
It's a tad difficult...
Got what you wanted, eh?
Would you look at that, Appa!
He's gotten Ashir to help him have his way again.
Let him have his way.
He'd be the one who'd miss Ashir the most when he's gone.
Innit? I was saying just that.
Why are you letting him go?
What do you say, bro?
-Adan!
He's kidding, Mum.
It's better if this isn't even joked about.
Be there on time. Don't be late.
I won't be able to, Suboor.
It's very difficult.
And it's very easy for me to murder you if you didn't come.
Suboor?
Alright, here's the best motivation for you to come.
Ashir's coming.
So?
As in,
What do I care if he's coming?
Really?
Is it so?
Yes.
I mean, what's it to me if he comes or not?
One shouldn't lie to one's best friend,
At least not so sincerely.
There, now.
Put a sock in it.
I've got so much to do. How'd I come if I'm not done with everything?
There!
You refused to come just a few moments ago.
The moment you heard Ashir's name --
-I was just playing around with you!
Please, leave it be.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
If you kept looking at the table for five more minutes,
I'd feel as if my face looks worse.
No, it's just --
Well...
Thank goodness.
I was beginning to get jealous of the table.
Where are Suboor and Fesl?
Shopping for the wedding; it'll take a while...
Shall we order something?
No, let's just wait for them.
What if they didn't come?
Yes?
Just kidding.
A great man once said that everything is fair in love and hunger.
Love and war...
Thank goodness you didn't wait for Suboor and Fesl to correct the proverb.
Come to me, my dear
Come to me, beautiful one
Don't keep me waiting...
What is it that sisters don't do for their brothers?
And then, there's your sister.
She said so much to you
Over such a trifling amount of money!
One'd have to listen to it all
If one's going to get the money.
As if she's given you any money!
She would.
She always does.
It'll take a while.
I say you look for a permanent and stable solution.
What's this?
Begging before her every other month?
Why don't you get a job over there?
-Oh...
I'd do a job!
I'm not the type to do a job.
I just can't do that.
Although you're right in saying that a permanent and stable solution needs to be found out.
Where's Farah?
Where'd she be?
She's sleeping.
She's a proper Empress, your daughter.
Sleeping all day!
I have to do everything on my own.
A permanent and stable solution...
Mum! Get me breakfast.
Mum!
Who has breakfast at noon?
Your Dad's about to get back.
You'd rather just have lunch with him.
It's better if I'm hungry, then.
He won't let me have lunch.
I'd also have to take his jibes.
He's right, isn't he?
How long will he take care of everything on his own?
You've grown up now. Help him.
Mum,
Leave it be.
You're scolding him all the time.
He's studying right now.
Why won't he help Dad
Once he's done with his studies?
Yes...
Here's your bread and egg.
Such affection for your brother.
-Because why not!
He's my brother.
Ruined my hairdo.
Always the hunk, eh?
And my sweet Mum,
Don't say anything to him.
Stop worrying.
I'll help Dad
While he completes his studies.
I've even started looking for a job.
Stop worrying about us, and start worrying about going to your home [= marriage].
Forget this job and all. Who knows what you're up to!
Mum --
Ahmed...
Would you drop me to Suboor's at night?
Oh!
So that's the price for this bread and egg.
I'm not taking you there.
Your friend's got quite the mansion.
Everyone would be coming in expensive cars,
And we'd ride this banger of a bike.
Don't you feel embarrassed?
Embarrassed over what?
I'm happy and satisfied with what the Lord has given us.
Remain happy and satisfied, then,
And go with Dad.
I have no interest in making a laughing stock of myself.
Didn't I say
There's no chance I'm taking you there.
No chance?
Exactly.
Mum, you'd have to cook breakfast for Ahmed.
Going on a date?
Excuse me?
No, it's just
That you're extra sharp-dressed today.
That's why I said it.
One doesn't ask such questions of one's elder brother.
Don't get away with this reason of me being younger.
Besides, it'd benefit you if you told me.
I can help you.
Help me with what?
Impressing my sister-in-law.
I can give you a few tips.
Mum's right.
You're getting out of hand.
For now, I'd just want to get out of your hand. Let go! It hurts!
Check yourself, or I'd have to be stern with you.
You can't be stern with me.
Oh yes, wee laddie, I can.
You've only seen my affection.
I can see the affection
For her in your eyes...
Adan, you nasty little twit!
-Phone -- phone!
Yes?
Yes, Sami?
Of course, I'm coming.
Okay.
Best of luck.
What's up with him?
Had a row with Kashif at school.
So much has happened and you didn't even tell me?
How could we? We found out just now.
He'd quietly listened to a load of guff.
What'd he say?
No -- nothing.
What do you mean, 'nothing'?
Nothing...
We'll get even tomorrow.
Don't get worried over these trifles.
I'll take care of Kashif.
Kashif...
Look what we have here!
The entire Mummy-Daddy gang with their Mummy-Daddy leader.
What's the matter? Angry?
What'd you say to Talha?
Is he stumm?
Didn't he tell you?
Hello?
Bro, we don't want to mess with you.
As if you've got the guts to!
If you ever said anything to him,
I'd kill you for real.
Someone seems to be waiting restlessly for someone...
It's nothing, really, mate...
That's the limit, mate.
You've fallen in love but lack the courage to say it.
How long will you keep it sealed in your heart?
It's about time you told Reham.
What are you afraid of?
Heartbreak.
If she rejected, this restless love, too,
Will be lost.
But what if she accepted?
This restlessness will gave way to eternal blissful peace.
There now!
It appears it's time for spring to blossom in the environs of your heart.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r,' O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
Adan, you shouldn't have attacked him, mate.
Aye, we should've garlanded him.
Whatever.
Besides, it's me he pesters.
Leave it be. Everyone knows it.
It's Adan he's after.
That's why he does it all.
All I me --
-Put a sock in it, mate.
Is Kashif so important that we discuss him like this?
I got furious
And hit him.
This is your last chance to speak your heart out.
It's been a few months since Suboor and I got married.
Your love story is still one-sided.
What do I do?
Propose to her in this gathering?
Not a bad idea.
She may feel compelled to accept.
-Stop it, mate.
Ashir, I'm leaving tomorrow.
Suboor will be in America in a few days too, and you won't get your chance.
Besides, you're leaving too --
-Hold it, she's coming here!
One should
Meet a few people rather than stand in a corner like this...
Some people would rather meet from afar,
Because their hearts are connected.
Come, Suboor, let's meet the guests. I'll leave you to yourselves.
Come here, my beloved
How are you?
I'm fine.
Come here, my beloved
Don't keep me waiting...
Enjoying the party?
Yes.
Of course.
It's almost 10.
I ought to be worried.
He's not even answering his phone.
Who knows where he may be!
He'd said he's going to meet Talha.
Appa,
Nothing he says can be trusted.
I never had any such tension with Ashir, but Adan!
There!
Hear that?
He's come on a bike again.
How many times have I told him off!
Adan!
Don't go out after 9,
Don't ride a bike,
You don't like many of my friends.
Mum, please don't waste your energy to tell me any of this.
My dear --
-Please, Appa Bi.
My mood's off.
I can't listen to another lecture.
Adan!
Did you see that?
Did you see how he misbehaved with you?
I won't spare him!
-Sofia!
Talk calmly in the morning.
I won't get any calm until the morning.
How daft can you be?
I'd served you a chance to talk nicely on a plate.
I trie --
-Leave it be.
Here's an idea: Click a picture of Reham, and take it to Australia.
Make do with the picture all your life.
Meanwhile, she'd have become someone else's here.
Gorblimey, mate, she likes you, but she's a woman!
She can't be the first one to say it.
Here's a tip. Come with me.
Fesl!
-Just come with me.
I say, stay a while longer.
It's Sunday; the driver hasn't come, but I'll drop you home myself.
It's very late.
And I don't even know how I'd get back.
-There! That's sorted out.
You'd drop Reham home, wouldn't you, Ashir?
It's Sunday, the driver isn't here,
And I can't leave the guests.
No problem, I'll do it.
You'd drop her, won't you?
Yes.
I will.
Shall we?
Yes.
Alright, then.
If you dropped her today,
You won't get to pick her up ever again.
C'mon, old chap!
Why have you stopped the car?
Because I want to capture this moment,
And ask you whether I could have your hand for the journey beyond it.
Please, give me my answer.
I would've answered it if I had the right to.
But I've given this right to my parents.
I know,
And I won't disregard their right.
I just want to know
What you think about it.
Didn't I say
That I've given this right to my parents?
And if they decided in my favour?
In that case,
I'd accept this decision from the core of my heart.
It's so late.
We haven't the foggiest where this girl is!
She'd called when she'd started from Suboor's place.
She'd be here any moment.
It's been too long since.
I say you
Call her again.
Looks like she's nearby, so she's not answering the phone.
So,
When do I bring Mum to meet Aunt and Uncle?
I'd need some time.
I'd talk to Mum first.
I'd be waiting.
You can drop me here. I'll walk the rest of the way.
Why?
Because I don't want that anybody should see you
And say anything about my parents' honour.
And my conscience does not allow me to drop you all alone and leave.
Don't worry,
Their honour is dear to me, too.
Take a left here.
D -- Dad, he's --
A friend of Fesl's, Ashir.
Good evening.
-Good evening.
How are you? Everything good?
-Yes.
Suboor's driver was on leave, and she couldn't come to drop her,
So she sent me to drop Reham.
Oh.
Thank you very much, my dear.
Why don't you come in and have a cup of tea?
Another time. I'll come with my Mum.
You're welcome here.
Good night, Uncle.
Good night.
I'm honest, mate.
I said it all.
So, did she accept?
What did she say?
She's half-accepted it.
She'd half-accepted it long ago.
There was always your one-sided love.
I'll be going over with Mum to formally propose to her.
She has no objections to that.
Then, she's fully accepted.
Whatever's left?
Her parents' acceptance.
Why would they refuse?
Our lad's a real gem.
When are you going?
She'd talk to her Mum and tell me.
We'll see then.
Alright, thank me.
Thanks for what?
Seriously?
If I didn't force you, you wouldn't have said a word for the next 40 years.
You'd have departed from this world, taking your quiet love along.
Okay,
Okay, thank you.
You're welcome. And best of luck.
And yes,
Keep me posted, okay?
Sure.
Bye.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
The girl comes home from her friend's with an unknown man, in his car,
And you're not worried at all?
Don't paint such a negative picture, Shakira.
Suboor had sent her with him, and Suboor knows what it's like
In our family.
She would obviously have sent someone she trusted.
Do you have the foggiest
What could've happened if a neighbour,
Someone from the family,
Any friend or relative had seen them?
They'd just need an excuse to spread rumours.
I don't care about anybody's rumours.
But I do.
Don't you trust your daughter?
Don't you have confidence in how you've brought her up?
-It's about a girl.
One misstep
Can lead to a lifetime of regret.
It's nothing!
Shakira, I have full faith in my daughter.
She's educated,
Wise,
She knows right from wrong.
Alright, I have to go to the shop.
If the royal duke gets up,
Send him to run the shop for one hour,
I have to go to the market to get some goods.
I'll get going.
Bye.
-Bye.
Ahmed!
Hi.
Yeah, I'd called to check about my applications.
I'd submitted them last week.
Yeah.
Sure, I'll be waiting.
Thank you.
Bye.
Hello there, young lady!
Whom were you talking to
With such a wide smile?
Look,
Don't you dare hide anything from me.
Mum!
What's up with you?
I'd called where I'd applied for a job for a follow-up.
Oh?
Aren't you a tad too serious about the job?
Obviously.
What've I studied so much for?
To assist Dad.
To change the condition of all of us.
Why don't you understand?
If your Uncle found out,
He'd make our lives living hell.
He's already said so much about you going to University.
Why do you bother about him so much?
Has he ever bothered about us?
It's because of him that we're in this condition.
He's taken Grandpa's land all for himself.
He didn't even give Dad his share.
He's an elder.
One has to bother.
Oh?
Then, ask him to show some maturity, too.
He's an 'elder' just to jeer!
Mum, I'd work
And assist Dad.
This girl will start a quarrel in the family.
This is the list of all our potential clients in Australia, Ma'am.
There's also the details of the initial orders that we have to deliver.
Good.
What about Ashir's accomodation and tickets?
We've bought a house near the office.
Tickets can be confirmed whenever you say.
Alright.
Please email me a soft copy of this.
-Sure.
Alright, thank you.
Come in.
Sorry, Mum, I got a bit late.
It's perfectly alright. Come and sit.
Ashir, you didn't ask me why I wanted to start our business in Australia,
Nor why I want to send you, of all the people, there.
You've decided it for me, Mum.
That's enough for me.
No.
It's important that you know.
Pray tell, then.
It was your Dad's dream.
He wanted that we
Compete in the international market.
And who could be better than you
To make this dream a reality?
I'd try my best, Mum --
Don't 'try'.
You have to make it happen.
You have to focus all your attention on this project.
And I know you won't let me down.
Yes, Mum.
Haroon has all the details,
You should meet him.
Okay.
Do you want to say anything, Ashir?
No.
Nothing.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Who's there?
It's me. Munir.
Munir...
Nobody's at home.
Dad's gone to the shop,
And Ahmed's outside too.
So is Mum.
Jeez, I'm your Uncle's son,
Not an outsider. Open the door.
No -- I can't open the gate.
Mum's told me not to open the gate
For anyone before she comes back.
I've brought this faluda [cold dessert] for you. You love it, don't you?
No, Munir...
I've got a sore throat...
Sore throat...
What happened? Should I take you to the doctor?
Reham!
'Faluda'!
Hello, bro.
Hello.
What's the matter?
Aren't you packing for the trip?
The trip's cancelled.
Cancelled? Why?
Landslide.
All the roads are blocked.
Oh...
That's wasted...
Well, fair enough, though.
Saves me the money.
Money?
Yeah, you were going on the trip, so I thought I'd give you some money.
But now...
No -- I'll keep this.
The thing is, I'm very sad now that the trip's been cancelled.
A round of shopping will fix the mood a bit.
Alright, tell me,
How was your date?
Little twit's never going to change, eh?
-Tell me and I won't say a word.
There's nothing like what you're thinking.
Oh?
That means it's much more dangerous.
You ought to do something of the sort real quick,
Before you're past the age!
You ought to think about your age before saying these big words.
Of course...
How about a game?
Why not? C'mon.
Barkat,
I've come here myself, putting everything behind us.
Yes...
Although it's not really something that ought to be put behind...
Now, if you
Don't mind my saying so,
Sending Reham to University was not such a big affair
That one would be so cross as to sever all ties.
Very good, Dad!
You sent the girl
To study with boys, and you think it's nothing to be angry over?
Please,
Leave it be.
It was a mistake.
Blimey, Mum...
Aye, it is a mistake.
But we're the elders.
We'd have to show some kindness and forgive you.
Parveen, let's get to what we'd come here for.
Yes, Barkat.
It's a very old one
If you remember.
Come to ask for something again.
What is it?
Reham and Munir were betrothed in their childhood.
Do you remember at all?
It's about time the two of them got married.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV