Long time no see!
You haven't brought Tasnim along?
She'd... Gone over to Aunt's; she's not well.
-Oh...
May the Lord give her good health.
Appa Bi...
Where are Ashir and Adan?
They're in the room upstairs.
I'll go and meet them.
Come.
-Alright.
I'll rouse Sofia.
Please, sit.
After you, Appa.
Please, sit. I'll call her.
-Sure.
Alright, alright...
We'll see.
C'mon!
Hello!
It's a good habit to knock before entering.
Sorry,
But I'm a bit short on good habits.
How are you, Farah?
I'm fine.
How are you?
He's very well. Why don't you wait downstairs with everyone? We're coming.
Adan!
Oh --
I don't really mind what he says...
I know he's joking.
I was quite serious.
Uncle's come, too?
Yes.
He's downstairs.
Alright, let's meet him.
No!
Wait! Let's finish this game!
-Later.
C'mon.
I'm asking you for the last time. Just help me this one last time...
Believe me, there's a lot of scope in this business.
Taufiq,
How many business ideas
Have you squandered millions on!
Oh, please...
You're saying all the wrong things to me...
I mean,
You don't have money to give to your brother,
And whom are you helping?
And whom are you helping? Your stepson!
You have tons of money to help set up his business in Australia!
Taufiq!
I'd better not hear that again!
As if I've said anything wrong.
I'm explaining a few things to you. Show some sense.
That Ashir is a snake, I tell you!
He'd have everything under his name and you and Adan
He'd have everything under his name and you and Adan thrown out one day!
If you're here for this load of cod, it's better that you don't come here, Uncle.
Ashir!
Mum, ask him to get out this moment.
Why?
Have I said anything wrong?
A stepson's a stepson.
-Enough, Taufiq.
Haven't you done enough damage already?
It's better that you show yourselves out.
And it's better that you don't show up again.
And you go back to your room!
Right now!
Your young'un's got a hot head.
Keep him in check
Or you'd be crying one day.
Remember that.
Come.
But --
-Enough, Barkat.
I thought you'd honour me now that I've come.
But I expected too much of you...
I hold you in the highest regard...
All I'm asking for is some time to think...
That's just a subtler way to refuse, innit, Barkat?
No, we're not refusing...
Munir's our own kid.
Oh, leave that be.
If he were your own, you'd not have asked for time.
You had so much confidence in your brother, didn't you?
Is so much respect enough?
Let's go.
Please,
Don't leave like that.
All I'm asking for is a couple of days to think over it.
Just try to understand my side of things.
Alright, Barkat.
Two days.
But remember,
After this decision,
Either we'd be in agreement until Judgement Day,
Or we won't even bear the pall for each other.
Come.
Tear me to shreds
That Ashir is a snake, I tell you!
Like a modiste tears rags
Wait.
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
Just wait and watch. You think of him as your own, don't you?
He'll prove he's your stepson.
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
He'd have everything under his name and you and Adan thrown out one day!
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
What happened? Isn't he answering the phone?
No.
I'm very worried.
Adan's locked himself inside his room, too.
It was very bad of Taufiq.
Both of them are very hurt.
I wish I could change Taufiq's mindset.
As if one can change the mindset of people like him!
For everything they lacked in their lives,
They'd get even by ruining others' happiness.
Appa,
You've seen that I've never discriminated between Ashir and Adan.
I won't let anyone else discriminate between them either.
I've not given birth to Ashir,
But I've always thought of him as a part of me.
I know!
I know.
I've seen it.
Neither of the kids doubts your love.
Don't get all worried.
If the Lord wills, their love will never change.
If the Lord wills thus...
Two days.
But remember,
After this decision,
Tear me to shreds
Either we'd be in agreement until Judgement Day,
Or we won't even bear the pall for each other.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
Don't start it all over again.
Farah had been at it all the way.
Lecturing me,
'It was very unfair', 'You shouldn't have said that',
'Ashir would feel bad about it', 'It'd have hurt him'...
May I say something?
We've spent our lives somehow.
We should just think of what's best for Farah.
What do you mean?
I mean
I think Farah has started liking Ashir.
Are you out of your mind?
That stepson?
Yes, he's a stepson.
But never forget
This flourishing business was his father's.
Bah.
'It was his father's'...
All of this -- The warehouse, the factory...
This business...
Sofia's built it up with her own effort.
Alright, alright...
Then, why quarrel over it
When something could be resolved with love and affection?
I think
That we can't find a better man for Farah than Ashir.
Get me some tea.
Okay.
Ashir...
Ashir!
You're up, Mum?
How could I sleep
With you gone like that
And not answering your phone?
I'm sorry... I thought it best to leave then.
No, my dear...
Believe me, Mum, I didn't think in the least that you and Adan think of me as an outsider.
No one is and will be dearer to me than the two of you.
But --
I don't get --
Why Uncle Taufiq --
-Didn't you just say
That Adan and I are the only ones who matter to you?
Then, why are you troubling yourself over someone's nonsense?
Believe me,
There is no one closer to Adan and me than you.
I'm starving.
Haven't you had dinner?
You wouldn't have, either.
And Adan?
Don't even ask.
I had to force him to have something.
He was furious.
C'mon.
Let's have dinner.
Are you insane?
You're kidding, right?
Do you actually think I'm kidding?
I'm actually worried, Suboor.
I don't want to marry
I don't want to marry that blimming Munir.
Don't, then.
As if anyone's forcing you.
Just refuse.
It's not that simple for me, Suboor.
The class I belong to
Has families fight over a daughter getting educated.
And this is about marriage!
Hold on...
Have you talked about Ashir?
When will you?
When Munir's here with the wedding procession?
Blimey, mate...
Brooding and worrying over it won't help.
I'm sure Uncle and Aunt would never refuse if Ashir's parents came here with a proposal.
And this Munir affair will end for good.
Suboor...
Would you talk to Mum about Ashir?
Thank you!
Is there anything
Left for you to say after yesterday
That you've come again?
I've come to apologise.
I'm very ashamed of myself...
I said a bit too much yesterday.
But I --
I'm under so much stress that I can't even tell you...
Besides, who do I have except you?
Whom would I share my problems with?
But I've ended up hurting you,
Grieving you...
Not just me.
Your words have greatly hurt Ashir and Adan, too.
I'll apologise to them, too.
They're like my sons; surely, they'd forgive me.
It's not as if it'd belittle me to apologise.
That will not be necessary.
But remember,
You will never say anything like it again.
Didn't I tell you, I'm so tensed --
Believe me, I've --
Sometimes, I have no idea what I'm saying.
There's so many problems at home --
Well,
I do what I can to --
Make ends meet,
But my heart sinks when I think about Farah.
But naturally, I have to get her married.
My mind stops working to think of it.
You don't need to worry.
Farah's my daughter, too.
I'll leave no stone unturned in doing my part for her when the time comes.
Thank you very much.
You've got this great weight off my chest.
I'm --
Very ashamed of myself...
Once again, I'm sorry...
C'mon, now, would you still be cross?
Won't you fix your mood and ask me if I want tea or coffee?
It'd be unfair, Aunt.
Does your heart consent to Reham and Munir's marriage?
What does it matter if her heart or mine consents to it?
The section of society we belong to
Decides not with their hearts but their minds,
And compromises are valued over happiness.
If her heart's committed the sin of hoping for something,
It'd be better that she atone for it.
That is what she'd do.
Bow her head quietly before your honour and your order,
But never be happy.
She'd quietly die from within every single day.
You have to decide, Aunt -
Do you want a life of happiness and satisfaction for Reham,
Or one where she regrets her very existence?
We can't take up arms against the family.
I know.
But Uncle's always done so for the sake of Reham's happiness.
Just talk to him once.
I know he won't be able to refuse after meeting Ashir's family.
Besides, he'd invited Ashir himself.
Please, Aunt...
Alright.
Ask Ashir to come here with his Mum.
Hello?
Are you ready to prove your love, Mr Ashir?
What happened?
Nothing yet,
But if you didn't go to Reham's with Aunt,
She'd be married off to her cousin, Munir.
W --
W -- What?
Aye.
So you'd better make haste with your proposal
Before he does.
So, hurry up.
They asked for time, and you gave them just that, Dad.
They'd staved us off on the pretext of her studies before. What is it this time?
It's just a matter of two days; can't you wait?
I don't trust Barkat's intentions.
Don't get too excited. He might even refuse.
Mum --
Please say something good.
Just let him refuse.
Just see what I'll do.
He won't refuse.
Do you understand what this refusal means?
He'd have to sever ties with everyone in the family.
Think again, Dad.
Hurry with whatever you're thinking of.
I can't wait much longer.
He's out of his mind.
Talk to Barkat quickly.
I'm afraid he may do something.
Oh?
That's splendid.
Quickly now, talk to Sofia.
How can I talk to Mum, Appa Bi?
She'd strongly emphasised that I focus only on the business, and that was my intention, too.
I didn't know such a situation would come up.
You know fully well how much she loves you,
How she dotes on you.
She'd be delighted and not angry.
Just talk to her for once.
What if she got angry?
Leave it to me.
Besides, even if she got angry with you,
It'd only be for a moment.
But if your love got angry with you,
What would you do about your own heartache?
For the first time in my life, I've apologised to someone on your insistence.
If this didn't bear fruit...
What are you talking about!
Why wouldn't it bear fruit?
Love is a powerful force.
And wily love
And wily love is exceptionally powerful.
Good Lord...!
Got to admit, you've done a rather exceptional duty as a wife!
Not once did it occur to me
That there could be no better suitor for our Farah than Ashir.
Just wait and watch.
Our Farah would rule over there.
And do you know the best part?
Sofia thought the same way, too.
She said to me immediately,
'Don't worry about Farah'.
'Farah's my daughter'.
Come here, my beloved
Come here
Don't keep me waiting...
Come here, my beloved
Come here
Don't keep me waiting...
This ambience is blossoming once again,
The ambience of this redolent world
And the Heavens are humming a melody once again
Come here already, my beloved...
Come in.
Hey!
You haven't gone to bed yet, Ashir!
Mum -- I --
I wanted to talk to you about something.
Come and sit.
What is it? Why are you thinking so much?
I'm not sure how I should ask you...
It's --
Just that you've given me everything in life without my having to ask for it.
You've fulfilled every wish and given me every happiness before I could say a word.
Now --
Now when I'm asking for something for the first time, I don't know --
How to ask for it.
In that case, I should be the one who's worried.
What is it that gives my son happiness that I've got no idea about?
No -- Mum -- It's not like that --
The thing is --
It wasn't planned at all --
I wanted to focus completely on the business --
Bu -- Now -- Th --
You like her very much, don't you?
Mum?
How --
Appa Bi?
It's etched on your face.
And once again,
You didn't have to ask for it.
You'll have no complaints from me, Mum.
I'd focus all my attention on the business.
Please, just for once,
Come with me...
-When are we going?
Tomorrow evening.
Done.
Thank you, Mum!
I love you so much!
Thank you!
O Lord! You know my predicament
My life has become an affliction
Every gasp weighs at me
Why don't these doleful nights come to pass?
How do I recount what has befallen me
Ashir here.
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
How do I recount what has befallen me
Hello?
I didn't know you were more eager to become mine than I was to make you mine!
Anyway, don't worry.
Let me tell you your wait's over.
Mum and I will be there tomorrow.
Tell Uncle that I'll not be coming just for tea.
I'd be coming to take his most precious treasure.
Come here, my beloved
Come here
Don't keep me waiting...
Splendid.
You'd invited him yourself,
And now you're asking, 'Who is it'?
Who are you talking about?
Oh --
The lad who'd come to drop Reham the other day? He had such a nice name... Whatzit...
-Ashir.
Ah, right, Ashir. I'd forgotten.
Yes... I'd invited himself myself.
He'd called, too.
Reham had turned him down,
I told her to ask Dad first.
No, turning him down would be improper.
Besides, a guest is a blessing from the Lord. And anyhow, I'd invited him myself.
When's he coming?
6 o'clock.
6 o'clock...
Alright.
Regale them when they're here.
Let me know if I have to get anything to eat.
No, we have everything at home.
Alright, then.
I'll get going.
Bye.
Thank you, Mum.
May you live long, my dear.
You're happy now, aren't you?
You've acted like an outsider, now, haven't you?
How many times had I asked you to tell you, but no...
You ignored it.
Alright, fair enough...
Everything happened so suddenly, mate... I couldn't tell anything.
-I'm not a kid who'd be satisfied to hear this.
What I'd been suspecting for long has happened at last.
Alright, you know now, don't you?
Are you happy now?
You didn't even tell me now.
Appa Bi broke the news that we're going to meet my sister-in-law in the evening.
Sorry...
Just a sorry won't do.
How can you select my sister-in-law without my approval?
She's so good
That you'd approve of her the moment you see her.
You have no idea
How tough my selection criteria are.
Ask her to brace herself.
You should brace yourself too. There's a surprise coming your way.
So confident!
Yes.
Are you happy?
Very.
That meets my selection criteria.
Thanks for understanding, man!
Alright, tell me, what should I wear?
I'm so confused...
I think this one will work.
This one?
Yeah.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
Right...
Wait.
I'll see.
Yes, I'm coming.
Hello.
-Hello.
How are you?
-By the Lord's grace, I'm fine.
Hello. Please, come inside.
-Hello.
How are you, Shakira?
I'm fine.
Hello.
-Hello.
Please,
Come and sit inside.
Here.
Come.
After you.
Mum...
What if Ashir and his family showed up before them?
God forbid that anything like that happen!
I'll serve them some tea
And get them going real quick.
Now,
May the Lord be so kind...
Ashir, Adan, quickly, now, we'll be late.
I'm already ready, Mum.
It's Ashir who's taking so long...
He's going to meet his bride. He, of all the people, would get ready proper.
In hindsight, it's good that my trip got cancelled.
I'd have missed all of this.
Right...
The trip
The trip you were going on on Ashir's recommendation.
You never turn him down.
For instance, this, right now. Here he said it, and there you agreed.
Because he always obeys me.
I'm a bit impish, innit, Mum?
Just a bit?
Get going already.
We'd get going once he's here.
R --
R -- Rehmat...
One can't decide
So quickly...
Just let me
Ask Reham what she thinks...
What Reham thinks?
Barkat, the elders have always taken decisions
For the daughters.
That's fine,
But my Reham is different from the other daughters of the family.
She's educated, so what she thinks --
-Oh?
What do you want to say, Barkat?
Are our daughters unlettered?
No -- Surely, he didn't mean that -- you --
I can understand what you mean very well.
Reham's taken a liking to someone from her University.
This is why you're saying all of this.
Rehmat...
My Reham is not like that.
She'd gone to the University to study!
Girls don't just study,
They also find high-born suitors in the name of love.
-Enough!
My Reham is not like that.
Oh?
But why are you so angry, then?
I didn't even mention Reham.
It must be your conscience speaking out...
If that's not the case,
Just get Reham and Munir married.
But remember this, Barkat,
If Reham
Married someone she likes,
I'll make sure you're banished from the kin.
You'll be utterly disgraced.
I'm a man of great dignity.
I trust my daughter completely.
The day this trust breaks, I promise you,
You won't have to do a thing.
I swear by the Lord, I'd slit my own throat.
Remember this vow, Barkat,
And, when it's time, honour it.
Come, Parveen.
Everything's gone to waste.
I was out of my mind to fall for everything you and Suboor had said.
Call him
And tell him
Not to come.
Haven't you heard
What your Dad has sworn to do?
It'd be the end of the world
If they showed up.
Call them quickly.
They'd better not come.
It seems you're growing restless by the moment!
Please don't come here...
What happened, Reham?
Is everything alright? Why are you crying?
Ashir --
I don't have the answer to your questions --
Just -- You're not coming here.
B --
B -- But you'd said --
-Forget it!
Just forget anything I'd ever said!
If you have an ounce of love for me in your heart,
Just an ounce,
For the sake of that love,
Forget everything.
I can't pay the price of your love.
Hello --?
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV