Good Lord!
Arshad!
That gunshot --
It came from inside.
Adan!
My little Adan!
Anyone!
Ashir!
My dear Adan...
Adan!
My sweet Adan...
Sofia!
My dear Adan...
Open your eyes!
Adan!
Adan --
You can't have done this!
My dear...
Someone save my little one!
The child has committed suicide, but we've not been able to get any more details.
Turned down in love, a child from Karachi has committed suicide.
We're trying to, but are not being allowed in. We'll update you as we get more information.
It's possible the boy was alone. We haven't been able to talk to anyone from his family yet.
We bring you a really tragic news. A 16-year-old student from Karachi, unsuccessful in love,
Shot himself dead.
We're reporting from Karachi. A 16-year-old student,
Having failed in love, shot himself dead.
We repeat, a 16-year-old student, smitten with his teacher, has committed suicide.
We can't show you some parts of this video which is viral on social media,
But we'll show you what this child said in his parting message.
'Top yourself'.
That's what you'd said, innit?
I'll top myself.
For you,
And for my love.
... has shot himself dead.
Read it over a few times. As many times as you can.
-We can't show you some parts of this video which is viral on social media,
I'm quite confident, given what we've just talked about,
-But we'll show you what this child said in his parting message.
That they'd sign it tomorrow.
-What are you punishing me for?
That
That I fell in love with you?
Out of respect for our relationship, I'd not mention your name,
Excuse me...
-Out of respect for our relationship, I'd not mention your name,
Out of respect for our relationship, I'd not mention your name,
But I'd prove to the world that I love you.
Love
That is cheap,
And a load of guff just because you're older than me.
Rubbish!
I don't believe in any of it.
'Top yourself'.
That's what you'd said, innit?
I'll top myself.
For you,
And for my love.
Adan!
Quickly, now, I'm late!
I'd told her, 'Appa',
'Keep the young lad in check! He's hot-blooded'!
'He may do something one day'.
Good Lord! What has happened?
It would've been the end of the world for her.
She only had one son.
Hold on to yourself.
By the Lord, get a grip on yourself. You've got to comfort her!
What do you mean?
Doesn't Appa know something like this has happened?
No. Bari Appa called to tell me.
Where's Farah?
Farah! Quickly now, mun!
We've got to get there before Appa!
Come on already, Farah!
Dad...
Did you tell Ashir?
No, I don't have the number he's using in Australia. I'll get it when we get there.
Come on.
-Quickly.
We're standing where the 16-year-old had committed suicide...
And now, we turn to a family where the child has committed suicide reportedly out of love for his teacher. We're here to find out the truth behind this story.
Was his mother aware of it or not?
We're waiting -- And his mother's here.
Ma'am, please tell us, we're reporting this.
-Please, tell us.
Were you aware that your son loved a woman?
Do you know her name?
Ma'am! Please!
Did your son do drugs?
Do you know who --
-Please, step aside.
Turn the camera. Ma'am! Ma'am!
Please, Ma'am!
-Quiet, please!
Adan!
Appa!
Adan -- I saw Adan on TV...
He's alright, isn't he?
-No -- yes...
He's alright.
-Then --
Why are you crying?
-I'm not crying -- not -- inside --
Don't go inside.
Why -- why not? Alright, why are you crying?
Why -- why not? Alright, why are you crying? Please, stop crying.
-I'm not crying!
Crying --
I'm not crying...
Sofia --
Don't go inside, Sofia...
No, Sofia --
Sofia! For Heaven's sake -- don't go inside!
Sofia!
My Lord...
Adan?
Adan, get up, my dear.
Get up, Adan...
Adan...
I'm something of a sweet little lad, innit, Mum?
'Something of a'!
God...
Adan!
Adan --
Sofia!
Sofia, get up!
Get up, Sofia!
Call the doctor!
The doctor...
Life has come to a halt; time is vexed
Each moment seemingly centurial
The reverie of love rewarded me with damnation
Even my home stings at me
Miasmic and etiolated, loathy is this garth
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
She'd come to in a while.
But seeing her current situation...
You'd have to watch her closely.
I will.
Come, I'll leave you outside.
Thank you.
Get me Ashir's number from Appa Bi so that I can call him.
Alright, I'll be back.
Sir, please do something about the media fellows. It's a blooming crowd outside asking all sorts of questions.
Right now, we don't want to meet or talk to anyone.
Throw them all out.
-Alright, sir.
Why are the police here?
Who could come at such a moment but the police...
Sir, this phone...
Get it unlocked.
Sir,
Although the video says everything about the reason for his death,
Protocol requires
A post-mortem examination of the body.
Please,
Have someone come along when we take the body.
I'd go along myself.
Right.
Razzaq!
-Yes, sir?
Take the body for a post-mortem.
Yes, sir.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
What are you punishing me for?
What was my sin?
That I fell in love with you?
'Top yourself'.
That's what you'd said, innit?
I'll top myself.
For you,
And for my love.
Adan!
Sofia!
Adan --
Adan's about to kill himself...
No -- No, my dear...
-Appa -- he's in his room --
No --
-No, Appa -- Let me go...
No -- It's nothing --
-No, Appa, he's in his room...
He'd shoot himself -- let me go!
Please, let me go to him!
Please let me go...
He'd kill himself...
Adan's left us forever, Appa...
He's never coming back...
Be brave, Appa...
Adan's gone...
My Lord...
Hello?
Hello...
It's Ashir, Uncle.
Is everything alright? You and Farah had called many times.
It's not alright, my dear...
Book a ticket and get back to Pakistan as soon as you can.
What is it?
Is everyone alright?
How's Mum?
Yes, she's fine...
Is Appa Bi alright?
She's alright, too, mate...
W --
Where's Adan?
Uncle?
Where's Adan? Is he alright?
Why aren't you saying anything?
Where's Adan?
Ashir...
Adan --
Adan's gone -- Adan...
Adan's left us forever... He's' gone...
Hello?
Ashir?
For Heaven's sake, Ashir, get a grip on yourself and get back to Pakistan.
Hello?
O Lord!
Bless my daughter with happiness.
The next chapter of her life begins tomorrow.
O God, make her path
A bed of roses.
Let there be no thorns in her way.
Give her eternal bliss, O Lord...
You've done what you wanted to.
'Top yourself'.
That's what you'd said, innit?
I'll top myself.
For you,
And for my love.
Tell us something.
Who was she?
What's her story?
And what do his family say?
We don't have much information right now.
Surely, that's not a lot like you, sir.
You would've gotten something.
We haven't talked to the family yet.
Alright,
But if there's any good story,
Please, do get back to me.
Alright.
I'll get going for now,
I'll be back.
Sir!
This phone's been unlocked.
Alright.
You may go.
Sunday is so boring...
-Back to your studies...
-Miss you soooo much.
Happy Birthday!
-Thank you, Adan.
Did you like my gift? Please reply. Call me. Please answer my call. Please call. Call me.
-I can't answer the phone. Text me.
-Please believe my love... Please, don't go forth with this marriage, Reham.
-Be done with this guff, Adan!
-Why don't you believe me, why don't you believe that I've fallen in love with you?
-I don't care about your love. Forget me.
-Please don't do this... It kills me...
-Go top yourself!
Good morning, officer!
I knew you'd have something for me.
Please, go on.
Oh?
Right...
What?
That's quite the news, officer.
Tomorrow's newspaper will be a bestseller.
Thank you, officer!
I'm trying, Uncle, but I can't get a flight before the day after tomorrow.
Yes.
Please,
Take care of Mum.
Bye.
He left all alone...
He could've taken me along...
What --
What do I do without him?
Who'd I live for?
His was the only voice that echoed around this house.
'Mum',
'I want this',
'Get me that'...
'Mum'...
This silence will choke me...
Who'd nag me and be cross with me, and whom will I sweeten up?
Didn't he think for once
What kind of love
Could be greater than my love for him?
What can we do, Sofia?
Perhaps that's what the Lord wan --
-No.
This isn't what the Lord wanted.
This is not what the Lord wanted.
I've talked to Ashir.
The earliest flight he can get is two days later.
Reham, I know
That this isn't your heart's decision;
Perhaps you don't have any right to take the decision that your heart wants,
Because we decide with our minds,
And we're expected to uphold them.
You'd have to, too.
Mum, Suboor's not here yet...
She'd be on her way.
Call her.
Ask her.
Phone --
Talked it all out, have you?
-No...
Just --
Well, then, go on.
Talk all you want.
Once I've taken her home,
You won't be getting a chance easily.
Rubina,
Go and tell your Dad
That the bride is ready.
He can bring the priest here.
Praise the Lord, my daughter looks so comely.
Come.
-Come.
Apologies for bothering you.
Please, sit.
I had to come because
Something had come up.
Mrs Raza,
This is the woman who led your son to commit suicide.
Reham?
Yes.
She's the one he loved.
Or is it that
She betrayed his love...
How could she be so selfish?
I don't know anything, I need to talk to her right now.
How could she betray me?
There are a lot of messages in this that show
That Reham didn't talk to him.
Everything was normal before this.
And then, Adan sent her her address and threatened that he'd come home.
Adan went over,
And found out
That Reham's getting married.
Adan kept on asking her not to get married.
But
But Reham virtually kicked him out.
And then,
Adan said in his last message
That it kills him,
To which Reham replied with
'Go top yourself'!
I want her arrested.
In the name of the Lord God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
Reham,
Reham, daughter of Barkatullah,
Your marriage is proposed to Munir, son of Rehmatullah,
With a dower of 25,000 Rupees in the current coinage. Do you accept this marriage?
I do.
Reham,
Reham, daughter of Barkatullah,
Your marriage is proposed to Munir, son of Rehmatullah, with a dower of 25,000 Rupees in the current coinage. Do you accept this marriage?
I do.
Reham, daughter of Barkatullah,
Your marriage is proposed to Munir, son of Rehmatullah, with a dower of 25,000 Rupees in the current coinage. Do you accept this marriage?
I do.
Praise the Lord. Bless you.
Here.
Sign this.
O Lord! You know my predicament
My life has become an affliction
Every gasp weighs at me
Why don't these doleful nights come to pass?
I'll tell you!
C'mon!
What is it? She's getting married today!
-'Mistaken' my foot!
What happened?
What is this?
Why are you here?
We're here to arrest Reham.
Reham?
W -- What?
Reham's my daughter.
Surely, you must be mistaken -- Why?
We have a very good reason, sir!
The lad she used to tutor
Committed suicide because of her.
Codswallop!
It ain't codswallop!
We've come here with strong evidence.
Trapped him with her love,
Then enjoyed herself on his money,
But when it came to marriage,
She betrayed him and led him to commit suicide!
You --
What are you saying? Everything --
My -- It's all a lie!
-It's a lie. My daughter couldn't possibly do this!
Put a sock in it!
If only faces
If only faces could show intentions!
Your upbringing must have had some flaw.
N -- No...
Ahmed...
Go,
Arrest her.
-Wh -- What are you doing?
Hey --
Listen --
Ahmed, listen --
-What are you doing?
Stop them!
-Stop her!
Just a minute!
-Stop!
You can't just arrest me like that!
-You can't just take her away!
You can't just arrest me like that! Listen to me!
Shut up!
-Let go!
-By the Lord!
You can't take her away!
-Let go of her!
-Reham!
Inspector, she --
By the Lord --
I swear I haven't done anything...
I'm honest!
-Shut up!
Inspector --
-Just come over to the police station!
You'll confess your crime.
I haven't done anything! Please, listen to me --
What are you doing, Inspector?
Halt!
Uncle!
Divorce her, Munir!
Wh -- What?
No, Munir...
But -- Dad!
Didn't you hear me?
Divorce her!
Goodness, what are you saying? For God's sake -- What are you saying?
Barkatullah!
We are honourable men!
We won't let her tainted honour
Tarnish our names!
But --
-Divorce her!
But, Dad --
Munir...
-If you don't divorce her,
I'm going to disown you!
Divorce her!
-Rehmat --
Munir --
Munir -- Please...
I hereby divorce you.
-Mu --
I divorce you.
I repeat, I --
I repeat, I -- Divorce you.
Come. We're done here.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
O Lord! Hear this call; why is my road engulfed in darkness
Pronounce a judgement now
From the Heavens as You see meet
With my head bowed, I accept
I am lost in this rout of woe
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
How do I recount what has befallen me
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV