Did you tell the lawyer that our daughter is innocent?
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r,' O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
O Lord! You know my predicament
My life has become an affliction
Every gasp weighs at me
Why don't these doleful nights come to pass?
How do I recount what has befallen me
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
O Lord! Hear this call; why is my road engulfed in darkness
Pronounce a judgement now
From the Heavens as You see meet
With my head bowed, I accept
I am lost in this rout of woe
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
Life has come to a halt; time is vexed
Each moment seemingly centurial
The reverie of love rewarded me with damnation
Even my home stings at me
Miasmic and etiolated, loathy is this garth
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
How do I recount what has befallen me
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r,' O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV