Very sorry to hear everything that's happened to you.
But please, try and talk to your Mum about it.
I would have, if only she'd honoured our relationship.
But I'd ask for your forgiveness.
If you can, forgive me for everything that's happened to Reham.
You don't need to apologise.
It's enough for me that my innocent Reham has braved every trial.
But Aunt...
I've wronged you as much as Reham.
Blimey...
I'm calling you my son, and you're testing my sincerity.
Ask parents for blessings. Not forgiveness.
May the Lord keep the two of you happy. Always.
Look what we have here! Regaling the son-in-law and daughter!
Why are they here, Mum?
Who let them in?
Ahmed!
A daughter needs no permission to meet her mother.
I'm not talking to you.
You'd better. Because I brought Reham here.
We'll be here again, and you better not say that next time.
What is it this time?
Reham's been proven innocent of what you were punishing her for.
It doesn't matter now that she's innocent, Shakira.
The people say all sorts of things.
I don't give two hoots, and I'm sorry...
But, more than anyone else, it was those we held dear who said all sorts of things when Reham was accused!
Should we forget our disgrace just because that scrote's forgiven his brother's murder?
I've seen Reham meet that boy in the park myself!
Don't leave anything out, Munir.
It's true that Reham had gone to meet him, to make him understand.
You took advantage of it and forced her to marry you, or you'd disgrace her before everyone!
No, Aunt --
Whatever, Shakira!
It'd be better if she didn't come here again.
Why not?
It's her mother's place.
You're forgetting, Shakira, that this house is now my daugh --
-And you're forgetting that your daughter's my wife!
It'd be better if Reham got no trouble from you.
Appa...
Do you still think I was wrong?
The deed is done, Sofia...
What does it matter...
But it does matter
Whether you think what you did was wrong.
But he never came back.
If he were innocent, why didn't he?
You asked him to get out of the house, Sofia.
I can't remember him ever disobeying you.
Whether it's something for him... Or against him.
You heard what everyone else said and declared him guilty.
What does it matter, now, indeed,
If he says something in his defence.
Look into your heart, Sofia.
I'm sure
That in some nook, somewhere,
You'll find proof of the boy's love and sincerity.
Yes, I'll be there tomorrow.
Okay. Thank you very much.
I'd applied for a job.
They've called me for an interview.
What happened, Reham?
Aren't you happy?
So you've decided you're going to stay here...
This is our home now, Reham.
We're starting our life here now,
Untouched by any bitter memories of the past.
And what are you starting our life with?
Our happiness.
Yours and mine.
I'm sure it'll give me enough strength to put up a smile after everything we've lost.
I'll need you right by my side, Reham.
Yes, Appa Bi, I'm trying my best, but he just won't give in.
Keep on trying, Reham.
I'm sure he will,
Someday.
Yes...
So, are you fine?
Fine...?
No idea, Appa Bi...
I'm restless with this strange sense of guilt.
I never wanted any of this to happen.
That Ashir -- be estranged from Aunt -- because of me...
But, despite everything...
Reham...
Don't be silly.
None of this is your fault.
I know how it feels
To have family snatched away, Appa Bi...
I know how much it hurts having to explain yourself...
And watch their trust
Shatter...
I know everything.
I can understand how Aunt and Ashir feel.
But sadly, there's nothing I can do.
I'm helpless.
What are you saying?
Never think that there's nothing you can do.
You don't know how much it eases me that you're with Ashir.
Take care of him and yourself, okay?
Yes, Appa Bi.
Take care of yourself... And Aunt.
Bless you.
Bye.
Bye, my dear.
You asked him to get out of the house, Sofia.
I can't remember him ever disobeying you.
Whether it's something for him... Or against him.
You heard what everyone else said and declared him guilty.
What does it matter, now, indeed,
If he says something in his defence.
Look into your heart, Sofia.
I'm sure
That in some nook, somewhere,
You'll find proof of the boy's love and sincerity.
But sir, an account this big has never been transferred from the company to anyone's personal account.
Didn't I say I have nothing to do with it, Haroon?
What happened sir? Neither you, nor Madame are coming to office.
I don't think it's something I should tell you about.
Just think I've got nothing to do with anything at the office.
And if you think Mr Taufiq's doing something wrong, you have the right to let Madame know.
Please don't disturb me.
Sir --
But sir --
We've got to do something.
Who knows what he's got on his mind!
What can I do, Reham?
Mum's given him the authority herself.
We know just why.
I've asked Haroon to tell Mum.
What else can I do?
Appa Bi! Tell her about it.
No...
They've already got so many issues with Appa Bi.
I don't want to create new problems for her.
What hasn't Mum done for Uncle Taufiq...
But he's always greedy for more.
I can't believe Mum can't see it.
Perhaps because there's something else that troubles her right now...
Ashir...
Soreness and silence always makes us soft targets.
If Aunt's wrong,
So, in a way, are you.
Don't meet her if you don't want to.
Be cross with her if you want to.
But if you know someone's taking advantage of her, it's your duty, Ashir, to save her.
Suboor!
I'm going, Fesl. Don't even think of following me.
You won't be able to stop me by the time you get back from office.
I know you'd be furious, but the truth is, you would never have let me go if I'd asked.
I can't live with this guilt anymore, Fesl.
Someone lost his life because of my mistake,
And another's life is ruined because of me.
I just can't live my life with no care for any of it, Fesl.
I have no idea what Ashir will do to me,
But trust me,
I don't even care now.
I'll accept whatever punishment he sees meet.
You're free to do whatever you want about our relationship.
I found out after I got home, Uncle.
You should never have left her in that condition, Fesl.
You know she's so adamant!
If I had any idea she'd --
-Oh God...
When will she be here?
In a few hours?
Alright, I'll handle it. I'm sending someone to the airport.
Okay.
Does Ashir or that girl know she's coming?
No idea.
You're her husband. You could've handled it!
Sorry, Uncle, but...
This was dead and buried long ago...
Anyway, I'll do something.
Alright.
Alright, I'll take care.
Bye.
Hello.
Where's everyone? It's time for breakfast...
Taufiq left for office.
And Appa would rather have breakfast in her room.
And Farah?
Farah isn't really well... She's in her room.
I know Farah's cross with me.
That's why she doesn't come to me.
It's nothing like that.
She's just a bit... disturbed.
After everything that's happened...
It's just natural...
Tasnim...
I hadn't taken responsibility for Farah with Ashir in mind.
You and Taufiq don't need to worry.
She is, and will be, my responsibility.
And, after everything that's happened, it's my duty to decide what's best for her future.
And so I will...
Indeed...
It was wrong of you to come here without telling Fesl.
He's your husband, Suboor.
I'm sure he's told you why I'm here.
Yes.
He has.
And frankly, I'm hardly surprised at your silliness.
This is precisely what I expected from you.
Well...
At least someone's lived up to someone's expectations!
I expected a lot from you, too.
That you'd stand by me.
But, regrettably...
Stand by you in what?
I've told you before
That what you intend to do is utter stupidity!
What do you think?
Would they forgive you after knowing the truth?
I don't want forgiveness, Dad!
I'm here for my punishment.
Don't be crazy.
You're not alone.
You've got family.
There's me.
Fesl...
If anything happened to you, it'd pain us, too!
I'm in pain, too.
Why can't any of you see?
I've hurt Reham as much as I could.
Honestly? I'm no happier at what's happened.
Suboor!
Please, Dad...
Whatever they want to do...
I'm ready for it.
You're mad!
Raving mad!
Blimming imbecile...
I thought you'd come to me and quarrel.
Be angry with me.
Complain.
I would have, Aunt...
If the one who's left had been my own...
Not in my case...
What good will it be to be cross or complain?
Ashir's hurt you so much, I --
-No, Aunt.
Not at all.
I've hurt myself.
And I think that's what you're doing to yourself.
I've realised
That happiness is never won through plunder...
I'm not calling to ask why you did that to me.
I just want to bless you in your new life.
The life you always wanted.
With Reham. Your love.
I knew about Reham and you, but I was foolish to think I could conquer you...
But no longer...
I'm setting you free from what was never meant to be...
I have no complaints or regret.
It's been three days!
Why hasn't the money been transferred?
It's against the company's policy, sir.
The amount's too big to transfer to a personal accoun --
-Then, change the company's policy.
It's our company, and it'll be our policy.
I'll need Madame's permission.
She's never transferred to her own account or M. Ashir's --
-And Madame Sofia's put me in-charge, right?
She's given me the right.
So you better do as I say.
We're buying materials from a new vendor. He's selling at half the price!
There's no room for an official transaction. Too much fuss with the tax department folks. That's why.
You will be responsible for any losses we suffer.
Go and do what I asked you to.
Ashir's hurt you so much, I --
-No, Aunt.
Not at all.
I've hurt myself.
And I think that's what you're doing to yourself.
Yes, Haroon?
Hello...
There was a problem I wanted to discuss with you, ma'am.
Please, go on.
M. Taufiq's asked me to transfer this huge sum to his personal account.
I told him it's against the company's policy, but he scolded me and asked me to do it, no matter what.
I told him we'd need your permission, but he said it'll be as he pleases, because he's in charge.
He's also stopped all the ongoing orders.
I mean, all the ongoing projects are on hold. He's starting with new ones.
Okay, Haroon.
I'll talk to him.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of it.
Okay.
Bye.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV