How long will you keep on grieving over your oul fella?
There's so much work to do...
So many clothes. Come and iron them!
You may go. I'm coming.
Oh, seriously!
You were sitting about like an empress.
And listen,
Don't give in to the misbelief
That everyone here would pity you and feel for you because your oul fella's died.
I don't want anyone to pity me,
But please don't talk about my Dad like this.
You may go. I'm coming.
Enough with this drama already.
You'd better know your place.
Come.
Iron my clothes.
Please, take a seat.
Sit.
Thank you.
I'll call her here.
Come in.
Yes, Appa?
Adan's Headmistress is here. She wants to meet you.
Alright.
Have her sit; I'm coming.
I'd been thinking for a while
That I'd pay you a visit.
I couldn't think how I could convey my condolences.
Then, I thought I'd come today on the pretext of sharing his result.
Believe me,
The news of Adan's death shook the entire staff.
Perhaps a life only so long had been destined for him...
Look at this.
Adan's result.
By the grace of the Lord, he's scored an A* in all subjects.
What are you doing here?
I --
I'd ironed your shirt...
Wha --
Who asked you to iron my shirt?
I thought I'd--
-How dare you touch my shirt?
Do you think I'd wear a shirt ironed by you?
It's useless to me now!
Listen carefully to this.
Don't enter my room again,
And don't touch any of my things!
Go.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
He used to hate accountancy and physics...
He'd say,
'I won't do well'
'No matter how hard I study'.
And he's scored the best marks in these two subjects.
After Adan started his tuition,
He changed completely.
I can't believe that it was his tutor who led him to...
I mean,
She used to teach him so well...
In fact,
He'd become a very good boy. He'd improved greatly.
Please,
Have your tea.
It's getting cold.
How dare you touch my shirt?
Do you think I'd wear a shirt ironed by you?
It's useless to me now!
How much longer --
What did you just do, you crazy woman?
I -- I didn't see --
I'm sorry -- I --
I'd patch this up...
You didn't see, eh?
Let me see how you like them apples!
-What are you doing, Farah?
Farah, what are you doing?
My hand -- Farah!
Farah!
Farah, please, let go of my hand!
What I don't get is
Why your sister has let that girl stay!
She's ready to kick her out everyday.
She's ordered her to leave many times, too but --
-But she doesn't kick her out, does she?
She's still here!
Who knows what Aunt wants!
Don't you know what she wants?
The flames of revenge for her young son's death burn in her heart.
That's why she's kept her here. She wants to exact her revenge.
Revenge?
Is this how one exacts revenge?
Sometimes scolding, sometimes staring, and sometimes kicking her away.
Is this how one avenges the death of one's young son?
Is this how one exacts revenge?
I'll tell Aunt how to exact revenge.
She burnt my shirt; I burnt her hand.
What?
Burnt her hand?
Yes, I did.
She's gone mad!
Whatever would her anger do?
As if she's done anything wrong!
It was just right.
Why are you having sympathy for that Reham?
You won't get it. You can't understand it.
If you kept on with this,
Ashir and Sofia would grow to sympathise with her!
From now on, you're not doing anything!
Let me handle everything.
Daft lass.
'I burnt her hand'!
It's my fault again!
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
Ahmed,
Ahmed, there's no need to sell your father's shop.
What do you think, Mum?
That I'd eat up all the money I'd get from selling Dad's shop?
That's what she thinks, innit?
That you'd waste every penny of it.
Why would he waste it?
He'd invest it in the business.
What kind of business?
Your Dad had been running a shop,
Why don't you take his place?
As if it's earning us any riches!
As if you'd start a business that would earn us any riches!
Mum, I'm --
I'll invest in Uncle's business.
You'll see, once the business gets going, the times will change for us.
Shakira, don't be adamant over every single thing.
Let him sell the shop to start his business.
Bless him.
Besides, it's not as if you have anyone else.
Everything's his.
Mum!
Adan would've been so happy to see his result...
Yes, Appa...
Very happy.
Who knows what kind of reward he'd have asked me for...
Strange, innit?
He almost had an aversion to books.
Hated studies...
But then, there came Reham,
Who taught him to love books.
She should just have taught him to love books.
Why did she ensnare him in her love?
It's possible
That Reham tried to explain to Adan...
Talked about this to him, but...
You know our Adan was always the stubborn type...
He was, sure.
Insolent, too.
A good-for-nothing, too.
But not so low and vile.
He never even said anything of the sort about his class fellows, Appa.
He never even made fun of them.
And -- Reham was much older than him...
Someone his age...
Is --
Is -- utterly puerile...
The first face one finds pretty
Stays close to one's heart forever.
When one grows attached
To those close to him.
Whatever, Appa...
It's all Reham's fault.
She could've talked to me.
She told me everything about Adan.
Why didn't she tell me this?
It was her selfish greed.
That's what killed my son.
You're bigly balky!
Always looking for an excuse to retreat to your room!
Do you ever feel like doing anything?
Who'd wash the mountain of dishes lying in the kitchen?
My hand hurts a lot...
Hey!
It's just a tiny burn.
How much could that hurt?
Don't try these lame excuses with me.
I won't be able to do the dishes.
How dare you
Argue back to me?
Let me work on that.
Let's see how you avoid doing the dishes!
Come!
Come along!
-Don't --
Come!
-Please, don't grab this hand --
-It hurts!
Please let go!
Please, let go. It hurts a lot!
Enough with this act! You're not in any pain, are you?
-Please let go...
Come! Why have you stopped?
Come!
-Please --
What are you doing?
Why are you tormenting yourself, Reham?
Let me wash them.
No,
It's alright, I can wash them.
Have you applied any medicine on your hand?
I'd applied some toothpaste.
That's the blooming limit.
'Applied some toothpaste'!
Leave it. Over here.
I said leave it. Put that down.
That's the bloomin' limit.
Does toothpaste help heal wounds? Sit.
Doesn't it hurt?
He almost had an aversion to books.
Hated studies...
But then, there came Reham, who taught him to love books.
-She should just have taught him to love books.
Why did she ensnare him in her love?
It's possible
That Reham tried to explain to Adan...
Talked about this to him, but...
You know our Adan was always the stubborn type...
He was, sure.
Insolent, too.
A good-for-nothing, too.
But not so low and vile.
I mean,
She used to teach him so well...
In fact,
He'd become a very good boy. He'd improved greatly.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
Don't worry, Mum.
Once my business is up and running,
Why just one shop,
We could open many.
Why are you so at ease?
How could you have so much patience?
I'd brought you here to punish you,
To torment you and make you suffer.
Why are you so at peace?
Are you made of stone?
Don't you feel any pain or humiliation?
Why don't you just leave?
I want
That you shouldn't be left with any desire to punish me.
Punish you?
You've become my punishment.
I'd brought you here a prisoner, but find myself immured!
There's the flames of revenge for Adan raging on one side,
And on the other, I'm restless over why
No bit of misery or cruelty meted out to you
Gives me any peace.
Why do I only grow more restless?
You're responsible for all that's happening,
And I can't take it anymore.
I want an end to this, Reham.
I can only end it one way.
Kill the one who's responsible.
I'm not so weak and heartless as you
That I'd kill another human.
Surely, it can't be easy to kill, can it?
I haven't killed anyone.
I can't even kill a bug crawling on the floor.
Avarice can give strength to the weakest among us.
Avarice?
Avarice, Ashir?
You're saying this to me?
Well, Monseigneur Ashir,
If it had been avarice, Ashir, securing wealth was easy for me.
Back when you were ready to die for me!
You'd come with a marriage proposal --
I was the one who had rejected it!
The Lord alone can testify about my innocence.
I have nothing else to say
In my defence.
O Lord! You know my predicament
My life has become an affliction
Every gasp weighs at me
Why don't these doleful nights come to pass?
How do I recount what has befallen me
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
Adan,
Did you see your marks in physics and accountancy?
Yes, I did.
Adan, I'm serious.
And why are your marks in Urdu so low?
My dear,
I don't know what you'll do...
And I don't know why you're so worried.
I'd become a great businessman one day, Mum,
And take care of everything.
You'd become a great businessman,
And take care of everything?
All without a degree?
Those who have their own business don't need a degree, Mum.
Now, it's not as if I have to apply to a company for a job.
Adan, I'm serious!
I'm in no mood for jokes.
I'm very worried to see this report card.
There, now, Mum. Don't get so worried...
I had no worries about Ashir's studies.
He'd study on his own.
My dear,
This business and I --
Who knows what tomorrow may hold?
What'd you do?
Don't say that, Mum...
Alright, I promise I'll concentrate on my studies and score good marks.
Don't make false promises to me.
Alright, if I scored good marks, what'd be my reward?
Whatever you want.
In that case, I'd ask for something really big.
I'd give you
Whatever you ask for.
Then,
Start a company in my name
Just like you've started one in Ashir's name.
All its profit would be mine.
Done.
Alright,
You can get whichever tutor you want to teach me.
My Lord...
Avarice?
Avarice, Ashir?
You're saying this to me?
Well, Monseigneur Ashir,
If it had been avarice, Ashir, securing wealth was easy for me.
Back when you were ready to die for me!
You'd come with a marriage proposal --
I was the one who had rejected it!
The Lord alone can testify about my innocence.
I have nothing else to say
In my defence.
Rubina, get me my breakfast quick, I'll be opening the shop late.
I'm coming...
Can't you wait?
Getting late...
As if you'd earn
Any good dough running that shop.
Whatever,
It's currently my only source of income.
Just think
How we'd run the household
If I closed the shop.
We were about to strike a great deal about that shop.
What was wrong with us investing a few bucks in the business with Dad?
It would've benefited you, of all the people.
But your Mum's
Almost seized control of it, and won't even let us talk about this.
Thank goodness
That Dad had this house transferred over to me in the marriage contract.
Who knows, your Mum
May have thrown me out of here.
No, it's nothing like that.
Mum's not bad at heart.
It was at her insistence that Dad had transferred this house over to you.
Then, why is she adamant about the shop?
You don't exactly have a loving relationship with her either...
As if she showers her affection on me!
Whatever, Rubina,
She's my Mum.
You'd have to live with her on cordial terms.
You'll see,
She'll agree about the shop, too.
Fair enough.
I'll try that, too.
But I know Aunt very well.
She won't even agree if I took care of her.
Just try for once, will you?
Hey!
Aren't you going to the office?
I'm rather unwell...
God forbid, do you have a fever?
I'm not that unwell.
Right now, I'm more concerned about your condition
Than your health.
What could happen to my condition, Appa Bi?
Sometimes, when the noise around grows louder,
One should look within.
It's the sinner who should look within.
Sometimes, when we look within,
We see the faces of those oppressed
Whom we,
Knowingly sometimes and sometimes not,
View as sinners.
What does that mean?
You need to rest.
I'll leave you to yourself.
But I didn't quite get what you were saying...
Would you like me to have breakfast sent here?
I'd like some coffee.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV