My designation ain't that good... But not that bad either!
In time, everything will be alright.
Everything?
Let me know if we're running out of rations and all...
No.
We've got all we need.
Why would I do that, when I know how upright you are?
But why would Haroon saying so?
I knew this would happen...
My presence is costing a lot of them a lot!
What do you mean, Taufiq?
I mean, you hadn't gone to the office for quite some time after Adan, you know...
Ashir and Haroon were in-charge of every right and wrong...
They did as they pleased.
How many times we spent above the budget!
How many tenders we got at higher prices!
I've lost count! And you may remember how he couldn't really explain the loss in Australia.
Holding them to account would definitely birth some sourness!
I don't want to hurt you,
But someone who's been up to monkey business with ties of blood might as well do it with the money.
Anyway...
I'd stay away from it.
That's all I can do.
No.
Keep doing your work.
I'll be back at the office in a few days.
Alright.
I'm pleased to hear that.
What the devil do you mean?
No one's going anywhere! We're staying!
Who's stopping you?
But I'm leaving.
I can't be a part of your game any longer.
What happened, Farah?
What are you saying?
-Please, Mum...
Don't try to explain or put one over on me.
I've made my decision.
You?
You would decide what we'd do, eh?
I'm still here!
Taufiq...
-Hold on!
Let me be very clear, young lady -
I can't let
What I've worked so hard for
Slip by so easily!
Nor would I let anyone - not even you - stop things when they're falling into place!
What do you want?
You want me to let go of everything for you and Ashir?
All I'm saying, Dad --
-You better not say a word!
Just listen to what I'm saying.
It's what's best for all of us.
Please don't doubt your mother's love.
I've seen in her eyes the fear of losing you.
Many have taken advantage of it.
Wouldn't she think
That you've broken her trust?
Please, Ashir...
No one matters to me more than you, and I'm with you in every decision you take.
But I can't stay quiet with the knowledge that your ties with her are soured just because of a misunderstanding.
Ashir...
Soreness and silence always makes us soft targets.
If Aunt's wrong,
So, in a way, are you.
Don't meet her if you don't want to.
Be cross with her if you want to.
But if you know someone's taking advantage of her, it's your duty, Ashir, to save her.
I know you're getting married,
You better stop or it'll be very bad.
Please believe my love...
Please, don't go forth with this marriage, Reham.
I don't care about your love.
Forget me.
Please don't do this...
It kills me...
Go top yourself!
Appa Bi!
Suboor?
Hello?
Where are you, Taufiq?
Get back, quick!
Why, is everything alright? I'm at the office.
Alright?
Nothing's alright!
What happened? Tell me!
She's back!
She's meeting Appa!
Reham?
Not Reham...
Suboor!
I -- couldn't think -- of anything.
I was very afraid...
I couldn't imagine
That Adan would do something like that...
I -- I admit it's -- my fault...
I should've told him...
I could've told this earlier...
But the fear of being punished held me back...
But -- I can't live with this guilt anymore...
I -- I've wronged
Reham and Ashir...
No less than you and Adan...
My silence...
Ruined everyone's lives...
I'm not asking for forgiveness...
I'm asking to be punished.
Punish me however you like.
I'd accept it...
How can you trust her?
Where's her proof?
Taufiq...
Why would anyone take something like this upon herself?
She's not just anyone, Appa,
She's Suboor!
A friend of Ashir's and Reham's!
Ashir knows that if he proves that it was all Adan's fault,
You'd not only accept Ashir and Reham, but forgive Suboor as well!
Believe me,
It's all a trick -- A grand plot to --
Enough, Dad!
Aren't you ever tired of lying?
Farah?
Everything Suboor said is true, Aunt.
She's lying.
Don't believe her. She's saying it out of her love for Ashir!
We knew everything Suboor told you already.
Ashir and Reham haven't wronged you.
We have.
For greed... For our gain!
No one else...
We plotted against you.
I've wronged you, Aunt.
I hid this from you to get Ashir.
And Mum and Dad!
Mum and Dad led you astray for their greed!
They haven't given up!
All they want is your money!
They've used all of us!
Daughter...
Sister...
Sofia, please...
Just give me one chance --
-Get out of my sights!
So many chances... I'd given you so many chances, Taufiq...
Thinking that you've changed...
But I was wrong.
Betrayal runs in your blood.
You can never wish for anyone's good.
You can fall to any low for your gain.
But...
I kept on trusting you!
No longer.
Let me put it the way you deserve.
Don't expect me to honour our relation
When you never cared to.
I've forgotten
That I ever had a brother.
Don't show yourself ever again!
And don't you dare so much as touch anyone from my family!
Or I'll give you a reply in your language.
Sofia...
-Get out!
Out!
It was very hard for me to believe that you'd left me in that situation...
Everyday, I hoped,
That even as the world stood against me,
You would be by my side,
You'd speak for me,
But I lost hope everyday...
-You weren't wrong to hope, Reham.
I was wrong.
That's what I should've done.
That's what I wanted to do.
But I couldn't.
Dad sent me to America right away.
I thought Fesl would help me when I'm there.
He'd talk to Ashir...
But that never happened.
Don't think I'm excusing myself by telling you all of this.
I've broken your trust.
You and Ashir have had to go through a lot because of me.
I don't think...
I don't think any of it matters anymore, Suboor...
The worst has already happened.
I know, Reham...
I can never recompense what you've gone through,
But I've made sure
That you don't have to suffer any more.
Before I came here,
I went to Ashir's.
I've confessed my crimes
Before Aunt Sofia.
I destroyed everything...
Everything...
Sofia...
I tried to tell you...
Tried to tell you about what's going on.
But grief, it seems, had blinded you...
No, Appa...
I can't blame grief and vindicate myself.
Reham's suffering...
Everything she's gone through...
I'll have to pay for it all.
And Ashir...
What I did to Ashir...
How would I ever make up for that?
I doubted the one
Who loved me more than himself...
I can't face him...
How would I?
Please don't say that, Sofia...
It'll only make it more difficult for you to rebuild.
I know Reham very well.
I never saw an ounce of hatred in her for you.
Everything she went through...
She did with the hope that you'd accept her when you'd find out the truth.
And Ashir...
You know Ashir's love better than me.
This place has been drained of all happiness...
Please, let them come back.
Why's she here when it's all over?
A truth spoken too late is no good.
She regrets what she's done.
I don't want her regret.
It means nothing!
No, Ashir.
That's what you wanted -
That my innocence be proven before Aunt. And it has been.
I'm sure Aunt would have no complaints now.
But I do, Reham.
Of her, and if you can't see it etched all over my face, of you too.
Do you think it's easy for me to be away from her?
No!
I miss her every single moment!
The part of me that wants to obey her battles the part of me that wants to go back every day.
I'm not going back until she calls me back.
Ashir...
Reham!
Would you see who it is?
There's only one thing about you that's very bad.
You obey everything I say.
You could've just refused sometime...
Fought with me...
Complain...
Be angry...
Otherwise, how would I learn to make it up to you, Ashir?
You shouldn't have called me an outsider.
I shouldn't have.
Nor asked me to leave the house.
You've hurt me so much...
I know...
Promise me it won't happen again.
It won't. I promise.
I'll never forgive you if you did...
Don't...
But forgive me this time.
Mum!
-Please...
I've missed you...
Reham...
Please don't do something I wouldn't like.
It'd be very difficult to make up to me.
I'm so sorry...
Adan!
Adan! Where are you?
Not here...
Blimey...
Adan!
Where are you hiding?
I hope you're not cheating!
The guard's blindfolded. Can't see us here!
We can even tickle each other and she won't find out!
-No tickle...
Adan!
Where are you?
Where's everyone? Adan!
Shh!
-Shh!
Let's go in?
In?
Very bad.
Look at her.
-He wanted to come here!
I'm tired...
You're hiding somewhere. I know you left me here.
I know it!
Adan!
Adan! Where are you?
Where are you all?
What happened?
Over there.
They tricked you again.
Not fair, Ashir!
C'mon, she's calling us.
-But wait...
Here!
-No, over there. See?
Come here.
He came to me. I promise I didn't take him.
-Come here...
Come here, little one!
You were playing with rocks? So big!
And you left me here!
With a blindfold! Want to see how it feels?
Want to give me a big hug?
I love you, little one.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV