So that's your 'tuition',
Your 'respectable job',
That Uncle takes so much pride in!
You --
You're mistaken...
-Right or wrong,
-Right or wrong, explain it to Uncle.
Let go of her! Get off her!
-Please, I beg you!
If you said so much as a word,
I'd kill you
And bury you right here.
Adan!
Adan?
Where'd he gone so early?
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
Every gasp weighs at me
Why don't these doleful nights come to pass?
How do I recount what has befallen me
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
Where were you?
Didn't I ask you not to go?
Didn't I say that you're not going anywhere?
I won't go anywhere, Mum.
But I had to explain it to Adan for once.
So you'd gone to meet him!
Why do you want to create trouble?
Why don't you understand?
-Nothing's going to happen, Mum.
There won't be any trouble.
Adan!
Open the door, mate, what's the matter?
It's nothing.
I'm studying.
You didn't even have breakfast. Have something.
I've had breakfast over at my friend's. You may go, Appa Bi.
Strange.
He never bothered to study,
And now he's so much into studies that he doesn't bother to eat.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
Life has come to a halt; time is vexed
Each moment seemingly centurial
The reverie of love rewarded me with damnation
Even my home stings at me
Miasmic and etiolated, loathy is this garth
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
Look, Barkat,
You educated Reham.
We accepted it, although not wholeheartedly.
Now, she's going out to teach, and we're quiet on it, too,
But we've told everyone in the family about Reham and Munir's marriage,
With the hope
That you won't turn us down.
Now,
Everyone's asking us the same thing.
Who else do we have to tell this?
We come here, almost begging,
And you kick us out every single time.
Believe me,
There's nothing like that in our hearts.
You are our elders and we will always respect that.
Granted, Barkat,
That Munir is not as educated as Reham,
But
Who cares about a man's education?
We have everything the Lord could've given us,
And Munir
Will be running the factory after me.
May the Lord keep you well...
And
I'm not opposing anything you've said.
All I want is that Reham's consent --
-Dad...
I have no objections to this match.
No, Appa, it'll take another hour.
There's some more work to do.
Goodness... Working all the time! Did you have anything at all?
I did.
Tell me, what is Adan doing?
Quite the thing to ask, really!
Adan's life revolves entirely around his studies now.
He's always got his head buried in his books.
That's splendid!
Alright, Appa, someone's calling me,
Please don't wait for me. Go to bed.
Alright. Try to come back quickly.
Alright, okay.
Hello?
Alright.
You sent the presentation, right?
Okay.
That's fine.
Alright, thank you.
Congratulations to you, Shakira!
Congratulations to you, too.
It's a Friday the day after tomorrow.
What could be a more blessed day, Barkat?
We'd be coming with the wedding procession.
How could it be so quickly?
Well, shan,
What's the problem with you now, Barkat?
Reham's accepted it herself now.
No --
It's not about having a problem, but...
One's got to prepare.
What kind of preparations, Barkat?
Surely, Shakira would've set apart clothes and jewellery?
It's no big deal if she hasn't, though.
It's not as if we'd desire anything of the sort...
She's not going to be married off to a stranger.
She's coming over to her Uncle's home.
So,
We're bringing the procession the day after tomorrow.
There's no pressure on you, my dear.
Don't worry about anything your Uncle and Aunt have said,
Nor about
What everyone in the family would say.
But
Munir and you --
-You have faith in me, don't you, Dad?
Do you think I'd ever take a decision
That's bad for me?
Besides, who could be dearer than one's own?
They're all but family.
Would you be happy?
Yes, Dad.
And if anything goes wrong,
You're there.
Mum's there.
Uncle and Aunt...
All the elders can call us down.
If I went over to an outsider,
I'd be all alone...
It's about your entire life, my dear.
Still, if you want, you can think about it through the night, and tell me in the morn --
-My decision would be the same in the morning.
O Lord! You know my predicament
My life has become an affliction
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
It's my fault.
No one has been able to chain it
I expected that you'd respect our relationship
He who understood the 'a' of amour
And honour it!
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
From now on,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
You're not calling or messaging me!
How do I recount what has befallen me
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
Munir, please listen to me -- Munir!
Enough!
Uncle was acting so stuck-up with his 'honour'!
Swearing by your virtuousness and chastity!
All his pride will shatter now.
You're mistaken...
I'd just come here --
-To give him a lovely little gift! I've seen everything!
It's nothing like that --
-Whatever it's like,
Go and tell Uncle.
In fact, why just him,
M -- Munir...
It was because of your good and virtuous name, innit, that my family had been insulted and sent back?
Go and explain yourself to everyone.
No, Munir, you aren't doing this!
Whom are you calling?
-Dad!
So that he can gather everyone and chronicle your escapades.
Flirting around with a schoolboy in the name of 'tuition'!
It's all wrong!
-Oh?
Pray tell, what's the truth?
I can take Romeo along if you want.
Everyone will see whatever happens next.
-No, Munir!
I beg you, Munir...
Please don't tell Dad, he'd die to hear it!
I'll agree to marry you.
I'll say yes.
By the Lord, don't tell anything to Dad!
O Lord! Hear this call; why is my road engulfed in darkness
Pronounce a judgement now
From the Heavens as You see meet
With my head bowed, I accept...
Look,
One can't sever all ties with one's family.
This is what Rehmat wanted, innit?
That Reham become his daughter-in-law.
When she was so little,
He used to say, 'She's my daughter'.
And about Munir being less educated,
When a man and his wife love each other,
No one pays any heed to it.
I know, Shakira, I know.
But I don't know why...
Despite a million attempts, I cannot calm my heart down.
Then, comfort your heart, thinking
That whatever the Lord has ordained
Is the best.
But how will it all happen so quickly?
We haven't prepared at all.
Mothers start preparing for their daughter's weddings
From the moment one is born.
Don't worry.
Everything will be alright.
I had just two options, Suboor.
There was Dad's head bowed in disgrace on one side,
And a life worse than hell with Munir on the other.
But believe me,
The second would hurt me less.
If there's something my Dad prides himself on,
If there's something my Dad prides himself on, it's me.
He's struggled all his life to earn this honour.
It's the only wealth he has.
I couldn't be so selfish as to plunder all of it.
But Reham,
You'd said that he isn't satisfied with your decision.
Just try to tell your side of the story for once.
It isn't any good.
Munir would make so much noise
That it would crush my side of the story and my innocence.
Dad won't be able to take it.
My side of the story and my innocence mean nothing before Dad's life.
Reham,
How would you carry on?
I mean --
-I'd have to, Suboor.
Or everything will be ruined.
Everything.
I won't spare Adan.
He's responsible for everything.
I'll let Aunt Sofia --
-You're not telling anyone anything.
It's already happened.
But Reham...
He ought to be punished, too.
It won't do any good.
Just
Don't tell anyone anything.
Forget her.
It's not like there's just one girl in the world.
It's just her to me.
What'd you do now?
I'll talk again.
I'll talk to her again and again until she listens to me.
She doesn't love you.
-She does.
She's not accepting it just because she's older than me.
Her family will create problems, her Mum won't agree.
I'd convince everyone if only she agreed.
Do you think she'd talk to you again?
She'd have to.
She can't do this to me.
Not at all.
Praise the Lord.
This gown would suit my daughter-in-law so well.
It's really beautiful.
Don't you dare call my daughter your 'daughter-in-law'.
She gives my heart peace. That's why I worry so much for her.
There, now.
I hope there isn't any bitterness now.
Your heart is at ease now, isn't it?
What bitterness, Shakira?
I just say it all for your good.
There isn't any need for me to be angry or bitter now that you've understood.
By the way, Barkat,
Don't worry one bit about Reham.
I promise you
That I'd love her like my daughter.
Right...
Mum!
Seeing Dad call her a 'daughter' with so much love,
I'm a bit worried nobody's going to remember me when she's here.
Fair enough.
The moment Reham comes home, I'd ask him
To start preparing for your marriage.
Rubina,
Take these away,
The guests would be coming for the Mayoon [ritual].
Sure.
That's right.
Who knows who's coming to celebrate, and who's coming to curse our happiness?
Quickly, now, take these away.
I'll help her.
Moiz, I'd need your bike.
What happened? Everything good?
I need it, mate!
Alright, come and get it.
Alright.
Mate,
Getting married so suddenly?
Everything's alright, innit?
Put a sock in it.
I'd grown tired of waiting.
She's agreed at last.
However did she agree?
She wouldn't even look your way.
It's not as if this guy's so worthless.
She had to agree.
Leave it be.
Some good deed would've gotten you this reward.
Don't hope for any reward in the Afterlife now that you've gotten it in this world.
Aye, there's one good deed of yours...
Get us some tea, guv!
Why just tea?
A dinner is deserved, given this good news...
From him!
Old chap's gonna become a groom.
Leave it, mate.
-He's acting coy!
Let's place the order, shall we?
Mustaqim!
'Congratulations on your wedding'!
Excuse me...
Yes?
Is this Miss Reham's house?
-Yes.
Then, all of his...
She's getting married tomorrow.
What happened, mate?
Whom do you want to meet?
Sorry,
I'd come to the wrong address.
Oh, well...
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
I can't believe this.
The way everything's happening...
Not believing in it cannot change the situation...
You aren't ready yet...
I was about to get ready.
I know
Why you accepted this proposal.
Remember this -
If anything goes wrong now,
Besides whatever your Dad would do,
I would kill myself.
Life has come to a halt; time is vexed
Each moment seemingly centurial
The reverie of love rewarded me with damnation
Even my home stings at me
She's getting married tomorrow.
I know you're getting married.
You better stop or it'll be very bad.
This stupid kid is getting on my nerves.
Suboor...
Hello?
Why are you doing this to me?
Who is it?
Get me through to Reham right now. I need to talk to her.
She's outside.
She can't talk right now.
She can't do this with me.
How could she be so selfish?
I don't know anything, I need to talk to her right now.
How could she betray me?
Alright,
I'll get you through in 10 minutes.
What's going on? Why aren't you out of this room yet?
Praise the Lord!
My daughter looks so beautiful!
Adan...
Who were you quarreling with?
Mum, Miss Reham's very selfish.
I'm having exams, and she took a leave...
When I called her, she said she can't come.
Regardless,
One doesn't talk this way, young man.
Hello?
Yes, Haroon?
Alright, I'm coming.
Okay. Okay, bye.
Alright,
You're not going to talk to her now.
I'll talk to her myself tomorrow.
Okay?
Okay.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
I can't answer the phone. Text me.
Please believe my love...
Please, don't go forth with this marriage, Reham.
Be done with this guff, Adan!
Why don't you believe me,
Why don't you believe that I've fallen in love with you?
I don't care about your love.
Forget me.
Please don't do this...
It kills me...
Go top yourself!
What was Adan saying?
The old load of cod.
Love, amour...
'Don't get married'...
What did you say?
What could I say?
Gave him an earful and switched the phone off.
And
I say you shouldn't worry so much either.
You've already ruined yourself.
He'd come to his senses on his own,
And trust me,
It could all be a distasteful prank
To act and look 'cool' before his friends.
My driver's here.
Alright, get some rest.
You've got a lot of torment to go through tomorrow.
I wish I'd gone to America already
Because I can't see you with that Munir bloke tomorrow.
Bye.
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
How do I recount what has befallen me
Why is every last vestige of love immured?
How about a beach trip on Sunday?
Alright, done.
Guys,
Matey's live on Facebook.
Who?
Adan.
What are you punishing me for?
What was my sin?
That I fell in love with you?
Out of respect for our relationship, I'd not mention your name,
But I'd prove to the world that I love you.
Love
That is cheap,
And a load of guff just because you're older than me.
I don't believe this
I don't believe this rubbish!
I don't believe in any of it.
Does one fall in love after thinking about all of this?
If that's so,
Then...
Talking so lovingly to me,
Smiling for me,
And --
Asking me to write my heart's feelings...
What was all of that?
Just an act?
You didn't mean any of it?
You've done what you wanted to.
Okay.
My turn.
'Top yourself'.
That's what you'd said, innit?
I'll top myself.
For you,
And for my love.
Call him! Call him!
Tear me to shreds
Like a modiste tears rags
No one has ever been able to tame the mind
No one has been able to chain it
He who understood the 'a' of amour
Dares not take up arms against fate
He who understood the 'm,' 'o,' 'u,' and 'r', O Bulleya,
Found himself reduced to a fakir.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV