Hello. I've got some imported tea for you.
This small one's for 150; the large one's for 250.
Ma'am --
Would you like some of this tea?
That would be enough!
It's the third week in succession,
And you've gotten us no sales at all!
Consider this a final warning.
If you return empty-handed,
Consider yourself dismissed.
Yes, sir...
'Yes, sir' won't do. I want sales, you get it?
I have to listen to my superiors because of folks like you.
Such fairness!
It is your performance that's abysmal,
And I have to listen to whatever the seniors say!
I have to bear their insults!
What are you looking at, standing here like this? Go!
And bring some good news today, alright?
Yes...
'Islamabad'
Good morning, sir.
If it isn't Alam!
Hello!
Hello, how are you?
I'm fine.
Where's everyone? I don't see them around...
These loving hands can only be my little doll's.
It's not fair...
You recognised me again.
I can recognise my doll in my sleep.
Because nobody else can play around with me like that.
Where's Mum?
Don't spoil her with your love like that!
How are you?
Great.
Long time no see.
Yes, I've been a bit busy.
The city of Karachi has snatched my brother from me...
But the city of Karachi has made our business flourish too...
As they say,
'Nothing sacrificed, nothing gained'.
Will we stay standing here, talking all day?
I mean -- I'm starving.
Starving the moment you arrived?
Nasrin, come; let's get him something.
I'm coming from my room.
Okay.
Where are you going? Tell me what you've brought for me.
Quite the haul; come!
Good morning, sir.
Yes?
Sir, I'm selling this tea.
It's imported.
Try this tea for once, I'm sure you'd love it.
I'm fed up of your lot!
Trust a new salesgirl to show up every day selling something --
We've got such a stockpile, and my wife's such a fool --
She buys every bloomin' thing.
It's very good, sir. Imported.
Check out the aroma, it's enchanting.
The little one's for 150, the larger one for 250.
I can even give you a discount if you buy it in bulk.
Can I have a demo?
Yes, sir.
Come inside.
Sir -- ?
Come.
Yes.
The Karachi villa ain't this lively.
The residents make a house a home.
Of course.
And where bachelors like me live
Is more accurately a hostel.
And
What about that little job that worried you?
You'd even offered a tender; has it been accepted?
How couldn't it be?
I'd asked you to pray that it is.
Yes, dear.
It's all about blessings...
Else, our kind, and this luxury...
Please call Ma'am.
What's the need?
Make a cup yourself.
You'd said you'd give a demo.
Sir, I can't make --
If you don't want to give a demo...
No, sir -- I can make tea.
Alright.
The kitchen's on the right side.
Consider this a final warning.
If you return empty-handed,
Consider yourself dismissed.
Nasrin,
I'd much rather you serve water with ice.
What happened?
Why are you crying?
Is it something someone said?
This, sir. Ashraf pesters me with his calls everyday.
He even calls me at 1 a.m.
Nasrin, is this the time to complain? We're having lunch.
Excuse me.
Where are you going? Have your food.
It's my responsibility, Mum. Please.
Come with me.
Couldn't she have found a better moment?
Ashraf!
Over here.
Yes sir?
You're pestering Nasrin with your calls, eh?
No, si --
Tell me the truth
Because if I caught you lying,
I won't spare you.
Sir, I swear --
She's lying -- I'm not --
I can swear on it, Alam -- He calls me repeatedly and says, 'Let's be friends'.
So you want to be friends!
No, sir --
S -- Sir, I don't even --
S -- Sir, I don't even -- talk face-to-face with her --
S -- Sir, I don't even -- talk face-to-face with her -- It's not --
Where's your phone?
At home, sir...
Is it?
Give me your phone.
Which one's his number?
-This one.
Here.
Sir -- I made a mistake, forgi --
It was a mistake, sir --
-Hands away!
I won't do it again -- Sir -- It was a mistake --
What do you think?
You'd pester an innocent girl and I'll forgive you?
Guards!
Sir -- it was a mistake --
Throw him out!
Break his legs if he comes near this house again!
A mistake -- sir --
Sir -- I won't do it again --
Just -- A mistake --
Thank you.
It's nothing...
You're our responsibility.
Your honour matters as much as Erum's to me.
Go, now.
Sir, if -- Ma'am's around, please ask her to come.
'Ma'am'?
'Ma'am' who?
Ain't no 'Ma'am' 'ere,
I live here by meself.
No, you'd just said that Ma'am --
Ain't no 'Ma'am' 'ere;
Just me all by meself.
Just me.
What?
How say you come 'ere everyday?
I will pay you lots
And purchase all your tea.
Sir -- no --
You're -- It's j --
Call Ma'am...
Ain't no 'Ma'am' around.
Just me.
Ma'am!
Nothing --
Help --
Sorry...
I'd given you a final warning.
But you've crossed all limits today.
If you could manage to escape, why did you leave your bags there?
Sir -- I could think of nothing --
I was afraid.
If you're afraid, why do you work at all?
You can't get us a single sale.
And you've made us suffer a loss today.
Sorry, sir...
'Sorry'!
You'll say 'Sorry' and leave; I'll have to face the music!
Look, Meryem,
I've done all that I could for you.
But now,
I can't risk my job anymore.
No, sir --
-Collect your dues from the Accounts department and leave.
What are you saying, sir -- ?
Please don't do this, sir --
You know my circumstances...
Without this job,
I can't pay for my father's medicines...
This isn't a charity
Where we help the helpless.
It was my favour on you
That I considered your circumstances and gave you a job.
But regrettably,
You are not capable of it.
And yes,
If I wanted,
I could, from your salary,
Deduct the amount of loss our company has suffered,
But I'm not.
It's better that you don't waste your time and mine,
It's better that you don't waste your time and mine, and leave.
Si --
-The door is that way.
This cold, callous life
This dolorous, damned life
Why are you worried? She must be on her way.
I've become a sack of diseases with each passing day,
What do I do?
Instead of lifting the burden off my daughter's shoulders,
I've become a burden on my daughter, Shaista Begum!
What are you saying! Don't get all worried!
She'd be here any moment.
Hello!
Where were you, my child?
Here she is.
Your dad was getting so stressed. He's already unwell.
I said, 'Have patience', and there you came.
I've brought the medicines, Dad.
Get some food for him, she must be tired; I'll take the medicines later.
Take your medicines; I'll give her food.
My dear,
What's wrong with you?
Something --
Is it something at your office? Is everything alright?
It's nothing.
Everything's fine.
I'll get you some water.
Something's
Off...
It's nothing, don't worry.
Meryem,
Should I serve the food now?
What happened, dear? Why are you worried?
Meryem?
What happened, Meryem?
Mum --
Mum -- I've lost my job...
Why?
What happened? Tell me.
I was selling tea leaves...
Went to this house,
I came across a man --
He said, 'Come in and make a cup of tea',
He misbehaved with me --
I ran away.
I could not think of anything --
When I returned to the office,
I realised I'd left everything there -- I was told, 'You won't work here anymore --'
They fired me --
Behold, now, as God makes His move
Shaista,
Is everything alright?
Yes, I --
Need some money.
I paid you your salary just two days ago.
Yes, but --
My husband is ailing, so...
I need some money for his medicines...
You can't even teach kids properly,
Look at Mohsin.
He's stuck on the fifth chapter for eight months.
And Ehsan? He's not even finished the first.
No --
I do my best, but your children lack the interest.
You're on leave four to five times a month, and then you blame the children?
No --
The kids don't pay attention...
I don't want to argue with you.
I pay you a hefty sum.
The neighbourhood teacher would charge half the amount.
And I don't like your asking for an advance every now and then.
You should quit this habit.
And if you can't,
Find somewhere else. I can't bear with this everyday. Please.
Pant-shirt?
[Western dress = minor taboo]
Yes.
You'll have to wear pants and a shirt.
[Western dress = minor taboo]
It's a perfume shop.
It's a favourite of the toffs.
No...
I've never worn those.
You'll have to.
And either way, wearing pant-shirt is rather common among girls...
But Saira --
Just look at your necessity.
And I don't think you'll get such a handsome salary elsewhere.
What's all of this, Mum?
Why? What happened?
You want one of these to be your daughter-in-law.
Yes, what's wrong?
They're from honourable families... Well-educated...
With a great background.
I don't think so by their looks.
See for yourself.
Not the right thing to say!
This...
Do these look like matrimonial pictures?
They're more like entries for a fashion show.
Check out the pose.
You can have it in writing
These girls must spend half their day on social media.
Not one would know what it means to run the household.
Y'alls are picking the best sister-in-law for me!
Oh really!
He doesn't like one of them.
Show me, Mum!
-What do you want to see -- Hey!
I'll tell you.
Look.
She's so adorable.
That's unfair. What do they lack?
I've been saying the same thing.
But all he does is find faults in them.
Anyway. Leave it be.
If you don't like any one of these,
Tell me the kind of girl you're interested in. What does she look like?
Mum... My lady should be one
With modesty in her eyes,
With long hair and earrings in her ears...
A beauty of the Orient in every way.
As for my disposition, well, you know it well enough already.
Now that you've said everything,
Tell me where I'd find your girl.
I'm sorry, that's your responsibility!
There, now!
-How say we make one taking the best of all of these?
Only he doesn't like any one of them!
You won't find one for him like that.
-All of them so comely!
Ain't she so sweet?
Meryem...
We're out of medicines,
And so are the rations.
I asked the good lady for some money, but...
She refused.
Don't worry, Mum...
I've talked to a friend about a job.
Just pray
That I get the job.
Nature has its strange way...
Some are given so much
As they don't need,
And some
Not even as much as to fulfil their needs...
Mum...
Don't worry.
If the Lord wills,
He'd give us a lot.
To be honest,
After this incident,
I do not want you to work.
But circumstances compel me...
If you don't work,
How can we get medicines for your father
Run the household?
How many times have I told you not to call me when I'm home?
I'm so distressed, Alam...
How do I help you from over here?
I'm pregnant...
Days go by and I have no idea what to do...
Alam, my honour rests in your hands now...
You're there, Alam, aren't you?
Yes.
Alam, why don't you ask your mother to propose our marriage?
Don't worry.
I'll do something.
Do whatever you have to quickly... I'm in a pinch...
I told you I'd do something...
'Karachi'
Sir!
Sir, may I help you?
Which brand would you prefer?
You're new here?
Sir?
I mean, I'm a regular around here.
Everyone knows me.
They know which brand I use.
You're new here, right?
Yes, it's just been a few days.
That is why I don't know about you...
I'll get someone else.
How are you, Mr Alam?
I'm fine.
Why did you bother to come, sir?
You could've asked us.
We would've delivered the perfume to you.
I was just passing by and thought I'd have a look.
Meryem, show him the latest Gucci perfume.
Right, sir.
I'll be here in a sec.
Sorry, sir... It's a call from the head office.
Happy birthday, Meryem!
You remember?
How can I forget my friend's birthday?
Thank you!
Keep it with you; I'm attending to a customer. Don't let it get spoilt!
Sir, here's the latest collection.
Which one's the most expensive perfume here for...
Women?
Come with me, sir, I'll show you.
Let's.
Come, sir.
Here, sir.
The most expensive one... This...
Issey Miyake.
And...
This one's real good.
Yuzu.
Yes, sir?
Which one do you like?
Sir?
What can I say?
You decide...
I'm asking for your advice.
Which one would've you have bought for yourself?
This one.
Then give me this one.
I'll get it packed.
-No.
I'll get it packed myself.
Okay.
This one?
Yes, sir.
Ma'am.
Ma'am, your tea.
Is Mr Alam here?
Not yet...
You may leave.
Happy birthday, Meryem!
But...
Sir, this --
This is for you from Mr Jan'e Alam.
What?
Yes.
No, but --
Why for me?
He's a rich man.
A man with a lot of money
Finds such ways to shower his generosity.
The likes of us can only say 'Happy birthday to you',
Or give
These roses.
This is for you from all of us.
Thanks.
Malik!
Yessir?
This girl named Meryem at the perfume shop...
I want her complete biodata.
Okay, sir.
It will be done.
Weeping and wailing like this will solve nothing!
Stop it!
You can't even begin to fathom how troubled I am!
Why can't I?
I know a problem's come up!
Okay, don't worry...
I've thought of something.
Alam --
Why don't you talk to your mother about our marriage?
It isn't so easy, Noor us-Saba...
One, Mum won't agree to it.
I'll need some time to convince her; this --
I think
It'll take a while.
How much more time do you need?
Why don't you understand that my situation is getting worse by the moment?
Alright -- come here.
Nothing's going to happen; I'm with you.
Look here.
I'm with you.
I won't let anything happen to you.
Won't you drop me home?
I would love to, but I have a very important meeting...
Don't worry. I'll ask Malik to drop you home.
I'll go myself.
-Hey!
How will you go alone?
That's my concern.
A weird kind of a man, really.
A complete stranger to me,
Yet he gifted me such a costly perfume.
It cost 15,000.
What?
Yes.
I think you should not have taken it from him.
I wouldn't have if he'd given me.
But he left it at the counter.
You're so simple, Meryem. You don't know men these days.
They're not as straightforward as they may seem.
Tell me - why would a complete stranger
Gift you such an expensive perfume?
Why?
Because he was trying to impress you.
He gifted you a perfume today; tomorrow, he'll take you out for coffee, and then he'll try to talk to you every now and then.
And you'll lose your job because of this.
God forbid!
You know, Saira,
How important this job is for me.
That's why I'm saying this.
Tell me, Saira. What should I do now?
Return the perfume to him, and remember -
The world is a market. It has good and bad people.
It is up to you how you identify them.
It's you, sir!
I was waiting for you.
Really?
No, I don't mean --
Just a minute; I'm coming.
I'm sorry sir,
But I can't keep it.
Why? What happened?
Don't you like it?
Giving away such presents may be usual to you,
But the price of this perfume
Exceeds my salary.
I can't keep it. Thank you.
Wait.
Prices don't matter when gifting, Miss --
Meryem, right?
Gifts make sense when given by your own.
But to accept one
From a stranger doesn't suit me,
Which is why I can't keep it. Thank you.
-Alright, listen.
I'll take it back, but let me be clear that it displeases me.
Would you do me a favour?
What kind of favour?
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV