Prices don't matter when gifting, Miss --
Meryem, right?
Gifts make sense when given by your own.
But to accept one
From a stranger doesn't suit me,
Which is why I can't keep it. Thank you.
-Alright, listen.
I'll take it back, but let me be clear that it displeases me.
Would you do me a favour?
What kind of favour?
If it suits you,
Let's get coffee sometime?
Sir?
What's so surprising about it?
I'm just asking you out for coffee.
He gifted you a perfume today; tomorrow, he'll take you out for coffee, and then he'll try to talk to you every now and then.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm on duty.
Besides, I don't like coffee.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to attend to the customers.
I've found about the popsy, sir.
She comes from a poor family.
Lives with her parents.
Her oul fella's a heart patient. Stays at home.
Her oul wan teaches the Holy Qur'an to the kids.
She and her daughter earn just enough
To make ends meet.
They're desperately in need.
You know what to do.
Don't worry, sir.
It will be done.
Mum...
Where'd all the stuff in the kitchen come from?
Ah, that -- I was just about to tell you...
A Suzuki had come here with rations.
A certain Malik...
Malik?
-Yes.
He said the construction company is distributing rations
For the needy.
How did they figure out we're 'needy'?
Well, this is a poor neighbourhood.
The rich don't live here.
They're distributing rations to everyone.
You shouldn't have taken it.
We were managing on our own...
Why did you have to accept this charity?
Meryem,
Not one in this great bath of poverty is clothed.
What with this tantrum of dignity...
They're distributing rations to everyone. What's wrong if I've taken some?
Who knows who they were...
Why they were here...
Just some toffs here to distribute rations to the poor.
Did they mention where they were from?
You mentioned a construction company. A name, perhaps?
Yes, he gave his card.
I'll get it.
And yes,
They also said
That the educated can work for their company.
I say, go there.
It'll save you from this job at the perfume shop.
Perhaps you may get a more respectable job...
I say, go tomorrow.
I can go there to get a job,
But I'll return this charity to them.
Alright.
I'll get the card.
This cold, callous life
This dolorous, damned life
Good morning.
They gave us some rations...
We won't be needing it.
We don't accept charity, so...
Please give these to someone in need.
Zakir!
Yes, Ma'am?
Take this to the warehouse.
Thank you.
The people who'd come mentioned they're offering jobs here.
Who do I meet to apply?
Jobs?
-Yes.
Just a minute, I'll ask Mr Alam and let you know.
This is for you from Mr Jan'e Alam.
Your name?
Meryem.
Miss Meryem's here to apply for a job.
Come.
What I don't understand is why you're being so generous.
I'm not the type
You think I am, sir.
You've embarrassed me...
Yes?
Here's the list of all the people we've distributed rations to, sir.
And the two ladies who were here last week?
They seemed rather needy. What about them?
For the moment, we've given them some cash and rations.
Okay. Good.
Make sure they get their rations every month.
Okay, sir.
Sorry...
I apologize if I ever came off the wrong way...
But alright,
Given how we first met, anyone would've thought as you did...
Believe me or not, I had no idea they'd gone to your place with the rations too.
No, sir,
It's not your fault.
I'm sorry I misunderstood you...
I doubted your sincerity.
-No issues.
Sometimes, one errs in identifying people for who they are.
I almost forgot to ask you - tea or coffee?
-No --
Thank you.
I should get going. I'm getting late for my job...
Speaking of which, sir...
I heard you're offering jobs, too?
Where'd you hear that?
I do, yes.
Why?
What are your qualifications?
I've got a BA.
BA...
Alright, drop your CV tomorrow.
I'll see if there's a job here that I can offer you.
Alright, sir.
How much do you earn where you're working?
10,000.
That's it?
You must be having a hard time.
No, sir, I manag --
-Hold on.
Submit your documents here tomorrow.
I'll arrange a job for you with a decent salary.
Thank you, sir.
No problem.
Who was that, Alam?
Who?
Someone in need, of course...
What was she doing here?
What do you mean, doing here?
Why would someone in need come to an office?
She was looking for a job.
A job...
Intriguing that of all the places in the city,
She should come where there's no vacancy!
You know her, don't you?
Are you raving bonkers?
A friend of mine had sent her.
Why does it seem like you're lying, Alam?
You're doubting me?
In my condition, I can't help but doubt...
And I don't know why you're taking my condition so lightly...
-Jeez --
Who's taking your condition lightly?
I'm very worried, Noor us-Saba.
I can feel your pain.
-No way, you can't!
If you did, you would've talked to your Mum already.
C'mon, Alam, just try to understand... I get more anxious with each passing moment.
I've been so busy at the office -- so much work these days, mate...
I couldn't get time to talk to Mum...
'Busy'!
You're too 'busy' to worry about the great mess we're in!
Or is it that you don't want to talk to your Mum?
You're just staving me off, aren't you?
-Why would I?
Don't I worry for you?
You worry for me, don't you? Here.
Right here.
You aren't busy right now, are you?
Call your Mum.
Talk to her. Surely, you aren't busy right now.
I'll talk about everything tonight.
No.
Talk right now.
I said I'll talk about everything tonight.
Go.
Back to your room.
Go!
So, why don't you marry her?
A woman who can get carried away once
Isn't the type one should marry.
She got carried away by you.
Yeah...
But if she can be carried away by my words,
She may get carried away by anyone tomorrow.
And you want me to marry that type!
No.
I wouldn't stoop so low!
'Stoop'...
You shouldn't have ruined her life if you didn't intend to marry her at all.
I haven't ruined anyone's life.
Everything that happened was mutual. I didn't force her.
No woman takes such a big step on her own.
You must've given her some hope...
Ah, yes, the hopes...
I loved her so much back then...
But I've grown weary of her...
Look at yourself...
Dropping in here with a new woman every other day.
Aren't you afraid?
I'm afraid, yes. Very afraid.
Of vilification.
My vilification.
So you'd toy with others' lives to escape your vilification.
I'm not here for your lecture.
Just tell me if you're helping me or not.
This --
This is the last time I'm helping you.
If something like this happens again,
Don't come here.
It's too awkward for me.
Aye, I'll go somewhere else.
I'll send her here tomorrow evening.
Take care.
I'm very worried these days, Noor us-Saba...
I tried to talk to Mum about you.
She won't give in...
I don't know what to do...
How do I tell her how much I love you?
She'd gladly throw me out, saying,
'Have a great life with her'!
But I won't be able to take it...
I can't go against Mum for you.
I love Mum far more than I love you.
I can feel your pain...
I know you're very troubled.
But please forgive me.
I can't help it, mate.
What about my helplessness, Alam?
What about this ugly situation I'm in right now?
I can understand.
I was concerned about you, so...
I've thought of a solution.
What kind of solution?
There's a hospital nearby...
Dr Kashif there - he's a friend...
Go and see him tomorrow.
He...
Can arrange a lady doctor for you.
Finish this trouble tomorrow.
Gor blimey, Alam!
However did you even imagine --
Alam, it's our child, what's up wi --
-I know, baby...
But we don't have another way out.
We'd both be in great trouble.
Just a minute. Here.
I'd had this payment order made. You'll need it.
Here.
Take it.
How rotten and vile, Alam --
What kind of woman do you think I am? I --
Alam, I --
I'm not that type --
I'm an upright woman --
Come again?
Well, baby,
'Upright' women don't live in their boyfriend's flat like this.
So --
You --
No way, sweetheart --
I'm not thinking anything wrong about you. You're very good.
This is hardly the time -- please try to understand.
I don't want to hear anything.
What did you just say about me?
Why must you act like a kid, Noor us-Saba?
At least don't scream like that!
I've tried to convince Mum a lot. What can I do if she's not giving in?
She's too conventional.
To her, working women do not make good wives.
She's got some oriental girl for me
Who'd do household chores and wears --
I mean, look at what you're wearing!
How could I even introduce you to her?
Please try to understand my helplessness.
If you were so helpless, Alam,
Why did you ruin my life?
I ruined your life?
Why do women forget so quickly?
Know what, Noor us-Saba,
I didn't force you.
Nor are you a kid who'd have no idea.
This house,
The cars parked outside,
The servants,
Your job -
I gave you everything.
You should be thankful to Jan'e Alam.
I have no shortage of women.
For the branded clothes you wear today,
The high society life of partying you enjoy -
You ought to be beholden to me.
Who doesn't make mistakes, mate...
I made one, too.
It slipped from my mouth out of frustration...
Please try to understand --
I'm very troubled. Helpless.
No, Jan'e Alam!
I won't let it happen the way you want it to!
You'd have to marry me,
Or I'll scream until everyone hears all that'd happened between us!
It's up to you how you convince your Mum.
So you'd scream and tell the world...
You destroyed, piece by piece,
All my hopes and dreams
In but a moment
Shattered my heart into pieces
From you, I got
Nothing but such contumelies
As those that left on me
Ineradicable smirches
My love bears witness
Listen, my duplicitous dear,
Behold, now, as God makes His move
This cold, callous life
You've got a BA...
Yes, sir.
Just about average marks...
Do you know how to use MS Office and all?
No, sir.
We haven't got a computer, sir...
Our school had one, but I never got a chance...
You'll get your chance now.
I'll ask my IT department to train you.
Just give me one chance, sir...
I'll work very hard.
I can learn new things quickly, sir.
That's the spirit.
I'm confident you'd do great, Meryem.
Just remember one thing...
Yes, sir?
All that I'll ever ask of you will be for your betterment and mine,
And the good of the company.
Everything clear?
A --
And, sir --
What'd be my salary?
Ah, yes, I forgot to tell you! Let's see...
30,000 a month.
30,000?
Would you need more?
N -- No, sir...
30,000 a month would be enough for me.
Splendid. You can start tomorrow.
Thank you so much, sir.
Mum and Dad would be delighted to hear
That I've got the job.
They'd bless you.
I'd need all their blessings...
Thank you, sir.
Dad...
-Yes?
Have some of these sweets [good news].
-Okay.
Guess what, Dad,
I've found a new hope today.
You'll see,
Our troubles would vanish into thin air.
Dad...
One needs just a point
To embark on a journey of hard work.
I've found that point, Dad.
You'll see
How I work hard
Day and night.
Don't you always say,
'The Lord holds the hardworking dear'.
He'll help me along the way...
The day He helps me,
The times will change for us.
What's with the haste, Mum?
Haste?
You're 35 already.
When would you get married if not now?
I'm not refusing to get married.
Just find me the kind of girl I like.
It's as good as refusing!
Tell me,
Where would I find the kind of girl you like?
That's your problem, innit?
Your job, like every mother's...
Alright, then...
I say, find someone for youself over there in Karachi.
No, Mum... I don't think it's proper...
Someone's daughter...
How could I --
With this virtuous innocence,
I'm afraid you'll always remain single.
You know that innocence is my weakness...
The times have changed, my dear.
Lads these days!
They show up with a girl, saying, 'Say hello to my wife! We've gotten married'.
No, Mum, I'm not like that.
You know me.
I would never marry someone who'd leave her family for me.
Someone who can leave her family today might as well leave me tomorrow.
Okie doke, mate, I got it. I'll find someone for you, but!
You won't say anything when I've found someone.
I wouldn't dare.
I just want someone
Who's honourable, homely...
And comely.
Okay.
Bye.
I'll talk to you later. Bye.
Modest, coy, docile... Pure homely material...
What happened, Dad?
Aren't you happy that I've got a job?
No?
So why are you so troubled?
I'm just...
Troubled at my fate...
I --
Should've been distributing sweets
On the occasion of my daughter's espousal...
But instead --
Because she's gotten a job...
That's why I'm troubled...
Dad...
Your treatment is more important than my espousal.
Get well quickly.
You'll get your wish, too.
Meryem,
Isn't 30,000 Rupees
A bit too much?
It's a big company...
Were it not for your Dad's treatment
And our present condition,
I would never have allowed you to work.
But...
I'm helpless...
Helplessness is a great fiend
That makes you do unimaginable things.
Why are the two of you worrying so much?
And Dad,
It's a good place to be.
And Mr Alam...
He's a very upright and generous man.
First impressions,
My dear,
Are hardly enough know a man...
And --
Do other women
Work at your office, too?
Yes, Dad.
Alright...
That's good...
You're worrying for no reason.
It's great there.
But --
When a poor man's daughter steps out of the house,
His heart grows restless.
Forget these fears.
Just pray for me...
That I do well on this job.
May you live long.
May the Lord bless you with good fortune.
Amen.
Dad...
I'll get some water.
Jan'e Alam!
What's this? Barging into my office like that!
Why aren't you answering my phone?
Keep your voice down.
Down!
My office isn't your home.
No need to create a scene here.
Get going.
I'm not here to create a scene.
I've come to get the answer to my question - when are you marrying me?
Go. I'll be coming over tonight. We can talk.
I'm not going home.
I need my answer right now.
How do I tell you, Noor us-Saba?
You don't seem to understand...
Noor us-Saba, I don't want anyone in this office to hear about it...
I'm not worried about myself.
I'm worried about your honour.
I worry about you a lot. I really love you.
If someone pointed a finger at you,
It would drive me really furious.
Go home, I'll be coming tonight.
We can talk at length and work something out.
Look at the kind of man you are!
Changing colours every moment.
Your romantic self
Can make hearts of stone melt,
And your stranger self
Can make the dearest think again if they'd ever actually met you...
Don't worry.
I'm with you.
Don't create a spectacle of yourself for everyone to watch.
Go.
I'll be there tonight.
Every bit of me afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
My life is now ruined
O Lord
Decide my fate
Hear my prayer
Look at yourself...
What happened?
You're looking at my heart's condition...
In one of its dark and lonely corners lies shattered a promise you'd once made...
And shards of all the dreams
Of my life with you lie scattered...
My tears...
My tears descend from my eyes onto my heart...
Did you take the pill?
Know what, Noor us-Saba, such is life...
It has its ups and downs.
Sometimes,
One's got to be like stone, and sometimes like wax...
That's the way it is...
You've grown weary of me, haven't you, Alam?
You're after the lass who'd come to your office the other day, aren't you?
Who?
You'd sweet talk your way right into her heart --
'Sweet talk'?
Look at me. Here.
Noor us-Saba?
Here.
There's nothing like that.
Nobody can take your place in my life.
You're lying!
-I'm lying?
Have I ever lied to you?
If you were telling the truth, you would've talked to your Mum.
How can I believe that so powerful a man can be so helpless?
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV
I did.