Praise the Lord!
How sweet you look!
I'm seeing you so happy after so long...
Seeing you smile like this
Gives peace to my heart.
Just
Keep smiling like this, my dear.
I...
Want to forgive
Jan'e Alam
For every bit of injustice done to me.
Really?
I've thought a lot before taking this decision.
To do what he did
Was his sensibility,
And my sensibility says
That I put all the pain
And bitterness behind us.
I knew it.
My daughter is very kind.
Sometimes,
To forgive
Is to dress
One's wounds.
Forgiveness
Eases one
And heals
The wounds of injustice.
Right.
So, may I sit here?
Sure, my dear. I'll meet the guests.
I'll leave you to yourselves.
-Thank you very much.
I'll be back.
-Okay.
I want to ask you something.
Yes?
You wouldn't change now, would you?
You wouldn't betray me, would you?
I would rather sacrifice myself, Meryem,
Than betray you.
How great would it have been --
If --
Dad had been here today, too?
But...
Why don't you put everything behind us?
I
Forgive you.
I accept you from the depths of my heart, Jan'e Alam.
By saying so, Meryem,
You've eased a burden on my heart.
Thank you very much.
I've got a surprise for you.
What kind of surprise?
Come.
Excuse me, everyone!
Come a bit closer, we've got a lot to talk about.
Thank you very much, all of you!
I am
Sincerely thankful to all of you
For honouring us
With your presence here.
I'm delighted today
To have been married to one whose family
Has such lovely people as these,
And I'm indeed fortunate
That I've been married
To someone like Meryem.
Wouldn't it all have been so wondrous had it been true!
That's right.
Innit?
I
Am the most unfortunate man in the world
To have been married
To one so depraved
As this chippy, Meryem!
I would've thrown her out the very next morning.
But no...
I wanted to teach a lesson to every slapper out there
Who's ruined the family of an upright man like me.
Wh --
What are you sa --
-Shut up, you blimming con woman!
Don't you dare move forward!
You thought this chippy would be an albatross around my neck?
Didn't you feel any shame?
Didn't you feel any shame? Eh?
You were all at the wedding, weren't you?
I'd accepted her with utmost sincerity,
Saved her honour, but she --
On our very first night, I knew that she --
She's not the decent type.
I mean -- Just imagine -- An honourable man like me --
I've never even lied -- Imagine what would've befallen me!
What are you saying?
You know that Meryem --
-I know that you
Are her brother.
You're in on this with her, aren't you?
Ensnaring men like me to extort money?
Jan'e Alam!
Don't you dare raise your voice before me!
Your screams
Cannot hide the truth.
I would rather sacrifice myself, Meryem,
Than betray you.
Malik, you've been with me for so long...
Yet, even you couldn't see through me...
Jan'e Alam
Can forget everything,
But never his humiliation!
Your blood's boiling, innit?
Just wait and watch what I do to you, Malik.
My dear...
-Hey!
You better know your place, you old hag!
I'm no one 'dear' to you!
All of you seem so upright and virtuous...
From respectable families... But these two!
They're besmirching the honour of your families.
Believe me, I've had a narrow escape!
So, I've decided
That you bear witness
As I teach this mare a lesson.
I'll end all your sorrows.
I'll give you the respect and honour
That you truly deserve.
Which is why...
I...
Divorce Meryem.
I divorce Meryem.
I...
Divorce her.
Felt all 400 of the volts?
This is Jan'e Alam's vengeance!
You will never forget it.
Halt!
For every single bit of injustice done to me,
My Lord God
Will make you pay!
Jan'e Alam!
Wait and watch
As God makes his move!
How my Lord God chastens you!
Whoa!
Mum!
-Hey! Get up!
What happened to you?
Mum! What's happened to her?
Five Years Later
Murree
Miss Meryem,
Are you and the other teachers ready?
Mr Shan would be here any moment.
-Yes, ma'am, we're ready.
He wants that this school should be no less than any private school.
Don't worry.
You'll have no complaints.
It's him.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you so much for this warm welcome.
And
It delights me
To see everyone like this.
I want to thank you, Madame Headmistress,
And all the teachers
Who have worked so hard with these children
And gotten us a better result than we'd ever expected.
Thank you!
Almir bin Sajjad, 1st position in class 4.
Humna Malik, 1st position in class 6.
But what about me, Mum?
Sarina Zahra, 1st position in class 7th.
For every single bit of injustice done to me,
My Lord God
Will make you pay!
M --
My sister --
My sister is innocent.
Wait and watch
How my Lord God chastens you!
Erum!
I'm coming, my dear!
My little doll!
I'm coming!
I...
I was looking for you.
So was I.
Looking for that sin
For which I've been punished.
Remember, Jan'e Alam,
If you swore a false oath,
Your sister would have to suffer its consequences.
I --
I've booked an appointment for you with the best plastic surgeon in town. I --
I'll get this scar off you.
Why are you laughing like that?
You're home now.
You're home.
What do I do?
Become all innocent again?
No...
Innocence is not a designer's dress
That you can buy me
And I can put on to dress my existence.
What could a surgeon do?
What's the best he could do?
Which scars could he hide?
Could he get the scars on my very existence, my soul, or my character off me?
I've talked to a psychiatrist.
She's called us tomorrow for therapy.
Just do me one favour.
Dig my grave in a corner of this room.
I can't step outside. I just can't!
You've always fulfilled every wish of mine, haven't you?
Please fulfil this last wish.
Shoot me dead!
No, Erum...
Set me free from this life.
Please, set me free...
Behold, now, as God makes His move
I'm in great pain. Please save me...
No...
Behold, now, as God makes His move
Please end my suffering...
My Master...
Please, take a seat.
No, I'd rather you sit. It's your seat and your office.
Please, sit.
-Thank you.
You've gotten me a better result
Than I ever expected.
It's all thanks to you, sir.
Who wants those at the bottom to climb up these days,
Or that the son of a labourer become a doctor, engineer, or pilot?
I believe that everyone has a right to progress.
It is not the patrimony of the few.
Everyone - rich or poor -
Should get an equal opportunity for betterment in life.
Anyway,
Let me know if you need any additional funds.
I'll get them transferred.
Sure, sir.
I want every child at our school
To get the same kind of education
As any private school in the big cities.
And believe me, the education system here is no less than that of any private school in the city.
I'm glad.
Thank you so much.
My dear...
My dear son...
It's been six months since Erum came home.
Why are you still in this condition?
Why do sisters get punished
For their brothers' sins, Mum?
That's how it is...
Women
Have to pay
For the sins of their men -
Fathers, brothers, husbands and sons.
If only I'd not sinned...
If only...
I hadn't sought revenge for my humiliation...
If only I hadn't ruined Meryem...
My sweet little doll...
Would've been fine.
She wouldn't have had to go through this pain, Mum.
Oh God...
Where could Meryem be?
I want to meet her once, ask forgiveness for my sins once.
If I see her,
I'd fall at her feet
And beg -- Ask her --
To take her curse back -- Her curse has struck me, Mum...
I'm in a great torment...
The Lord has heard her prayer.
There is no peace left and I grow restless!
Do me a favour, Mum...
Curse me that I die!
God forbid!
Don't say such things, my dear...
Don't say such things...
My daughter is as good as dead,
Please don't torment me by saying such things.
Don't say these things.
You're still worrying about me so much...
I've wronged you, too, Mum.
No...
I've wronged you, Mum, haven't I?
Mum, just do me a favour...
Before anyone else does it,
Kill me!
Why are you doing this? No!
-Kill me!
What are you doing?
-Please, Mum -- I'm in great pain...
-Please kill me, Mum! Kill me!
Calm down, my dear...
Every bit of me afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
Kill me, Mum...
Calm down...
Every bit of me afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
Meryem!
Where are you, Meryem?
Every bit of me afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
Calm down, my dear...
God...
My life is now ruined
Calm down...
O Lord
Mum --
Decide my fate
Jan'e Alam?
Hear my prayer
Wake up!
What happened to you?
Hear my prayer
You don't get it, Ma'am. The Chairman's having a meeting inside.
So?
You can't go inside.
You don't know
What Mr Shan's like.
He'd leave every other thing to hear the poor out.
The Headmistress has asked me not to allow anyone in during meetings.
Look, sir, it's very important that I meet Mr Shan.
I've got to talk to him.
Let's see who can stop me!
Step aside.
-Hey!
Wait, Ma'am!
-Let go!
Hey!
How'd you get in -- Why did you let her in?
I tried to stop her, Ma'am, but she barged in.
She said she's got to talk to the Chairman about something.
Just a minute.
So you want to talk to me?
Yes, Mr Shan. I want to talk to you.
Pray tell?
Mr Shan, I want to tell you something
About what's going on in your school.
They're just looking after their own!
You'd said, hadn't you,
That there's no difference between the rich and the poor?
But why differentiate between the kids?
What do you mean?
I don't get it.
Sir -- It's -- The teacher, you know --
She gave her niece the first place,
And my daughter the second place.
What's she saying, Madame Headmistress?
Who's she talking about?
Sir --
I have no idea.
I don't know what she's talking about -- I don't get it.
No need to cover it up, Ma'am.
You know everything.
I know the teacher, Mr Shan!
Her name's Meryem!
Her niece and my daughter are in the same class.
They're class-fellows.
They've scored the same marks.
But she awarded
The first place to her niece...
And the second place to my daughter.
These folks think
That we're poor...
What would we know about
The first place
And second place?
But sir,
I expect fairness from you. My daughter's been crying so much...
She's always stood first!
Please don't cry.
Please.
I say, take her to the waiting area.
Please wait. I'll call you.
Thank you, Mr Shan,
Thank you so much.
Mr Alam,
You're alright.
Just continue taking your medicines.
You'd get worse if you stopped taking them.
Thank you, Doctor.
Take care.
Alright. Nasrin, leave the doctor outside.
Why didn't you take your medicines?
You do know that your depression will get worse if you don't take your medicines, don't you?
No medicine in this world can possibly help
Someone who's been cursed by the sobs of the helpless.
But yes, a lethal injection
Could surely ease the woes of life...
Does ease the woes of life...
-Shut up.
Don't say that again.
You're a wise man.
Just look at what you're saying.
What would happen to me?
Do you know that despair is sinful, too?
It displeases the Lord.
Doesn't everything that Jan'e Alam does?
What is going on?
Despite your --
-I have no idea what she was talking about.
I don't know anything.
-How come you don't know?
S --
I say...
What's her name?
Meryem.
Please call her here.
But sir --
-I'm saying call her here.
Right now. I want to talk to her. Please.
Okay.
Hello?
No.
Send Miss Meryem to my office.
Quickly.
Look, Madame Headmistress,
I can't tolerate any kind of injustice in my school.
Alright, listen to this.
Listen carefully.
Don't jump to a 'no', okay?
My dear,
I say you
Think seriously about your marriage.
I'm confident
That you'll be better quickly.
I've married once already...
Just forget all of that...
How can someone forget the destruction of another,
Especially when one's responsible for it?
Jan'e Alam...
If you keep on thinking like this -
Heavens forbid - Your condition will only get worse.
Please, don't...
I feel the same way.
I won't get better.
No.
Don't ever say that.
Okay?
Never.
Look, Aunt, I've scored 100 marks!
-Really?
I made the report cards but didn't notice!
What?
Why didn't you tell me?
Do you know how tensed I was, Aunt?
Could I have seen this broad smile if I'd told you before?
Congratulations, Humna!
Thank you, Aunt!
Alright, come and sit here. Tell me what you want as a gift.
Gift?
How much money have you got again?
Let's say...
Let's say... Five bags?
5,000?
I'll have to think, then!
Oh?
Then, think hard about what you'd want!
-Miss...
The Headmistress has called you to her office.
I'm coming.
I'll be back, okay?
How long will this go on?
How long will you continue to torment yourself?
Have you seen the scar on Erum's forehead, Mum?
I feel that my past
Is etched in those scars.
Whenever I look at her forehead,
I feel like my past is standing before me,
Screaming,
For every single bit of injustice done to me,
My Lord God
Will make you pay!
'Jan'e Alam',
'Watch how the Lord chastens you!'
God...
I should've been punished for my sins.
Set me free from this life.
I'm in great pain.
Meryem's curse should've destroyed Jan'e Alam and spared my sister...
My sister's suffered a lot...
Erum's so innocent, isn't she?
She still thinks I'm an angel...
If only she found out
That she's been punished for my sins...
How much she'd grow to despise me...
Look, Miss,
This is a disciplined school,
And I will not tolerate
Any kind of injustice to any student.
If your niece studies here, don't ever think that you can favour her.
It's nothing like that, sir!
I've worked on the results with utmost fairness.
-Fairness, you say?
When your niece and my daughter scored the same marks,
Why did you award the first place to your niece?
Your daughter's stood second because --
-Oh? Can't kids fall sick?
She pushed my daughter back just because she had a fever for one day?
What kind of fairness is that?
It's noth --
-Please...
I don't want any dispute here.
Please,
Revise the results.
I'll announce the new results in the class tomorrow in person.
But, sir --
-I don't like having to repeat myself.
You will revise the results and award both the girls the first place.
It's your responsibility now.
Are we clear?
Okay, sir.
-Yes, sir.
Bleedin' nepotist!
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV