Shani...
What happened, Mum?
What is happening!
It is time...
No way, Mum...
Please don't say that.
As the Lord wills.
We can't do anything.
I don't -- have time...
Lis --
Listen to me...
Think of your brother --
As your Dad...
Don't ask him anything...
I won't, Mum...
Don't --
Don't ever leave him alone...
Why are you saying that, Mum?
Nothing's going to happen to you.
Please...
Be generous for your brother...
And --
Consider this my will...
I'll do as you say.
Please don't talk about leaving us.
We'll be all alone...
You can't leave us...
My dear...
Get Jan'e Alam here --
I need to -- talk to him...
Go...
Send him in.
Okay...
-Get Jan'e Alam...
Go.
-You'll be alright.
Quickly...
Jan'e Alam...
Mum.
What happened to you...
My sweet...
I --
I've --
Apologised on your behalf...
To whom, Mum?
Now --
Yes?
Please --
Forgive yourself...
I forgive myself.
Mum...
Mum!
M --
No! Mum!
Be brave.
I hope Aunt will be fine.
Be brave, mate.
Mothers always protect their kids
From the harshness of the world.
Mum will be alright, right?
Of course...
-So, how can I let you be disgraced?
You talked to her, right?
Once Malik's released,
I'll go to Meryem myself and ask forgiveness for everything you did,
And, if it seems meet,
Bring her back in your life.
What happened?
Mum's no more, Shani...
I think I should get going.
-Where?
Home, of course.
What happened, Mum?
You haven't even had dinner.
Please, stay here. With me.
She's left us...
I'm all alone now...
All alone...
Aunt...
We'll go with Dad when Uncle Shan will be there to talk about the marriage, right?
For the sake of your mother, Meryem,
Please do this mother a favour
And save her family.
Aunt?
We'll be there, right?
No.
Why?
Because I don't want to marry him.
But you liked him, didn't you?
Yes.
Not any more.
Is Uncle Shan a bad man like Uncle Alam too?
Will he leave you after marriage too?
Might as well...
They're brothers, after all...
Enough talk.
Get ready quick. It's getting late.
I still can't believe it...
How did Mum have an accident just like that...
Why did she leave us...
This heart is its own nemesis
It ruins its life
O Lord! Sap away my life
Hear my plea
I'll pray for your forgiveness.
I'm sure the Lord will forgive all your sins.
You pray for me, Mum?
But of course, my dear.
Don't mothers always
Pray for their children?
Perhaps that's why they say there's no greater bounty than a mother.
Mothers always protect their kids
From the harshness of the world.
Ah, m'boy!
-Here to brighten everything up as always!
How are you?
I'm fine. Why didn't you tell me you're coming?
Be brave, Shani.
You'll sicken yourself weeping.
I mean --
How can she leave us...
We're all alone...
All alone...
Alone...
It's what God has willed... All we can do is be brave...
I can't be brave, mate.
I just can't be brave...
It lingers on, lingers on
This dolorous, damned life
Alam will be all alone if you kept crying like that.
You have to be brave for him.
Okay?
C'mon, Humna.
Let's get going.
Good morning, ma'am.
-Good morning.
What happened? Why is the school closed?
School's out for three days.
Three days?
Why?
I'm not aware about anything of the sort.
Who told you?
Mr Shan's mother passed away.
What?
But how?
She had an accident last night.
May she rest in peace...
That may be why he didn't answer my call in the morning.
I should convey my condolences...
Should I call him right now?
No...
He'd be very upset right now.
I shouldn't call him right now.
Just a minute.
Who is it?
It's you!
Where's Humna?
Inside.
Humna!
Dad!
My little doll...
You're back!
You won't leave us again, will you?
Please stay with us forever.
Do you know how much I've missed you?
Most of all on results day.
Everyone's parents would be with them.
But only Aunt came with me.
Please don't leave us again.
Never, my sweet doll. I'll be with you now. Always.
Here.
Look what I've got.
-For me?
And this dress.
Thank you, Dad.
Please, come in.
I'll get your things.
You like it?
Yes.
Look at this here.
Meryem...
I can never thank you enough
For how you've looked after Humna in my absence.
Please don't say that.
I've done no favour.
You've been very kind to me.
What haven't you gone through for me...
In a way...
I'm responsible for separating Humna from you.
No, Meryem.
You've illuminated my life.
Made me see the light...
Were it not for you, I don't think I would ever have become human...
I, too, would've had to suffer a Meryem's curse...
That my daughter would've had to suffer for.
Dad, do you know that Aunt was about to get married?
Aunt?
We thought of coming to Karachi to tell you.
But no idea why... Aunt doesn't want to marry Uncle Shan now.
Why don't you keep everything inside?
No. I'll go and show Feryal first.
I'm going to Feryal's, Aunt.
Get back quickly.
Meryem?
What is it?
After what you've gone through,
It wouldn't be easy for you to trust my love,
But I promise you,
I'll never let you down.
I hope you can trust love so much.
Then, his mother had me promise...
That I'll be out of her son's life quietly.
Strange...
You had found refuge with the brother
Of the man who'd been looking for you for so long,
Yearning to meet you...
Did he meet you?
Not just once.
He tried to ask me where you live.
I've been released before I've done my time
So that I can lead him to you.
Jan'e Alam got you released?
Yes.
He'd come to me a broken man.
I beg you, Malik.
My soul is tormented.
Just tell me where Meryem lives. I want to apologise to her before I die.
He would never have imagined what your curse had done to him.
What happened to him?
His sister got abducted four years ago.
M. Alam looked for her like mad,
But found no trace of her.
And then?
He found out she was in Dubai.
Dubai...?
A notorious gang had kidnapped her.
I'm very afraid! He'll be coming for me again! I'm serious!
Before all of you have to suffer for my sins, please kill me...
M. Alam's innocent sister
Had to pay for every single life he had ruined and more.
Your Lord has pronounced his judgement, Meryem.
I'm at a loss for words...
How do I tell you how we've been disgraced...
I think God, Meryem,
Has exacted your vengeance.
You should forgive him.
What are you saying?
You know what he's done...
He's been punished for it.
Perhaps He has forgiven him, too.
Now,
Would we be any better if we continue to punish M. Alam?
Even He retaineth not his anger for ever, because He delighteth in mercy.
Won't you do as your brother asks you?
You'll forgive him, won't you?
Amidst shards of dreams
Forgive him...
A rough and repugnant slumber
Weighing down on my eyes
Both restless and unsettled
I might die of them...
Let's see who's been calling...
'I'm sorry Mr Shan but I don't want to marry you'.
What's up with her now?
Why is she saying that?
She was fine until yesterday.
Had no problems...
Why is her phone off?
Meryem!
I don't see Humna around.
She's gone over to her friend Feryal's.
She'd rather have it this way while school's out.
Plus, she'd like to show her friend everything you've got her.
By the way...
I'm going to Islamabad.
Islamabad?
Everything alright?
For the funeral of M. Alam's mother.
I'll get you your breakfast. You haven't had anything.
-No, thank you.
I forgot to clean the kitchen last night, too, it's all --
-Meryem...
M. Alam will ask me about you.
What should I tell him?
Whatever you feel like telling him.
I understand
That it won't be easy for you to forgive him.
Well, in that case, why are you forcing me?
Because he's suffered a lot.
Life and death is in God's hands alone.
He's lost his honour.
Believe me...
Just meet M. Alam once.
You'll feel his pain if you saw him.
You'll meet him, won't you?
Alright...
If that's what you want... I won't force you.
Okay?
I'll get going.
I'll be back in the night.
Bye.
-Bye.
Wait...
I'll meet him.
I can understand your pain, M. Alam. Please, gather yourself.
I'm all alone now, mate...
Come in.
You didn't tell me how you found out
That Mum had passed away, Malik...
I was surprised about how I'd found out, too.
I don't get it.
Meryem told me.
Meryem?
Yes.
The same Meryem you've been looking for.
How'd she find out?
She lives in Murree.
Meryem's in -- Murree?
I was just as surprised as you are.
All this while, the one you'd been looking for
Had been living under the roof you'd given,
And you hadn't a clue...
There's something else you should know.
Meryem's agreed to meet you.
Malik...
Did I catch that right?
Yes. You heard it.
I can't believe how quickly you convinced her. How?
She would never have agreed to meet you.
But I told her about Mme. Erum.
Come.
Where, M. Alam?
To Meryem's.
Right now? But --
-Yes. I --
No, Malik, I can't wait anymore.
You don't know how I've longed to see this day.
Prayed day and night for just one thing...
That I get to meet her once.
I want to ask for her forgiveness.
I can't bear the weight of my sins anymore, Malik.
I'm very tired, mate.
-Come.
Some people are here to convey their condolences.
You're... Leaving?
Yes. Something came up.
I'll be back in a few hours.
Something came up?
But...
People are coming for the funeral.
I'll be back in a few hours.
Please, meet them in my absence.
Alright, but...
Will you be in town?
We'll be in Islamabad.
And you are?
Malik.
Who?
An old friend.
He's here to help. I'll need him by my side.
What kind of help?
Just pray, Shani...
That I succeed
At what I'm going to do.
I'll be back. Come.
You'll drive?
Why, what happened?
It's nothing really, but every time you've been in the car with me...
I've been your driver...
Not today, Malik.
I'm not your employer, and you're not my driver.
C'mon.
Sir...
I don't quite like it this way...
That you drive when I'm here.
Give me the keys. I'll drive.
Keys?
On you shall descend one day
The wrath of the Heavens
Obloquies yours
Shall resound in this world
Ashes yours
Shall be blown away with the winds
Dead ends shall you find
In your room in every heart
Recompense for my pain
Is my perseverance
Behold, now, as God makes the next move
Very sad...
But as the Lord wills...
May He protect us all...
Amen.
By the way, I don't see M. Alam around?
I would've met him if he were around.
Something came up and he had to go...
He'll be late.
Don't worry about the factory.
We'll take care of everything in your absence.
Thank you.
Yes?
Where's Alam?
Why are you asking?
I saw Alam's car here in Murree.
Alam's car... In Murree?
Yes.
And he was in the car.
With another man.
How can that be?
He'd just left to do something --
And I even asked him. He said he'll be in Islamabad.
I wouldn't lie to you like that.
I was a bit surprised too.
Well... I may've been...
Mistaken, maybe?
Might've been someone else.
Alright, I'll be coming there.
Okay.
Bye.
Nobody must hear a thing. Don't tell anyone, okay?
C'mon, now.
-They'll take me with them. I won't --
Please -- Let go --
-Come!
Dad!
Behold, now, as God makes His move
I have heard the skies
I'll end all your sorrows.
Have rained all night
I'll give you the respect and honour...
Which is why I...
Have rained all night
...That you truly deserve.
...Divorce Meryem.
Have rained all night
But it is that city that has remained athirst
My Master...
Behold, now, as God makes the next move
Stop right there.
Not one step forward.
Meryem, M. Alam's apologising to you...
I know
He's here to apologise.
Apologise for murdering my parents...
Calling me a chippy before everyone...
For marrying me and divorcing me two days later, all to exact his revenge...
And for who knows what else!
Innit?
Right.
That's it, right?
Yes...
I asked you to stop right there!
I...
I have no complaints...
For all that I did --
-You don't need to remind me...
The memories are still green...
I've wronged you, Meryem...
I'm tormented...
Please... Forgive me...
He doesn't even know how to apologise!
How can I forgive you so easily?
What do you mean, Meryem?
That he beg forgiveness
Like a sinner ought to.
I'll do what you say...
Please, forgive me.
Down on your knees...
And say after me, begging with your hands folded...
What are you saying, Meryem?
I don't mind one bit.
Say,
'I've wronged you, Meryem'.
I...
I've wronged you, Meryem...
'And all that happened to my sister'
'Was the punishment the Lord ordained for me'.
And all that happened to my sister...
Was the punishment the Lord ordained for me...
'Now that I've suffered every punishment the Lord meted out to me',
'I beg you - please, forgive me, Meryem'.
Now that I've suffered every punishment...
The Lord meted out to me...
I beg you -- Please -- forgive me, Meryem...
Behold, now, as God makes the next move
Go, Jan'e Alam!
Meryem forgives you!
It lingers on, lingers on
I...
I forgive you!
It lingers on, lingers on
This dolorous, damned life
Malik...
It lingers on, lingers on
Did you hear that, Malik?
This dolorous, damned life
Did she just forgive me?
This heart is its own nemesis
Meryem forgave Jan'e Alam!
She forgave me...
This heart is its own nemesis
Forgave me...
It ruins its life
Forgave --
O Lord! Sap away my life
Meryem forgave me...
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV
Hear my plea