A thing remains alluring
Every bit of mine afflicted
Only as long as it remains distant.
With this eldritch malaise,
Instead of lifting the burden off my daughter's shoulders,
I find myself reduced to my daughter's burden.
Ask your sister
My life is now ruined
How invaluable and priceless honour is to a girl.
You've ruined their lives for but a few bucks!
O Lord!
Decide my fate
Hear my prayer
What is a woman's greatest weakness?
Love...
Kill me, please! Kill me!
Amidst shards of dreams
A rough and repugnant slumber
Weighing down on my eyes
Both restless and unsettled
Erum!
I might die of them
Your truthful treacheries
Leave me! I want to go home!
All that you have done
You know it in your heart
Watch, now, as God makes his move
He was lying -- Dad's n -- Mum!
This cold, callous life
Let go of me!
What happened, Dad?
This dolorous, damned life
If someone's sacrificed everything for you, it reflects the intensity of her love.
This cold, callous life
But one who lost her heart to me so easily can, someday,
Lose her heart to anybody else.
This dolorous, damned life