But sir...
It's a big sum... I don't think I'll be able to pay it back...
Don't worry.
It's not like you're quitting the job.
You can pay it back in parts.
Here.
Sign here.
I'll transfer the amount to your account today.
But it's blank, sir...
Ah, yes... I had it made rather quickly... Nothing we can't work out later, I'm sure?
Go on.
What happened?
Don't you trust me?
It's nothing like that, sir...
Then just sign it, will you?
I'll transfer the amount to your account today.
Thank you, sir.
No problem.
Hello?
M -- Meryem?
Yes?
It's Noor us-Saba. I'm outside the office.
Could you come for a second?
Just a minute.
-Okay.
Hello... You called me here. What is it?
You look so... Happy...
I am happy. Mr Alam's helped me a lot.
Lent me some money for Dad's operation...
Wow...
Mr Alam's so nice...
So... Caring.
Indeed...
He can feel our pain...
And how to give them pain...
I didn't get it.
I'm sure you will...
Meryem...
Time opens our eyes...
So will it open yours.
This -- This is where bad luck begins...
When you blind yourself to the truth and start believing the lies, the deceit...
Just because it promises the world of our dreams that we know isn't real...
We're so foolish, Meryem...
So foolish that we choose to live the lie with the most vile of people... Until... Until...
Until one day...
They desert you and you find out...
There's no going back...
Yeah, I talked to him... He said tomorrow... I --
I'll get back to you in a sec.
What are you saying? I don't understand anything.
You will... Soon, you will...
But when you do, I may not be around to comfort you.
Know what's the problem with our type?
Our desires, our needs... They kill us!
He's not a good man!
Jan'e Alam! He'd rob you of your dignity, your love! That's how he rewards loyalty!
Believe me, Meryem, I know him!
I don't think it's likely, but if you can bring yourself to it...
Think about what I've just told you...
He's not a good man!
Jan'e Alam! He'd rob you of your dignity, your love! That's how he rewards loyalty!
Know what's the problem with our type?
Our desires, our needs... They kill us!
Meryem!
Yes, sir?
We're meeting a client right now.
Okay, sir.
I'll be waiting outside.
With me.
Every bit of me afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
My life is now ruined
O Lord
Decide my fate
Are you sure you don't want to have anything?
Yes, sir.
By the way, I haven't brought you here to meet a client.
I wanted to tell you something...
Something you don't know.
Sir?
Noor us-Saba didn't resign from her job.
I fired her.
Sir? But why?
She was blackmailing me.
Wanted to slander me.
'But why', I can hear you thinking.
I loved Noor us-Saba a lot, Meryem...
Love that women would only dream of...
I wanted to marry her, too...
But unfortunately, Mum...
She didn't want her as my wife...
I tried convincing Mum...
But - it pains me even as we speak - I couldn't...
Noor us-Saba asked me to get married in court.
I couldn't go against my Mum for her...
So, naturally, I refused.
She started blackmailing me... Threatened to shame me.
Which is what she did when I did not give in.
Accused me of the unimaginable... Slandered me before everyone at the office...
I can't even look anyone in the eye now...
You may never believe it, but when Noor us-Saba first came to me, she had nothing...
I gave her a good job, a place to stay, a car...
This is how she returned the favour...
Anyway... I'm sure He's watching...
I'm sure she'll try to tell you her lies, and you will eventually start believing her...
No, sir...
Don't worry...
I trust you. No matter what she says.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Thank goodness someone trusts me...
The tea's fantastic, by the way... How say...
Excuse me!
One cuppa please?
Well ain't someone gettin' a little too close to Jan'e Alam?
Where'd he take you, eh? For dinner?
-Eww!
Hey!
Ohhh...
I nearly forgot!
He's already impressed you!
Aye! Already impressed you!
Impressed!
He's right, though...
It's a doddle to trap our type!
Don't you dare say another word, Noor us-Saba!
Or --
-Or what?
What can you do?
NOT JUST YET!
Where are you off to?
Gonna tell Jan'e Alam?
Go. Go tell Jan'e Alam, sweetie.
He can't do nothin'!
But remember...
Ever thought why he's being so... Kind to you?
Blimey, he's real kind!
I thought he was kind too...
Real...
Kind...
I've had to pay a real big price for it...
Real big price...
AND SO WILL YOU!!!
You will, too!
Tick, tock, tick, tock...
You're gonna be Jan'e Alam's next target!
Ah, yes...
Where's it?
If you'd allow me...
-Sure.
Say the Lord's name and put the ring on her. Show him your hand, love.
Congratulations!
-Congratulations!
This is the true face of your good samaritan Jan'e Alam...
He's a wolf, a BLIMMING WOLF!
He ain't no man...
He's a wolf...
Save yourself, Meryem...
There's still time.
No way...
You're lying.
I won't believe a word you say.
And keep your fake pictures with you!
Keep them.
Remember this day when you look at them.
I knew it...
I knew you won't believe me.
I knew he's blinded you...
Like he blinded me...
I'm coming back...
From the road you're travelling...
You don't want to go on, Meryem...
Please...
Believe me... Just... Don't...
Ma'am... Please be kind to me. In the Lord's name?
He'll bless you.
-NO!
I don't want any blessings...
Just a minute...
Gold chain.
Want it?
Here.
First, pray...
Pray... 'Noor us-Saba... May the Lord'...
Pray... 'Noor us-Saba... May the Lord kill you'!
Good Heavens, what are you sayi --
-DO YOU WANT IT OR NOT?
-Of course, Ma'am...
Pray.
May the Lord...
May the Lord kill you! Kill you...
RAISE YOUR HANDS AND SCREAM! I WANNA HEAR YOU SCREAM! 'NOOR US-SABA, MAY THE LORD KILL YOU'!
May the Lord kill Noor us-Saba!
There!
Say... 'May the Lord kill Noor us-Saba right there'!
May the Lord kill you right there -- Noor us-Saba... Right there...
May the Lord kill you!
May the Lord -- May the Lord kill you!
May the Lord kill Noor us-Saba!
-Kill Noor us-Saba...
Right there...
May the Lord kill you!
-Kill Noor us-Saba...
Amidst shards of dreams
A rough and repugnant slumber
Die, Noor us-Saba... A rough and repugnant slumber
Weighing down on my eyes
Die... Weighing down on my eyes
Both restless and unsettled
DIE!!! Both restless and unsettled
I might die of them
Die... I might die of them
Your truthful treacheries
Die... Your truthful treacheries
All that you have done
You know it in your heart
Behold, now, as God makes his move
Why don't you have something?
-Sure, thanks!
Want some more?
-No, thank you.
Where's your daughter, by the way?
She's studying with her friends. Exams these days, you know.
Okay... Bless her...
Well if you're done with the investigation...
-Okay...
What is it?
We're here to ask for something very dear to you...
We wanted to ask for your daughter's hand in matrimony. For our son.
But isn't it...
Please don't refuse.
We want Erum to be our daughter-in-law.
I'm sure, but...
Your daughter is going to be our daughter-in-law...
So this would be...
-So what?
You liked our daughter the moment you saw her. The same way we liked Erum.
Would you have refused if we'd proposed our son's marriage first?
You don't seriously mean... A sister-exchange?
No. Just think it's best for our families.
-Of course.
I'd need some time...
I can't decide alone. Alam cares for Erum like a daughter.
I'll have to ask him.
Sure.
I'll meet Alam when I go to Karachi. I can talk to him myself.
As you wish.
Okay.
You've got to have this!
Thank you, you're very kind... After you.
'Karachi'
You didn't have to bother yourself, Uncle. You could've called me to Islamabad.
It's nothing, really. I thought I'd see you while I'm here for business.
And, there's something we need to talk about.
-Yeah?
I'm sure your mother's told you that we've asked for Erum's hand in marriage for our son Jahanzeb.
Yeah, she mentioned it.
I need some time, Uncle.
Oh...
Erum's my only sister... I'd like to ask her.
I have no problem if she's happy with it. We can organise a small engagement ceremony.
That's good.
I hope you decide in our favour.
May the Lord will thus... Please, have something.
Do you enjoy being disrespected again and again?
Why are you here?
Gotta have some respect to be disrespected.
You never gave me any.
What are you doing? Get off!
Mind the cameras!
Put up with me one last time.
You won't see me again...
Even if you wanted to.
Can't believe it, can you?
But I assure you.
But...
I've got one last wish, Alam...
Please?
One last wish?
What?
I want to visit your room.
Why?
Your room...
It's redolent with your fragrance...
I want to take you in...
I want to drown in it one last time...
You're not gonna stop me, are you, Alam?
Okay...
But there's one condition.
I better not see you again.
Not in my office, not around here, not... Anywhere.
Go.
Psycho!
Behold, now, as God makes his move...
My Master...
I worry about you a lot. I really love you.
If someone pointed a finger at you, it would drive me really furious.
Amidst shards of dreams
A rough and repugnant slumber
Weighing down on my eyes
Both restless and unsettled
I might die of them
Your truthful treacheries
All that you have done
You know it in your heart
Behold, now, as God makes his move
We'd have to sacrifice the kid...
This cold, callous life
Otherwise... You risk losing me forever...
This dolorous, damned life
This cold, callous life
We're doing what's best for us. I'm with you.
This dolorous, damned life
Every bit of me afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
My life is now ruined
Please don't leave me... I'd die without you...
O Lord
Hell!
Decide my fate...
My Master...
When'd you see her?
I was going to pray when I saw her. I called you right away.
Who's here at night?
No one, sir.
Everyone leaves at 7.
I'm stationed at the gate.
Did you see anyone come here?
I want the statements of everyone here.
-Yes, sir.
No one's leaving before we've talked to you.
Forget the tea, Mum, I'll just do with the breakfast!
Just a minute!
The rickshaw's been waiting for half an hour!
M --
-Here.
You had to bring everything!
-Have your breakfast properly.
I'm getting late...
Easy there. What's with the hurry?
I should get going.
Finish your breakfast.
I gotta go. I'm late already.
Meryem...
Your Dad has an appointment with the surgeon next week.
Ask your boss for a leave.
I'll talk to him today.
Hey! Finish your breakfast! You haven't had anything!
I'm really late, Mum. Have to dash!
Noor us-Saba had been all distressed ever since Mr Alam sacked her.
What happened?
Don't you know?
Noor us-Saba committed suicide.
What?
RAISE YOUR HANDS AND SCREAM! I WANNA HEAR YOU SCREAM! 'NOOR US-SABA, MAY THE LORD KILL YOU'!
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV