If you were telling the truth, you would've talked to your Mum.
How can I believe that so powerful a man can be so helpless?
I did.
I tried to convince her, Noor us-Saba, but she just won't listen!
Well, make her, Alam! A mother would do anything for her son!
I've tried everything!
She doesn't like working women.
She doesn't want that kind of a daughter-in-law!
She's a dinosaur... She doesn't get any of it...
Alam...
Don't tell me you think the same way...
If someone's sacrificed everything she's got for you, it's because of her love!
Just shoot me, Alam...
-Are you out of your mind?
Just shoot me if you ever thought I'm 'that type'.
But please don't disgrace my love like that...
I'm really sorry if it hurt you... I just blurted it out in anger... I was... Unsettled...
I couldn't see a way out.
But...
I found an excuse to call Mum here.
Really?
She'll be in Karachi in a few days...
And I'm gonna introduce her to you.
So smile now, will ya?
That leaves just one loose end...
What?
Your, uhm...
Mum doesn't know about your -- uh -- condition.
Didn't you tell Mum --?
Are you mad? Do you really think I'd tell her that? 'Didn't you tell Mum' -- Jesus...
Forget about accepting this proposal... She won't even meet you!
What can we do, Alam?
Noor us-Saba...
We'd have to sacrifice the kid...
Wait. Sit down. Let me finish.
We don't have another way out, Noor us-Saba.
I can't be so selfish...
Selfish?
As if it isn't my child! It pains me much more than you.
There's no other way.
-Well, then, make one!
How?
Noor us-Saba... I need your help.
Please, stand by me. Don't add to my worries. How'd I tell anyone --
She doesn't have to know. Not before the marriage.
Oh? 'Not before the marriage'! As if Mum won't get a thing! What do you think she is?
Even if she accepted the proposal, there's no way I'm getting married before Erum. What are we gonna do?
Still, let's say we do get married.
Do you think society would accept our child? Do you think Mum would accept him?
Who do you think would have to suffer?
I know it's very difficult for you...
But if you truly love me...
Please do as I say...
Otherwise...
You risk losing me forever...
Every bit of me afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
My life is now ruined
O Lord
Decide my fate
Hear my prayer
Waiting for someone?
Yeah, Mum's coming here.
I thought I'd go to the airport to pick her up.
Just a few days... When she's fine, I'll introduce her
Just a few days... When she's fine, I'll introduce her to Mum.
Come...
Just a minute.
Don't worry. Be brave.
We're doing what's best for us. I'm with you. Go.
Go. I love you.
Take her to Dr Rukhsar.
Not fair, Alam.
Did you see her, Alam?
Did you see the pain on her face?
-Here we go again...
You her friend or mine?
My honour is at stake, but all you can see is her pain!
Blimey...
Well, who cares about honour these days anyway?
Mum!
Get me my breakfast, Mum! I'm getting late for work!
Just a minute!
Here.
Okay...
What is it, Mum?
What are you thinking?
I went to the doctor with your Dad's reports.
And?
What'd he say?
He told me to get a bypass done as soon as possible.
-A bypass?
Yeah...
Just how? I'm afraid we haven't got anything...
How'd we get the money?
The doctor even said that if we didn't get it done in time...
-Don't say that, Mum! Nothing's gonna happen to Dad.
Just pray...
I'm sure God will show us the way...
We haven't got anything we can sell...
Mum...
I'll talk to Mr Alam. Ask for a loan.
But...
You've just started working...
Why'd they give you a loan?
We should try.
Do you see another way?
That's what I'm worried about...
You've just started working... What if he got angry?
Why would he? The worst he can do is refuse.
I think we should try.
Who knows? God may make him have mercy.
As you think... Anyway, have your breakfast.
I can't have breakfast. I'll get going. Talk to him first thing I get there.
You've been discharged. Please change.
But...
Jan'e Alam -- The man with me?
I don't know about him.
And the bill?
It's been paid.
Please vacate the room as soon as you can.
Every bit of me afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
My life is now ruined
O Lord
Put some music on, Malik.
A touch of innocence, a stranger you are...
My life-breath, my longing you are...
Everything's fine now, right?
No problems?
Of course. Everything's okay now.
Thank you, Alam...
Is Aunt here?
Why?
What do you mean, 'why'?
She was never coming here.
But you said she took the flight last night...
I was lying.
I mean, when you can blackmail me...
Can't I tell you one teeny tiny lie?
Speaking of which, here's your gift. For blackmailing me.
Miss Noor us-Saba!
What is it?
Your termination letter.
It's all a prank, innit?
Please don't... I'm so worried, Alam...
-No.
Time has played a dreadful prank on you.
What are you saying?
What did you think?
Did you think I'd give in to you?
Did you think I'd actually marry you if you blackmailed me?
Blimey, you must be raving mad.
A man may imagine a relationship with you...
But it ain't gonna be marriage...
What's the meaning of all of this?
You said you loved me! You wanted to marry me!
Ah, yes... Love...
Do you know what's a woman's greatest weakness?
Amour...
Love. That's what she craves.
That's all she wants from a man.
She'd give anything to get a man who gives her that...
Even her life.
Some are so stupid that they know their man's faking it all, lying to them...
But this game of love is so... Alluring...
That they'd rather live a lie blindly for just a tiny bit of a man's attention.
Not your fault.
You're a woman, after all.
Alam...
I really love you.
Really?
I've sacrificed so much for you, Alam.
Please...
Well, let me tell you this, Noor us-Saba...
The allure of anything lasts only as long as it's distant.
It's this allure...
That women like you mistake...
For love...
I had no idea that's who I was in your eyes...
Whoever you were in my eyes...
You can't say I didn't give you your worth.
Gave you a decent job, a house...
Gave you rides in my luxury cars...
But... I've had enough of you...
By the way...
You should change. Get going. I've paid the bills.
Don't go to my apartment. I've sold it.
Alam!
Alam...
Please don't leave me...
Where'd I go without you?
I'd die without you...
Actually, there's one place you can go to...
Where?
Hell!
Every bit of me afflicted with this eldritch malaise,
My life is now ruined
O Lord
Decide my fate
Hear my prayer
Amidst shards of dreams
A rough and repugnant slumber
Weighing down on my eyes
Both restless and unsettled
I might die of them
Your truthful treacheries
All that you have done
You know it in your heart
Behold, now, as God makes his move
Mr Alam sent me here.
He wants you to move out as soon as you can.
Don't worry.
It ain't like this one but... I've got a flat if you need one.
Same deal as with Mr Alam - you just have to keep me happy.
How dare you!
What do you think I am?
I know what you are. A helpless woman desperate for a man's help.
I can help you.
Take it that you've been demoted...
Shut up and get out of my place!
Your place?
I said get out -- Out --
Or?
Or else?
You gonna call the cops? Complain to Mr Alam?
Funny, innit? I mean, he was complainin' about you!
I gotta go. I'll be back tomorrow. You better move out.
Or I'll throw you out myself.
It'd pain me... Really...
And...
Please consider my offer.
Get out!
Yes, Ma'am?
What's your name?
Meryem.
What are you doing here?
I work here. I'm Mr Alam's PA.
Why do you ask?
There was a time, not long ago...
When I used to sit here.
I'm your Mr Alam's ex
I'm your Mr Alam's ex-PA.
Who he fired and...
Replaced with you.
Oh...
You're a decent girl, Meryem...
Just -- quit this job, okay?
What are you saying?
I don't get it.
Just wait... I'm sure you will...
Is he in his room?
Yes.
Do you have an appointment?
I don't need to take one.
But -- Ma'am! Please! Stop! You can't just --
No, I don't like --
-You can't -- He's busy right now!
I'll get back to you.
I tried to stop her, sir, but she barged in.
You may leave.
-Yes, sir.
Sit.
I figure you've found my replacement.
No one's replaced you, Noor us-Saba.
You did it all to yourself by not listening to me.
I would've gladly let you keep your status if only you'd listened!
I'm sorry, Alam...
-Hey, hey, hey... Watch it! Back off! It's my office.
Hands off me.
Yeah?
I'm sorry, Alam...
Please don't leave me...
Take me back...
Alam...
Please marry me...
What?
Are you out of your mind?
Jesus... How many times do I have to tell you? And you think I'm rude.
You're not - how do I put it nicely - marriage material.
You aren't homely.
So just forget about this marriage thing, will you?
But you always said you want to marry me!
-Well, turns out I'm a natural liar.
So, quite naturally... I lied to you.
But I really loved you...
Really?
My heart beats for you...
Your heart...
Let me tell you this, Noor us-Saba... This 'heart'...
It's a picture frame.
With time, the picture gets dusty... Until you tire of seeing it.
That's what's happened...
I've grown tired of seeing you... It's time to change the picture.
Alright, don't worry. Here's the deal.
How say you stop remembering everything? The memories will only trouble you more. Just move on...
-Enough, Alam...
Stop it already...
Just look at me!
-Yeah?
Don't you feel my pain? Don't you feel pity?
-Jeez, Noor us-Saba, what's up with you?
You're so sweet. So lovely they'd all die for you.
You'll find someone better, someone richer than me, and... Perhaps someone who'd even marry you.
I don't want anyone else... I'm not that type!
-There, now...
I know you inside out.
Don't tell me what --
Anyway... Why are you here?
If you can't do anything else for me...
Please don't snatch the roof over my head...
Where'd I go? What'd I do without this job?
Just give me two months...
I'll be out of your life as soon as I've found another job.
Hmm...
Two months?
Alright, you've got two months.
You can stay at my flat for two months.
You'll get your salary on time too.
But you better not come here again!
I never thought...
That I'd become an untouchable in your eyes!
Sorry, what?
'Untouchable'?
Looks like someone's been watching too many Indian dramas!
'Untouchable'! Jesus...
Get out!
I better not see you in my office again!
'As if I'm untouchable, Jan'e Alam'!
But I don't get why she warned me.
Meryem...
You've got me worried too.
What did she want to tell you?
Didn't you ask her why she was kicked out?
I never thought I should...
I'm worried the boss might kick you out someday too...
God forbid, Mum...
I've barely got this job...
I must say you've raised your daughter well! Girls these days, they don't usually dress so decently.
She's got simple tastes. We never said a word.
Really?
Yeah. We've never forced our children to do anything. It's their life.
What a splendid coincidence! My son thinks the same way!
How say we introduce Jan'e Alam to Arooj? If you don't mind, of course.
I'll ask Jan'e Alam.
He's a bit conservative.
Sure.
With that sorted out, may I take a selfie with my sister-in-law to-be?
Sure, why not? Go ahead! Please!
May we go outside?
-Sure.
Thank you!
Hello, Mum.
Hello. Erum just sent you a picture on WhatsApp. Did you see it?
Yeah, just did.
Who's she? The girl with Erum?
Arooj - your bride to-be! Do you like her?
Is that 'mission accomplished' I'm hearing?
'No' isn't an option. You left it to me, and I took care of it!
I'm not saying no, Mum. I'd do as you say.
As always... I'm sure you'd be delighted to meet her! She's so lovely, so smart, and so nice!
You'd look great together!
Right...
I'm sure you'll do what's best.
Talk to her parents if you like her.
Okay.
Come to Islamabad for a small engagement ceremony. We can fix the date of the wedding then. What do you say?
Fine by me.
I'll come over when I'm free.
We'll be waiting.
Yes!
He likes her!
-How couldn't he? I mean, just look at her!
Just... Why do people get married?
I wonder, Mum...
Why do we fear our past so much?
There's always happy memories to ease the pain of bitter ones...
Why do we forget them?
Why do we always remember our helplessness, or what we lack?
Because we're afraid of losing whatever we've got and pushed back to helplessness.
It's always the pain, the hurt, the hardships that affect us in the long run... More than happiness.
Mum?
Why are you so sad?
I...
I went to the doctor today...
He said we've got to get a bypass done quick or it will be bad...
I've talked to Mr Alam...
Let's hope for the best.
It's a lot of money... So...
Yeah...
I'll go check on your Dad.
Fix an appointment for tomorrow.
Alright, I'll confirm.
I've approved a loan of 500,000 for you.
500,000?
But I only asked for 200,000.
I know, but it won't get you anywhere. Not in this day and age.
I think you're going to need all of it for your father's treatment.
But sir...
It's a big sum... I don't think I'll be able to pay it back...
Don't worry.
It's not like you're quitting the job.
You can pay it back in parts.
Here.
Sign here.
I'll transfer the amount to your account today.
But it's blank, sir...
Ah, yes... I had it made rather quickly... Nothing we can't work out later, I'm sure?
Go on.
Translation: J. Mir © GEO TV