He used to ask everyday;
Then, he'd ask
Whenever he'd see her picture,
Or anything related to her;
He's stopped asking now.
It was he who said to me one day,
'Get me into boarding school, Papa'.
'I'd come to you'
'When I've grown up'.
That was the day I felt he'd grown up.
Just look at your condition!
That's what I'm thinking.
A few months of grieving is enough.
I'm thinking I'd change my condition.
Please, help me, will you?
Do you need money?
Yes.
How much?
Some 200 to 250 million?
Perhaps even more.
Not on loan. Personal.
What'd you do with it?
I'm thinking what I'd do without it.
I want to be a businessman, Mr Matin.
Have everything I want -
Friendship, loyalty, love...
Everything sells; I'll buy it all.
You're angry.
-No.
I'm fully in my senses.
She opened my eyes as she left.
I swear, Mr Matin,
I was not angry with her one bit when she was leaving.
I was angry with Shehwar.
You bugger, if you've actually fallen in love,
Talk about someone
Who'd stay true to her vows of loyalty.
It is not in a woman's nature to be disloyal,
And one who's disloyal is unworthy of being called a woman.
See for yourself.
Good men
Don't make this world go round.
Good women do.
You only need to move on.
Surely, you'll find someone
Who'd tell you, 'I make this world go round'.
Could I get the bill, lad?
I'll pay.
Leave it be, Mr Matin.
What does it matter?
Just think about how one could get 200 million.
240 Rupees, sir.
We'll meet again, Mr Matin.
Please, do think about it.
Good morning, Danish.
-Good morning.
Please, come and sit.
Please call Miss Hania.
-She's coming.
She's coming.
-Okay.
You may leave.
Right...
Mr Danish...
This is your son's progress report...
Exams...
Average marks - 42%.
Attitude...
'Does not cooperate'.
Games, sports...
'Does not participate'.
Student interaction...
Zero.
May I come in?
Please, come in, Miss Hania.
Please, sit.
Good morning.
This is Miss Hania. She's in charge of Rumi's class.
And he's Rumi's father, Mr Danish.
Yes, I'm his father.
First, I'd like to know why you've chosen to get him into boarding school.
Because he'd suggested it himself.
God...
He suggested it to you?
And you agreed?
How many children do you have?
Just Rumi.
He suggested it, and you got him into boarding school.
I think I was wrong...
Wasn't I?
And I think he won't able to continue in this school.
No -- surely -- please...
With respect, sir,
I think he has a problem.
He'd pull a long face when you talk to him, sits all alone in recess, and homework?
He'd pull a long face when you talk to him, sits all alone in recess, and homework? Always incomplete.
He doesn't answer when you ask him,
And thinks for long before saying anything.
Mostly, he just goes on thinking. He never says anything.
Please --
Give him one chance...
Just one chance.
-With all due respect, sir,
It's affecting the other students very much.
In fact, a few of them have even said
That they're afraid of him.
Why are they afraid of him?
Is he the Dracula or something?
No...
He's absolutely normal.
Intelligent.
There's just been -- some problems -- and he's been behaving like this because of that.
Just give him one chance; I assure you -
If he didn't improve,
I'd withdraw him from here myself.
Alright,
Please ask his mother to come and state her committment.
I can give him a chance.
How would I ask his mother?
She's divorced me and left the country.
How'd you have her commit?
I'm sorry...
The thing is,
I can't hear anything against my son.
He's my son.
Look,
I know he's very intelligent.
He's just grieved about being separated from his mother,
That's why he's been performing like this.
I'll meet him today,
Talk to him,
And if he promised me, you'll see,
He'll be fine.
His results will be good, too.
It's okay, Mr Danish.
We understand.
Take your time.
It's okay.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
And I'm sorry again,
I --
Spoke a bit too loudly.
-No, it's okay.
Okay,
Good day.
Papa!
Your Principal had called me.
I know.
And your class teacher...
She said that you can't continue in this school.
I've seen your report card.
Exams? Only 42%.
Attitude? Not satisfactory. Debates...
You don't participate...
Interaction? Zero!
You don't talk to anyone, do you?
Don't answer questions when asked.
Do you know,
My grief is greater than yours.
A mother's a mother even after she's left.
A wife's no longer a wife when she's left.
Still, I go to office everyday.
Work hard.
Go home and cook myself food.
And what are you?
A coward?
Accepted defeat at the slightest scratch?
You didn't even think
That Papa would be insulted when he'd be called to the school.
Tell me, can't you continue here?
I was furious when I heard that.
I said to the teacher angrily, 'My son is very intelligent'.
'Give him one more chance'.
'He's grieving over being separated from his mother',
'So, he's not performing well'.
'Just give him a chance',
'He'll give you results'.
Was I wrong in saying that?
No problem.
One's got to say something to save one's honour.
Do you know,
I too, cried once out of this grief.
I felt like I'm a coward.
But then I thought that I've got Rumi.
Rumi is my strength.
But know what, you're my weakness.
Okay.
Come and give me a hug.
Don't take anything I've said to heart.
One can study at another school.
Go now, it's time for your class.
I'll come and get you on Saturday.
Wait!
Your chocolates.
Thank you, Papa.
Listen, Papa...
Rumi is not your weakness.
Rumi is your strength.
Don't ever cry again, Papa.
Maman's no longer Maman when she's left.
Good morning, sir!
Good morning.
Tea or coffee?
I'd like some tea.
In a moment.
I got very late...
No problem.
I'd gone to Rumi's school.
His Principal had called me.
Look at this envelope.
Guess what's in it?
What is it?
You've been promoted, Mr Danish.
By the Lord's grace, you've become a 17th grade officer!
Oh!
Just an 'Oh'?
At least be delighted properly, Mr Danish!
I'm delighted.
Very delighted.
Then, how about some sweets?
Get some, quickly.
Alright, my good man, over here.
Here.
Get me some sweets.
Please, sit, will you?
His progress report's not very good.
As in, it's very bad.
And the teacher's said
That he's not normal.
Then?
Then, I met him.
I talked to him.
He's promised to me as I left.
Mr Danish,
You've been promoted.
What good is that, Mr Matin?
I mean, I --
I'm happy.
I've been promoted...
But his teacher's said...
That he can't continue in the school.
Yes?
No, I'm not in such a hurry.
Yes, I go to bed by 10 to 11 p.m.
Sometimes 12.
Okay.
Goodbye.
Mr Matin!
Haven't you had lunch?
I'd been waiting for you.
I've gotten habituated to your company.
Are you buying something?
No, I'm selling something.
What?
My flat.
But --
But you used to say...
-I used to say a lot, Mr Matin.
But what does it matter if a man like me says anything?
Why are you selling your flat?
I kept on thinking when I got back after meeting you last night.
I remembered something someone had said once -
'In business, your first hundred thousand is the only thing that matters'.
But that's an old saying.
So, I figured that it's the first 10 million that matters,
And I thought I'd earn the first 10 million by selling the flat.
But that bugger's just giving me 7 million.
You'd start a business?
Didn't I tell you?
But Mr Danish,
One can't run a business along with a job.
I'll quit my job.
Mr Danish,
You've just been promoted today,
And now you're saying...
-Why are you getting so emotional, Mr Matin?
What do you think?
That I won't be able to live if I left this job?
Don't worry, then.
I'd live on.
But it'd surely kill me, Mr Matin, if I didn't get
My 250 million.
Sometimes, it's nagging me,
And sometimes, making me weep.
Forsake your place in my heart,
Gently and stilly;
Bless you with this parting,
Fare thee well.
Sometimes, it's nagging me,
And sometimes, making me weep.
How are you, Mr Diwan?
What?
You're such an amazing partner!
And you're such a --
What?
Why aren't we getting married?
I want to call you 'hubby' too.
Why are you laughing?
Have you grown tired of love?
Look at what you're saying!
I've only just realised what love truly is.
Tell me, when are we getting married?
Mind if I ask something?
Not at all.
Why do we want to get married to live together?
Why can't we just love and live together?
You're kidding.
No.
I'm not kidding.
It's a million dollar question.
We've been together for so many months,
We've toured all of Europe,
And it never felt for once
That one needs to marry to love.
Have you ever felt my love lacking?
Tell me.
Am I ever tired of you?
That's alright,
But --
-Why this 'but' when it's alright?
Why do you think like lower-middle class women,
Who'd pray to get married
To get to love?
Shehwar...
Didn't I just say...
Let there be just love...
When it seems important that we get married, we would.
And sweetheart,
There are divorces in marriages,
But none in love.
Sorry, I got a bit late.
It's no problem.
Has your anger cooled off?
Anger?
When was I angry?
You were
Talking about quitting the job the other day. I got a bit worried.
I didn't get worried at all.
I've talked about the flat.
The old dealer was tricking me.
The other one got me 8 million.
Sold the flat?
No.
Not yet.
I will, 10 days later.
I'd get the advance tomorrow, and resign after 10 days.
Please think again, Mr Danish.
I used to think too much, Mr Matin.
But now, I feel
That He gets angry when you think too much.
He just wants man to keep on working.
I'd like some tea.
And two aloo parathas.
Where'd you live after selling the flat?
I'd rent a flat.
And where'd you work?
I'd think about it when I've got the money in my account.
May I suggest something?
Why, sure, that's what I come to you for!
Please don't resign until your business is up and running.
You've grown old, Mr Matin.
Cowardly.
If one started a business thinking it'd not go well,
It would never go well,
And if I'm dishonest with my job,
I'd be earning what I don't deserve.
I can't do that.
I'd dive right into the sea, confident that I can swim;
I'd never wear a life jacket.
I'll get your parathas.
Alright.
Get married.
Why?
One needs a woman behind him to move on.
Do you believe that?
No one could believe it more than me.
But I don't.
Even if it is true,
I'll prove it wrong.
You should see a psychiatrist.
One often loses
One's battles because of anger.
She's left,
Just bless her.
If she gave you grief,
If she gave you grief, she also took your grief along.
Give her a salute and say,
'If you aren't mine, my dear',
'Know that I'm not yours either'.
Eight years ago,
When I said I'd 'met' my wife, I hadn't actually met her.
It had struck me down, and I realised that I'd fallen at her feet.
Her husband was with her.
Still, it pained her to see me hurt.
She picked me up from the footpath, supporting me,
And cleaned the wound on my feet.
Meanwhile,
Her husband had gone to get medicine for my wound.
I asked her,
'Didn't you feel the slightest hatred for me'?
She smiled,
And said,
'One pities the disloyal, Matin Ahmed',
'One doesn't hate them'.
Cigarette?
Her husband called the day before she died,
And said, 'Samina wants to talk'.
I talked to her.
She was gasping for breath.
She asked me,
'Does one ever get punished for disloyalty, Matin Ahmed'?
I said, 'Yes'.
She asked, 'How much'?
I said,
'Those who are loyal'
'Wouldn't even get so great a reward'...
She said,
'Alright, Matin Ahmed',
'I forgive you'.
Her husband told me later, 'She asked me'
'Before she died',
'"When I said I'd forgiven Matin Ahmed, do you think I'd actually forgiven him"?'
Have your parathas. I won't be able to eat.
Could I get the bill,
My good man?
Bye, Mr Matin!
Mr Matin!
Quickly! Come here.
You too!
You too! Hurry!
-What happened?
It's the good sir!
Get him out quickly!
Here.
Quickly!
Careful there!
Mr Matin!
-What happened?
Careful!
Sir!
Are you alright, sir?
He's a very good man.
Right...
He's had a heart attack before.
At our bistro.
He used to smoke a lot back then, too.
Why don't you inform his family?
Do you know their details?
No.
Are you with Mr Matin?
Yes.
-Who would you be to him?
He's alright, isn't he?
He hasn't come to yet. Who are you to him?
I'm his friend and colleague.
Alright. Submit your ID card at the counter, and take his cell phone and purse.
Okay?
-Alright.
Thank you.
He lives in Gulshan.
Call them, will you?
Who?
His family.
We'd called from his phone back then, too.
Look for 'My Daughter' on his phone.
Hello?
It's Danish here. Mr Matin's colleague.
You're his daughter, right?
Mr Matin's had a heart attack.
He's in the hospital's CCU.
Talk to her.
Hello?
Good evening.
Doctor,
How's Mr Matin?
Unfortunately, he's not good.
We're trying the last thing we could,
Just have faith.
Who's with Mr Matin?
Yes?
I'm sorry,
We tried our best,
But he didn't make it.
As it pleases the Lord...
Please, be brave.
Dad!
English translation: J. Mir