Who's with Mr Matin?
Yes?
I'm sorry,
We tried our best,
But he didn't make it.
As it pleases the Lord...
Please, be brave.
Her husband called the day before she died,
And said, 'Samina wants to talk'.
I talked to her.
She was gasping for breath.
She asked me,
'Does one ever get punished for disloyalty'?
I said, 'Yes'.
She asked, 'How much'?
I said,
'Those who are loyal'
'Wouldn't even get so great a reward'...
She said,
'Alright, Matin Ahmed',
'I forgive you'.
If you're still awake, why aren't you answering your phone?
Phone?
Did you call?
Yes.
No?
It didn't ring.
Anyway, please, come.
Here.
The battery's dead...
But it was ringing just now.
You must've been somewhere else.
The thing is, a very close friend of mine passed away so suddenly...
I'm very upset.
Please, sit.
Thank you.
I'm sorry but I can't offer you tea.
That will not be necessary, thank you.
Tell me, should they come to pay you the advance tomorrow?
Yes.
But it'd be better if
We made it the day after tomorrow.
He was a very dear friend of mine.
I'm missing him...
No problem; it's alright.
We'll make it the day after tomorrow. Please, get some rest.
Alright?
We'll meet the day after tomorrow.
And yes,
Once they
Make the full payment...
You do realise, right?
What?
You'd have to give them the keys and leave.
Yes. I know. I'd leave.
I can arrange something for you if you want.
I'll let you know the day after tomorrow.
I want to rest for now, Mr Jameel.
I'm very tired.
Sure, get some rest. We'll meet again the day after tomorrow.
Goodbye.
Okay.
May I bring Rumi over for a few days?
It's been a few months now
And I haven't even seen his face.
As if he'd come here!
His father would've made him your enemy over all these months!
He's not the type.
What?
I mean, he won't poison his ears.
I know him.
So, may I bring him over?
You don't mind, do you?
Why would I mind, mate?
He can come and live with you.
I'd be happy.
Just... He'd better not stare at me every moment.
Why would he?
They do.
Stepsons stare at stepfathers a lot.
He won't.
I promise.
Alright, I have no problem.
You can bring him over today.
Then, just call him.
Ask him to drop him here.
Call who?
Danish.
That's his name, right?
Goodness...
As if I'd call such plebs
For such trifles!
You have his number, don't you?
Yes.
Then, just call him.
Tell him, 'I'm sending a car; send Rumi with the driver'.
You can go too if you like.
Thank you so much!
Now, would you thank me for that?
You rule over my heart.
Reign like an Empress.
Don't ask for permission like the subjects.
Okay, I'm going to the office.
Here.
And why don't you ask me to come to office?
Would you rather come even now?
Alright.
Come to office
Once Rumi's left.
And yes,
Don't ask.
It's your office.
Mr Diwan!
Just a minute, Diwan.
Give that to me.
It's no longer your responsibility.
There.
Hello?
Who is it?
Who are you?
This is Danish's number, innit?
No...
This is my father, Mr Matin's number.
How's it possible?
This is Danish's number.
Honestly - who are you?
Shut up!
Who are you?
Whoever you may be,
Give the phone to Danish.
Or tell him that I want to meet Rumi.
Rumi?
Look,
I told you, this is not Mr Danish's number.
Please don't call me again and again to disturb me.
How many times do I have to tell you that this isn't Mr Danish's number? It's my father, Mr Matin's number. Why can't you just understand?
It's you, Madame!
'Madame'?
Who?
I'm the dealer, Madame. Khwaja Jameel.
I'm selling your flat, remember?
I'd called because I wanted to talk to Mr Danish.
Is he sleeping?
Do you think this is Mr Danish's number, too?
So it isn't his number?
Not at all.
Sorry -- Sorry, Ma'am...
6 p.m.?
Mr Danish?
Who's this Mr Danish?
Hello?
Hello...
Right...
A Mr Danish had called me from this number.
I, too, got a call
From a Mr Matin from your number.
Mr Matin?
It's Hania, Mr Danish.
Oh...
I think the two of you have identical cell phones.
Yes.
They're identical.
It seems you've accidentally given me your phone,
And kept Dad's phone with you.
Oh...
Alright, I'll come and give it to you in a while.
Okay.
Thank you.
Hey...
Danish is not answering his phone.
A woman's answering.
So?
Just go, mate. How many times have I told you not to ask?
Okay.
I hear you're selling the flat, sir?
Yes.
Why, sir?
I had to, mate.
Don't you have the keys?
I don't live here anymore.
I know.
The good sir had told me that you were posted in another city,
And wee Rumi had gone with you.
Rumi?
W -- Where'd he gone?
With you?
Where's Danish?
He just left on his bike.
When would he be back?
No idea. Sometimes, he's back quickly, but sometimes, he gets very late.
I'll be waiting in the car.
He's not at home.
Where are you?
I'm in the car, waiting for him.
Why are you waiting?
Just meet Rumi.
Or just bring him along and come.
He's sent Rumi somewhere.
Sent Rumi somewhere?
He's told everyone here that I've been posted in another city
And I've taken Rumi along.
He would've felt embarrassed to say his wife's left him...
The same old
'Honour' problem...
Well, no problem...
There is a problem, Shehwar.
Where's he sent Rumi?
Where would he send him?
What's the worst that a bitterly defeated pleb and a wounded husband can do?
He'll try to leverage his son to hurt you,
Or, more accurately,
Blackmail you.
What else can he do?
But don't worry.
If Rumi didn't meet you within two days,
He'll get a notice from your lawyer on the third day.
You'll see,
I'll blow the bugger to bits.
Come back.
Don't wait for him.
No, Shehwar -- please.
Just wait a while.
I'll come back right after meeting him.
-Goodness...
You're ruining such a fantastic evening.
Do you know,
I was enjoying thoroughly
Before you called?
At the slightest rustle,
I felt that you're back.
But now
My eager glances at every rustle would be wasted.
Okay, fine.
Wait for him...
Your phone.
Thank you.
Here's Mr Matin's.
Sugar?
No, thank you, I won't have tea.
How could I?
It's...
Just been three days...
I miss him so much...
I miss him a lot, too.
I was reading his diary today.
There wasn't a single one of its last ten pages that didn't mention you.
He'd even mentioned having tea with you at the bistro.
One teaspoon.
When you came to the school the other day,
You didn't mention that you
Were Dad's colleague?
I couldn't even imagine you were his daughter.
I'm sorry about that day.
Why?
That's what a good teacher should have done.
No compromise.
It's good.
Mehwish is your wife, right?
Was...
Yeah, about that...
She called today. I happened to answer.
Heaven knows what she thought about it.
I'm sorry,
But she's rather insolent.
Why
Are you selling the flat?
Don't be surprised.
Your dealer called in the morning. He told me about that.
And I'm asking you because
Dad was greatly worried about you.
He'd written in his diary, 'I'm worried about my friend'...
'He's in a fit of rage',
'And in his state',
'One is strong, but never sensible'.
Has Rumi improved?
Yes.
You were right that if he promised it, he'd get good results.
He's doing well.
In fact,
He now talks, laughs, and plays pranks and all...
Oh, those monkey tricks!
When I gave him a star on his hand the other day,
He said, 'Will you marry me'?
What?
I'm honest!
I said, 'You're too young, lad',
And he said, 'Just wait a while; I'll be old enough in time'.
Then, get married.
It'd delight my son.
I'll meet your wife someday.
I'd like to see
If one who could cheat her own son for her own self
Could look just like any other woman.
I'll take my leave.
As you please.
Bye.
Listen...
Don't worry about Rumi's studies.
He's my responsibility now.
I'll make sure he improves,
Even if I have to marry him.
Bye.
Good evening!
Evenin'!
-How are you?
Fine, thank the Lord!
-Who's in this car?
A guest.
For?
Mr Danish.
Oh, Mr Danish's guest --
-Wait, Monty.
Yes?
It's a lady.
Oh...
Good ol' Danish's here.
How are you, Danish?
Someone's come to meet you.
Over there in that car.
It's a lady.
It's Madame!
Where's Rumi?
Why are you here?
I had to come here because you didn't answer your phone.
I didn't have the phone with me.
I know.
It was with a girlfriend of yours.
Come upstairs. Then, we'll talk.
I'm not coming upstairs.
You'd have to, now that you're here.
Otherwise, there'd be a scene for everyone to watch right here.
Good evening, Madame.
Nobody here knows that you've left forever,
Or that we've been divorced.
And look at yourself, waltzing right in,
Almost as if to tell everyone that you're nobody to those who live in this flat.
Who am I to you?
Believe it now, it's all over.
Why do you want to hide it?
I won't hide it for long,
But if anyone here found out, I'd be embarrassed greatly.
That's how I feel.
Where's Rumi?
In boarding school.
What?
You got him into boarding school?
-Yes, he felt he's better off in a boarding school.
I agreed when he said so.
I want to meet him.
Why, sure.
He must be missing you, too.
I'd take him along on Saturdays and Sundays.
Where?
To my home.
No. He's not going there.
Why?
I won't let him.
You're his mother. Meet him whenever you want.
But I wouldn't like it one bit if he met that sort of people because of you.
'That sort of people'?
As in, Shehwar?
You're just creating a problem for no reason.
I thought I'd never see you now that you've left.
That's why I sent Rumi off to a boarding school
So that you can meet him whenever you like.
I meet him there, too.
Rumi's hostel is very good.
It's large,
And there's no problem
About calling, meeting, or even playing with him.
I play with him for hours.
He'd be with me on Saturdays and Sundays.
Didn't I just say?
He won't!
Never.
Besides, nothing like this was decided at the time of the divorce.
Remember, then,
You're the one creating problems.
I'm going to court on Monday if he didn't come tomorrow.
Court?
Are you out of your mind?
Remember, Mehwish,
Have I never done anything good for you in these 8 years?
It'd be better if you decided right away.
From now on, neither will I wait in the parking in front of your flat,
Nor hear your girlfriend's voice over the phone.
She's not my girlfriend...
She's Mr Matin's daughter.
Mr Matin passed away,
And we switched phones at the hospital by mistake.
Our phones are identical.
Whatever.
Aren't you sad at Mr Matin's death?
May the Lord give him Paradise.
Sit.
Danish, I don't want to go to court,
Nor make the headlines with this story,
So, it'd be better if you just agreed that he'd be with me on Saturdays and Sundays.
Never.
You'll regret it.
You'd spend every penny of your salary paying your lawyers.
Please, Mehwish...
He's mentally unstable.
He'd be furious if he saw you with Shehwar.
His progress report just a month ago was so bad that I was worried he may not be able to continue in the school.
He's just begun to get better.
Started enjoying things, having fun, playing tricks...
Please...
Please, do go and meet him,
But don't be adamant about taking him along.
If that's your reply, remember,
We're meeting in a few days in court.
A bitter defeat awaits you there, Danish.
Please, show yourself out...
Please show yourself out!
Out!
Y --
You're leaving already?
Where have you been posted?
Get moving.
Shehwar Ahmed, as in,
The Shehwar Ahmed of Shehwar Chemicals?
Yes.
So she's marrying him.
What do you do, Mr Danish?
I'm an officer of the Government.
17th grade.
How much do you earn?
About 65,000.
How old is your son?
6 years.
Right...
So you don't want that he should be with her at her place.
He won't live there.
Speak for yourself, Mr Danish.
I don't want it either.
The thing is, my son
Is very intelligent
And sensitive.
He'd be upset if he saw his mother with another man.
Such things affect his studies.
So,
Look for a middle path.
No, she's adamant that he'd be with her at her place on Saturdays and Sundays.
Then, just let him.
I can say from my experience
That it'll only be a matter of 2 or 3 Sundays.
He'd never tolerate his lover's son
Spending Saturday and Sunday nights clinging to his mother.
Why are you saying such things?
I won't let it come to that.
I'd fight him in court.
Mr Danish,
You'd lose if you chose to fight.
He'd hire the top lawyers,
And level accusations so low and base on you
That you'd be ashamed to be yourself.
Your son, being sensitive, won't be able to listen to any of it either.
And if you don't earn anything above your salary,
You'd be spending every penny of it paying your lawyers and on the court proceedings.
Don't look at the court.
Look at who you're up against.
And honestly?
A bitter defeat awaits you.
Here.
What am I looking at, Mr Rehmati?
Shehwar Chemicals' share
Has fallen by 2.25 Rupees
Even when the market's risen by 95 points yesterday?
If the banking sector's doing well, do you want me to start a bank?
I want to know the reason.
We're working on the report. So what if it's late by 3 weeks?
The company's goodwill matters, too, doesn't it?
No.
I want to know the actual reason.
Alright.
Meet me at 12 today.
What?
Why aren't you having your breakfast?
The same Saturday-Sunday thing?
Jeez, mate, get a grip on yourself.
Should I care about the business,
Or waste all my time with you at the court, just to fix that wretch?
You've threatened him, right?
That should be enough.
Didn't I tell you last night
That he'd cling to you every moment if he stayed here on Saturdays and Sundays.
What about me?
I don't have anything except Saturdays and Sundays.
And would you look at the state of the company!
I left home for two and a half months,
Only to find out today that the company's share has fallen by 2.25 Rupees.
As in,
I've fallen in the eyes of the stock dealer.
Alright, fix your mood.
You can call him here once he's grown up.
I'll give him a bedroom of his own.
But
He'd just be a bother for now.
He'll keep calling 'Maman' all the time,
And I'd be left looking at him.
As in, I'd lose both ways.
I'm adamant about it, Shehwar.
When he heard the threat, he said,
'Get out'!
He's so cheap...
Mr Diwan!
Here.
It's good if he's gone to a boarding school.
Go and meet him.
Take him in the car,
Take him on a drive, go shopping,
That's enough.
I'd like it
If you remained a lover.
If you act like a mother,
I'd feel you've aged 50 years over one night.
Alright, send her in. Thank you.
Alright, I'll come back later.
-No, please, keep sitting. I'd need your help.
Good morning, Ma'am.
Good morning. Please, come in. Come and sit down.
Miss Mehwish...
Please, sit.
This is Miss Hania,
In-charge of Rumi's class.
Hi.
I suppose we've met before?
No.
We've talked over the phone before.
So, you've come to meet Rumi?
No, I've come to take him along.
I'll take him with me when school's over at 1.30.
I'd leave him here before the evening.
-Of course.
Would you like some tea?
No, thank you.
Okay.
Have you got a permission letter
From his father?
Permission letter?
I'm his mother, Ma'am.
Of course, you may be,
But how'd I know that?
I'm meeting you for the first time.
Please call Rumi; he'd tell you.
If Rumi said you're his mother, I could allow you to meet him,
But I can't send him with you.
If he told you I'm his mother,
Why can't he come with me?
Look...
If you don't have a permission letter,
I can't send Rumi with you.
I'm sorry, but these are the rules. We have to follow them.
I'm surprised.
I'm sorry.
Call his father.
Ask him.
We can't depend on phone calls.
You know very well
That anyone can say anything over the phone.
Besides, just a few days ago, his phone had accidentally ended up with
Besides, just a few days ago, his phone had accidentally ended up with Miss Hania.
I need a letter.
A permission letter,
Or...
Or?
Or an order from the court.
English translation: J. Mir