You look so calm.
Have your tea.
I hear you've gotten married?
-Yes.
You didn't even invite me.
You wouldn't have come.
Why?
You know...
I'd punched you and all...
So you'd punched me, too...
I'd taken so many punches back then that I can't even remember
That you'd punched me, too.
It's okay.
You punched me, I took it...
We're even.
We're not even, Danish.
I'm in your debt.
You've changed a lot.
It seems you've got a nice wife.
Very nice.
And she's bought the flat. She's living there now.
I would've been delighted to meet you if you hadn't told me that...
I had to tell you, Danish.
She's put up a plaque reading 'Akhtar Ahmed'.
Please, come someday.
You'd be surprised.
The building has a new feel to it.
I lower my gaze when I see her.
I call her my sister when I talk to her;
I even said, 'Brothers can do anything for their sisters.'
She's been with my wife all day, praying.
She's looking for rites to perform.
My wife told me about one -
If she read it 7 times, blew over a glass of water thrice,
And drank the water,
You'd come.
You have to meet her.
She said to me, 'You've done so much for your sister',
'Please, go and ask him to come and meet me once.'
Just once.
I knew right then that she'd set me a difficult task.
But I made a promise to her.
I thought
That the worst that can happen is you saying, 'I'm not going'.
I'm not going, Monty.
That's alright,
And I knew you wouldn't come if I just asked.
But what about that rite?
She would've blown over the water and drunk all of it.
What about that, Danish?
Would you rather stand against the Lord's words?
You're scaring me?
No, Danish. There's nothing to get scared about.
There are many in the city who don't believe in the power of such rites.
Don't worry.
Nothing can happen to you.
Nothing can happen to her, either.
But something does happen to one
Who's seen her perform the rite in such pain.
One stops in his tracks to wonder...
I've had my tea.
I can swear to her that I'd met you.
And asked you to come.
Threatened you with rites, too.
But you didn't give in.
Which is why you didn't come.
Please, forget the punch,
Or hit back with one if you still remember it.
And then?
What else...
His tea had gotten cold.
He drank it all in one sip,
Shook hands, and said --
-You've told me about that...
Tell me what you said.
What could I say?
I was scared.
Hmm...
'Hmm', what?
When are you going?
Where?
To meet her.
When did I say I'm going?
I won't.
Why did you say, 'I was scared'?
I mean --
Sort of...
I -- was a bit scared, but --
-When one does get scared,
One doesn't get just a bit scared.
He's utterly scared.
He just says, 'I was a bit scared', so to speak.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Hmm...
'Hmm', what?
I'm utterly scared.
So, when are you going?
Shall we?
Don't go there alone.
Some dal halwa for you!
My first try at it.
I thought I'd treat you to it,
And, if you liked it, Monty.
Otherwise...
So I'm your taster, eh?
You'd try it on me before serving your husband?
Splendid.
Come.
He loved it too.
But I didn't know how to make it.
I've learnt only now.
Why didn't you learn back then?
I'd learnt to two-time back then.
If you're devoted to two-timing, you can't learn to cook for the loyal.
Please, sit.
I'll get you some tea.
I've longed to live today after months.
Monty came and told me that he may be coming,
And I took his word for it.
Since then,
I've been living heartily.
And
What if he didn't come?
I know he won't.
He considers the unfaithful as sinners,
And Dad would pay him a visit in his dreams if he thought about meeting a sinner.
Hi, handsome!
Hi.
Going somewhere?
Yes.
To Miss Hania's?
No.
To your Maman's.
Really?
Wow!
She wouldn't let you come back if you went looking so dashing.
That's what worries me, too.
I feel that I may not be able to come back if I went there.
Don't think about me.
I'm waiting two hours and coming there with the driver.
And take the ring off. She'd ask if she saw it!
Put it on when you're back.
Keep it with you.
You're fully in the mood, mate.
Do I look dashing?
Yes.
Alright, go now.
I'll change.
Okay?
Hey --
I was just coming your way!
He's coming, Monty!
Ask Ifrah to chant an incantation
To stop him from ever going back.
You'll ask her, won't you?
Alright,
I'll get ready -- Yeah --
Ask Ifrah to come. I'd need her help.
Come to me after two hours.
You don't feel like going, do you?
I don't.
But I've decided to go.
Because it'd delight both of you.
What about Miss Hania?
Don't worry.
Men are rather famously
Natural two-timers.
My Papa can't be a two-timer.
A compliment?
Yeah.
Shall I?
Yes.
Wait, Papa...
Take care, mate.
I can see you don't want to go.
I don't want you to go either.
But Maman...
She's my weakness...
There yet?
No. He's left.
He'd be there by the time we're done talking.
Is his heart a bit worried?
Yeah...
Same here.
I know.
That's why I've called you.
May I ask something, teacher?
Sure.
Do those who go to 'meet' like this ever not come back?
That's what Papa was saying.
He said, 'Come to me if I'm not back in two hours.'
Tell me, teacher, is it possible?
Yes...
It's possible.
L --
Listen...
Would you be coming to school tomorrow if it happened?
I will, sure.
Then, bring my ring back from Papa.
Going somewhere?
Yes.
Where?
Back to the home
Where I'd sprung up to here from.
Know what, Maham,
The likes of me cannot digest it
When they get respect out of turn
And vomit it all out.
Let me clean it now.
So,
You're taking just that?
I'm even ashamed to take this.
Something in it may be yours.
Could you check
If there's nothing of any worth in it?
It was the faith that was priceless, Shehwar,
That love, that trust,
That vanished with the slightest hint of betrayal.
Priceless goods cheapen
Where there's no love.
I want to apologise to you again.
But apologies won't quite do.
Divorce me.
No.
If I divorced you, I'd feel that I've still got the power.
No...
I wish I could say that an unfaithful man
Shouldn't even have the power to divorce someone.
You file for divorce.
I give you the right to divorce me.
May I leave now?
Sure.
Bye.
Wait.
Would you resign from the job?
No.
Fire me.
I'll work hard
As long as I'm on the job.
Should I drop you?
No.
I've booked a car.
Paying for a cab after years
Would remind me of my true place.
Sorry.
I've bothered you a lot.
No.
I've given you too much grief.
You thought I'd never forgive you.
I was afraid that you might forgive me.
Thank goodness
That we don't have a Rumi.
It's just you that I've ruined,
Or myself.
You've ruined Mehwish, Shehwar Ahmed,
And Danish.
I will never admit that.
No man ruins a woman like her.
The courage to destroy her own household is within her.
Dreams too big for her eyes do.
Such women don't see
What they've got.
All they see is what the others have got.
Such women are blind
And anyone can lead them astray in the name of helping them.
One doesn't have to be a Shehwar Ahmed to do that.
And yes,
If you ever meet Danish Akhtar, ask him to thank me.
I've shown him
That if a wife's got the option of another man,
The husband's got nothing.
Wait.
I'd gone to meet Mehwish once.
I gave her her money and said,
'I can give you the money',
'But not Shehwar.'
Tell me - why did I say that?
Tell me.
No idea.
I don't know either.
It just occurred to me.
Or maybe we're just that way.
Our Shehwar Ahmed
May be as unfaithful and stone-hearted as you,
Yet, we hold on to him.
We never give him to anyone.
Think carefully before going -
You're not getting the chairmanship back.
I can give you a car to go to the office.
You can even get a promotion.
I'll even take back the condition about the tiffin.
But I won't forgive you.
One more thing.
If you still want to leave, just go.
But remember -
I'll be filing divorce papers in the morning
And firing you by the evening.
Why are you trembling?
What do you think?
She'd seize his hand and take him along?
I was learning
That one should love like you.
Love with such loyalty
And pride
Made love seem something worthwhile.
But looking at you now,
I'm worried.
You're jealous
That he's meeting her?
Do you feel she could snatch him from you now that he's meeting her?
I'm not jealous.
Now that he's meeting her, talking to her,
It doesn't feel that she could snatch him from me.
I feel that he'd be snatched from me.
English translation: J. Mir