He's gone to the market.
He said, 'I'll get something to eat'.
For you?
I'm not hungry at all.
He's a proper character, mate.
I've never seen a man like him before.
Like what?
When he sat in my office, it seemed as if he'd kill me.
Don't even ask about his furious eyes.
After he heard the phone recording,
He was relaxed.
He cooled down.
He looked at me when the recording ended,
And smiled, saying...
She has such a beautiful voice.
Yeah.
She studied with me at University.
Know what,
I hadn't seen her face first.
The sound of her voice had startled me.
I turned back
And found her on one of the seats behind me.
She looked back,
And curled up, unsettled,
As if my gaze had pinched her.
I listen in on her at home
When she's talking to Rumi.
I call her from the office every now and then, everyday.
When she answers the phone
With a 'Hello',
I quiver for a moment.
But now,
Even her 'Hello' has lost that touch, as in --
Lost it for me.
Anyway, what do you think?
Do women two-time?
They do.
There are scores of examples.
Oh...
I used to think that only men two-time.
But
I'm noticing something -
When a woman two-times,
She goes the whole nine yards.
Didn't you get it?
I mean, she completely turns away.
Sometimes, I think
That she'd remember my name in the morning,
So that she may not slip and utter someone else's name.
Smile, would you? I'm talking about your name.
What have you thought?
I'm thinking...
Let me just grasp it...
Alright, tell me - When she went to Islamabad,
Did she agree, like, instantly, without any hesitation?
Yes.
She hesitated a bit.
But you know very well there's no hesitation in love.
She must be a bit afraid when she stepped inside the hotel room.
Leave it be... What are you talking about?
-No.
I'm just reassuring myself.
Yes.
She wasn't afraid.
But a bit nonplussed.
She must be taking a good look at the room.
She's never seen the room of a 5-star hotel.
I could never show her one.
Dad would come at my throat.
If I so much as thought of taking a bribe,
He'd stop and scold me.
Just a few days ago, I thought I would,
And even brought a million home,
But he created such a scene
That I had to return it.
But as far as I know, your father passed away almost 5 years ago?
Yes.
It's been four and a half years.
But if I think about doing something wrong,
He shows up in my dreams,
And slaps me right in the face.
You're not well.
No, I'm perfectly alright.
I'm just asking for my knowledge.
The thing is
That I'd just
Heard about it.
I'd never seen it before, M. Shehwar.
It's alright...
She's decided...
You can take her.
I'll go home and call you.
I'll tell you when you should come.
Take care of her.
Sure.
Bye.
Just a minute.
This...
This is mine; I'd borrowed this from someone.
Goodbye.
And I thought the two of you had struck a deal,
That he's taken money to divorce me.
Yes, I'd made an offer...
50 million?
Yes.
I think I'd said 50 million.
I'm surprised the money couldn't break him.
He didn't know how priceless you are in my eyes.
He believes that one can't name a price for one's love.
I say,
That, if anything, is what has a price.
The higher the price,
The greater the love.
And I thought you would've pitied him.
I did.
So much that I agreed to what he said,
And let you remain with him for another night.
He's here.
Okay.
See you.
Why were you ringing the bell?
Rumi could've gotten up.
I'd called first, but it was busy.
Why have you brought all of this?
Who'd have it all?
I've always been bringing so much for 7 years.
I do on this day.
This day?
Today's our last wedding anniversary.
Just 15 minutes left!
Take out the cake,
Light the candles, I'll bring a knife.
Why are you doing all of this?
You're insulting me, aren't you?
What are you saying, mate!
It's the wish of a crazed lover.
Please, fulfil it.
Stay here for a while now that you've stopped.
Take out the cake.
Take it out, will you?
They say one should keep one's trust
They say one should keep one's trust even if there is no love.
One more request...
Yes?
You'd keep smiling while the cake is cut.
Okay.
I'll go and change.
Danish, give me my phone.
I've never stayed up at night. I sleep even in sorrow. But I'm up tonight; I don't know why I don't feel sleepy at all... Or is it that I'm waiting for it to be 9 a.m.?
Just one minute left.
So, light the candles, will you?
Happy anniversary.
May you always remain happy.
Why don't you have something?
I'm starving right now.
I'll take it out.
Tell me where you keep everything before you leave.
Boot polish,
Brush...
Where you keep the laundry after washing,
And where you keep them after they're dry.
Don't you know?
I do, but...
I don't remember.
You remember, don't you,
That I even forget
Where I've kept the thread and needle.
I do remember the things in the kitchen.
I go there every now and then.
I don't remember anything else.
I think you hang the clothes out in the balcony to dry, don't you?
Yes.
And Rumi's clothes?
They're in the cabinet in his room.
Toys
And all...
And the spare keys?
I'll give those to you before I leave.
I don't really need them...
But you know, I'm rather forgetful.
They'd be useful if I forgot one somewhere.
Rumi has milk in a glass, now, doesn't he?
Don't tell me you forgot that, too!
Honestly?
I never remembered anything except you,
Thinking
That you'd remember everything else.
Ah, the aroma!
I'm starving! Why don't you have something?
Your phone's ringing.
Not mine; it's yours.
Oh.
It's mine...
Mr Matin!
He's started loving me, too!
Hello, Mr Matin!
Happy wedding anniversary!
Thank you. How did you find out?
I was surprised to hear it when you were telling someone else last year.
That's when I'd befriended you.
Today used to be my wedding anniversary too.
Oh...
Surely, your injuries are alright by now?
Yes.
They're better.
So, aren't you coming tomorrow?
I would, Mr Matin.
But I'd be a bit late,
Around 10?
It's enough that you'd be coming.
Take care.
Likewise.
Goodbye.
Mehwish!
It was our wedding anniversary today.
He was celebrating it.
-What?
Don't tell me the two of you cut a cake too!
Of course.
He'd brought a cake.
I didn't even remember... He asked me to cut the cake when he'd brought it.
I thought, 'Alright, let's do it'.
This man's round the twist.
I felt so many times, too.
How would you live with that mad man?
There's still 8 and a half hours left.
Please, just come over, will you?
Me?
Ask him if he will allow me.
Please, come. I'm afraid of him.
I said...
I said... Ask him.
Okay.
C'mon, mate. Your food's getting cold.
I suppose he's unable to sleep.
That's just how one feels
When his girlfriend's with someone else.
Just think
How I would've felt the night
He'd taken you to Islamabad?
It was my wife, mate...
The thing is...
He wants to come.
Here?
The bugger must be itching to come here.
But what'd he do here?
He'd just sit around like a weed among the roses.
Alright...
Call him.
But ask him not to ring the bell.
Okay.
Hey!
Sit here and talk.
What's with the shame now?
He refused, didn't he?
No.
You can come now.
Sure?
Sure.
Okay, I'm coming.
Just 20 minutes.
Look back.
Have I ever turned you down?
How could I turn you down today?
Then, rouse them.
Tell them that we're having an important guest.
The room should be in order when I come back.
There shouldn't be a single cigarette stub around.
Take my packet away, too.
When would you be back?
By the morning.
What are you doing?
Cleaning up.
The house is a small one,
But one's got to maintain his image, mate.
The thing is, I'm poor,
The thing is, I'm poor, but I ain't dirty.
Here.
I'll do it.
-Hey!
Who works just before bidding farewell?
[Rukhsati = ritual of sending the woman off with her husband]
Sit down.
I'd be doing all of this.
I could as well start now.
Hey!
Sit down, will you?
Sit down, mate, sit.
Over here.
When will he get here?
He said about 20 minutes.
That means he'd be here in 10 minutes.
I'll put some water on.
I'll prepare the tea, Danish.
Why, mate?
Why would you?
Who'd prepare the tea tomorrow morning?
Who'd prepare the tea tomorrow morning? Tomorrow night?
I would, of course.
So, I would this time, too.
So, I would this time, too. And you'll see
That I'll make it nice and strong.
Your hand's bleeding.
Goodness...
Over here. I'll bandage you.
Isn't it enough that you've given me these wounds?
I have the bandages. I'll put them on.
What is it?
50 million.
They're divorce papers, mate.
I swear, they're divorce papers.
You may check.
Quickly, now, keep them in your bag.
He'd be here any moment.
Sorry -- I forgot to tell him...
Hi!
May I come in?
Please, come in, Mr Shehwar.
What happened to your head?
Had an accident.
We bikers have trifling accidents now and then.
Come.
Sit.
I'll get you some tea.
Here.
I'll pour.
-No.
Don't pour.
I won't have it if you did.
Sugar?
One teaspoon.
Thank you.
Sugar?
I won't have tea.
You'd have to.
You know I don't take sugar.
Ah, right...
I'd known that.
Know what, Mr Shehwar,
Back when I loved her,
And she loved me,
I rose up to 6 feet,
I was a bit stiff-necked.
What it is is
When his wife is loyal,
A man stands proud and tall.
Like this.
But, Mr Shehwar...
I've fallen in stature.
Of late, I've been feeling
That I'm no more than a mouse.
Anybody could trample me underfoot.
The relationship between a man and a woman is strange, Mr Shehwar.
As long as she's only got eyes for you,
She raises you to godliness;
The moment she turns her gaze away, she separates you from God.
I can understand your sorrow, Mr Danish,
But the times have changed now.
It happens.
Women realise after getting into it
That their old love was a wrong decision.
At such moments, men like us should help them,
And bid them farewell like you are.
[Rukhsat = sending the bride off with her husband]
But of course, I'm bidding her farewell.
I've divorced her.
That's great.
Don't say that, Mr Shehwar.
I'd feel
That 'great'
Is a bland word we throw around just about anywhere.
Plundering someone's life-savings
From the rubble of his home...
Surely, that can't be 'great'.
I'm going to the room.
-How can you go to the room?
I've handed you the order of your release from that room.
You can't go in there.
So, what was I saying, Mr Shehwar?
I don't know... You were saying something...
-Yes!
You were saying that men should help
Those women who want to escape the shackles of love,
Those who realise later on
That they'd made a mistake.
So, remember, Mr Shehwar,
I've helped.
I've packed her things too.
Just a moment.
Here's the bag.
Nothing that's hers is left...
Nothing that's hers is left... Except Rumi.
I would've liked it if you'd had tea, Mr Shehwar.
No, thank you.
You won't have tea either?
No.
Then, get going. Why are you standing here?
Teach me your ingenious skill
Of forgetting as you leave;
Come, I'll leave you at the door.
Efface every trace of your memory
Come.
From my life, now that you're leaving.
Please, Mr Shehwar, come.
What does it matter if it's 9 a.m. or 2 a.m.?
As nothing more than a formality, if nothing else,
Turn back and glance at me for a moment;
Goodbye.
Fulfil the vows of our bond for once
As you break it.
You seem to be a rather intelligent businessman,
But you surprised me when dealing here.
You were offering me 50 million
For a woman who's not even worth spare change.
Forsake your place in my heart,
Gently and stilly;
Bless you with this parting,
Fare thee well.
Sometimes, it's nagging me,
And sometimes, making me weep.
I had thought that with you by my side,
What else could I ever wish for
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
I had thought that with you by my side,
What else could I ever wish for
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
What does it matter, if I don't have
Anything in this world;
I was under the misbelief
That I had you;
But, from you, I have learnt
That, even in love,
One could rather betray
One could rather repulse.
It was just yesterday
That your hand was in mine,
And your heart beat in mine;
These ebrious eyes
That have altered beyond recognition -
There was a time when I was their ardent devotee.
Should you chance upon me somewhere,
Surreptitiously, turn your gaze the other way, and move away.
I have to live out my days
Without you
I am destined, now, to live out my days without you.
English translation: J. Mir