She didn't have her car, Papa. She'd come on a rickshaw.
She went back on a rickshaw, too.
It seemed like she'd come to say sorry.
Hello?
Watching TV?
No. I've just gotten home.
So, you haven't heard the news, have you?
What news?
The FIA [Federal Investigation Agency] have arrested Shehwar Ahmed.
His wife's snatched everything from him.
No comments?
No comments.
Alright.
Bye.
'No comments'.
You were right.
You've killed him.
He wasn't even delighted to hear that the man who ruined him
Is now behind bars.
You're wrong there, Salman.
Shehwar hasn't ruined him.
I have.
You can't work for me.
I've --
Partnered with Danish.
He sits in the same office, in the room just in front of my own.
But
Give me your address.
I'll try somewhere else.
I'll let you know if something works out.
May I stay at your place tonight?
Sure,
Why not?
No, Mehwish.
You can't stay here.
The grief I've seen on his face
Won't allow me to keep you here at my home,
Nor is my heart willing to be so kind.
I'm sorry.
If Salman had asked me before calling you here, I would just have refused.
For all that you've done, it's between you and the Lord.
But I swear by God,
You've insulted every woman out there who's loved.
Hey...
I've come to meet you.
I won't take too much of your time. I promise.
Thank you.
I was not myself the other day.
I said just about anything I could.
I'm sorry about that.
It's okay.
Thank you.
I've come to you because I think you can do something.
Like what?
That's what I'm thinking... Where do I start?
Is he marrying you?
It's just a guess -- I'm not doubting --
I just asked because I'd been wondering --
You answered the phone when I called Danish the other day, so...
I thought -- Perhaps...
I'd understand if you just said 'No' --
-No.
I knew it.
Know what, ours was a love marriage.
I used to think like him, too.
But I made some mistakes later.
I couldn't quite come up to his love.
He used to say,
'So what if we have a small flat'?
'So what if'
'I've just got a job to keep things going'?
'So what'
'If we don't have a car, or a big bank balance'?
'I've got you, Mehwish'.
'I don't need anything else'.
Surely, you didn't have a class?
No...
If I did, I would've met you after my class.
Oh...
So, I was saying...
I couldn't believe such love of his...
Today, I think
Why he wanted to stop me even after so much had happened.
Even on the day we got divorced,
He'd tried so hard to make me stop.
But I was already gone.
I didn't want to stop.
I admit that I was wrong.
But isn't it
Just human to err sometimes?
I won't believe that.
I don't allow a married woman
To commit such a 'mistake',
Much less a mother.
I wouldn't call it a 'mistake' if a mother did this.
I'd call it a 'sin'.
Don't men commit such mistakes?
I know scores of women who
Weep and wail for a few days, and forgive them.
They even accept them like they're squeaky clean!
My Dad used to say, 'Demand your rights from men',
'But never a share of their rights'.
So, do men have the right to make such 'mistakes'?
No.
I didn't say that.
I said that it's easier for women to forgive.
Why?
Because men don't give birth from their wombs,
Women do.
It is her mercy and generosity
That defines lineages.
At least that's my point of view.
You may disagree.
But what happened so suddenly? You were married to Shehwar Ahmed, right?
We never got married.
He betrayed me.
His wife showed up right at the time of the marriage,
And he turned out to be a fraidy-cat.
What is your name? Hania?
Yes.
Right, Hania,
So, I was saying
That it's for the better
That I've been punished for my sin.
You were right...
I've wronged him.
You've not wronged him.
You've wronged God,
For he used to entrust you to God when leaving you at home;
And you've wronged love,
Because love alone can give the courage to trust.
I need your help.
What did you say?
I said...
I need your help.
What good is asking for someone's help when your fight is against the Lord Himself?
And if you think that you've been punished for your sin,
Go and pray
To be saved from any further punishment.
Because as it happens, Mehwish, it is here that the punishment begins,
And He can be as infinitely ruthless as He is infinitely loving.
I've seen my Dad go through it.
Ideal: 18 Rupees,
Starwest: 9.80,
Nogia: 3.80.
And even Nasir Textiles has risen by 3.80 Rupees.
This share's fallen by 16 Rupees and risen by 0.10 only once in the last one and a half year, Salman.
Has he gone through the statement?
May I come in, sir?
Shut up, mate. Come.
Put out the cigarette, boyo.
Please.
What are you doing?
I'm paying homage to you.
You're the new pundit of the Stock Exchange.
My guide.
Look at this.
I haven't the foggiest about what's going on, Salman.
Don't think you haven't the foggiest.
Just look at how it suits you.
Who is it?
Tell me, who is it?
Be done with it and come out with it.
At least don't lie to your friend.
There's someone who's after you.
It impossible that a woman's not behind your success.
There's no one, mate. Really.
If I'm successful, it doesn't mean there's a woman behind my success.
No woman can ever be.
Then?
My son is behind my success.
He's my strength.
And Mehwish?
Get even with her.
How?
Fall in love with someone else and marry her.
Why are you laughing now, boyo?
I'm laughing at what you just said.
So, you haven't forgotten her yet, have you?
I forget her every day.
That's how I can sleep.
Haven't you seen
How I come to the office on time,
And I'm always fresh?
Alright, tell me,
If she came back, apologised,
Fell at your feet,
Talked about old love,
What would you do?
Riddling me this?
Yes.
A riddle of love?
A riddle of love.
What is it this time, boyo? Why are you laughing?
Let me tell you something from experience.
When love becomes a riddle,
It's no longer love.
And what you said about her falling at my feet, talking of old love...
That was the funniest part of it.
You silly bugger,
If you have to call it 'old love' like this,
Know that it wasn't 'love' in the 'good old days' either.
She
She wants to apologise.
She regrets it a lot.
Mehwish?
Yes.
I swear, her condition's really bad.
She doesn't have a job or a place to stay.
She's ruined,
Helpless and hopeless.
Where'd you see her?
She'd come to my place.
She wanted to stay there for the night, but Ayesha refused.
Oh.
Could you forgive her?
Sure, why not.
Just ask her to ask forgiveness.
Right.
-What are you doing?
Calling her, of course.
-No.
Wait.
Riddle me this - would it solve her problems if I forgave her?
Obviously.
Then, don't have me talk to her.
Just call and tell her
Just call and tell her that I've forgiven her.
By the Lord, I've forgiven her.
She'd come to meet me today.
Who?
Mehwish.
Splendid.
Why?
Tell me.
Why had she come to meet you?
She felt
That there was something going on between us
And that I may marry him...
What?
Well, one can venture a guess...
The other day,
When she'd called Danish, I'd answered the phone.
We know why I'd answered his phone.
What did you say?
I said, 'No',
'It's nothing like that'.
Even if it is, how is it her problem?
One can't even control the man one's got.
She hasn't even got him anymore.
What are her fears about him?
Actually, she's disturbed.
Shehwar's left her.
The poor woman's come back humiliated.
He betrayed her.
'Poor woman'?
In that case, the 'poor woman' must be very sad.
She's been so unfortunate...
Her heart's broken...
'Poor woman'...
Be done with it, Watira.
Don't mock someone like that.
Be done with it, will you?
'Poor woman' is not such a worthless expression that it'd be okay to use it for Mehwish.
You're a teacher, mate.
Don't you feel ashamed when calling her a 'poor woman'?
Looking at her, I feel mercy for her.
She wanted to cry so much before me,
But she couldn't.
She must be thinking
Why she's crying after all this time.
Please, Watira.
I was actually pitying her.
Danish wouldn't have answered her call, right?
No.
She never called him.
When I asked her, she said, 'How could I call him'?
She would, now.
Why?
Jeez, mate,
She'd come to check on you.
Now that she knows
That you're not in the way,
She'd call him.
You'd taken the SIM out of Dad's phone
To clear her way, right?
So she can go straight home,
And Danish can pull her into an embrace, saying,
'Where were you all this time, Mehwish'?
'I've been waiting for you'.
So,
Your job's done.
But you'd better stand firm, too.
Even if you fall in love with him,
Never install Dad's SIM in his phone.
As if I'd fall in love with him.
Splendid. How and when did you think that?
When you took the SIM out,
When you laugh like that at the mention of 'love',
And how you quieten after laughing, like right now.
Well,
It's good that you did what you did.
Trampled your heart to help a grieving person.
You let her go to him.
But promise me,
If he turned away and came to you,
Don't say to him,
'I don't love you'.
You'd be losing on a lot.
Listen!
For now, sit back and think.
Tell me later.
Hello?
Danish...
Yes, it's me. Who is it?
So you've deleted my number, too?
Mehwish?
Wh -- What happened? Why are you crying?
How are you?
I'm fine.
Do you want to talk to Rumi?
No.
I want to talk to you.
Sure.
Go on.
I want to meet you.
Please, don't do that, mate...
I won't be able to do that.
W -- Why?
I've spent five months telling myself
And getting myself to believe
That I can't meet you now.
Can't even call out to you now.
Can't say, 'Mehwish',
'This button's fallen off my shirt'.
Danish...
Please, Mehwish,
Don't say my name like that.
I'd feel
That you're somewhere around here. With me.
No -- You're nowhere...
I never thought that I'd ever see you again.
That you'd come to meet,
And leave again.
I won't leave.
And if I did, grab my hand and stop me.
I swear by you,
I won't.
I'd stopped you.
I'd said, 'Please don't go'.
I'd sworn too.
Don't you remember?
That's all I remember.
I'm scared ever since.
'Don't go'... I don't say that to anyone.
Nor do I say that the one who's gone will come back.
But I still remember you.
I miss you sometimes.
I miss you very much
When one proudly talks of love, or the vows of loyalty in love.
Bye.
Of vexed hearts,
The path is straight
Never is it
That they look back.
The strands of love,
The bond of loyalty
Once broken, can never be mended
To meet you once is all I ask for
Meet my gaze for once, and move away.
Hi.
What are you doing in the kitchen?
Hello. Brewing coffee for you.
Brimming with love for you.
Brimming with love, or are you fearing me?
That's how it is, Salman.
One bad woman
Insults ten good ones with her deeds.
That's why I'd refused to let her stay here for the night.
I don't even want to be in the company of the disloyal.
Shut up, mate, what are you saying!
But
You're right.
I believe there aren't many women like Mehwish.
But when you've met one, you grow to suspect many.
Innit?
Anyway,
What did you do?
I've fit her in.
Got her a job.
She's got a room in a working women's hostel, too.
I wanted to give her some money, but she didn't take it.
And when I got up to leave, she seized my hand and said,
'Help me be forgiven'.
Did you talk to him?
Yes.
I did.
Did you talk about forgiving her?
He didn't agree, did he?
He agreed immediately.
He said, 'Just tell her I've forgiven her'.
'By the Lord, I've forgiven her'.
Then, he picked up his bag
And left.
Know what, I was with Mehwish all day.
Even had lunch with her.
She used to be my best friend at the University.
I used to skip breakfast to have breakfast with her.
Don't you remember
That that's why we used to be together at the canteen in the morning?
I was so fond of her,
But I felt today
That I'm a Brahmin having lunch with an untouchable.
When I got up, she said, 'Please, sit a little longer',
And when I did, she started asking odd questions.
Such as?
She said,
'Someone had deceptively trapped my love',
'But what happened to Danish's love'?
What does it mean?
As in, 'Why doesn't Danish love me anymore'?
Blimey, why should he?
As if love is some duty!
So, you can run away,
And he should just keep chanting your nam --
-Just a minute, Salman.
Pay attention to her question.
You won't be able to answer it in anger.
Just try to understand what she's saying.
She's saying
That Danish will always honour his vows of love.
Why is she saying that?
Hold on.
Remember -
In the beginning, it didn't matter to you what I said in response to your messages.
Do you remember?
I'd even complained against you in our third semester.
Told the Dean, 'I'm afraid of him'.
Showed him all your messages, too.
Ah, that...
And the Dean had called me to his room and thrown the worst four-letter words he could.
And on the day of my wedding, he whispered, 'I'm sorry'.
Leave the wedding be.
Just stop
At the time I didn't love you.
Remember that you'd told Danish,
'So what if she doesn't'?
Remember?
Yes.
You'd also said,
'I love her',
'And that's all that matters to me'.
Correct me if I'm wrong.
No.
You're right.
I'd said it.
Why?
If it didn't matter to your love that I didn't love you,
Why should it matter to Danish that Mehwish doesn't love him?
Know what,
You're very intelligent.
Ain't I?
Actually,
You're not.
You said I'm not intelligent?
Oh, do you mind it?
Sorry, mate.
Why did you say it?
Should I say it?
Okay.
Why did we
Get married?
Because I'd fallen in love with you, too, Salman.
But why was it necessary to get married?
I mean, wasn't it enough that we'd fallen in love with each other?
What kind of question is that, Salman?
I'd been listening to your speech for 15 minutes.
Did I say, 'What kind of question is that, Ayesha'?
Alright, go on.
What?
I've asked you. You tell me.
Why did we get married?
Because socially and religiously, we're required to get married to be together.
We're required, sure,
But it's not like love cares about this fuss.
Honestly,
Who've you been reading of late?
For many days, Danish,
And Mehwish, for a while.
I can tell you why we get married
Even when we fall in love.
We gather everyone that day,
And tell everyone that we've chosen each other,
And that we're not available for anybody else. Am I right?
Right, but --
-Let me answer that 'but' too.
'But',
'She made a mistake'.
She forgot
That she'd signed a social and religious bond to live together.
Or
She had to break that bond
For a better opportunity.
She broke it.
Made a mistake.
She'd apologise.
Sacrifice herself.
How would the world go on like that?
There are opportunities at every step, Ayesha.
Each better than the last.
If I took a liking to someone else,
Or you fell for someone else,
You'd meet me after a few days,
And say, 'I made a mistake';
I'd say, 'It's okay',
'Go home; I'm coming'.
My mistake would go on for but a few days.
So, Ayesha Salman Ibrahim,
How would the world go on like this?
Wow...
I'm just talking about the social commitment,
Or the religious bond.
I haven't even started about love.
Love is for the blind.
It's a game
Where one doesn't see anything except the one.
But suddenly,
If one of them started seeing someone else,
It opens the eyes of the other.
His eyes have been opened, Ayesha.
He won't be blind for Mehwish again.
How do you fall asleep without me?
In the beginning, I couldn't, Maman. When I went to the hostel, I'd stay awake all night.
My dear...
That's why my results were so bad.
But when Miss Hania found out that my Maman isn't with me,
She explained to me that there are thousands of kids in the world
Whose Maman is not with them.
So you've told Miss Hania that your Maman is no more?
I told her that she's fine,
But she isn't with me.
Does she meet your Papa?
No, they just talk over the phone.
Everyday?
No, just sometimes.
Now, they won't even talk over the phone.
Why?
Her phone's switched off.
I've been trying for two days.
Why do you try?
Nothing really, Maman. I like her a lot.
You don't like me, do you?
Not way -- You're Maman, after all.
Why don't you call me, then?
I'm angry with you.
And how long will you be angry with me?
Honestly?
As long as Papa's angry with you.
Why are you laughing?
Guess what happened one day
Back when we lived in the flat?
You'd left by then.
Papa came back in the evening
And called out,
'Mehwish'!
Have you ever called out to him like that?
No, right?
And then?
She started crying.
I know why she was crying.
Why?
Because she's begun to miss us.
She lives in a hostel.
I know.
Go and meet her.
Everyday?
Yes.
Everyday.
She said sorry.
She said before disconnecting, 'Tell Papa I'm sorry'.
You used to say that quarrels end when one says sorry.
She'd called you, too.
Yes.
Didn't she say sorry to you?
She did.
Then?
What?
The quarrel ends now that she's said sorry.
I'll tell you
When you're older
That there was never any quarrel between the two of us.
There was a bond between us,
Breaking which is a sin.
One says sorry
When one commits a mistake.
But there's no forgiveness
For a sin.
So, would she never be forgiven?
She'd be forgiven
The day I forget her.
Then, just forget her, Papa.
Please.
English translation: J. Mir