Sit.
I've come to meet you.
Just think
As if I've come to see
What someone who's been disloyal looks like
When betrayed herself.
I won't pick a fight
Or slap you.
Sit down.
Let's have a little chat like old friends, shall we?
Forgive me for the slap the other day.
It occurred to me later
That it was unnecessary to slap a woman
Who'd clawed her own face apart.
So, I'm sorry.
No.
You've come to meet me.
Otherwise, I thought I'd meet you someday,
Kiss your hand, saying,
'Thank you for slapping me'.
One who's been sleeping for five months is as good as dead,
Or, rather, one's conscience is dead.
Nothing less than a slap can wake one up then.
Would you like something?
You can get tea, coffee, or whatever you like.
No.
Nothing, thank you.
Why have you come, then?
It sounds odd to ask this,
But we were not supposed to meet.
I figured we ought to meet one last time.
I'd apologise to you,
You'd forgive me,
And I'd ask you what I could do for you.
Please ask the Lord
To forgive me.
I will.
Perhaps I already have.
That's why I've come.
Diwan told me after you were gone
That you've been with my husband for five months.
I saw that he was getting married to you that day.
He'd brought you on equal footing with me.
Have you been living with him for free?
You're so stupid...
I'm his wife.
Even I haven't been with him for free.
He gives me 5 million every month.
Even if I stay in America for five months.
So, I thought
That you've officiated as a wife
For five months,
Enjoying my status,
As my equal,
But you haven't gotten an equal pay.
Mr Diwan!
Give me the cheque.
This is a cheque for 25 million.
5 months' worth of equal pay.
No.
I don't want the money.
You can't get Shehwar Ahmed.
When a husband's wronged his wife,
She gets to have a ball with him for the rest of her life.
I won't give you that.
I don't want him, either.
Then, keep the money.
When one's fallen in love with such a man,
It's more a wish than love.
Fulfil your wish,
Otherwise, the punishment that is destined for you
Might as well kill you before it's over
If you haven't got any money.
Please,
Don't die so quickly.
Looking at you,
Many women
Would learn a lot.
Perhaps, then, it may even be
That you'll not have to beg someone else to ask forgiveness of God.
We'll never meet again.
Aren't you happy?
The portfolio's risen by 25%
In about 15 days
And look at your blooming expression, boyo!
I'm filthy rich, right?
Any doubts?
This
This doubt will remain, Salman.
She left me so poor
That that poverty
Never lets me get rich.
Please meet her once.
Rumi wants the same.
That's what we talked about over breakfast.
He's just a kid.
I couldn't tell him properly that I couldn't live without Mehwish,
And I haven't, really.
I'd died the moment she'd left me.
Dead in a way
That no doctor can tell by my pulse or eyes
That I'm gone.
But the truth is, I've been long gone by now.
I swear, I'd died.
But now,
I do get a bit of this feeling
That I'm alive again.
If indeed I am, just let me live, mate.
I'd died back when she'd left me,
And I'd die again if she came to meet me.
So, stop it, please.
This love is not your bleedin' stock market.
In love, when a value falls,
It falls forever.
What a splendid timing!
Timing?
You'd hide it from me?
Hide what?
Call her upstairs. As if you've got anything to hide from me.
Hide? And call who?
She's down in the parking lot, by your car.
Ask her to leave.
I wanted to stand here by your car for a while
And feel how you'd look in this grand car,
And marvel at how you've raced ahead,
Leaving me behind,
But Ayesha spotted me.
I would've left without writing this apology if she hadn't seen me.
I wouldn't have had to say,
'Sorry for showing up without permission'.
Hey there.
I talked to your Papa.
You rapscallion.
So you'd get me married to him?
You shameless lad.
Sorry.
Apologised right away. Fair enough.
Actually, he can't get married.
He would after he's forgiven Maman.
And why would he marry someone else if he forgave Maman?
You won't get it.
He says Maman would be forgiven
When he would forget her.
He can't bring himself to call Maman back.
You should marry someone else.
And there he was, sitting quietly in a corner. I thought I'd ask.
Why?
He's my student.
Do you have just one student?
Why do you only talk about him?
Because he's one of my favourites.
Put a sock in it.
As in?
His Dad's a favourite of yours, too.
There's something in you
That pulls you right towards him.
Are you touched in the head?
You've started using your brain in your heart's matters.
You're making a mistake...
Not good for you!
You!
Good evening.
Please, come in.
Do you know why I've come?
Pray tell.
Y --
You'd feel bad to hear it.
How would you know that?
Because I feel so.
I'd thought I'd say it right away
But I couldn't.
Try it now.
I'd say 'I don't mind it' even if I did.
You'd asked for tea.
Please -- when -- ask when it'd be ready.
Right here, sir.
Here's your tea.
I figure you've been listening in?
Please, sit, will you?
I'd talk before you.
Right...
I'd come to ask Hania to marry me.
J -- Just a minute. Don't get worried...
I'd just come to say it.
But I didn't.
I changed my mind right at your doorstep.
I felt that
I was just getting even with Mehwish.
I do want to, yes,
And I know
That it'd hurt her a lot
To hear about my marriage.
Not least because
She couldn't get married to her boyfriend.
Plus, I've gotten rich too.
You're listening, aren't you?
Yes.
So that's why I changed my mind.
I felt like I was just using you.
What?
I mean
I thought
That if you agreed,
You'd end up as just a means to get even.
I'm sorry.
I'm not good with words.
Back in my schooldays, I'd write,
'Bitter melon makes bitter foes'.
Hello?
Yes, it's me.
What?
Oh my God...
Salman!
Won't you wait for Papa today?
No.
Please give me my phone, Uncle Latif.
Sure.
Hello?
Just five days after Mehwish and I had started talking,
I said to her, 'Will you marry me'?
If I said the same to someone else,
I'd feel like it's nothing special,
That it's not heartfelt, that it's just a formality.
Samosas...
I've had enough already...
Here.
So, maybe,
If I came again,
Saying the same thing to you,
Please don't take it seriously.
The thing is, Rumi likes you a lot.
Thank goodness
He's not grown up, otherwise, he would've proposed to you!
If he insists, I may come here again.
And yes, I'd bring him along.
If I said, 'Will you marry me' to you before him,
Please say, 'No, no way'!
Just refuse.
So...
So, may I go?
W --
-I mean, I'll take my leave.
Alright.
-Alright.
And thank you.
Oh --
Please, allow me.
Over here.
Thank you.
Okay.
Good night.
Wait.
Please don't come here to say all of that even if Rumi insists,
And, even if you do come, please don't say, 'Will you marry me'?
I might as well say 'Yes'.
Bye.
What has she done?
She's slit her wrist.
Please don't come here to say all of that even if Rumi insists,
And, even if you do come, please don't say, 'Will you marry me'?
I might as well say 'Yes'.
My words had scared you.
I'm a tad possessive, innit?
So, I say things I shouldn't really say.
Obviously, you'd be afraid...
One lies when afraid.
A wife does, 100%.
I'll apologise to you when we get back.
And please, have no fear.
Just let me know if you're going to Islamabad.
Is everything alright there, sir?
Where?
At the hospital.
Hospital?
Who's in the hospital?
Don't you know?
Rumi's Maman.
It's very serious.
What?
Where's Rumi?
He left the moment he heard.
The driver insisted, 'Inform Papa',
But he didn't agree.
He said,
'Papa would rather not go there'.
Open the door.
Is she alive?
Yes, she's alive.
Sleeping?
Yes, sleeping.
Will she get up?
Hopefully.
Papa!
You haven't said a word since he left.
You didn't tell me anything.
There was nothing left to be said.
He was lying.
In that case, he was sinning.
Oh? Well, that's no proper reply.
I'm not giving the reply you want.
I'll just say that if he was lying,
He's committing a greater sin than infidelity.
There are two kinds of sinners in love -
The disloyal,
And those who weep for them.
She's come to.
Will you do me a favour?
Sure.
Take care of the cops.
And pay the bill if there's any problem.
Alright.
Thank you.
Maman!
Rumi!
Hello?
Hello.
Danish here.
Are you at the door?
No. I'm in the car.
Going home.
Oh.
I wanted to tell you that Rumi won't be going to school today.
Please send in a leave application from him.
For how long?
Not sure.
Just one day for now.
I'll let you know if any more would be needed.
Needed, as in,
What's the matter?
What it is is
His mother's in the hospital.
He'd be with her.
It may be more than a day.
Alright, I'll --
Did you come here with Papa?
No. With the driver.
Didn't Papa come?
Where is he?
He went back.
Did he see me?
No.
I want to meet you.
I've spent five months telling myself
And getting myself to believe
That I can't meet you now.
Can't even call out to you now.
Can't say, 'Mehwish',
'This button's fallen off my shirt'.
Alright, tell me,
If she came back, apologised,
Fell at your feet,
Talked about old love,
What would you do?
You silly bugger,
If you have to call it 'old love' like this,
Know that it wasn't 'love' in the 'good old days' either.
She's happy that he'd come,
Even if he'd left without meeting her.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Please, tell me.
I'm afraid, Ayesha.
Such repentance scares me.
It feels like
Leaving Danish was her mistake,
And wanting to come back is her sin.
Mistakes can be corrected, Ayesha.
Not sins.
You've taken a leave today.
You'd stay with me?
Yes.
Won't Papa mind?
No.
We'd gone to Murree once.
It was so cold...
My ankle got sprained while climbing the stairs at the hotel.
My foot hurt so bad.
Just a spot of blood, but your Papa was so distressed over it.
It was 2 a.m.
He booked a cab,
Got me in, and rushed me to the hospital.
Papa was not at peace
Until I'd been bandaged
And had fallen asleep.
That's what your Papa was like.
Remember, also, how he used to cook food whenever you had a headache.
He didn't know how to cook.
He'd only make an omelette.
You didn't have a headache either. You'd just say it.
The doctor says they'd discharge you by the evening.
Promise me, Mehwish,
You'll never do something like this again.
I promise.
Yes, Rumi?
The doctor says she's fine now. She can go back by the evening.
Good.
Are you happy?
Yeah.
Is Aunt Ayesha there?
Uncle and Aunt are here.
We'd all go and drop her.
Alright, see you at dinner.
Not dinner, Papa. Breakfast. Maman's asked me to stay with her tonight.
You're being unfaithful.
Please, let me be, Papa.
Just joking, Papa.
I love you.
I love you more.
See you.
Please wait here. I'll leave her inside.
Thank you so much.
I'll take my leave.
Alright. Thank you.
Call me if there's any problem.
Rumi's with me.
He'll handle everything.
Bye, Rumi.
Take care.
Hello, teacher.
How's your Mum?
Fine.
We're back from the hospital.
What'd happened to her?
Her wrist had gotten cut.
I didn't come to school either. Didn't tell about my leave either.
Would I have to pay a fine?
No, you won't.
Your Papa had informed me.
Are you at home?
No.
I'm at Maman's hostel.
Is Papa with you?
No.
Get me through to your Maman.
My teacher wants to talk to you.
Hello?
Hania here.
I know.
I thought I'd ask you when I got to know about your health.
Who told you about my health?
Danish.
He told me that you're in the hospital when he called to inform me about Rumi's leave.
I'm fine now.
I thought I'd come to the hospital to meet you,
But...
But?
I figured I ought not to.
He might've stayed a while longer if you'd come.
He came and left without meeting me.
You'd feel bad about it, right?
No -- Why -- Why would I?
I know him.
He's cautious about his relationship.
He'd think,
'This will definitely hurt my girlfriend'.
Sorry.
I just uttered 'girlfriend' by mistake.
I can't say 'wife' just now.
Bye.
-Uh --
What happened?
You're absolutely fine now.
That's all I wanted to know.
Bye.
She's suspecting me!
Who?
Danish's ex.
Mehwish?
Did she call you?
I called.
Why?
She'd been in the hospital after slitting her wrist. I thought I'd ask her how she is.
Who's she to you?
She's Rumi's mother.
And who's Rumi to you?
C'mon, Watira!
He's my student, mate.
Don't your other students have Mums?
You don't ask how they are.
Why always Rumi?
What are you looking at?
What's this guff?
It's not guff.
I'm telling you that you ought to be suspected.
And I totally believe
That if he actually showed up and said,
'Marry me',
You'd say right away, 'Sure'!
He'd never say that.
He hasn't got the guts.
This time, he wants to love someone who, besides love, would guarantee her lifelong loyalty to him.
There's no woman
Nor guarantee like that.
This time around, too, he'd just have to trust.
Understood?
Hi, Danish.
Hi.
How are you?
I've been awake all night.
Just freshened up and came here.
And why have you come here?
Because of her.
What is it?
Why is she looking at me like my Mum?
Sit.
Sit down.
Just listen to me quietly.
I've spent a few hours with her,
I've learned something, to say the least.
Slitting one's wrist and killing oneself doesn't hurt so much
As living on in repentance does, Danish.
She's suffered these wounds by her own hand, so she can't even tell the name of the one who's hurt her.
She must be dying a million times over every night.
And do you know
Why she's dead, but still dragging on?
She feels that you'd say her name and call out to her one day,
And bring her back to life.
I know that it hurts men,
But just for once,
Just once, try to muster the courage to forgive your wife's disloyalty.
There must be a man out there
There must be a man out there who would forgive the woman.
That's what I think, too.
I want to forgive her, too.
But then, I think of the Lord.
What do you mean?
Even the Lord does not forgive unfaithfulness to Him.
English translation: J. Mir