Sorry, mate.
Sorry.
Are you blind?
Even if I am, can't you see?
Get a move on once the signal's turned green.
Don't you know how to talk to girls?
Do you know how to talk to boys?
You think of yourself as a boy?
Have some shame.
Why are you arguing, old fella?
The fault is yours.
So I'm an 'old fella' to you, too!
Look at your own age! Get going.
Mind your own business.
So, what do you do
When she calls you at night?
Smoke a cigarette.
Not good.
What do I do?
Do you know what her tone's like?
You'd be inflamed to hear it.
It pains me to hear it.
Back when I didn't smoke,
I'd vent my anger on any employee.
I'd curse myself later -
'What was his fault'?
Just -- Don't answer her call.
I have to.
She's my business partner.
I want it all to end.
I want to live in peace, Mehwish,
Or rest in peace.
Please, sir.
Anyway,
This will go on at least until December.
Besides, December isn't all that far away.
-What's her problem?
If the business is doing well, why isn't life going on smoothly?
I know what the problem is,
But I can't tell anyone.
I feel ashamed to utter such a thing.
Okay, no problem...
What'd I do with it?
Right...
What'd you do with it?
What's this pill for?
I just have a slight headache...
I'm boring you, right?
No, not at all.
You may leave.
Go back to your room.
We'll meet again
When I get better.
No.
I'll leave only when you get better.
What are you made of, really!
Ordering around like this suits you.
Where were you all these years?
I'm afraid.
Why are you afraid?
I will develop a habit of it -
You telling me not to smoke,
Pulling the cigarette from my mouth and throwing it in the dustbin,
Seeing you,
Being with you...
I'm right here, with you.
You're doing a job.
Who knows, one of these days, he may get angry and stop you,
And you may resign and leave.
I would never leave.
He can't stop me now.
Hello?
Yes.
I'm going home.
It's 5.
I thought if you'd left before me.
Why, what happened?
I wouldn't be able to see it, mate.
There's something else I need from you...
Yes?
-But it's not a part of your duty.
Do it if you like,
Otherwise, just say 'sorry'.
Don't go anywhere.
I'm coming.
Satisfied?
Very.
Do you know
What I'd be thinking of on the way?
What?
Why you fell for a 'love marriage'.
Well...
Marriage can just happen,
But why did you ever fall in love with him?
Why is this first-aid box here?
Maman, Papa's shoes!
He's taken off his shoes here...
Danish!
Alright, to your room.
Danish?
Danish! Get up, will you?
Mehwish?
Where's Rumi?
In the lounge.
When did you come back?
And why is the first-aid box lying in the lounge?
I got injured at a crossing...
Alright, get up, will you?
I want to show you something.
Come on already!
-Where to?
There!
Do you see that car?
Yes.
Guess whose it is!
Whose?
Mine!
What are you looking at?
I'm beholding your beauty.
Hey!
What's this wound on your neck?
There's one on my elbow, and another on my leg.
But you didn't see it last night.
I bumped into a car at a signal.
What were you thinking?
About you...
You didn't message me when leaving,
Nor did you answer my call.
I got the text.
'Happy first day in office'.
Thank you so much.
Alright,
Take a leave tomorrow.
Why?
We'll go to Rumi's school
For his admission.
Did you make this tea?
Yes...
Surely, you'll go there when you've gotten your salary?
Don't worry,
I'll ask for an advance.
As in, an advance salary.
Our maid would be here today.
In fact, she'd be here any moment.
She was asking for 10,000.
She said she'd cook, too.
She'd cook, now?
How would I cook, Danish?
If I'm at my office morning to evening,
I would much rather just have dinner!
Right...
I hadn't thought about that.
What else would he give?
Who?
My friend,
Shehwar, of course.
What else could he give?
He's given me a good job, a car, a driver...
And the necklace.
You forgot about that.
He'd given that, too.
He had, yes.
That's it?
'That's it', as in?
If God is so benevolent to a woman, it feels proper,
But not when another man is.
What?
What are you saying?
Does it hurt you?
I don't know.
But it does hurt me very much.
I couldn't sleep all night.
I'd get up to look at you again and again.
Do you know why?
Just ask why.
Why?
I'd look at how invaluable you are,
Yet, someone wants to buy you
For a hundred thousand a month and a car.
Shut up, Danish.
It hurts to hear that, Mehwish,
It sounds as if I'm growing suspicious,
But I swear by you, I'm not.
I'm afraid.
I don't feel bad that you should dream,
But I don't like it when someone else makes you dream.
I'm doing this for Rumi.
For his future.
And it was just yesterday
That you thought his intentions aren't bad, that he's a good man,
So, why do you feel today that he wants to buy me with the job and the car?
My eyes had begun to trust him,
But my heart has not.
Then, go to a doctor and get yourself treated.
You're envying me, aren't you?
Even after five years, you only have a salary to make ends meet,
And that banger of a bike.
That's why you feel bad, innit?
Typical men's mentality.
A man always wants the woman to live at his mercy,
Or regard him as a god.
My Mum used to say,
'It makes me laugh if a woman suspects a man',
'But it makes me tear up if a man suspects a woman'.
And honestly,
Looking at you, I feel like tearing up.
What else would he give?
What else could he give?
He's given me a good job, a car, a driver...
And the necklace.
You forgot about that.
He'd given that, too.
He had, yes.
That's it?
'That's it', as in?
If the Lord is so benevolent to a woman, it feels proper,
But not when another man is.
Good morning, Madam.
Good morning. Please, come in.
Over there.
Good morning, Ma'am.
The boss was asking about you.
Alright.
He was asking you to come to his room first.
It's something important.
Alright, I'll be there.
What is this?
What is it, sir?
It says 'refused' here.
So you'd refused the request!
I hadn't, sir --
-As if I had!
You took the life of an old employee, and you're blaming someone else!
Sir, it was an issue over entitlement, and the HR --
-Get out!
Or admit it that your departmental procedures have taken a life.
A poor soul was dying because he didn't have
Some 7 or 8 million,
And you were busy
Thinking about his entitlement!
You 'saved' the company from a loss!
Listen!
All such applications will henceforth come directly to me.
Is it clear now?
Yes, sir.
Oh!
Come.
Why were you so furious?
What happened?
And why are you smoking?
I woke up to the news of Mr Mirza's death...
Who's Mr Mirza?
He was an old employee of the company.
A lung cancer patient.
He needed some 7 or 8 million for his transplant,
And these folks just sat about, thinking
Whether he's entitled to it!
The wretches!
By the time the application reached me,
Mr Mirza was breathing his last...
You won't smoke now.
Sir!
You aren't feeling dizzy, are you?
No?
Got a headache?
No headache, either.
Why are you wearing these socks, then?
What socks?
My good sir, look at your feet.
Your socks don't look alike!
Mr Matin's told me.
Hey!
It's you!
I just came back from your room!
That's the problem...
The room is as glum as I am when you've come back from it.
Alright,
Let's go out.
Where?
Have lunch, of course.
You're worried
That if someone saw us, he'd think we're out on a date?
Alright,
I won't have lunch.
I can't see you worry.
Just a minute.
Why won't we have lunch?
I'm coming with you,
And I don't fear anyone.
Yes, sir?
What could I have?
Lentils, vegetables, potatoes, queema, curry and rice...
Which vegetables do you have?
Mashed aubergine, ladyfingers and aloo bhujia.
Aloo bhujia.
With two rotis?
Just one.
One roti and aloo bhujia to table no. 4!
Haven't you brought your lunch today?
-No.
I used to bring lunch too,
And I'd get caught when I did not.
Everyone would find out I'd had a domestic.
No.
It's nothing like that.
I haven't had a domestic.
We've hired a maid.
I can't bring myself to eat what she cooks.
Oh...
Yes, please.
That'd be enough.
Thanks.
Welcome.
Didn't your wife call today?
She did.
But I got the news about Mr Mirza's death before that.
I didn't answer her call.
Sometimes, it feels like you're a little kid.
Angry over a trifle one moment,
Giving in the next,
Delighted if someone came along for lunch.
Not delighted, elated.
Has Rumi started school yet?
No.
Why?
I'll go tomorrow.
I've asked Danish to take a leave.
So you're not coming to office tomorrow.
I don't know
How long it'll take.
Talk to me.
One call would get everything done.
But I'd have to be there.
I don't think so.
Ask Danish to take a leave.
He could go and let me know if there's any problem.
He won't talk to you.
What is it now?
His eyes had begun to trust you,
But not his heart.
'Heart' --
Jeez, mate, what kind of a man is he?
He'd create a big problem!
He'll keep doubting, suspecting...
And stop you one day, saying, 'Don't go to office'.
What would happen to me if you stopped?
Don't worry.
I'll come.
I know, hearing your words,
Looking at your kindness,
One does suspect you sometimes...
But I can't put my job in harm's way because of baseless suspicion.
What kindness are you talking about?
Shehwar, I'm talking about him --
He thinks --
That each of the car,
The salary,
And the necklace you've given me is kindness I don't deserve.
He thinks I'm not worthy of any of it.
The truth is, he's not worthy of you.
He doesn't know what he's got.
Alright,
Don't get upset.
I'll do something.
He thinks I'm not worthy of any of it.
The truth is, he's not worthy of you.
He doesn't know what he's got.
Yes --
I'd bought some dresses. I was trying them on.
You've bought new dresses?
You didn't even tell me.
What could I tell you?
You've been quiet since you came back.
I wasn't quiet.
Didn't you see how I was laughing?
Show me.
Right...
Do you know what happened today?
I went to the office wearing different socks on either foot.
Everyone was laughing at me.
Here.
Lovely...
They're very beautiful.
They must be expensive.
-Yes.
They're branded; of course,
They'd be expensive.
When should we go tomorrow?
You can leave around 8.
'You can leave'?
Do I have to go alone?
I couldn't get a leave, Danish.
In fact, take it as if
I didn't ask for a leave at all.
Honestly, I felt embarrassed.
Asking for a leave on my third day at work, you know...
I didn't feel it was right...
What's the big deal?
Shehwar's a friend.
It's not as if his office was running only because of you.
You'd told me yourself
That both the parents have to be there for the admission.
There's some rule they have.
No, they don't.
They shouldn't have one, really.
Not every child's parents live with him.
One of them
May even be dead...
I've talked to the boss.
He says,
'Ask Danish to call me if he has any problem'.
You're still awake, aren't you?
No, I'm sleeping.
It's 2 a.m., Danish, this isn't a time for jokes.
I'm not joking.
I'm actually sleeping.
You're just bothering me, aren't you?
The light's on, and you're talking to me with your eyes shut.
That's how I've been sleeping of late, Mehwish.
I turn off the light,
Close my eyes,
And lie in pain.
It occurred to me today that I should leave the light on
And show you how much this new way of sleeping pains me.
What's the problem?
I want to tell you, Mehwish,
That I can't live a life supported by one Shehwar Ahmed.
Even if I needed him,
I wouldn't call him at the time of the admission.
Alright, don't.
Do you think I'm bad?
What you're saying is making me feel bad.
You're feeling bad, aren't you?
But what I'm saying is not bad.
Why do we work at an office?
Why?
To run a house,
Or to make it a home.
And what am I doing?
That's what I'm asking -
What are you doing, Mehwish?
I'm helping you make it a home.
And the man you call a friend but don't accept as one
Is silently supporting you.
But why is he supporting me?
Am I handicapped?
Had I gone to him, begging?
And why is he offering all his support in your name?
And he's signed you a cheque for five hundred thousand?
And you'd gone to another bank to open an account?
I'd gone there
Because that bank had issued the cheque.
We wouldn't have to wait for two days to transfer the funds now.
Why didn't you tell me about the cheque?
-Because of everything you're saying now.
Do you think I don't know you haven't been able to sleep for the last few days?
Or that you're troubled?
I'm troubled because you are, too.
You've created a very negative image in your heart about Shehwar Ahmed.
Worse, you've begun suspecting me.
Tell me, how could I tell you
That he'd given me a cheque for five hundred thousand?
But why?
He hasn't done a favour.
He's given me five months' salary in advance.
Whatever's gotten into you!
That's how he is.
He was ready to sign a cheque for 8 million
To save the life of a sick employee.
But
Before the 8 million was sanctioned, he died...
Your problem is that a salary of a hundred thousand,
A car worth around 2 million, and a cheque for five hundred thousand matters to you.
None of it matters to him,
Because he loves his staff with all his life.
Please, go to sleep.
Please, turn off the light.
Who looks after your son if both of you work?
The two of us.
But the two of you are at your offices.
You'd only have Saturdays and Sundays.
Yes...
So, that means
Your son stays with his grandparents?
No.
They're not here --
As in, they're no more...
Oh...
But we've hired a maid
To look after him.
You don't quite get it.
No, I got it.
You're talking about his home tuition, innit -
Who'll teach him,
Who'll check his homework, and the like...
I will, sure.
I'll teach him.
And my wife will, on Saturdays and Sundays.
And believe me, he's very intelligent.
He understands everything in a moment.
I guarantee you,
You won't have any complaints.
Your son's done very well on the test,
But my question is the same -
Why didn't your wife come for your son's admission?
I mean,
It's her only son's admission,
Mothers are usually very emotional on such occasions.
Yes, she was very emotional.
But
She couldn't get a leave from her office.
She's just started working.
So...
He's been admitted, right?
Yes, he's been admitted.
Is the meeting over?
Yes, at last.
Well, there's good news for you.
What?
You've been appointed as Secretary to the Board of Directors.
Seriously?
Yes.
Thank you so much!
We're going to Islamabad.
Everything alright?
It's a business trip.
How long are we staying there?
We leave in the morning and come back in the evening.
Okay.
So, talk to your husband today.
Talk about what?
You're going with me.
You'll be going with me wherever I go.
What is it?
That's impossible.
What's impossible?
He --
Won't let me go to Islamabad.
And with you? Never.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Look,
A foreign delegation's coming;
There's an important meeting.
It's very important that I go.
I understand, but I can't go.
He'd be mad with rage if he found out.
Don't talk about him.
What do you want?
In fact, what does your heart want?
Okay.
Call Mr Asim and tell him I'm not going to Islamabad.
The meeting's been cancelled.
Just a minute, sir, please.
I swear I have no issues.
I have no problem going with you.
But -- He's begun suspecting me.
He'd create a scene if he found out.
He won't find out.
We'll board a flight at 8 a.m.,
And come back by the 6 p.m. flight.
Just say that
You'll be late on Monday.
Say that
There's a lot of work to do in the office; there's an important meeting.
He won't have the foggiest.
Still, if it's not possible,
Call Mr Asim and tell him.
Just two more minutes.
Still two minutes?
You're very hungry?
Very.
'Sec...
It'll be ready in a while.
And Maman's here!
What's going on?
I'm making an omelette for Rumi.
Didn't he eat anything?
How could he? Nothing had been cooked.
Hey!
Didn't she cook food?
The maid left at 12.
She called,
Telling that her Mum's been rushed to the hospital.
She said she had to go.
And you said, 'Go'?
What could I do?
Her Mum was at the hospital.
Would I have stopped her here to have her cook?
Come here,
My sweet.
My son will sit here and have his omelette.
Maman's going to change and come, okay?
When did you come here?
I came back early.
So what are you doing now?
Preparing tea
For you.
Don't talk about him.
What do you want?
In fact, what does your heart want?
He won't find out.
We'll board a flight at 8 a.m.,
And come back by the 6 p.m. flight.
Just say that
You'll be late on Monday.
What about Rumi's admission?
-Why didn't you inform Asim.. ? He got the booking done.. Why?
Yes, Mehwish?
When does the flight leave?
9 a.m.
And when's the return?
6 p.m.
I mean, when would we land in Karachi?
Around 8 p.m.
Okay, thank you.
You're welcome.
Bye.
English translation: J. Mir