English translation: J. Mir
What's this, sir?
300, not 200.
300 for what?
We'd agreed on 200.
We had, sir,
But we hadn't agreed that you'd stop for half an hour for some chaat [snack].
Half an hour?
More like 5 minutes!
You look like you're a learned man, sir...
What do you mean?
Why are you lying, sir?
What?
It took your son ten minutes to relieve himself.
What are you saying?
-Just give him 300, will you?
Don't create a scene on the road.
Thank you, sir.
Hey!
And where are you off to?
Milord!
I'm no Lord, mate!
-But you are, to me. Sit.
Bye!
C'mon! I'm starving!
Never mind!
There.
Right here.
Alright.
Here.
Have this.
We'll have dinner later in the evening.
Done.
Hey!
Ask where we'd have dinner.
At home?
No, sir.
We're eating out.
Why?
Look at how much we've spent...
Don't be such a Scrooge.
I'll manage.
Alright.
-Here.
Fine.
We're eating out.
By the way...
What?
Nothing.
Look at this one.
Here comes the food...
Come here. Sit down, quick.
Yummy!
Here.
Sit down.
Have him stop here.
Why?
What is it?
I'll show you something.
Yes, but...
I'm not asking you to buy me anything.
I just want to show you something.
Please stop it here.
Right, stop here.
Come on. Just a minute!
C'mon!
Just two minutes,
Mate.
Quickly, now.
What is it?
This is the necklace.
How much does it cost?
I didn't ask the price.
I saw it when I came here with Anoushay.
It's beautiful, innit?
Very.
I've saved 28,000.
I'll buy it one day, for sure.
It'll be sold out by then, Mehwish.
So what?
I'll buy another one like this.
It's absolutely lovely.
Innit?
C'mon, it's been two minutes already.
The rickshaw driver will charge an extra 100 Rupees. Come!
-Double time!
Get in.
Get in!
Quickly now, have a shower and go to bed.
-Okay.
What's with the TV?
Go to bed right now.
Always glued to your cartoons!
What's up?
I'm beholding my affluence.
There, now.
I'm honest.
If I ever feel that I don't have much money in my pockets,
I pull out my wallet and look at your picture;
In but a moment, a gust of opulence overwhelms me.
Get me that necklace, will you?
That's what I'm thinking.
But first, I need to know its price...
Around 80 or 90, perhaps?
And you said you've only got 28,000.
Yes.
That leaves...
50 to 60 thousand...
It's too much, isn't it?
Two months' salary...
So, what now...?
Just go to bed.
You're actually awake, aren't you?
How would you sleep...
How must it feel to think that your husband
Can't even get you a piffling necklace!
Honestly,
I'm troubled far more than you are.
Please, go to sleep.
I can't sleep.
My status jeers at me, Mehwish.
However do I tell you,
My heart wants to get you all the necklaces in the world.
You're insulting me now, Danish.
Insulting?
What are you saying?
I'm drowning in shame.
When did I ask you to actually get me that necklace?
Just --
I liked it.
I thought I'd buy it one day.
It's not like I'd die if I didn't.
C'mon now.
Go to sleep.
You have to go to office in the morning.
You're always late on Mondays.
You're pitying my helplessness, aren't you?
Well...
Here we go again.
There's nothing like that, my dear.
I'm happy with how you keep me.
I love you.
I love you too.
Go to sleep.
Good morning.
Good morning., sir.
'Morning.
-How are you?
Everything fine?
Good morning., sir.
-Good morning..
Tea?
Yes, please.
By the way,
Surely you don't smoke?
No.
Well, sometimes...
Give me one too.
Sir?
You'd smoke?
I don't really smoke
But you know, like... Sometimes?
Tell me,
What happened to Mr Mohabbat Ali?
Did he see the boss again?
He showed up the day before yesterday as you left.
The boss gave him a prompt reply,
And even said,
'I'll sign it only'
'If Mr Danish signs it'.
This is the necklace.
How much does it cost?
I didn't ask the price.
I saw it when I came here with Anoushay.
Very beautiful, innit?
Very.
I've saved 28,000.
I'll buy it one day, for sure.
Your tea, sir.
If I ever feel that I don't have much money in my pockets,
I pull out my wallet and look at your picture;
In but a moment, a gust of opulence overwhelms me.
Hello!
-Hello!
So early?
Strolling about till the evening drives me mad.
How are you, you wee kid?
Not 'wee kid', it's Rumi.
Alright, wee Rumi, how are you?
Strolling about, as in?
You know my blighter of a brother?
He suddenly figured he should get married.
What?
He's getting married?
Yes.
Getting married as if
The girl's running off to marry someone else on Saturday
If he doesn't marry her on Friday.
What?
The wedding's on Friday?
The wedding's on Friday, the Mehendi's on Thursday, and the Dholak's on Wednesday [rituals].
Wow...
Honestly, though,
I'm pitying Danish.
Why?
Well, obviously, if he had to get three gowns at the end of the month,
He'd curse me along with my brother too, right?
Could you please speak in a low voice? I'm watching this cartoon.
Awrite, sir.
But...
Why are you watching a cartoon right now?
Shouldn't you be at school?
He --
Hasn't started school yet.
I'm thinking of getting him enrolled next month.
My Meerab's younger than him, isn't she?
Jeez, she's a full two months younger than him!
She'll be going to prep now.
And this rascal's at home, watching cartoons!
What rascal?
Hey!
She's just joking.
Watch your cartoon.
May I come in, sir?
Come in, Mr Danish.
Sit.
Danish,
This is Mr Mohabbat Ali.
He wants to talk to you.
Please, discuss it thoroughly with him,
And if you understand what he says,
It'd be great,
Otherwise, for my part, I've told him that
It's a tad on the illegal side of things.
He's saying 'a tad illegal' because of you.
I say it's completely illegal!
It's neither under my control,
Nor his authority.
There may be
Some questioning later.
Who's there to question?
A man who'd question those
Who've been running this country for 70 years is yet to be born,
And those who feared questioning
Back in the day
Used to walk on foot.
Now, they ride a bike to office.
You have a bike, don't you?
Yes?
When are you buying a car?
I mean, how'd you buy one?
If you got caught up in questioning,
You'd have a 2014 car in 2024,
And I can't guarantee
That cars then will run on petrol.
That's right, but --
-But what?
Look, Mr Danish,
This is a government office.
Someone else will do what you will not.
He may take 150 instead of 100 thousand.
I can give him 200,
But it'll work for me.
But what'd you get?
The truth is, you'd laugh
If you heard my problem.
Amuse me.
I mean, tell me your problem.
Back on my first day here,
Dad was still alive.
Sitting by my side, he said, 'My son',
'Where you're about to start working'
'Is an office of the Government.'
'Of the Government, as in, of the nation.'
That's how Dad thought.
Working for the Government was working for the nation,
And the Government's money was, to him, the nation's.
He said, 'You don't need a pile of money'
'Or a lofty position to become a great man',
'But remember -'
'He who plunders a treasure'
'Is no great man'.
I think you didn't quite get it.
The Government's money was the nation's to him,
And the nation's money was the treasure.
He was absolutely right, sir,
But he forgot to tell you one thing:
A treasure is something under your watch.
What do you have?
Whatever is it that's under your watch?
Nothing.
The thing you call a treasure
Gets distributed among hundreds
Right under your nose,
And you sign its distribution, too.
Believe it or not,
You can bet your head
That you'll sign it but get not a single penny out of 200,000.
But you just said 100,000...
I mean --
You'd said you'd pay 100,000.
So you were asking for a raise!
No...
It's nothing like that.
I was just reminding you that you'd said 100,000.
Alright, mate, my apologies; I'll pay you 200,000.
Give me one day.
One day?
I'll think over it,
And if necessary, visit Dad's grave and say,
'Your view about the treasure isn't correct.'
Let me know about the boy's fees, too.
The boy's fees?
No -- he hasn't started school yet.
But he will one day, right?
You'll have to pay the fees then.
Of course.
How?
Fees for a good school start at 18,000.
Hey!
I saw when I went to the mall yesterday
Your necklace is still lying there.
Didn't you buy it?
How would I buy it?
We can save just about a thousand or two from his salary.
Who knows how long it will last!
Consider it all spent once Rumi starts school.
Oh...
But I've put this through to him.
I've told him how much I like the necklace.
What good will that do if you haven't got the money?
A lot can happen.
I just want him to get rid of his fear.
He feels ashamed now,
Or remembers Dad's words.
Surely, I'd heard his Dad's no more?
But his words aren't.
He's left them well and truly alive for us.
Then, put it plainly,
'This is not how one runs a household.'
'I'll work too.'
He doesn't agree to it.
Why won't he?
He says, 'What about Rumi?'
'Who will take care of him?'
Jeez...
But he's right in saying that.
Where'd poor Rumi go if I go to work too?
But you know what,
He's determined this time.
He'll do something for sure.
Did he say anything?
No.
His eyes did the talking.
They clearly said, 'You'll get the necklace at all costs',
Even if he has to sell himself.
Good afternoon.
Show me this necklace, sir.
Which one?
This green one.
Alright.
Show him the green necklace.
Sit.
No, I won't sit today.
I've just come to know the price today.
I'll purchase it tomorrow.
103,000.
103,000...
See you tomorrow, then.
Okay, sure.
Tomorrow.
Goodbye.
I've asked the price of the necklace.
When?
On my way back from the office today.
What good is it?
You'd trouble yourself for nothing.
There.
By the way, how much does it cost?
103,000.
Two months' salary...
Alright, leave the necklace be.
Listen to this:
A new trouble is upon us.
Pray tell.
Anoushay's brother's getting married.
We'll be there.
Listen to the whole thing.
Ask when the wedding is.
When is it?
Friday.
The Dholak's on Wednesday,
And the Mehendi's on Thursday.
We have to attend all three.
We will, Mehwish.
We'll go shopping when I'm back from the office tomorrow.
And I know
Why you're stressing that we have to attend all three.
No problem.
You'll get your three gowns.
You'll get something else, too.
What?
Mum's the word!
I'll surprise you tomorrow.
Finish it quickly, now.
I'll be back early today.
When?
By 2 or 2.30.
How?
You used to say that you can't step outside before 4.30.
Don't you remember when I had to see the doctor last week?
Everything changes tomorrow, Mehwish.
I'm making friends with the boss.
Splendid.
In fact, think as if I've already made friends with him.
I just --
Delayed it by one day.
Why?
When he wants to be friends,
Why keep him waiting?
It takes a day, Mehwish, doesn't it,
To step down from one's stature,
Or to accept a friendship with someone above one's stature?
It takes a day, at the very least.
You didn't ask me why I'd be back at 2.30.
I almost forgot!
I'll take you shopping.
Be ready.
Finish this,
And I'll get you another paratha.
Finish this already.
Here. Have this.
One,
Two,
Three,
Four,
Five.
Very good.
Have a nice day, Papa.
Here's an idea:
Ask Anoushay
Which school Meerab's attending.
Why?
We'll get him enrolled in the school.
The rascal spends his entire day watching cartoons.
Bad word, Papa.
Look at him speak English now.
'Very good, Papa',
'Have a nice day, Papa'.
Alright.
Do you know the fees for the school?
Must be around 10 to 15 thousand.
And your salary?
You do remember how much it is, don't you?
48,400.
You don't know the power of my signature.
Signing a twopenny file
Signs a cheque for 200,000.
See you.
How are you, Danish, mate?
Fine.
And you?
I'm fit too.
Tell me about Madame.
What about her?
How's she?
She's good.
You're going to office?
I'm cleaning the plug right now.
But you'll be going to office, right?
Do you need anything?
No.
I was just asking.
Come to our place someday, and bring Madame along.
I will, someday.
Okay.
I'll get going.
Bye.
One minute, mate!
Just a second.
Yes?
How much does it cost?
What?
Your car.
Would you buy it?
I might as well.
Tell me the price.
Around 1.2 million.
1.2 million...
Is it too much?
No.
Not at all.
Then, let's seal the deal, shall we?
No.
Not now.
In a few days.
Just show it to Madame,
She'll be delighted.
I told you,
Not now.
I'm just considering it right now.
Don't worry if you don't have the money.
An instalment payment will do; just for you.
Buy it.
Madame will be delighted.
I'll talk next month.
Sure.
Okay.
I'll get going, mate.
The bugger's always itching to talk about 'Madame'.
What happened?
Why the grim faces?
Is it --
Has someone died?
I'll be back to record the statements of every one of you.
Please stay here.
Not at all.
All of them always said, 'Not at all'.
I have but one reply to your question:
'Not at all'.
Because --
-Because?
My Dad used to say,
'Every penny in the possession of the Offices of the Government'
'Is the nation's treasure in the possession of the employees',
'Never plunder this treasure'.
Sounds good.
Sounds like your Dad was a wise man.
Your phone's ringing.
Wait.
Give me the phone.
My wife's calling.
Don't worry. If it's your wife, I'll let you talk.
Here.
Give me the phone.
Why aren't you back yet?
Look at the time.
It's 3.
It's your wife.
Talk to her.
Hello?
What did I just ask you?
What?
You'd said you'd be back by 2.
I've been ready since 2.
I won't be coming.
What?
Will you believe me if I swear on it?
I swear by you I'd forgotten about Dad,
And decided to take the money.
In fact, it had been decided
That I'd get 200,000 in the first deal.
That --
That surprise I mentioned, at least ask me what that was.
I was going to get you the necklace.
The same one.
Or perhaps one even better.
Should I sell the motorcycle?
How would you go to office, then?
That's my problem.
There's a bus that goes that way.
Leave it be.
I'll tell her we can't afford it if she asks me.
Who?
I'm talking about Anoushay.
I'd bragged a bit before her when she'd come today.
She thinks I can wear anything I like if you want.
Alright, don't worry, I --
-Please.
Don't give me any hope now.
And don't even talk about selling the motorcycle.
It costs no more than 30,000.
Do you remember how much the necklace costs?
Get something to eat from the market; I haven't cooked anything.
Go and sit there on the sofa.
Always up to his shenanigans!
I've come to realise now, Mehwish,
That Dad's words
Are of no use in 2019.
I've even seen the anti-corruption folks now.
I don't fear them anymore.
Putting the necklace aside,
I'm even thinking of buying Monty's car.
What if you got caught?
My boss has been bailed
After the courthouse called it a day, at that!
When you've made a billion,
A million can get you acquitted.
After a week's act of fairness,
Everything will be alright.
What will I wear to her brother's wedding?
I mean, I've purchased all three artificial sets with her.
Her brother's getting married in such a haste th --
Alright,
What do I do?
Selling the motorcycle won't get me enough either.
Take out a loan.
Don't tell me that Dad had advised you against taking out a loan.
But from whom?
What else are friends for?
They'd gladly lend you 80 to 90 thousand in tough times.
I don't have any friend except you.
I never thought I'd need any friend
When I've got you.
Tell me,
Have I ever gone to a friend?
I'm only friends with you.
You should, then.
Make some friends.
The kind that will help you in tough times.
Alright, Rumi,
I'll cook you an omelette.
Come.
I'd like ha--
-Give me 10 kg of fish, mate.
Give him first.
Sure.
Take out a loan.
Don't tell me that Dad had advised you against taking out a loan.
How much for you, sir?
Half a kilo.
You should, then.
Make some friends.
The kind that will help you in tough times.
And here I've brought dinner!
Maman's gone to sleep without putting me to sleep.
Have you had anything?
I had an omelette with bread.
Good.
I'll rouse your Mum, okay?
Mehwish?
Good morning.
Shall I get you some tea, sir?
Yes, please.
I wanted to talk to you about something, sir.
Yes?
I would like to take out a loan
Of 2,000 Rupees.
I can have it deducted from my salary.
My wife will be giving birth,
And I may have to take her to the hospital any time today.
Why don't you
Ask Mr Shams?
He even earns overheads.
Those who earn overheads are proper blighters, sir.
I'd asked him yesterday,
And he said, 'I'll tell the boss.'
And what about the boss?
What about him, sir?
He's in his office,
Sipping his coffee.
Alright, wait,
I'll do something.
Thank you, sir.
May I come in, sir?
Come in, Mr Danish.
What a pleasant surprise, sir!
Surprise?
It's a surprise, sir, isn't it,
When the anti-corruption folks had taken you yesterday, I'd thought you're...
I was astonished when Shams messaged me at night.
You were bailed in two hours!
Because why not, mate?
The anti-corruption folks wrote
That they found nothing in the raid.
And how is that, sir?
Six files had been opened before my eyes.
Everything had been done only in the files.
It was nowhere to be found in the city.
They found everything within an hour.
The wretch demanded a million from me.
I offered him two.
He stopped the car right there,
And said, 'Let's have a cup of tea.'
A -- cup of tea, sir?
Yes.
After tea, he said, 'Go home',
'And show yourself'
'Before the Special Magistrate at 1.30.'
And guess what,
When I arrived at the Magistrate's office at 1.30,
The same officer opened the door of my car,
And said,
'Sorry for the inconvenience.'
He was throwing his weight about yesterday,
Determined to catch everyone in one day.
The poor souls who won't pay
Will get caught.
So that's it!
But I've decided to set an example of honesty for a week.
A week, sir?
Why?
What is it?
The thing is, sir, when there'd been this thing about the 200,000,
I'd promised my wife to get her a necklace.
Her friend's brother
Is getting married in two days.
She was very worried.
Well...
'Well' what?
Keep the promise you've made
And get your wife the necklace.
But how, sir?
My salary --
Call Mr Shams, please.
Wait.
Yes, sir?
Shams,
Transfer 200,000 Rupees to Mr Danish's account.
Actually,
Don't transfer it to his account.
Give him 200,000 in cash.
Alright.
There.
That's all it ever was.