Dad used to say,
'You serve good food'
'To win one's heart'.
So, tell me, Mr Danish,
Have I been able to win yours?
Do you normally talk so little,
Or am I speaking too much?
I'm listening.
I'm looking at the confidence in a man's tone
When he's successful.
You've been successful, sir.
That's what I think.
Getting whatever you want
Is no success.
To get the one you like
Is success like no other.
Hey!
Serve him some soup.
Try some of this soup.
Hey!
-Papa!
What's this?
Couldn't you pour it carefully?
Mr Diwan!
Danish,
You're alright, aren't you?
Please, take him to my room,
And give him a shirt from my wardrobe.
And stay with him.
He might need something.
Please, don't come downstairs.
You --
Just got worried so suddenly.
He'll be fine.
He'll be back in about 15 minutes.
Please, sit.
Sit.
He'd ask me why I didn't go with him.
Then, just say,
'I would rather not go inside another man's bedroom'.
Everything happens as you wish.
I wish that he not come down all night,
But that won't happen.
How long have you been married?
8 years.
-Oh.
That's enough.
What do you mean, 'enough'?
It's enough
For a lovely lady like you to give a pleb
8 long years of her life.
It's hurt you?
Yes.
What do you like?
To live in pieces?
To live, entrapped by a man
Who's caught you like a hunter?
He loves me so much.
-Tell me, also, if he deserves your love.
Or if he deserves you.
Look, Mr Shehwar,
I like to talk to you,
But I'm sorry, I don't want to talk about these things.
Okay, sorry.
I won't say it again.
Where's your wife?
Who knows where she'd be!
Perhaps in New York, perhaps in Toronto...
She'd be somewhere...
She tells me when she calls.
What do you talk about?
About the business, about the profit...
Or, she gets angry
If a company's facing a loss.
Doesn't she ask about you?
Yes.
Sometimes, she does ask about me, too.
She even says, chuckling,
'Why don't get married a second time'?
Have you had any issues?
Yes.
What?
We haven't had any issues of 'love' between us.
I'm sorry,
But sometimes,
I laugh at the wrong things.
Excuse me.
-Alright.
Did you have fun?
You enjoyed your movie?
How was the movie?
Innit?
Oh, great!
Mr Danish,
Here's a watch for you.
Hey -- Why?
Please, keep it.
Consider it a friend's first gift.
Also, it's a tradition in my family
To give a gift to our guests
On their first visit here
To cherish the memories.
Please, take it, or it'd hurt me very much.
Thank you.
Here.
And
This is for you, Rumi; there's lots of chocolates in it.
And here's a little piano,
It also has the tune I just played.
-Thank you.
You're welcome.
And
This is for you.
All of this is very expensive, Mr Shehwar...
Your lady is priceless, too.
Lovers are priceless.
Such things are an offering unto them.
In fact, why don't you have her
Put it on right now?
Please, put it on her.
I'd be chuffed if you put it on her.
Should I take this one off?
Mehwish!
Why are you sleeping here?
It's --
I thought I'd just --
Try it on and see how it looks.
I fell asleep looking at it.
It's very expensive, innit?
Yes.
It suits you.
It looks priceless when you wear it.
Mr Shehwar's got a big heart.
Yes...
You don't mind it, do you?
What?
He gave a necklace,
And I accepted it.
Not at all.
He gave me a wristwatch
Before he gave you the necklace.
Right!
That looks very expensive too!
I've got it in charity.
What?
I'm kidding, mate!
Just kidding.
Come. We should sleep now.
C'mon.
Why did you say 'in charity'?
You would've minded it if I'd said 'brokerage'.
Even a tip is a kind of charity.
It doesn't sound as bad.
Why are you saying all of that?
What does it mean?
I don't know,
But in the beginning, when someone used to take a good look at you,
You'd whisper in my ear,
'Look at how he's staring at me'!
He was looking at you wide-eyed today,
And you never felt
That he was looking at you the wrong way.
So that's it!
So you're doubting his intentions.
I'm not talking about intentions.
I've seen his gaze.
So you're doubting me!
Shut up, Mehwish!
I cannot doubt you.
I'm just surprised that you couldn't see through his gaze today.
I felt it, too, in the beginning,
Had my suspicions, too,
But then, I realised
That it's impossible for him to not praise something beautiful,
Even if that's someone's wife.
Perhaps...
I would've felt bad about the same.
I can return the necklace to him if you want.
No, leave it be.
Why?
Because then,
I'd have to return the wristwatch too!
You're wicked!
I do feel, today, that I'm wicked.
I couldn't give you everything.
If you hadn't been so foolish as to return that money,
We would've gone there in our own car today.
Do you know, whenever I look at you,
I say to God, 'Thank You so much',
And whenever I'm about to make a mistake,
I feel that I'm insulting Him
By thanking Him.
Oh, please...
May I ask you something?
Sure.
Why don't you think like I do?
Like what?
Just think you've got me.
Surely, I have.
Then, just say that you don't want anything else.
As in, say to God that I don't want anything else?
If He heard it,
He'd actually give nothing!
Please, go to sleep!
I want a lot from Him besides you.
C'mon, now! Off to bed!
He'll be back in about 15 minutes.
Please, sit.
Sit.
He'd ask me why I didn't go with him.
Just tell him, then,
'I would rather not go into another man's bedroom'.
Everything happens as you wish.
I wish that he not come down all night,
But this won't happen.
Your phone's ringing, Maman!
Hello?
How are you, mate?
You haven't called since you went back!
Anoushay?
Yes,
Didn't you see the number?
I didn't...
-Alright, listen.
The bride and groom have left for their honeymoon.
Where to?
London.
Wow...
I find the cow a dodgy type!
Who?
My sister-in-law, of course!
Why? What happened?
One look at her had told me enough.
But don't worry,
I can be more dodgy than her!
Has Danish left?
Yes, he'd left at 7.30.
Why not come over, then? We'll have a nice chat.
Oh!
How surprised I was that day!
Danish and Shehwar have made such friends!
Yes.
Have you ever noticed Mr Shehwar?
He's stunned for a moment at the sight of you.
Why?
It's natural, mate...
Men are stunned for a moment when they see a comely woman.
Did you talk about anything?
Talk?
Just the usual 'His' and 'Hellos'.
I know he doesn't even bother that someone's sitting right there...
Do you know what he'd said when he'd first seen you?
What did he say?
'Who's that angel, Anoushay'?
Anyway, I'm going shopping. Want to come along?
No.
I have neither the mood, nor the money...
Poor people...
Well...
Bye.
Yes?
Right!
I almost forgot to tell you!
What?
He might invite the two of you over for dinner.
Please, don't decline. Just go.
Sure, we will.
Why are you so teed off?
No -- I was just -- giving Rumi his breakfast.
Alright. Give him his breakfast.
Bye.
You haven't finished it yet!
Here.
Let me feed you.
Good boy!
You have to drop it!
Mr Danish!
Please sign this.
What's this file about?
The boss has served you a memo.
What for?
You came late twice,
And left at 3 one day
Without even telling the boss.
I'd told him, Mr Matin. I swear to God I did.
You would've told him over the phone.
So?
One informs in writing, Mr Danish.
Telephonic conversations are off-the-record.
Mr Matin --
-Write in the reply that you'd informed him over the phone.
But of course, I will.
Then sign it and write today's date.
Give me the pen.
That's what would happen
If you turn Plutus down when he knocks.
What do you mean?
You've returned a million Rupees,
But do you know how many months' worth of salary that is?
It's a lifetime's worth of disgrace, sir!
One's dishonoured in his own eyes.
Yes, Danish?
Hey!
So romantic a voice!
You've just gotten up, haven't you?
No, I've just taken a bath.
Oh.
So that's why you didn't answer the phone.
Yes -- Everything alright?
I've --
Gotten a memo.
Memo?
The boss has asked for an explanation about arriving late twice and leaving early once.
What did you leave early for?
That was
When I'd come to you with the one million.
Oh,
So didn't you ask when coming?
I did, mate.
But asking and informing over the phone is off-the-record.
But I know
What my actual crime has been.
What?
I didn't take a bribe of one million.
Then you deserve this memo.
I would've done the same in your boss' place.
Someone's ringing the bell.
Yes.
Hello?
Hi!
I've been thinking of calling you since the morning,
But realised that merely talking won't satisfy me.
I -- I'm sorry, but I can't --
Allow you in.
I won't come inside.
I've seen you.
That's enough.
I can while the day away now.
Bye.
Who were you talking to?
Someone rang the bell by mistake.
He wanted to go to 408.
I thought it's Shehwar Uncle.
Why would he come here?
Can't he come here?
Why did we go there?
Of course he can.
But
He'd come if we invited him,
Just like he invited us, okay?
Then, invite him.
He'd bring a lot of chocolates for us.
Ask your Dad; he'd invite him.
That's alright, but what if he didn't bring chocolates?
Hello?
I'm so sorry.
Why are you saying sorry?
I showed up
Uninvited, without a word,
Without a thought, without asking...
But what could I do?
I had two important meetings today,
But I don't feel like going anywhere.
You're alright, aren't you?
Obviously, I wasn't alright.
That's why I'd come to you to get cured.
Seeing you was like this patient getting his medicine.
Know what, one can't help but remember your words...
May I ask something?
Yes?
Don't you feel like meeting the one
Whose words you can't help but remember?
We just met last night?
Just that?
Is one night enough?
One regularly meets those one likes in memories.
I swear, I stop in my tracks, thinking of your words.
You say whatever comes to your mind.
I start stammering if I lie,
Or start taking long pauses.
You lie, too?
A lot, now.
I even tell myself if I'm unable to sleep
That you're with me.
Danish is calling.
Okay, bye.
Yes, Danish?
You hung up as the doorbell rang.
Who was it?
It was --
Someone wanted to go to 408. Came to 308 instead.
Oh...
I didn't hang up. The call got dropped.
Alright, listen.
I've written the reply,
And I've also written that it's the first time someone's served me a memo.
Who've you written to?
The boss had asked for an explanation, remember?
Right...
I'm talking about that.
Alright.
Alright,
Alright, I'll go and prepare dinner. Bye.
Okay,
Bye.
Here's a watch for you.
It's a friend's first gift to his friend.
Also, it's a tradition in my family
To give a gift to our guests
On their first visit here
To cherish the memories.
And
This is for you, Mr Rumi; there's a lot of chocolates in this.
And here's a little piano,
It also has the tune I'd just played.
-Thank you.
You're welcome.
And
This is for you.
All of this is very expensive, Mr Shehwar...
Your lady is priceless, too.
Hey!
It's you!
You live in our building, right?
-Yes.
Please, sit, then.
Thank you.
I've seen you around many times.
Yes. The name's Nasir.
Yes, I'd forgotten the name.
Do you work around here?
No, I'd come here for the Judge's work.
I'm the Civil Judge's reader.
Oh.
Yes.
No, he's not here yet.
He'd be coming any time.
Do you stay at home all day?
Yes.
I'm at home most of the time.
Sometimes, I go shopping,
Or we go out on Sundays.
How say you start working?
Working?
For me, at my office?
I'll pay you a hundred thousand as salary.
What does Mr Danish give you?
I mean,
How much does he earn?
Very little...
Then say yes, will you?
It'll be a job for you,
And a cure for me.
What kind of cure?
I'd told you, mate.
To get to see your face is what lures me,
He may strike a deal with me about it.
Tell me.
He won't agree.
So he doesn't listen to you.
He does, but...
But he wouldn't ever agree if I were to talk about working for you.
Does he doubt you?
He doubts you.
You, too, look at me like that...
It's clear that you're only looking at me.
But you know what, I can't help it.
That's the problem with me -
My eyes start looking for you
The moment I wake up.
I know it isn't good for either of us.
He'd obviously feel bad about it,
But I fear
That you may feel bad about it too...
I'm sorry, but inviting you over for dinner,
Offering you a job,
These were all but excuses, Mehwish,
To see you,
To meet you.
You, too, said the other day, 'I won't listen to such things'.
Do you know
I kept cursing myself all night?
Why did I say that?
Why did such a thing ever come out of my mouth
That you minded?
But what can I do, Mehwish?
If I meet you,
Look at you,
I won't be able to stop myself.
That's the problem with me, Mehwish - I can't hold my heart's thoughts in
Because I'm not an actor.
Okay,
I'll do something.
I won't meet you.
I won't call, nor talk to you, nor show up at your doorstep to see you.
I'll try to explain to myself, control myself,
And just think
That I have no right over your any bit of your splendour.
Bye.
Thank you so much, Mr Danish.
It's nothing, really.
Come over someday, perhaps when you have an off?
We'll have a nice chat.
I live in #408.
408?
-Yes.
The flat just above yours.
Splendid...
What a strange coincidence!
Just today,
Someone who wanted to go to 408 showed up at our flat.
Oh?
Alright,
We'll meet properly on a Sunday.
-Sure.
Bye.
-Okay.
Sir!
Someone had come to meet you, too, sir.
Mentioned your name and asked your flat number,
So I told him.
Didn't you say I wasn't at home?
No, sir, I couldn't dare, seeing his personality.
But I kept an eye on him anyway.
He never went beyond the door.
Rang the bell,
Talked to your wife, and came back.
I think she told him that you're not at home.
Right...
He came in a big car, didn't he?
Yes.
Okay.
Alright.
Thank you.
I think I should start working.
May I?
Have I ever stopped you?
You wouldn't agree in the beginning...
I used to think like any other young man back then -
'I'd do this for you',
'I'd do that for you'...
But I couldn't do anything.
Is there any offer?
One doesn't get an offer sitting at home.
I'll prepare a CV and go a few places.
Let's see how it goes.
You won't get a good salary because you don't have experience.
But you should try.
You know why I'm doing this, right?
Yes.
You want to give me a hand,
Send Rumi to a good school.
By the way, you could surely get a job as a PRO.
Good looks matter more than experience.
Don't send just your CV.
Send your pictures along, too.
You'll see,
You'll get an offer in a flash.
Had your dinner?
Didn't I eat properly?
I'd had a few samosas with Mr Nasir,
So...
Who's Mr Nasir?
He lives in our building
On the floor upstairs.
He asked for a lift, and we became friends,
And two friends enjoyed samosas on the way back.
I'd like some green tea if you're making some.
Alright?
Rumi!
Come here and have something.
Coming, Maman!
Should I talk to Anoushay?
About what?
Mr Shehwar, you know,
He's got such a flourishing business.
So?
I'll ask Anoushay
To talk to him about a job.
Why do you need to talk to Anoushay about that?
You can
Talk to him, too.
Me?
How could I?
We're friends with him.
You won't even have to send your CV and pictures.
And I'm sure
You'll be getting a good salary.
So --
Why don't you talk?
No...
If I talk, it'll seem as if I'm acting as a souteneur.
Souteneur?
Look at what I just said!
I mean, it wouldn't seem proper if I talk.
Go and change first. Put the remote down.
Quickly, now.
Should I get you some tea?
Please.
If I talk, it'll seem as if I'm acting as a souteneur.
The thing
About being a souteneur is still bothering me.
Why did you say that?
I didn't really think when saying that, Mehwish.
It just slipped from my mouth.
I'm sorry.
You're feeling bad about me working, right?
Tell me.
Right?
No.
I don't mind it.
I just don't like it.
And
Where'd Rumi go?
Rumi would be at school, of course.
School's over at 1.30.
Then?
Then, he'd be with a maid.
Yes...
But how would we get a maid?
We would, Danish.
Think over it...
But if you get him admitted to a school that costs less,
I can manage.
We could've done so last year if we wanted to.
You know what, school is really important!
You haven't even started working,
But you've started speaking English so fluently!
Practicing, eh?
The water's boiling.
I have no problem if you work somewhere else.
I have a problem if you work there.
There, as in?
I'm talking about Mr Shehwar.
Maybe he's a good man,
But...
When he looks at you,
It feels like he's ogling you.
Why haven't you slept?
I'm trying to sleep.
You feel bad about it, don't you?
I'll tell you something.
People would look at me like that
Wherever I go.
They'd talk about me, too.
And
Praise me when they get the chance, too.
But they'd pay me less.
I'd get a better salary there.
I know you're very possessive about me.
You don't like it
If someone looks at me or talks about me again and again.
But people do look,
And try to talk,
Even when I'm with you.
What do you mean?
It'd be bad if I look at someone,
Start talking to someone.
People's intentions and ways won't change if you fear their gaze.
So, stop thinking about them.
Think about me.
Look at me.
Why, then,
Did you not tell me he'd come here?
Why did you lie that someone who wanted to go to 408 came to 308 by mistake?
Because he'd come here uninvited.
I was shocked to see him, too.
Do you remember that I'd hung up the phone while talking to you?
Ask me why.
Why?
So you can't know
Or get angry to hear about it;
So you don't think anything wrong and get all worked up.
Why did he come at all?
And why did he come when he knew I wouldn't be home?
Because I wasn't answering his call.
What?
He calls you, too?
He doesn't call me; he'd called me once.
I disconnected when I saw that it's Shehwar.
How did he get your number?
He'd come to tell me about that.
He'd gotten my number from Anoushay
Because he wants to help you.
He wants that I should work at his office,
Help you.
And
He's even offered me a salary.
He said he'd pay me a hundred thousand a month.
A hundred thousand a month?
As in, start at a hundred thousand?
That's what he'd said.
What did you say?
I said, 'Please talk to Danish'.
He didn't talk to me about anything.
He's even got my number.
Listen to me, will you?
He said, 'I'll talk to Danish'
'If you agree to it',
'Or he'd think I'm doing a favour on him'.
Oh...
He's so clever!
He's not clever,
He's just a friend.
But if you still think he's not a good man,
And he's -- very clever, it's okay.
I won't work there.
Go to sleep, please.
And ask your spies
Who've told you
That he'd come -
Did I let him in?
Is there any problem?
No?
Maman's angry.
No, she's fine.
I'm honest, Papa. She talks a lot while cooking breakfast.
Ask her.
Maman!
Go on!
See that? She said 'Go on'; she usually says, 'Yes'?
What is it?
You're angry?
100% she is!
C'mon,
Finish it quickly.
What are you doing? Let go!
Listen for a moment.
I don't have any spies.
I'd given Mr Nasir a lift the day before yesterday.
He lives in #408.
The guard told me before him,
'A man who looks like that had come to your flat'.
'I left him at your doorstep when he asked me your flat number'.
Leave it be.
-I was just angry that you hadn't told me.
We'll talk after breakfast.
Don't talk about working for him.
Please.
I've seen his gaze, Mehwish,
And before that, I've seen the world.
A man's gaze is his first introduction,
It shows his intentions and what his character's like.
English translation: J. Mir