Is there any problem?
No?
Maman's angry.
No, she's fine.
I'm honest, Papa. She talks a lot while cooking breakfast.
Ask her.
Maman!
Go on!
See that? She said 'Go on'; she usually says, 'Yes'?
What is it?
You're angry?
100% she is!
C'mon,
Finish it quickly.
What are you doing? Let go!
Listen for a moment.
I don't have any spies.
I'd given Mr Nasir a lift the day before yesterday.
He lives in #408.
The guard said to me before him,
'A man who looks like that had come to your flat'.
'I left him at your doorstep when he asked me your flat number'.
Leave it be.
-I was just angry that you'd not told me.
We'll talk after breakfast.
Don't talk about working for him.
Please.
I've seen his gaze, Mehwish,
And before that, I've seen the world.
A man's gaze is his first introduction,
It shows his intentions and what his character's like.
Our problem
Is finding a good school for Rumi.
We don't need a hundred thousand a month for that.
You can start working,
But work where
You get the salary you deserve.
Oh!
Why this 'Oh'?
It pains you that I'm earning a hundred thousand.
Are you crazy?
Why would it pain me?
It pains me that I couldn't give you every bit of happiness you desired.
Yet, I didn't take the one million
That I didn't deserve.
I'm trying to tell you the same -
The money one deserves
Is his salary, and the money one doesn't deserve
Is his price.
Here.
Go and return all of this to him,
And say to him,
'Your gaze is improper, Shehwar Ahmed';
'We can't be friends'.
Go, will you?
Why are you looking at me like that?
Before naming my price, we've been paid an advance.
Only if you return this will he realise that I'm no item for sale!
I've decided
That I won't work.
We'll send Rumi to a school that costs less.
Doesn't that make you happy?
You aren't happy either...
This was something to be explained calmly,
But you're saying it angrily.
The same thing's been said, Mehwish,
But its meaning has changed.
This --
These are not gifts.
That's why
I tremble with fear when wearing this watch.
I swear, when you wear this necklace,
You don't look beautiful to me.
Trust me, Mehwish.
These are not gifts.
These are scorpions stinging me.
Relax.
Danish took the watch and necklace and left for your place.
Hey!
But why?
He's coming to return them.
But why does he want to return them?
What's gotten into him?
He feels your intentions aren't right,
That your gaze when you look at me isn't right.
He's right about that.
I swear, my intentions aren't right.
It's not a joke.
Such words are precisely what anger him.
He's also found out that you'd come to meet me the other day.
Not to meet you,
Just to see you.
I haven't thought about meeting you yet.
What would you do now?
What should I do?
Let him be told at the gate that you're not home.
I won't do that.
I'll meet him if he comes.
Listen to him, talk to him,
And see what he's made of.
Then, you don't know him.
He'd stand his ground before you.
He doesn't know me either.
He's coming to challenge my intentions.
I swear by you,
I'll send him back bitterly defeated.
Alright, tell me,
Do you feel, too, that my intentions are not right?
That I look at you the wrong way?
Honestly? Sometimes, I feel that too,
But then, I feel it's nothing like that.
You're just a good friend.
I'm his friend.
Who are you to me, then?
Pray tell.
When I first saw you,
My heart asked,
Why are you someone else's?
I had to tell my heart the next time I met you,
Quiet it like one would a child, explain to it
That you're not a toy
That I can buy and keep with me.
And when you came to dinner,
It felt as if
Someone from the Heavens had descended into my heart.
I remembered you after you left,
And fell asleep, thinking
That fairies do not visit barren wastelands.
If these words make you think that my intentions aren't right,
I'll say to him today,
'But of course, Mr Danish',
'My intentions are not right'.
Why are you quiet?
Please, go on.
Isn't he there yet?
No.
May I request something?
You'd request me?
Hey!
Just order me.
Just don't say, 'My intentions aren't right'.
I won't.
Don't worry.
And if he shouts, just listen.
He'd shout?
Normally, he doesn't,
But he gets furious if someone brings me up when talking.
Splendid.
I'd have proper fun.
You won't have fun, you'd be enraged.
He may get very foul,
And if you say anything in return, things will only heat up.
Please don't do that.
Just a minute.
Alright.
Have him sit;
Tell him I'm coming.
He's here.
Good Lord!
Don't worry.
Just remember that I'd send him bitterly defeated.
May God will so!
Trust me,
He'd come back wearing the watch,
Saying,
'I'm sorry, Mehwish',
'But I was wrong'.
'His intentions weren't bad'.
Come.
Please, sit.
He'll be here shortly.
What would you like to have? Tea, or a cold drink?
Nothing.
That's not possible.
If he found out, he'd be angry with me.
Get me a glass of cold water, then.
-In a moment, sir.
What a pleasant surprise, Mr Danish!
This Sunday was such a put-off!
Please, sit.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Did you have anything?
I've asked for some water.
You'd just have water at your friend's house?
That's brilliant, Mr Danish!
You may leave.
Here.
Thank you.
Why didn't Mehwish come?
There, now!
I've complimented her in every way imaginable,
But it didn't seem to have had any effect on her.
I thought
She'd say to you herself,
'Let's go to Mr Shehwar's place'.
Someone had once said that to win a woman's heart,
Compliment her.
In fact, say it plainly,
'No one can be more beautiful than you'.
I thought she'd be chuffed to hear,
And I wouldn't have to invite you here.
That's alright, but --
-What's alright, Mr Danish?
Rumi had come the other day.
He watched a film in the theatre,
Had fun in the lawn;
We had dinner together;
I felt that
I wasn't alone.
Remember
How lively this place had been?
I was prancing about
As if you'd never go back,
As if the four of us are family,
As if we're all bound to each other,
And then...
You left,
And I --
I swear, this very house stung at me when you'd left.
Please, have your juice.
Call Madame and tell her you're having lunch with me.
I won't hear a no, Mr Danish.
Please.
Mr Diwan!
Serve us lunch.
Has he fallen asleep?
I've told him 10 different tales.
He fell asleep after the 10th one.
He was asking,
'Where are the djinns, Papa'?
'Why haven't you shown me one'?
What are you reading?
Nothing, really.
I thought I'd read this magazine while waiting for you.
Anoushay had given me this one.
Should I turn off the lights?
-No...
I don't feel sleepy.
It's 1, Danish.
Let it be.
Do you know, it pains me so much...
I'm cursing myself.
What happened?
You haven't asked what happened there.
I went there in fury,
And have come back as soft as wax.
What'd happened there?
He'd said so much before I could utter a single word!
There was sorrow and truthfulness in his words,
I was pained to hear it, Mehwish.
I forgot that I'd gone there for a reason.
I'd gone, thinking I'd break his face if he said anything dodgy.
But I was left looking at his face quietly.
He defeated me without even fighting.
Trust me, coming back from there,
I felt like
I was a warrior who'd faced defeat.
Everything I'd thought turned out to be wrong, Mehwish.
I was wrong.
His intentions aren't bad,
Nor is his gaze wrong.
Alright, go to sleep; you have to go to office in the morning.
Listen, please.
They'll be divorced very soon.
Who?
Shehwar and his wife.
-Oh.
Shehwar worked at her office before he married her.
He was her employee.
And she used to treat him as her servant after their marriage, too.
She was rather foolish, really.
What do we know what went on behind the scenes?
Looking into his eyes, one can see that the poor man's lonely.
He misses her a lot.
And she --
She's gadding about in America.
I've said, 'You should get married'.
As in, 'Marry a second'?
Hey!
As if his first marriage's anything like a marriage!
What did he say?
Nothing.
He just laughed it off.
He said, 'Let me know if there's someone like Mehwish'.
'Only then would I get married'.
I realised, then,
That I tell the truth.
What truth?
That I don't have a grand job,
Mansion,
Or car,
Nor a bank balance like Shehwar's,
But I've got Mehwish.
I've got you, Mehwish.
Have you prepared your CV?
No?
I thought you would've.
What'd I do with a CV?
Start applying, of course.
Go to his office, now.
Give him your CV and get your appointment letter.
You --
You're talking about Mr Shehwar?
Of course, I'm talking about him.
Go.
It's a good opportunity offering a good salary.
And I have no problem.
Sure?
200%.
Where do I leave Rumi?
Why, with Anoushay.
It's just about today.
We can
Hire a maid tomorrow.
What are you looking at?
You're happy, aren't you?
What does it look like?
Looks like you are, but
If you got angry over something again...
I would never get angry now.
I promise.
Go and get me my bag, will you?
Now, don't boss over me.
Why would I boss over you?
You'd be getting a hundred thousand a month.
You may start acting proud.
You're getting jealous, aren't you?
Get going, now.
Hold on. Just a moment.
Here.
Bye!
Bye.
I'm headed for the office, sir!
Good morning, Mr Danish.
Good morning, sir.
Please, Mr Danish,
Surely, you wouldn't call me 'Sir'!
I'd have to, sir.
When Mehwish would call you 'sir',
I'd have to, too.
What do you mean?
She'd be coming to your office today
To start working.
Oh!
When should she come?
I'm just leaving for office.
Tell her to come now.
One more thing, sir.
Yes?
If she could be picked up and dropped for a few days,
It'd ease me.
Why just a few days?
When you request me, Mr Danish, it feels as if you're insulting me.
No...
I wouldn't dare imagine.
Then however did you imagine that she'd have any problem
About coming and going back if she were to work for me?
Don't worry,
She's my responsibility now.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you so much.
My pleasure.
Bye.
Bye, sir.
She'd be having breakfast right now...
Are we going somewhere, Maman?
Yes.
You to Aunt Anoushay's,
And I to office.
You'd go to office, too?
Yes.
So would I --
Everyday --
Be -- Stay at Aunt Anousay's?
No.
You're starting school tomorrow,
And until I'm back, you'd be with our maid.
Where's the maid?
She'd be here, mun.
Get a move on, now. Don't ask so many questions.
I would ask you.
Yes, Danish?
Had breakfast?
Yes.
Alright,
I've talked to Mr Shehwar.
About what?
About you working at his office.
In fact, I've even talked about picking and dropping you,
And he's agreed to arrange for it.
Think again, Danish.
What's left to think about?
You're happy, aren't you?
I swear, I'm very happy.
I was just thinking of how you'd go and come.
That's been sorted out, too, now.
So, when should I go?
Today.
In fact, go right away.
Should I get ready?
Yes.
Just text me as you're leaving.
Also, is Rumi up?
He got up a while ago.
Give him the phone.
I'll tell him not to bother you.
Just focus on your work, will you?
I'll explain it to him.
Okay, then,
Bye.
You didn't even tell me this thing about working at Mr Shehwar's office, mate!
What could I tell you?
I didn't know what Danish would say until the last moment.
Then?
No idea how he agreed to it today.
He called from his office when he got there.
He said, 'Go'.
Would you look at how you've decked yourself up!
Would you do your work, or kill with those looks!
Alright,
I'm leaving Rumi with you today.
Just for today.
Tomorrow, I'll hire a maid,
And I won't have to bother you.
-No problem, mate.
Alright, I'll pick him up on my way back.
Okay, no problem.
Rumi,
I'm leaving.
Don't bother Aunt too much.
Bye!
Alright.
Tell me,
Is that necklace a real one?
Of course,
It's a real one.
Then,
How could Danish's salary have gotten you that?
When did I say Danish got me that?
Bye.
Hey!
I'm feeling dizzy.
Dizzy?
No --
I think I have a headache.
Do you have a head pil --
I mean, a pill for the headache?
Yes, I can get you one.
Just a moment!
You've built me up.
All the companies of the group are profiting because of you.
I just come to the office, sit on my chair, sip my tea, and go back.
Shut up!
You're here for two months a year,
Doing the numbers for one and a half,
And spending the other 15 days encashing cheques for yourself.
What else do you do?
I have given your business my life blood.
Actually,
There should be a 1:6 ratio
Between your assets and mine.
I work for 12 months,
And you for 2,
But unlike you,
I remember people's favours on me.
Yes?
Ms Mehwish is here, sir.
So, send her to me.
Okay, sir.
Come.
You are busy with your numbers whenever you're here, right?
About the money, the accounts, the assets?
So,
When you come this time, do the numbers about those five years of my life, too,
And tell me
Which of the group's profit
And my life's loss is the greater.
Okay, I have to go now.
I have to attend a very important meeting.
Why are you standing?
Please, sit.
Alright.
You're looking gorgeous.
Everything's alright now, innit?
He came back wearing the watch yesterday, right?
Yes.
What's the date today?
It's the 16th, right?
Yes.
I would never forget
The 16th of September.
I'd write in my diary,
'She came to my office for the first time on the 16th'.
Here's your appointment letter.
Thank you.
I've signed someone's appointment letter myself after long.
There's also a cheque for me.
That's five months' salary in advance.
Just live the way you are.
I've also given you a car and a driver.
Don't say anything.
You deserve all of it.
Come, I'll show you your office.
I'm feeling dizzy, sir.
I have a headache, too.
I took a pill, sir, but it isn't getting better.
So?
I was thinking it's --
Better if I could get a leave.
A half day's leave.
Okay,
You may take a leave.
Thank you sir.
Thank you very much, sir.
This is your room.
How is it?
Beautiful.
But...
But what?
This letter mentions neither my designation
Nor what I have to do.
Tell me,
What'd you do?
I should tell you?
Before you came, I was thinking about what you'd do,
But I figured
Everyone's going about their job, right?
Let them.
How say you change things a bit?
How?
-Don't do your job!
Just stay with me.
Come to me
When I want,
And remind me
That I haven't had lunch,
That I haven't had coffee.
I smoke a couple of cigarettes
When my wife calls me.
Don't give me a cigarette.
The doctor's told me not to smoke.
So it was your wife right now!
What did she say?
Nothing.
Hey!
You won't smoke.
May I have coffee?
Yes.
Maria!
Please, get me some coffee.
You're doing your duty, right?
What duty?
Stopping me from smoking,
Allowing me to have coffee...
Whatever you say,
I won't let you smoke.
Why are you leaving?
My --
Cellphone's in the room;
What if Danish called?
-So what?
One doesn't have the time
To answer a phone when at work.
Alright.
I'm afraid.
Why are you afraid?
I will develop a habit of it -
You telling me not to smoke,
Pulling the cigarette from my mouth and throwing it in the dustbin,
Seeing you,
Being with you...
I'm right here, with you.
You're doing a job.
Who knows, one of these days, he may get angry and stop you,
And you may resign and leave.
I would never leave.
He can't stop me now.
Sorry, mate.
Sorry.
Are you blind?
Even if I am, can't you see?
Don't stay put; Get a move on once the signal's turned green.
Don't you know how to talk to girls?
Do you know how to talk to boys?
You think of yourself as a boy?
Have some shame.
Why are you arguing, old fella? The fault is yours.
So I'm an 'old fella' to you, too!
Look at your own age! Get going.
Mind your own business.
So, what do you do
When she calls you at night?
Smoke a cigarette.
Not good.
What do I do?
Do you know what her tone's like?
You'd be inflamed to hear it.
It pains me to hear it.
Back when I didn't smoke,
I'd vent my anger on any employee.
I'd curse myself later -
'What was his fault'?
Just -- Don't answer her call.
I have to.
She's my business partner.
I want it all to end.
I want to live in peace, Mehwish,
Or rest in peace.
Please, sir.
Anyway,
This will go on at least until December.
Besides, December isn't all that far away.
-What's her problem?
If the business is doing well, why isn't life going on smoothly?
I know what the problem is,
But I can't tell anyone.
I feel ashamed to utter such a thing.
Okay, no problem...
What'd I do with it?
Right...
Whatever would you do with it?
What's this pill for?
Nothing really... I just have a slight headache...
I'm boring you, right?
No, not at all.
You may leave.
Go back to your room.
We'll meet again
When I get better.
No.
I'll leave only when you get better.
What are you made of, really!
Ordering around like this suits you.
Where were you all these years?
English translation: J. Mir