Hello!
-Hi!
How are are you?
Fine!
What should we order?
What do you say?
Alright.
Is this spicy garlic fish any good?
I'll be back. Excuse me.
Hi.
May I sit?
Yeah, sure.
You -- here...
You're here too.
What are you doing?
I'm here to have dinner.
You have your dinner at the bistro.
That's quite the change, mate.
Are you on a date?
Sorry.
I get quite personal with you because of Dad.
I hope you didn't mind it.
Not at all.
And I'm not on a date.
I just felt like going somewhere nice to have dinner.
So --
What about you?
Is everything good?
Is Rumi fine?
Absolutely fine.
He said to me, 'Tell Papa to get married'.
What'd you like to have?
I've already ordered.
No -- I'm here with my friends. I won't have anything.
Seeing you, I thought you'd be caught red-handed today.
I just felt so.
You don't really listen to the thing about marriage.
Know what, Rumi's found a match for you.
Says she's very cute.
Looks good with you.
When did you
When did you start smiling like that?
Do you know what that smile means?
That the person before you is saying a load of pure guff.
No.
It's not like that.
Then, get married, will you?
I won't get married.
There!
That's what he says, too.
'Dad won't agree to get married'.
Alright, just see her for once.
Who knows, she may begin to grow on you.
Pl --
Please don't go just yet.
I was going to my friends --
-Just for a while.
-Just for a while. Please.
My --
My heart's thumping really fast.
Okay...
Relax. I'm right here.
Ours was a love marriage.
A rather famous kind of love marriage.
And would you look at it now!
Both the love and the marriage
Have been scotched.
What are love and marriage, exactly?
I mean, can one love and marry
Just about anyone, just like that?
My heartbeat's fine now.
I'm okay now.
And thank you very much.
You may go.
Please go and
Have fun with your friends.
Sure?
Yes.
Absolutely.
Bye.
You're still thinking about him, right?
Yes...
Why did he get up and leave?
He didn't even have his dinner.
His heart had start thumping really fast; he was sweating.
He should've gone to a doctor!
He should just have gotten up and left.
Why?
Because Mehwish had come right in front of him with her new boyfriend.
Mehwish?
Why didn't you tell me?
I wanted to see her.
He's really become something of a friend of yours.
Told you that his heart's pounding,
That he's sweating.
He doesn't realise what he's saying when he's frightened.
Something dangerous is about to happen.
What?
Love.
He curses love.
What about you?
You've never cursed.
After what I've seen today,
I feel that way too.
To curse anyone who talks of love so badly...
I pity him.
You would, too.
And you can't love those you pity.
I just want him to be happy.
Dad would like it this way, too, wouldn't he?
He always wanted to see him smile brightly.
Yes, an omelette would do, too. And a chapatti with that.
It'll do without one. I'll have two slices of bread, then.
And a cup of tea.
Thank you.
Yeah, I'll be waiting.
Hi.
You bugger!
Do you know what Shehwar Chemicals has closed at?
Don't tell me just yet.
I'll ask you on Monday.
Are you absolute nuts?
If I told you I am, would you rest at that?
Honestly?
When people rob you of everything, be happy.
Just think that the Lord is about to give you everything.
Anyway -- come over for dinner tomorrow.
Ayesha was crying when she found out about your divorce.
She wants to meet you.
Please, come over, boyo.
She's learnt to cook, too.
Alright, I'll come for dinner.
But please tell her to not shed tears before me.
I'd seen Mehwish today.
She's very happy.
And if she's so happy after the divorce,
Why are we crying?
Just pray for her.
May she remain happy.
Text me your address.
I'll be there tomorrow.
Bye.
Okay.
As if someone's tripped and fallen in water, but not quite drowning yet...
Call him.
Why?
Ask him if he's had dinner,
And if he has,
It means he doesn't need any sympathies or pity.
He's just looking for someone he can trust to love.
I don't love him.
Do you want it in writing?
Alright.
Just call him, will you?
Ask him
If he's had dinner.
Just ask indirectly.
Mention Dad.
Turn on the speaker.
Hello?
Yes, Mr Danish,
How are you?
Fine.
Have you had your dinner?
You didn't have anything at the restaurant.
I felt so hungry the moment I got to the guest house that I had dinner immediately.
You live in a guest house?
Yes.
I'm here for a few days before shifting to my home.
May I tell you something?
Yes?
You notice me just like Mr Matin.
Innit?
100%.
He'd even notice that I didn't quite smile while talking.
Just think that
I notice because he used to.
I know.
You've read his diary, haven't you?
Yes.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Take care.
Likewise.
Good night.
Mind if
Mind if I told you something?
I've lost a lot because of Mr Danish,
And perhaps you will, too.
How?
I can now believe that there are men like that.
Now, I'll be left looking
For a man like him.
Why do you need to look for one?
You've got one right before you.
Give him his life back.
Shut up, Watira.
Promise me.
If he said it himself,
Just accept it.
Don't say,
Don't say, 'I pity you'.
I'm the one who's at loss here.
I, too, can believe that there are men like that.
I'd be left looking for one...
Just wait here.
Alright.
I'll be back.
Please, wait here.
Excuse me, sir.
Over here.
How much does this black car cost?
3.4 million, sir.
3.4 million?
Just a second.
It's at 52.80.
Sell a hundred thousand.
Just a hundred thousand?
I'm selling them at a loss.
Sell them quickly, and send --
What's the name of your showroom?
[BLEEP]
The money to [BLEEP] showroom.
What are you doing there?
Buying a car.
Are you there right now?
Yes.
Look for Gohar over there.
Gohar --
Is there a Mr Gohar around here?
I'll call him here.
Please.
Just a minute.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Please talk to him, Mr Gohar...
Yes?
Salman! How are you, ol' fellow?
Alright.
Right...
It's done, right?
I'll tell him.
I'm giving you a discount of 50,000, sir.
Thank you.
Welcome.
Over here.
Waqas! Prepare an invoice.
Oh --
Whose car is this, Mr Danish?
It's mine, Mr Jameel. I've just bought it!
Splendid, sir!
So quickly!
That's brilliant.
What about this bike, Mr Danish?
Please park it on the porch of the house I've just bought.
I'm coming right away. I'll give you the money, too.
Alright.
Where is it?
Inside the car.
Which car?
What do you see here?
You've brought a car, Papa?
Whose is it?
Yours.
Haha. Good joke.
It's not a joke.
It's your car, Rumi.
Really?
Yes.
It's nice, innit?
Very nice.
Sit.
Where are we going?
We're going home.
Thank you, Papa, I love you.
I love you too.
Fasten your seatbelts; a nice ride awaits!
Ready?
Have you bought it, Papa?
No, I've rented it.
It's huge.
It's not huge, Rumi.
You feel this way because you've come out of the flat for the first time.
Let me show you your room. It's upstairs.
Come here.
Mr Danish!
This is Latif.
He's quite the cook.
I've brought the driver too. He's outside.
Alright.
Give the keys to him.
Please, prepare the day's meal.
Everything's in the kitchen.
Let me know when you've talked about their salaries.
Alright.
I'll show you the kitchen. Come.
Is this my room?
Have we gotten rich?
Yeah...
How?
Bad question.
Look in the drawer.
The pink one.
For me?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Must be very costly.
You like it, don't you?
It's priceless now.
I hope it's not a dream.
It's not!
Alright.
I believe now it isn't a dream.
Wow...
That's quite the meal!
Hello?
It's 9.10.
Salman!
Where are you?
Oh, mate, I almost forgot.
The thing is,
I'm with my son today. I thought I'd be with him today.
I brought him from the hostel, showed him the house,
And now we're having dinner.
I'm sorry, but I'd come on Sunday.
Alright.
But bring him along on Sunday too.
I will.
Promise.
Okay, bye.
Okay.
Alright.
In the name of the Lord, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
Bon appétit!
Dinner's ready, sir.
So it is, but
Where's Mehwish?
She had her dinner in her room.
What do you mean?
Mehwish!
Who is it?
Who could it be, sweetheart?
The prisoner enchanted by your charm,
Your Romeo, madly in love with you...
What is it?
Splendid.
What a question!
It's been two hours and I haven't seen you.
Come out,
And have mercy on these helpless eyes...
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
After the marriage?
I'm observing the Mayoon [ritual of separation] until then.
I'm observing the Mayoon [ritual of separation] until then. I won't meet you before that.
Observing the Mayoon [ritual of separation]...
Not meeting me...
Please don't laugh.
If you don't come out, I'd keep on laughing like this all night.
I won't.
I won't show you my face before tomorrow.
You'd get to see me when all the rituals are done and over with.
Go and sleep.
Or think what you'd give me [= ritualistic gift] when you see me.
You sound so serious about it.
Yes, Shehwar, I am serious.
We'll meet after the marriage tomorrow.
The marriage is in the evening, Mehwish...
Did I ask for it to be in the evening?
Alright, just open the door.
Didn't I say that the door's not opening?
Mehwish...
Good night!
Eh?
'Observing the Mayoon [ritual of separation]'...
Well,
Well, I suppose I should, too...
Good night.
Have we gotten very rich?
Catch some sleep, mate.
Don't you see him in your dreams?
Who?
Grandpa.
I do.
Doesn't he scold you?
Why would he?
Nothing, really.
He used to before...
You can't sleep, can you?
Get up. Sit.
What do you think? Your Papa's earned these riches unfairly?
No.
I'd sold a flat worth 8 million,
And invested 7.8 million out of it.
I've earned a huge profit on it.
More than 35 million.
In just a few days?
Yes.
In just a few days.
When He starts giving,
He gives everything in minutes.
Do you mean God?
Yes.
My teacher says that God doesn't let sorrows near you when He's happy with you.
She's right.
Won't you ask the teacher's name?
What's her name?
Miss Hania.
Alright.
Now, catch some sleep.
I will, but tell me, does my new phone work?
I've installed a new SIM card in your phone.
I've saved my number too.
Just yours?
Whose number do you want?
Miss Hania's.
She's also my friend.
Please give me her number too.
I don't have her number.
I have her father's.
I just call that one.
So, give me that one.
Alright, old chap, I'll send you.
Where are you off to?
To my room.
But you just said you won't be able to sleep alone?
I feel I may now.
-Little rascal!
Dad's phone is ringing.
Where is it?
In my room.
Then -- Just see who it is.
Hello?
Okay.
It's Rumi.
Rumi?
-Yeah.
Hello?
Hello, teacher.
Haven't you gone to bed yet?
No, I don't feel sleepy right now.
Rumi...
And whose phone are you using right now?
Mine.
The warden would not spare you if he found out.
It's not funny, Rumi.
I swear it's funny, teacher.
I'm home now.
Papa's bought me a phone.
Splendid.
How did that happen?
We've gotten rich now.
Super rich.
Papa's bought a car too -- a big one. Black.
Has he bought a house too?
Yes, and it's huge!
Has your Papa hit a jackpot?
Yes. He's changed completely.
Good for you.
But not good for Papa.
Why?
No idea why
But he's just busy with his numbers all the time.
He even sat down to put me to sleep.
He couldn't.
That's why I'm still awake.
It's 12, Rumi.
12.05.
It's time to sleep now.
Alright, teacher, I will.
Do you know, you're the first person I've called?
So sweet of you!
Please call Papa.
Why?
Didn't I tell you that thing about the girl?
Yes?
Just tell Papa to meet her once.
He should just see her once.
-I --
I talked to him,
But he changed the topic.
Just insist.
C'mon, Rumi.
It's hard to stand firm about something like this.
Besides, it's not like we're exactly friends that I'd pull his ear, saying, 'You have to meet her'!
Know what, you have a typical girly problem.
What?
Make friends with him, will you?
You're too young, Rumi.
You don't know what you're saying.
I don't know why I feel that once Papa gets richer and richer,
He'll be out of reach.
He won't do that. Your Papa is a good man.
Just try to understand, teacher.
It won't be good if he liked someone else.
Just pray that he likes someone.
Everything will be good then.
What were you saying in class the other day?
What was I saying?
'One has to make an effort'.
Yes, so?
I'm making an effort.
Splendid. Keep it up.
And you'd also said, 'Help others'.
So I had.
So, won't you help me?
I'm feeling sleepy, Rumi.
If someone asked me for help, I, too, would say that I'm sleepy.
Okay, good night, teacher.
Hold on --
Yes, teacher?
I'll talk to him.
Thank you, teacher.
Alright, catch some sleep now.
I'm really very sleepy now!
Good night.
How much is this for?
650 thousand.
I can have sleeves added, right?
-Of course, Ma'am.
Alright, get one like this ready.
-Alright. Thank you.
Please come to the jewellery shop as soon as the dress is ready.
Mehwish?
Anoushay?
What a surprise!
You've surprised me.
Started an affair with Shehwar, divorced Danish...
And disappeared!
However did you manage it?
C'mon, mate.
It was written in my destiny.
Right...
When at a loss for an answer, just say, 'It was written in my destiny'...
What else is destined for you?
I'm marrying him.
Wow...
Didn't the poor chap cry?
He must have.
How come he left you so easily?
It killed him to be away from you.
He just did.
He didn't bother me too much.
And Rumi...
Where's he?
He's with him.
That's fine,
But however does he sleep without you?
After all, he's just a kid.
What does he know that his Mum has an affair with someone and has left the house?
Do you
Meet him?
No.
He doesn't meet me.
It's good that I've met you, Anoushay.
Why don't you meet him?
He's in boarding school.
His hostel's just by the school.
He'd meet you.
Please, try to convince him.
You only needed to ask.
Danish has poisoned his ears.
He doesn't even want to see my face.
Does he take good care of you?
Who?
Shehwar?
Very good, in fact!
Does he actually love you?
Very much.
Do you know his wife?
Yes.
I just know that it upsets him when she calls.
He hates it when she calls.
It's thanks to her that he's gotten here.
In fact,
I've heard that he's taken over 1.2 million of her shares through forgery.
In fact, even the house he lives in
Is owned by her.
That's mine.
Besides, this is all hearsay.
Everything will be settled when she comes back from America,
And once everything's settled,
They'll be divorced.
Shopping around here?
By the way,
May I ask something?
Didn't you feel pity for Danish?
Do you remember
How he'd say proudly,
'I've got Mehwish',
'So, I've got everything'.
Honestly,
Did he ever have you?
He used to suspect me so much, Anoushay,
And I was really fed up of it.
Don't say he used to suspect you.
Besides, even if he did,
His suspicious turned out to be true...
Anyway,
Good luck for you new marriage, I suppose.
You're going?
Yes.
Won't you be there at the wedding?
I'd come if you invited.
We just bumped into each other, and you remembered that I'm someone, too, so you thought you'd just as well ask me,
'Are you coming'?
I mean,
Call me, request me, insist a bit.
I'll surely come if you did.
Alright, I'll call you
When you get back.
I'll insist a lot.
Okay, see you.
Bye.
Hi, teacher!
Hi!
So, were you waiting for me?
No, I was just watching you play.
Here.
Show me your car.
I'll show you when the driver's here.
Good.
So, I'll talk to your Papa today.
For sure?
For sure.
But if you introduce me to her,
I'd insist all I can.
I don't have her picture.
Alright, tell me, where is she? What does she do?
I won't tell you that.
Why?
It's a secret.
Say, what if your Papa agreed, but she didn't?
I didn't think about that.
Then, talk to her first.
I'll talk to Papa if she agrees.
Otherwise, all my effort will go to waste.
50% of it is up to me.
What?
That I'd convince her.
And what about the other 50%?
That's where the problem starts.
Normally, girls are committed, or engaged.
Committed, as in?
It means, Rumi,
It means, Rumi, that they like someone, or they've promised someone.
No, it's not like that.
Have you asked her?
I guessed from her words.
How to tell if she's been engaged?
She wears a ring in this finger if she is.
Like you are?
No, this is an artificial one.
A real one's either gold or diamond.
Why?
Have you seen a ring on her hand?
No, she wears an artificial one too.
Please don't break your promise and talk to Papa.
And what if he said right away, 'I'm not marrying anyone'?
So what? Tell him Rumi's very lonely...
'He feels lonely when you're not at home'.
Tell him also that he's friends with her and won't have any fights with her.
Alright.
And
If he said,
'What do you care about it'?
Just hang up and don't say anything.
Have some water.
How do I look?
Haven't you seen yourself?
Tell me.
I'm seeing you through your eyes today.
Then I'm sure I look very comely!
Crazy lass.
Who is it?
Everything's ready for the wedding.
The priest and the witnesses are here.
Please come downstairs in 15 minutes.
Is Shehwar here?
Yes, he's here.
He's sitting by the priest.
Alright,
I'll come the next time you knock.
Alright.
I have a business proposal for you.
Pray tell.
Share a membership with me.
50-50.
I lack the experience.
But I don't.
And I know that experience doesn't matter one bit before luck.
So you think I'm very lucky.
God is happy with you.
So, you're lucky.
The stock exchange pundits around here say, 'Partner with those who are lucky'.
'Don't compete with them'.
Tell me.
Let me think until Sunday.
Sunday's the day after tomorrow. What's there to think about?
Just try to understand, mate.
I'm not in the mood to talk about business today.
What happened? Is there any problem?
Once again, I've got a feeling something's not right...
My heart's sinking.
Then --
Then, c'mon, you need to see a doctor.
No, mate.
It's not sinking in the drowning way.
It's suffered one last wound.
It's just a bit shocked again.
It's just a bit shocked again. That's all.
She's getting married today.
We'll meet on Sunday.
Then, today would've been an auspicious day, Danish.
All the rituals of separation will be done and over with today.
Alright, Anoushay, they're waiting. C'mon.
-C'mon.
Right...
I'm Maham.
Shehwar
Shehwar Ahmed's
Shehwar Ahmed's wife.
English translation: J. Mir