I can't think of anything, Shehwar...
I don't feel like going home when I'm with you,
And --
My intentions begin to falter when I'm home.
He won't let me go to office.
He's firm about that.
Then?
What then?
You'd have to decide.
Decide what?
Who'd you rather live with?
Me,
Or him?
Tell me,
Or I can disconnect while you sit back and think.
No, please don't.
Alright, tell me how much you trust me.
You shouldn't be asking this now.
Then, why do your intentions begin to falter?
Take the leash of 'marriage' off your neck
And shove it in his face.
What do you mean?
Ask him to divorce you.
Divorce?
Is there any problem?
He won't divorce me, Shehwar.
Leave that to me.
What about Rumi?
What's with him?
Whatever does a kid want?
Things that he likes?
He'll get whatever he can lay his finger on.
By the time he'd grow up,
He would've found out that there's something called 'divorce' too.
The times have changed.
More than bonding with parents,
Kids look at what they're getting from them.
He's coming to return the 500,000 to you.
He may misbehave, too.
Just let him come.
If he misbehaves with me, the security guards will throw him out of the office.
Listen.
Yes?
Should I talk to him?
What'd you talk about?
I'll ask him to strike a deal with me.
Take his money,
And set you free.
Money for what?
You won't get it.
A large sum of money crushes large sorrows under its weight.
Naturally, he'd feel the sorrow of leaving you.
So, let's buy that sorrow.
It'll lead to a fight, Shehwar.
Then, he won't worry that your security guards might throw him out.
Just tell me this -
If he asked you,
'Do you want a divorce'?
You'd say,
'Yes'.
'I want a divorce'.
I'd said it last night, too.
But he didn't agree.
He started explaining to me like I'm a kid.
Well, then, we'll talk later.
Just let him come here.
Let's take a look at his price,
And see how much he sells for.
Mr Danish!
Here.
There's a cheque for 80,000 Rupees in this.
Please, don't say 'Thank you'.
Alright, I have to go.
I'll be late on the way back.
Alright.
No problem.
Wait.
You're fine, aren't you?
Yes.
I can come with you if you want.
No.
I thought I'd ask because you seemed a bit worried.
It's --
Just that I'm a bit late.
Alright, go.
-Okay, then.
Is he there?
N
No
Not
Not y
Not ye
Not yet
Not yet.
He's left the bank; he'll be there anytime.
Just let him come.
Yes?
A certain Mr Danish is here, sir.
Have him sit. Let him have some tea...
Send him when I ask you to.
Okay, sir.
Please wait a while. The boss is busy.
Okay, I'll wait.
Hello?
He's here.
Before you?
No.
I've had him sit at the reception.
He'll understand his place when he'll wait a while.
Pack your bags.
Why?
He'll divorce you today,
And I'll come to take you home myself.
The home that you deserve.
But, Shehwar --
-Don't think about Rumi.
I won't let there be any problem for him.
I hope you trust me.
Yeah...
I do trust you.
Leave your money and jewellery there.
It'll help him.
I will, sure,
But my heart doesn't quite think
That he'll divorce me so easily.
But mine does,
And I know
Exactly what I have to say.
He'll be knocked for six to hear it.
Hear what?
My words.
It's words that can win a heart,
And words that can take a life.
Okay, bye.
I'm calling him.
Shehwar --
Be careful.
Wish me luck.
Good luck.
Right.
Send Mr Danish in.
Please, come.
Right.
Won't you take your bag?
Are you Ms Mehwish's husband?
Yes.
-Please, come.
Come in, Mr Danish. What a pleasant surprise!
Sorry, but I had an important meeting.
Come. Please, sit.
Tell me, sir,
What'd you like to have? Tea or coffee?
Nothing; thank you.
I won't have anything at your place.
Oh --
Alright, Mr Danish,
Pray tell what brings you here.
You've been too kind to Mehwish.
I'm here to return every bit of that kindness that I can.
Such as?
Such as
500,000 here,
This necklace...
You gave her this necklace,
But it's an albatross around my neck.
I've come to take it off.
I figure
You've been angry with her for going to Islamabad without asking.
There's a lot I'm angry at, Mr Shehwar.
But I'm no longer in a position
To be angry with her for going to Islamabad.
The thing is,
That ours was a 'love marriage'.
We've got a son, Mr Shehwar.
We've got dreams we've cherished for ages.
A fear of those dreams shattering has struck me.
So, take these things of yours,
And hand me the receipt.
I won't even look back at you when leaving.
But she will.
She'll look for me,
And when one's looking for someone,
One can't see anyone else on the way.
Neither an old 'love marriage',
Nor sweet Rumi,
Nor dreams that could never have been fulfilled.
You're crossing the line, Mr Shehwar,
And I want this conversation to end with a 'Thank you', 'It's okay', and 'Bye bye'.
I want the same -
That you divorce Mehwish,
I say 'Thank you' to you,
You say 'It's okay', and leave with a 'Bye bye'.
That's the spirit.
Otherwise, she was worried you'd be furious to hear something like this.
Who?
Mehwish, of course.
Take all of this,
And give me the receipt.
I'd need it.
I couldn't even complete my line.
I'd known that you'd come to return the money
And the necklace to me,
But didn't know that you'd
Still hold on to Mehwish.
Let go of her, too, sir.
What good is holding on to a wife who isn't even yours in the first place?
The fact is that she isn't yours anymore.
Don't strive for her.
I have a compliment for you.
Yes, please?
You're the most vile person in this world,
Sinking in this arrogance, intoxicated with wealth.
What are you, then?
You're holding fast to a woman who doesn't even want to live with you
Just because of the fact that you're married to her.
She made a mistake --
She went to Islamabad with you without asking me.
She's very sorry about it, in fact --
-Oh?
Is this how she's sorry?
Just a minute.
Here.
You'd see when you take a look.
Have some water.
I said she's made a mistake.
With a trader like you, a woman's delighted
To hear a higher price.
This delight leads one to make a mistake.
Only later does one realise
That, no matter the price, if a woman's sold,
She becomes cheap.
I can offer you 50 million.
For what?
For divorcing Mehwish.
Don't trouble yourself.
You'd be wishing, right now, to throw that glass in my face,
Or sap away my blood,
But that's not wise.
Why do you trouble yourself for a woman
Who isn't even loyal to you?
She's forgotten your 'love marriage',
And that you've got a son,
And that there were dreams the two of you cherished.
You may still cherish them, mate,
But she's jumped ship to fulfil them.
Didn't I show you something
A short while ago?
Here's something for you to hear.
Our conversation over the phone.
He's here.
Before you?
No.
I've had him sit at the reception.
He'll understand his place when he'll wait a while.
Pack your bags.
Why?
He'll divorce you today,
And I'll come to take you home myself.
The home that you deserve.
But, Shehwar --
-Don't think about Rumi.
I won't let there be any problem for him.
I hope you trust me.
Yeah...
I do trust you.
Leave your money and jewellery there.
It'll help him.
I will, sure,
But my heart doesn't quite think
That he'll divorce me so easily.
But mine does,
And I know
Exactly what I have to say.
He'll be knocked for six to hear it.
Hear what?
My words.
It's words that can win a heart,
And words that can take a life.
Okay, bye.
I'm calling him.
Be careful.
Wish me luck.
Good luck.
Pack your bags.
Why?
He'll divorce you today,
And I'll come to take you home myself.
The home that you deserve.
Why do you trouble yourself for a woman
Who isn't even loyal to you?
She's forgotten her 'love marriage' to you,
And that you've got a son,
And that there were dreams the two of you cherished.
You may still cherish them, mate,
But she's jumped ship to fulfil them.
But my heart doesn't quite think
That he'll divorce me so easily.
Wish me luck.
Good luck.
Okay,
Monty,
You may go.
Are you sure?
You won't trip and fall now, would you?
-No -- I'm alright.
Alright, here's your medicines,
And your bag.
Okay.
-Thank you.
What happened, Papa?
Has Maman left?
No, she's sitting in the room.
Tell me, Papa, what happened?
Nothing, my dear...
Tell me, how did you get injured?
I had an accident.
Fell from the bike.
Don't you know how to ride a bike?
Maman, look, Papa's gotten injured again!
The bandage looks bigger
Than the wound.
Did you see a doctor?
That's where I'm coming from.
He gave me a shot, too.
And
He's told me to apply this medicine to it.
Could you get me a cup of tea?
I will.
Did you run into a car?
Yes.
Did you bleed, too?
A little.
I'll be fine by tomorrow morning.
Just a minute.
Yes, Mr Matin?
You didn't come.
What do I tell you, Mr Matin...
I had an accident.
My head's been wounded.
I've just gotten it dressed and gotten home.
Sorry.
No, it's okay.
Take care of yourself.
Right...
You were a bit worried today.
I was a bit worried, seeing you leave.
You ride your bike so fast, too...
Yes, sometimes...
But I won't, now.
Take good care of yourself.
Listen...
Yes?
I'll return your 80,000 tomorrow.
So quickly? How?
You'd said it'd take a couple of months.
It didn't.
A couple of months passed in a moment.
I picked up my 80,000 and came back.
Surely,
Mr Danish, you're alright?
Yes, it's --
Just this injury; otherwise, I'm fine.
Are you coming to office tomorrow?
Yes.
Sure.
See you, then.
See you.
Did you finish your homework?
A long while ago.
Go to bed early.
Yes, Mr Shehwar?
Hope everything's fine.
Yeah.
Fine.
So, when should I come?
After 10 p.m.
Rumi goes to bed at 10.
Anything I could do for you?
You're so intelligent, Mr Shehwar,
But sometimes, you say such strange things.
Pray tell,
What else could I do for you?
You wound with every word.
I'd like you to hear a saying before you hang up -
'When one's wife chooses to let go',
'Do not stop her',
'For she's left before she lets go'.
I'll call before coming,
Or you can call me
When Rumi's gone to bed.
Bye.
Okay.
Hey!
Sit.
I've listened to your call.
You, talking to Shehwar
Before I got there.
He'd recorded everything.
I even saw the selfies you clicked
With Shehwar at the hotel in Islamabad.
As I saw them, I didn't see
That you weren't wearing the black dress;
I saw
How you were truly smiling.
You're blooming.
That's exactly what I wanted -
That when you laugh,
It feel like there's no sorrow in the world,
And when you're blooming,
I tell the world that that's how flowers bloom.
But that bugger turned the tables on me.
He gave you everything I could only imagine,
But never give.
That was the day I surrendered before him.
I said,
'I've lost',
'And you've won'.
I'd gone there to save love,
But I could barely try to save my honour,
And I'm not sure if I've saved it.
People will start asking me tomorrow,
And I'll start lying.
I'm worried more about Rumi.
He'd sleep for now,
But I don't know what I'd tell him
When he'd get up and ask where Maman is.
Tell him I'm out of the country.
I'd stay there a few days.
I'm sorry, Danish,
But I have to go.
What are you looking at?
I see that Rumi hasn't gone to sleep yet.
It's 8 right now.
Rumi doesn't sleep before 10.
Alright, pack your things.
Don't leave anything that's yours.
Ask --
Me if you need any help.
I'll try and put Rumi to sleep.
Does it hurt?
Yes, a lot.
Danish!
Rumi's fallen asleep.
He has?
Good.
He's snoring.
It's almost 10.
Packed your things?
Yes.
I'll call Mr Shehwar.
Where's my cellphone?
Over there.
Listen...
Can you do me a favour?
Go on.
Just a random thought.
Don't leave tonight.
I'm not stopping you.
Just requesting.
You can leave in the morning.
Rumi would've gone to school,
And I, to office,
And you, home.
The night is a long one, Mehwish,
And it feels like it'll never pass.
The night will fall tomorrow, too.
But a day will dawn before that.
I would've gathered the courage by the time the day would pass.
I would've told enough lies to Rumi
To while the night away acting them out.
Please.
It'd seriously help me a lot.
Tell Rumi the truth after a few days.
If he came across me somewhere,
It'd hurt him.
Right.
So, you'd leave in the morning, wouldn't you?
Talk to Shehwar.
Of course, I'd have to.
I will.
Hello?
Danish.
It's Danish, Mr Shehwar.
Yeah, I know.
Has Rumi gone to bed?
Yes, he has.
But I'm a bit afraid.
No -- Not like that.
I figured that Mehwish should leave in the morning
When Rumi's gone to his school,
And I, to office...
Sometimes, he gets up in the night.
He searches for his Maman when he's up.
It doesn't happen everyday,
But I fear it'll be very difficult for me
If he got up tonight.
Ask Mehwish.
What does she say?
She's asked me to ask you.
Oh --
Be a man.
You sometimes talk like kids.
I know.
Please, do me this favour.
I'd be delighted.
I'd bless you from the depths of my heart.
Okay, fine.
I'll come at 9 a.m.
Perfect.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
He's agreed to it.
Have you struck a deal with him?
Deal?
Have you taken money to divorce me?
No?
Why are you asking that?
It just occurred to me...
Seeing how you were pleading,
And thanking him when he agreed,
I thought there was something like that.
I haven't taken money to give you to him.
It was something he said -
'When one's wife chooses to let go',
'Never stop her',
'For she's left before she lets go'.
Although, yes,
He'd offered me 50 million...
Come again?
50 million.
It'd hurt me
That you'd landed straight in the market when you left home.
Shut up!
Do you know how much 50 million is?
I know.
I could buy a lot,
But not that one moment
When I'd be eager to get back home,
When I'd see you open the door
For me...
I just saw you.
I never put my needs above you.
I can understand.
Stay in your well,
Croaking like the proverbial frog.
Listen!
Should I get something to eat?
Teach me your ingenious skill
Of forgetting as you leave;
Fulfil the vows of our bond for once
As you break it.
Sometimes, it's nagging me,
And sometimes, making me weep.
Stay in your well,
Croaking like the proverbial frog.
Forsake your place in my heart,
Gently and stilly;
Bless you with this parting,
Fare thee well.
He's gone to the market.
He said, 'I'll get something to eat'.
For you?
I'm not hungry at all.
He's a proper character, mate.
I've never seen a man like him before.
Like what?
When he sat in my office, it seemed as if he'd kill me.
Don't even ask about his furious eyes.
After he heard the phone recording,
He was relaxed.
He cooled down.
He looked at me when the recording ended,
And smiled, saying...
She has such a beautiful voice.
Yeah.
She studied with me at University.
Know what,
I hadn't seen her face first.
The sound of her voice had startled me.
I turned back
And found her on one of the seats behind me.
She looked back,
And curled up, unsettled,
As if my gaze had pinched her.
I listen in on her at home
When she's talking to Rumi.
I call her from the office every now and then, everyday.
When she answers the phone
With a 'Hello',
I quiver for a moment.
But now,
Even her 'Hello' has lost that touch, as in --
Lost it for me.
Anyway, what do you think?
Do women two-time?
They do.
There are scores of examples.
Oh...
I used to think that only men two-time.
But
I'm noticing something -
When a woman two-times,
She goes the whole nine yards.
Didn't you get it?
I mean, she completely turns away.
Sometimes, I think
That she'd remember my name in the morning,
So that she may not slip and utter someone else's name.
Smile, would you? I'm talking about your name.
What have you thought?
I'm thinking...
Let me just grasp it...
Alright, tell me - When she went to Islamabad,
Did she agree, like, instantly, without any hesitation?
Yes.
She hesitated a bit.
But you know very well there's no hesitation in love.
She must be a bit afraid when she stepped inside the hotel room.
Leave it be... What are you talking about?
-No.
I'm just reassuring myself.
Yes.
She wasn't afraid.
But a bit nonplussed.
She must be taking a good look at the room.
She's never seen the room of a 5-star hotel.
I could never show her one.
Dad would come at my throat.
If I so much as thought of taking a bribe,
He'd stop and scold me.
Just a few days ago, I thought I would,
And even brought a million home,
But he created such a scene
That I had to return it.
But as far as I know, your father passed away almost 5 years ago?
Yes.
It's been four and a half years.
But if I think about doing something wrong,
He shows up in my dreams,
And slaps me right in the face.
You're not well.
No, I'm perfectly alright.
I'm just asking for my knowledge.
The thing is
That I'd just
Heard about it.
I'd never seen it before, Mr Shehwar.
It's alright...
She's decided...
You can take her.
I'll go home and call you.
I'll tell you when you should come.
Take care of her.
Sure.
Bye.
Just a minute.
This...
This is mine; I'd borrowed this from someone.
Goodbye.
English translation: J. Mir