Did you eat anything?
Didn't the maid cook anything?
She would've; I didn't take a look.
Alright, I'll get you some bread; you should have something.
No.
You're angry?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
It's okay, Mehwish.
A --
Foreign delegation had come.
When Shehwar asked me to come,
I thought it'd be a good experience for me.
Shall we sleep?
First, fix your mood.
What should I do? Laugh?
No...
Just smile in a way that feels like you're actually smiling.
Did you eat anything?
Yes,
On the flight.
You must've travelled business class.
Yes.
Mind if I ask something?
Not at all.
Didn't you think of how much I love you?
Oh, please leave that be.
When I said 'sorry', it means I made a mistake.
Tomorrow onwards, you're not going to office.
I'll manage everything.
How?
I'll take bribes.
I'll get you hundreds of thousands of Rupees a month if you want,
But you won't go to the office.
This brew is strong!
Would you like some butter on your slice?
No...
How much
Of the 500,000 is left?
I'd paid the school fees on my own.
Did you spend any?
Yes.
How much?
80 to 90 thousand?
No problem. It's not a big deal.
They'll be added up tomorrow.
And then?
Then, I'll give it to him,
And tell him that it's no longer needed.
Look, Danish, I've not committed a sin.
No, Mehwish,
Don't say that.
You have sinned,
It's just that I haven't said so.
Let's forget it.
Let's rewind our lives,
At least to the point
When there was no Shehwar Ahmed in our lives.
Let's start our life again.
He's a toff,
He's got a lot of money; he can even buy love if he wants,
But I'm wealthier than him, Mehwish,
For I can't sell my love.
It won't do this way.
Which way?
I can't live with my head bowed in shame before you.
No...
I can't hold my head high if your head is bowed.
Look up,
So I can hold my head high.
Do you know what he was saying on the way to the school?
'The two of you had a row, didn't you'?
I said, 'No'.
'When did you see us have a row'?
Do you know what he said?
He said,
'The two of you have a row'
'When you don't quarrel with each other'.
We'll have one to show him
When he gets back from the school.
He'd be delighted to see.
Why didn't you go to office?
It's nothing, really.
Mr Matin, you know,
The man in charge of the office?
He
Notices me.
What does he notice?
If I get the chills,
Or I feel
That my heart's sinking, or if I have a headache,
He asks what the problem is.
He starts telling tales of himself two-timing.
He'd been disloyal to his wife.
Hearing it, I said,
'Mr Matin',
'I'm not your type'.
Go to the office.
But
It's 11 right now...
Just say that you've come now that you're better.
Oh, it's nothing like that... It's not as if the work comes to a halt if I'm not there.
And
I'd thought we'd spend time with each other
Before Rumi gets back.
I can even cook
If you like.
Don't say that, Danish.
I want no files for an hour.
Sure, sir.
I was in Islamabad yesterday; I was busy.
I'd disconnect right now if you go on with this cod!
Shut up!
Thank you very much.
Why have we come here?
There's no meeting here.
So?
Let's make it one
Between the two of us.
We'll sit,
Have tea,
And decide
Where
We're headed.
Where are we headed?
The return flight leaves at 6.
Doesn't it?
Get some rest.
You won't smoke.
The 6 p.m. flight's confirmed,
You'd land in Karachi at 8,
That's for sure.
But
Must you go back to him
When we get back after going anywhere?
If you want to go back to him, why take the 6 p.m. flight?
Flights leave earlier, too.
Please, Shehwar,
He's very possessive.
He won't let me go anywhere.
-The decision is always up to the one who goes, and not the one who stops.
I've seen it many times.
I'm sure you would've, too.
People get on the wrong train in their hurry.
What do they do?
Do they keep sitting?
Where'd they go if they kept sitting?
That is why they don't sit tight like you.
They wait for the next station, and get off the moment the train stops.
You have six hours.
Think about it and decide.
Just think
That we're almost at the next station.
Should I get off?
You'd have to, if you know you've gotten on the wrong train.
Knock on my door
If you decide to get off.
I have to get off, too.
I've left many stations behind, looking for you.
Have you fallen asleep?
No, I'm awake.
I'm going to get Rumi.
Okay.
Fix your mood, will you?
We're going out in the evening.
I'm alright.
Sir, I've talked to the driver;
He'd gone over to pick Ms Mehwish up,
But her husband sent him back.
He'd have said something about her health?
No, sir, her husband said, 'Don't come here again'.
-What?
Call her.
Wait.
Leave it be.
Hello.
There.
It's happened, innit?
What?
That's what I feared.
He'd shut every way out if he found out.
Would you keep fearing him like that?
What should I do?
Do exactly what you'd knocked on my door to tell me.
Do you remember?
I do.
But the sight of him at the airport is stuck in my eyes.
How did he figure out I'd be at the airport?
And that I'd be there right then?
This was bound to happen one day.
That day came too quickly, Shehwar.
I feel pity when I see him.
It's simple, mate,
You pity him, but you don't pity yourself.
Send in your resignation and live out your days with him.
I can change how you think,
But not your fate.
Why are you saying such things?
What should I say?
You don't pity me, you don't pity yourself,
But you pity the man
Who'd rather imprison the most priceless beauty of the world
In that rubbishy flat!
What's the solution?
Just get to the office.
That's not possible.
He'd have me write my resignation in the evening,
And leave the resignation with all of 500,000 on your table tomorrow.
Fair enough.
Nobody will stop me from smoking now.
Shehwar, please.
What should I do?
It's beyond me to come and take you,
Or ask your husband to take everything I have,
And give me my Mehwish.
Would you give him everything if he actually asked for it?
I swear by you, I would.
Are you there?
Yeah.
Do you know how I feel?
I've been distressed since the morning.
I'm furious every now and then.
I've smoked, too.
You're not going to smoke; full stop.
I think he's here; Bye.
Bye.
Hi!
Hi.
Where's good ol' Danish?
He's gone to get Rumi from the school.
Oh...
Tell him that the Building Management's meeting tomorrow
At 7 p.m.
Ask him to take some time out and come.
Sure, I'll tell him.
I'd like to tell you something if you don't mind.
Please, go on.
You're the most charming lady in the building.
Thank you.
Alright.
Alright, recite the poem for me, will you?
C'mon.
Go on.
Didn't you make any new friends today?
I did.
Who?
Almi, Hamza...
You mentioned Hamza yesterday. Didn't you say you make new friends everyday?
Maham, Raza, Mohammad Hasnain...
Greetings, Danish!
How are you, Rumi?
Ayat, Ayeza,
Maham, Raza, Mohammad Hasnain...
I'd like to tell you something if you don't mind.
You're the most charming lady in the building.
What should I say?
You don't pity me, you don't pity yourself,
But you pity the man
Who'd rather imprison the most priceless beauty of the world
In that rubbishy flat!
Rumi's back.
My sweet little one.
Got homework?
-So much!
What's this?
Burgers.
I thought
We won't cook at home today.
We'd have burgers in the afternoon and a pizza in the evening.
The pizza was my idea.
Okay, mate.
It was your idea.
Alright, have your burgers,
Do your homework, and go to sleep.
Okay.
-Alright; freshen up and come.
Why don't you have some, too?
They're delicious.
Yes, Mr Matin?
How are you, sir?
I hear you're not well?
I'm fine now.
I even thought I should come to the office, but my heart didn't quite agree to it.
I've grown rather close to you, Mr Danish; you're a proper good chap.
Seeing your chair empty,
I felt sad.
You're too kind, Mr Matin.
You sound like you're perfectly fine now!
Yes.
100%.
So, are we meeting tomorrow morning?
Sure.
And tell me about the cigarettes.
Do you still smoke?
I'd told you.
I don't smoke like the smokers.
-You hadn't told me, sir.
You'd told the peon and I overheard it.
I never smoke at home.
Oh!
So you fear your wife!
Yes -- Very much.
You're the first man I know who says that he fears his wife openly!
You'd live such a happy life! Take care.
See you in the morning.
Likewise.
Bye.
-Bye.
I want to get off at the next station, Shehwar.
Sure?
Sure.
Maman!
Maman, we're here and you didn't even realise it!
Alright.
Is there any problem? Why aren't the two of you talking?
No.
It's nothing.
Say something, then, Papa.
You don't even say, 'Mehwish, you're spending so much'!
I would never say that.
Ice cream! Papa, ice cream!
Where -- Oh...
Stop here, will you?
Come here. Where are you off to?
Would you like to have an ice cream?
No.
Right...
Come.
How are you, Guard Uncle?
Fine!
We've just had an outing. We had pizza, too!
That's great!
-Here's an ice cream! Do you want some?
No, my wee Rumi will have this.
Rumi!
Come, quick!
Why are you scolding him?
Come, Rumi.
Didn't you see how he's befriended the guard?
Alright, don't be angry over it.
This isn't just anything, Danish.
Be stern with him.
I found it so weird.
Stop it, Mehwish.
He was the one who was with him that night.
We were both out of our senses.
By God, I didn't mean anything else.
I just said it,
But figured later that it isn't proper to say it like that.
Who knows how many years this will go on...
Just try to understand what I mean, Mehwish.
We'd -- forgotten Rumi that day.
Not me.
Alright, I'd forgotten.
The grief of your going had made me forget.
There!
You said it again.
Stop it, Mehwish.
It'll come up for a few days
Now that it's happened.
Don't look at the words,
Look at my intentions when I say them.
So, what were your intentions?
You decided the moment I got back that I should not go to office.
What are your intentions?
You're not going to office, Mehwish.
No matter what happens.
You'd tether me here?
-Tether -- what?
We fell in love, got married,
We're the parents of a child.
These are relationships, Mehwish.
And relationships do tether us.
What'd I do when you're at the office and Rumi's at his school?
This rotting flat suffocates me!
It's not a flat, Mehwish.
It's our home.
Whatever.
But I'm going to office from tomorrow, full stop.
-You're not going to office.
Please, don't even think about it.
Or else?
Would you beat me?
What are you saying?
Have I ever raised my hand on you?
Look at your eyes.
It looks like you'd eat me alive.
Looking at you, it looks like you'd slap me!
-No way, Mehwish, I'd never do that!
You're picking a fight with yourself for no reason.
You think you've sinned because of a trifling mistake; it's not like that.
You're not a sinner,
And I have no complaints of you.
Alright, then.
Let me go to office.
-Didn't I say you're not going to office?
That --
Blighter, Shehwar Ahmed --
Is a wicked man --
-Don't insult anyone!
Don't look at anyone, Mehwish.
Look at me; I'm your husband.
I'm your other half.
As if I'm looking at anyone!
What are you saying?
What's up with you?
Honestly, Danish?
We can't live together anymore.
The same old anger.
We'll talk in the morning --
-I'll say the same in the morning - we can't live together.
Crazy lass, I can't live without you.
But I can.
And I want to.
I'm fed up of this relationship.
I had thought that with you by my side,
What else could I ever wish for
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
I had thought that with you by my side,
What else could I ever wish for
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
What does it matter, if I don't have
Honestly, Danish?
Anything in this world;
We can't live together anymore.
I was under the misbelief
That I had you;
But, from you, I have learnt
That, even in love,
One could rather betray,
One could rather repulse.
I'm fed up of this relationship.
Mehwish.
He's fallen asleep.
Come.
C'mon, Mehwish.
Let's sleep in our room.
I'll sleep here.
You're mad, Mehwish.
Who knows what you're saying!
Do you know what you'd just said?
You'd said,
'I'm fed up of this relationship'.
Is that the kind of thing to say, even in anger?
Please,
Let's go and sleep; it's 2 a.m., and I have to go to office in the morning.
So do I.
Won't you let me go?
No, Mehwish.
That's the only thing I wouldn't agree to.
Go and sleep, then.
I have nothing to do with that room, now.
Let's think about another option.
What other option?
You won't work at his office.
Work anywhere else.
Does my handsome salary irk you?
Your stubbornness over working for him irks me.
The thing about going to Islamabad has hurt you.
Remember that I'd apologised for it the moment I'd come back.
Not the moment you'd come back.
I'd seen you at the airport with him.
You were very ashamed.
But I've forgotten that.
Now, I want to forget whatever I still remember.
Remember that we'd fallen in love,
Loved each other ardently,
We've shared our lives with each other and lived it together,
Never thinking that our wishes are much greater than my salary.
I never thought that.
Seeing that people had
Riches,
Cars, mansions, businesses,
I'd say proudly
That I've got you.
And I don't need anything when you're with me.
There's a lot to life beyond you and me, Danish.
I hope you know that.
Beyond you and me --
There's Rumi, Mehwish.
Just look at him sleep peacefully.
Perhaps children sleep with the belief that their parents are only theirs,
And that one of them will not have left them by the morning.
Please, come.
Good morning, Mr Matin!
Good morning.
'Morning.
-'Morning.
How are you, Mr Danish?
-Fine.
Good morning, sir!
Good morning.
Tea or coffee?
Coffee.
In a moment.
Is Rumi alright?
Fine.
Yes?
Mr Matin, this is Danish.
No --
Don't look at me.
I need a favour,
But I wouldn't be able to ask for it if you look at me.
Oh, well -- C'mon, mate...
What is it?
I need to borrow 80,000 urgently.
I'll return it in 3 months.
Sure, you'll get it.
Just
Meet me in the canteen; I'll give you a cheque.
Thank you very much.
There's no thank yous
And sorrys in friendship, old chap.
I can't think of anything, Shehwar...
I don't feel like going home when I'm with you,
And --
My intentions begin to falter when I'm home.
He won't let me go to office.
He's firm about that.
Then?
What then?
You'd have to decide.
Decide what?
Who'd you rather live with?
Me,
Or him?
Tell me,
Or I can disconnect while you sit back and think.
No, please don't.
Alright, tell me how much you trust me.
You shouldn't be asking this now.
Then, why do your intentions begin to falter?
Take the leash of 'marriage' off your neck
And shove it in his face.
What do you mean?
Ask him to divorce you.
Divorce?
Is there any problem?
He won't divorce me, Shehwar.
Leave that to me.
What about Rumi?
What's with him?
Whatever does a kid want?
Things that he likes?
He'll get whatever he can lay his finger on.
By the time he'd grow up,
He would've found out that there's something called 'divorce' too.
The times have changed.
More than bonding with parents,
Kids look at what they're getting from them.
He's coming to return the 500,000 to you.
He may misbehave, too.
Just let him come.
If he misbehaves with me, the security guards will throw him out of the office.
Listen.
Yes?
Should I talk to him?
What'd you talk about?
I'll ask him to strike a deal with me.
Take his money,
And set you free.
Money for what?
You won't get it.
A large sum of money crushes large sorrows under its weight.
Naturally, he'd feel the sorrow of leaving you.
So, let's buy that sorrow.
It'll lead to a fight, Shehwar.
Then, he won't think that your security guards might throw him out.
Just tell me this -
If he asked you,
'Do you want a divorce'?
You'd say,
'Yes'.
'I want a divorce'.
I'd said it last night, too.
But he didn't agree.
He started explaining to me like I'm a kid.
Well, then, we'll talk later.
And let him come to me.
Let's take a look at his price,
And see how much he sells for.
English translation: J. Mir