You're laughing?
I thought you'd be angry with me.
No way.
I'm delighted.
I feel so good.
You're taking so much interest in my life.
Are you joking?
No way, mate.
I'm complimenting you.
Go and call your Maman.
Say, 'I've found a match for Papa, and I will not rest until I've gotten them married'.
She'd be chuffed to hear that.
She'd give you a kiss.
No, she won't be happy to hear that.
She'd cry, but say, 'That's great. Well done, Rumi'!
Then, go and tell her. Hear her compliments, too.
I already did.
I've already told her.
I'd called her on the way.
She said, 'Go and ask Papa'.
Alright, I'll ask tomorrow. Have your dinner.
I'm starving.
You're starving?
C'mon.
Let's have dinner.
Maman had told me
That she thinks you like Miss Hania.
But you're so shy...
You can't bring yourself to say it.
What can't I say?
'I like you'.
So it's your Mum who's been feeding you these big words.
No, Papa.
These big words are all mine.
I'd told her about everything.
What did you tell her?
You'd gone to visit Teacher, right?
Sat there for a while, had tea...
You'd gone to say, 'Marry me'.
But you couldn't say it.
Did Hania tell you this?
No.
Ms Watira did.
I'm friends with her, too.
Why are you so shy?
Why don't you just say it?
Why do you stop eating in anger?
I haven't stopped eating.
I'm done.
Good night.
Wait, Papa...
Judging by the Teacher's smile, she'd agree.
You don't even say 'No', Papa...
Hania?
What's this?
What?
I'd heard you laughing when I came here, only to find out you're actually crying!
Ah --
I was laughing at the way he proposed to me on behalf of his father,
And I'm beginning to tear up
At his helplessness, Watira.
What helplessness?
Back then, he was behaving like his Papa's Dad.
Like a father looking for life-saving drugs for his son
With no money in his pocket;
He was almost begging that someone save his father's life.
Then, save his life.
You'll get your due reward.
The Lord will save you in return.
I have no worry for my life.
That's what you think.
Otherwise, death stands just around the corner.
Remember, Hania -
It hurts far more to lose your love
Than to lose your life.
Bashir,
Is this Mehwish's bag?
Yes.
Is she going somewhere?
Please, keep it in the car.
How much longer would I stay here?
I don't like it
When you talk all day, before me,
To the one I want to talk to,
When he doesn't talk to me at all.
I'm leaving after breakfast.
Where are you going?
I have a place.
Besides that,
I can only go to my grave.
You'd live alone?
No.
He'd be with me.
I have countless memories of him.
I'd remember something about him every day
To while the day away.
That's my final punishment -
That I miss him every moment,
And he never miss me.
Please, Mehwish...
You didn't ask me
How I'd while away the nights
After spending my days talking about him.
I've given him so much grief, Ayesha,
Hurt him so much
That the rest of the nights of my life
Will be spent shedding tears of repentance.
It's enough for this life for me to remember
That, deeply hurt, he used to say,
'I've got you',
And I knew all along that he was actually saying,
'I haven't even got you, Mehwish'...
Listen...
One's wife
Shouldn't really put a tie on him.
Why?
It's nothing, really...
If she remembered something
While tying its knot,
And got angry to remember it...
So?
It's not good for the husband.
You look very handsome.
Wait.
Your bag.
Go, now.
Aren't you coming?
No.
The staff goes first.
Didn't you always say,
'The Chairperson should always come an hour late'?
And, naturally, you used to go an hour late.
Bye.
Go and sit there on the sofa.
Always up to his shenanigans!
Come here.
Yes?
How do I look?
Look at me, will you?
Tell me.
Flirt with me.
What are you saying?
You're afraid today?
Crazy lad...
Danish ain't around anymore.
I'm all alone.
Take me out for coffee.
Just try and ask me out for once.
I'm sorry, Mehwish.
I'm really sorry.
Alright, promise me, then.
Even if you have a row with your wife,
You'd never say to another woman,
'You look so beautiful'!
Never.
Well, the fault isn't entirely yours...
It's the fault of the likes of me, too.
A husband can't really say every day,
'You look so beautiful'!
'I haven't seen anyone like you'!
And the likes of me!
We'd believe it if someone else said it
That there's no one like us.
There are many of us.
Come with your wife sometime.
I'll tell her
That we're all very beautiful,
But not the most beautiful of them all.
What will I wear to her brother's wedding?
I mean, I've purchased all three artificial sets with her.
Her brother's getting married in such a haste th --
Alright,
What do I do?
Selling the motorcycle won't get me enough either.
I don't have any friend except you.
I never thought I'd need any friend
When I've got you.
Tell me,
Have I ever gone to a friend?
I'm only friends with you.
You're very hungry?
Very.
Just...
It'll be ready in a while.
And Maman's here!
What's going on?
I'm making an omelette for Rumi.
Didn't he eat anything?
How could he? Nothing had been cooked.
Hey!
Didn't she cook food?
The maid left at 12.
She called,
Telling that her Mum's been rushed to the hospital.
Let's pause for a while, shall we?
Cheating, eh?
No, I'm very tired.
The thing is, I've got so many responsibilities...
Oh...
What time is it?
4.30.
She hasn't called yet.
Who?
My teacher.
She'd said, 'I'll tell you tomorrow'.
Shall we continue?
Aren't you afraid?
I mean, aren't you worried?
No.
There's nothing to worry about.
I'm worried her smile may have been that kind of smile.
What kind?
Like, laughing it off.
Alright, Papa, let's continue.
Yes!
Did you see that? You lose!
You take the slightest thing to heart.
There was nothing like that in Teacher's smile.
C'mon, Papa, it's time for swimming.
Didn't I say you're not going to office?
That --
Blighter, Shehwar Ahmed --
Is a wicked man --
-Don't insult anyone!
Don't look at anyone, Mehwish.
Look at me; I'm your husband.
Honestly, Danish?
We can't live together anymore.
The same old anger.
We'll talk in the morning --
-I'll say the same in the morning - we can't live together.
Crazy lass, I can't live without you.
But I can.
And I want to.
I'm fed up of this relationship.
Good evening.
We thought we'd have dinner with you.
She's my wife,
Hello.
I'm Ifrah.
I suppose you'd know me?
Come in.
There isn't even a proper place to sit here.
We'd had chairs sent.
We forgot the table.
Please, sit.
I'll go get it.
You do know me, don't you?
Yes.
You would've heard my story, too?
No.
Look at me.
Take a good look at me and remember me.
Monty holds you in the highest regard.
He even told me about what he used to do.
He's ashamed of it.
He even teared up
While talking today.
Careful.
Right over here.
Right. Thank you, mate.
My things would be here by tomorrow.
-The same old?
Nothing of the same.
Even you're not the same anymore.
You've become so good like me.
Do you know when we become so good?
When we've tried being bad.
But then, people don't believe that we've become good now.
Well,
You were just 'bad',
Not a two-timer.
Infidelity is like becoming piebald, Monty,
Even if your condition gets cured, its scars remain.
I'll get you some water.
Hello?
It's Rumi, teacher.
I know.
You'd said, 'I'd tell tomorrow'.
Sure, I will, but first, tell me what the gentleman says.
Gentleman?
Yes.
Oh, you're talking about Papa!
Yeah.
I'll ask him later.
Why, mate?
Why'd you ask him later?
You'd have me insulted?
How would you be insulted?
Splendid.
What if I said 'yes', and the gentleman refused, saying, 'I don't want to marry Hania'?
It'd be so insulting then, right?
He won't say that.
Believe me.
In fact, he'd even kiss my face.
Are you there?
Yeah.
So, tell me, would you?
You're saying 'Yes', right?
Give me an hour.
Another hour?
One doesn't hurry in these matters, Rumi.
Look at the gentleman. It seems you're already very late.
Alright, I'll talk later. The gentleman's coming.
Hey!
You're doing the dishes at my place?
We're doing our dishes at your place.
Just think we're getting no water in our flat.
Besides,
I'm like your brother.
Just think that I am your brother.
Brothers do so much for their sisters.
What else can you do?
Awaiting orders!
You won't be able to do it.
I'll get it done even if I couldn't do it.
I promise.
Would you go to him?
Would you beg him
To come and meet me once?
To visit this flat
Just for once?
It'd rid this barren wasteland of the stench of infidelity.
Would you do me this favour, Monty?
Mind if I ask something?
Would you go to him?
Don't just ask him to come and meet her.
Ask him
Why it is that she can't be forgiven.
Granted
That she'd made a mistake,
She'd sinned...
She's admitted it, too.
She's performed every penance and more.
So, ask him,
'Even the Lord would grant absolution',
'So why don't you'?
There are countless examples, Monty,
Of people marrying the one they divorced again.
Why can't he just...
There are divorces in marriages,
But not in love.
Seeking another man is plain infidelity,
And if he forgave her infidelity,
Wouldn't he become no less than the Lord Himself?
Such godhood
Is what he fears.
She's coming here? But why? Papa doesn't even know!
So?
It doesn't look good
That the lady comes all decked up and the gentleman's running.
Isn't she there yet?
Is she almost here?
Oh my God...
Alright, please disconnect quickly. I'll ask Papa to get ready.
Hold on, Ms Watira...
Yes?
How's her mood?
Very good.
As in, she was very pleased.
There! So she'd say 'Yes', wouldn't she?
Not sure...
She can say anything when she's laughing.
Oh! She's here. Bye.
Oh, it's you, Teacher!
What a pleasant surprise!
You're quite the actor!
Actor?
I know.
It's no surprise. You knew I was coming.
I knew it. But I didn't believe that you're actually coming.
How are the preparations?
Preparations?
Yes -- I mean...
How are the gentleman's preparations?
I've just told him.
He ran into his room the moment he heard it.
Ran into his room?
He was running on the treadmill.
He was sweating.
What's it with you?
Hello?
Hi.
It's Hania.
Please come downstairs.
We've got to meet.
Coming.
Listen...
Yes?
Rumi won't be there when we meet.
Promise?
He won't be there.
I promise.
Okay.
Is your Papa happy?
I didn't see.
I was not there.
Alright,
Don't be disheartened.
I should be saying that, right?
Please don't be disheartened, okay?
It happens.
What's she wearing?
She looks good, doesn't she?
It looks like she's here for her wedding!
I swear, she looks right batty!
Maman?
Maman...?
Dad used to say,
'If you want to see your Dad's childhood, look at your first son'.
'He's just like your father'.
My Dad used to say the same.
In fact, when Rumi was born,
He said,
'Don't think of him as Rumi'.
'This little rascal's Akhtar Ahmed'.
'Even if I die, now, never think that I'm gone',
'For you will find me in him'.
And, honestly? I've never felt
That Dad's no more.
So,
Your 'Dad' had proposed your marriage to me,
And he wanted me to say 'Yes'.
No way.
He --
The bugger!
Bad word for Dad!
In that moment, he was just... Dad.
I looked into deeply into his eyes,
Felt his love as he asked for my hand in matrimony;
Felt, also, that he was as self-seeking as a father would be for his son,
Which is why I just couldn't refuse.
So, I accept the proposal.
I've even brought an engagement ring.
Please,
Put it on if you accept.
Please call me when you've put it on.
Otherwise, I'll take it
That you didn't listen to your Dad.
What's this?
Your tiffin, sir.
But why?
Who gave it to you?
I did.
Remember how you used to carry a tiffin?
With two shami kebabs,
Cucumber and tomato salad,
Two rotis, leftover curry, and sometimes a little gulab jamun, too...
You may go.
I thought I shouldn't have to remind you of the category you fall into now,
Of where you've fallen down from the chairman's position.
Stop it.
I'm your husband, Maham.
Yes.
You are.
Be a husband at home all you want,
But you'd have to work at the office,
And, my dear husband,
You know just how important this job is for you.
Yes, I know.
Bye.
Wait.
A car's here to pick you up.
Messrs Hassan and Shamshad are waiting.
Have a nice chat with them on the way.
Your tiffin.
Bye, sweetheart!
Have a good day!
I felt she was right.
You'd be calling us,
But never calling upon us;
We'd talk about you,
But you'd never be there.
She'd be envious, wouldn't she?
It was Dad's flat...
She shouldn't have gone there.
You could've bought it.
You could buy the entire building.
I didn't want to buy it.
I wanted that someone else buy it and live there.
You're exacting your revenge?
By the Lord, I'm not.
I'm writing a story with the searing ink of my blood.
I'm writing, 'The choice to two-time was her right',
'And, having used her right in choosing that',
'She's lost every right she had over me'.
Yes?
What's his name?
Monty?
Okay.
Here's a glass of water.
Read this 7 times,
And when you have,
Blow over the glass 3 times,
And drink the water.
Hopefully, if the Lord wills so,
He'll be here.
English translation: J. Mir