I've never thought that I haven't got a luxury car,
Or a mansion,
Or more than what I earn right now.
Do you know why?
Because I've got you.
I had thought that with you by my side,
What else could I ever wish for
Mind if I call you if I miss you?
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
You don't need to ask.
Of course not.
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
And if I miss you a lot?
Call me again, then.
Get going already.
Even when I go to the office,
I have you sit right by my side.
And when nobody's listening,
I talk to you, too!
All the grand dreams...
And then you imprisoned me in this tiny flat after our marriage.
Should I sell the motorcycle?
How would you go to office, then?
There's a bus that goes that way.
Your motorcycle costs no more than 30,000.
Do you remember how much the necklace costs?
Rumi's four now and he hasn't started school yet.
If we save something for his admission,
It gets spent somewhere quickly.
You're pitying my helplessness, aren't you?
People spend money like they're mad these days.
Even the servants' gowns cost no less than 7,000.
Just think you've got me.
Surely, I have.
Then, just say that you don't want anything else.
As in, say to God that I don't want anything else?
If He heard it,
He'd actually give nothing!
I want a lot from Him besides you.
May I have this dance?
I know your husband doesn't like it,
But I want to.
What have I done?
You know what you've done.
You were doing the same.
Weren't you dancing with your arms around Anoushay's waist?
Anoushay's like my sister.
As if he's my boyfriend!
-Stop it, Mehwish!
Shut up!
It's very natural.
Would the pain of it not kill me
If someone put his arms around my wife's waist?
These hands,
These arms --
This waist -- It's all mine.
I know I'm possessive.
But what is love without possessiveness?
How long have you been married?
8 years.
-Oh.
That's enough.
What do you mean, 'enough'?
It's enough
For a lovely lady like you to give a pleb
8 long years of her life.
I'm the luckier one, Mr Shehwar,
She's completed me.
I feel that I don't need anything else
When I've got her.
Honestly, whoever would've gotten her
Would've said the same.
'I don't need anything else.'
Call your husband,
And ask him to take everything that I have,
And give me his Mehwish.
There's also a cheque for me.
I've also given you a car and a driver.
Don't say anything.
You deserve all of it.
The money one deserves
Is his salary, and the money one doesn't deserve
Is his price.
I'm doing all of this for Rumi.
For his future.
And it was just yesterday
That you thought his intentions aren't bad, that he's a good man,
So, why do you feel today that he wants to buy me with the job and the car?
My eyes had begun to trust him,
But my heart has not.
You're envying me, aren't you?
A man always wants the woman to live at his mercy,
Or regard him as a god.
My Mum used to say,
'It makes me laugh if a woman suspects a man',
'But it makes me tear up if a man suspects a woman'.
And honestly,
Looking at you, I feel like tearing up.
People get on the wrong train in their hurry.
What do they do?
Do they keep sitting?
Where'd they go if they kept sitting?
That is why they don't sit tight like you.
They wait for the next station, and get off the moment the train stops.
I want to get off at the next station, Shehwar.
You're not going to office, Mehwish.
Please, don't even think about it.
Would you beat me?
What are you saying?
Have I ever raised my hand on you?
Look at your eyes.
It looks like you'd eat me alive.
Looking at you, it looks like you'd slap me!
-No way, Mehwish, I'd never do that!
You think you've sinned because of a trifling mistake; it's not like that.
Honestly, Danish?
We can't live together anymore.
The same old anger.
We'll talk in the morning --
-I'll say the same in the morning - we can't live together.
Crazy lass, I can't live without you.
But I can.
And I want to.
I'm fed up of this relationship.
I had thought that with you by my side,
What else could I ever wish for
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
What does it matter, if I don't have
Anything in this world;
I was under the misbelief
She's forgotten your 'love marriage',
That I had you;
And that you've got a son,
And that there were dreams the two of you cherished.
You may still cherish them, mate,
But she's jumped ship to fulfil them.
The relationship between a man and a woman is strange, Mr Shehwar.
As long as she's only got eyes for you,
She raises you to godliness;
The moment she turns her gaze away, she separates you from God.
Teach me your ingenious skill
Of forgetting as you leave;
Efface every trace of your memory
From my life, now that you're leaving.
Goodbye.
You seem to be a rather intelligent businessman,
But you surprised me when dealing here.
You were offering me 50 million
For a woman who's not even worth spare change.
Forsake your place in my heart,
Gently and stilly;
Bless you with this parting,
Fare thee well.
Sometimes, it's nagging me,
And sometimes, making me weep.
It is not in a woman's nature to be disloyal,
And one who's disloyal is unworthy of being called a woman.
See for yourself.
The three of us used to share a home.
Now, there's three different houses...
It's all because of that evil uncle.
It's all because of your Maman.
If she comes here,
Meet her.
Go along if she takes you.
You're not my strength, Papa, you're my weakness.
I've come here to invest.
How much money do you have?
-7.8 million.
Splendid.
So, my mate's been earning his riches, eh?
I've sold my flat.
Dad had bought it.
Will you marry my father?
It's been two hours and I haven't seen you.
I'll have mercy on your eyes tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
After the marriage?
I'm observing the Mayoon [ritual of separation] until then.
I'm observing the Mayoon [ritual of separation] until then. I won't meet you before that.
If I was laughing, it doesn't mean I was actually crying.
But I can cry for him, too.
And when I said I don't love him,
I mean that I don't.
But I might as well be in love with him.
What I don't get is whether it's proper for someone who's loved so intensely the first time to love a second time...
So, I say --
What is going on?
What the devil are you doing in my room?
How dare --
I want to meet you.
Please, don't do that, mate...
I won't be able to do that.
W -- Why?
I've spent five months telling myself
And getting myself to believe
That I can't meet you now.
Can't even call out to you now.
Can't say, 'Mehwish',
'This button's fallen off my shirt'.
Of vexed hearts,
The path is straight
Never is it
That they look back.
The strands of love,
The bond of loyalty
Once broken, can never be mended
To meet you once is all I ask for
Meet my gaze for once, and move away.
I want to forgive her, too.
But then, I think of the Lord.
What do you mean?
Even the Lord does not forgive unfaithfulness to Him.
Dad used to say,
'If you want to see your Dad's childhood, look at your first son'.
'He's just like your father'.
My Dad used to say the same.
In fact, when Rumi was born,
He said,
'Don't think of him as Rumi'.
'This little rascal's Akhtar Ahmed'.
'Even if I die, now, never think that I'm gone',
'For you will find me in him'.
And, honestly? I've never felt
That Dad's no more.
So,
Your 'Dad' had proposed your marriage to me,
And he wanted me to say 'Yes'.
No way.
He --
The bugger!
Bad word for Dad!
In that moment, he was just... Dad.
I looked into deeply into his eyes,
Felt his love as he asked for my hand in matrimony;
Felt, also, that he was as self-seeking as a father would be for his son,
Which is why I just couldn't refuse.
So, I accept the proposal.
I've even brought an engagement ring.
Please,
Put it on if you accept.
Please call me when you've put it on.
Otherwise, I'll take it
That you didn't listen to your Dad.
I felt she was right.
You'd be calling us,
But never calling upon us;
We'd talk about you,
But you'd never be there.
She'd be envious, wouldn't she?
It was Dad's flat...
She shouldn't have gone there.
You could've bought it.
You could buy the entire building.
I didn't want to buy it.
I wanted that someone else buy it and live there.
You're exacting your revenge?
By the Lord, I'm not.
I'm writing a story with the searing ink of my blood.
I'm writing, 'The choice to two-time was her right',
'And, having used her right in choosing that',
'She's lost every right she had over me'.
Yes?
What's his name?
Monty?
Okay.
Here's a glass of water.
Read this 7 times,
And when you have,
Blow over the glass 3 times,
And drink the water.
Hopefully, if the Lord wills so,
He'll be here.
English translation: J. Mir