Come.
Hey!
What happened to you?
Were you playing cricket, Papa?
Why did you go with him?
He was insisting so much...
So you'd go along with anyone who'd insist?
Are you in your senses?
I'm not in my senses, Mehwish.
How could you sit in the car with another man without your husband's permission?
He said he's your friend, and that makes me like his sister-in-law...
When did I say he's my friend?
And even if I did,
You should ask me before sitting with my friend.
Okay, it was a mistake.
Won't do it again.
'Won't do it again', as in?
Is it so simple for you?
Don't make it difficult, Danish.
Goodness knows what's happened to you suddenly.
-What's happened?
Don't speak, blood is gushing out from your mouth!
Not gushing --
It's stinging at me.
I'm stung.
And you're saying something's suddenly happened to me.
I say something's suddenly happened to you.
What is going on?
One, you'd say 'Yes' in good temper,
Two, you'd give in to insistence.
Tell me,
How do you think you're an upright woman?
Am I not an upright woman?
-You are.
Very upright, in fact.
But what you're doing is not right.
If I got in the car with someone in a moment's daftness,
Or danced for two minutes with someone to please him,
What's wrong with that?
Do you even know what you're saying?
That's not reason; it's just wayward stubbornness.
An upright woman has the courage to stand up to another man's flattery,
And to refuse his offer despite his insistence.
And a woman who doesn't have the courage to refuse
Is no woman at all.
She's not a woman.
What?
He's sleeping.
Go and watch TV.
Again?
Yes, go and watch your cartoon.
Alright, get up now.
We have to go to the wedding.
I promise you
That I won't make such a mistake again.
How could I go?
Can you see this bruise?
Yes, you didn't tell me --
How did you get this?
Monty's punch.
The bugger hit me.
Well, I hit him, too,
But his punch worked.
But why?
Why did the two of you fight?
Because of you.
I got hold of him just as he came.
I asked him why he took my wife along.
He said, 'I didn't abduct her'.
'She went willingly'.
Would you look at how he's twisting everything!
Didn't he tell you how much he was insisting?
He didn't,
But he did say, 'Your wife's lovely',
'And you can't control her'.
Good Lord!
The blighter!
I swear by you, my head sunk with shame.
He said he's like my brother-in-law!
He got me with his sweet words.
I told you,
I won't make this mistake again.
Get up, now.
I will get up, Mehwish.
But how would I go?
This --
Is this the kind of face to show at a wedding?
We'd have to go, though, Danish.
I've got just got one friend. What would she think?
She's already angry that we'd left the Mehendi.
You go, then.
Alone?
No...
Take Rumi along.
How could I leave you?
Do we ever leave each other?
Even when I go to the office,
I have you sit right by my side.
And when nobody's listening,
I talk to you, too!
You wouldn't feel bad about it, would you?
Why should I?
He'd be there, too.
So what?
When a woman gathers the courage to refuse,
She may go wherever she wants to.
Nobody can conquer her.
How would you go?
I'll ask Anoushay.
She'll send a car.
She'd pick me up and drop me.
Perfect.
Meet Aunt Anoushay, okay?
Greet Meerab too.
Hello!
Hello! How are you?
-Alright.
Where's Danish?
He didn't come.
Why?
He got into a row with someone from the building over me.
He punched him.
He has such a large bruise!
Oh my...
Good evening! How are you?
Everything good? Thank you so much for coming.
Hi beautiful.
Hi.
Apologies for yesterday.
Apologies, as in?
I danced with you and it enraged your husband.
I'm apologising for that.
Where is he, though?
I've come to make friends with him today.
He hasn't come.
He's unwell.
Right.
It seemed so yesterday.
I think he shouldn't be out on the roads either.
Why?
Don't you know?
He almost came under my car last night.
What?
Your car?
-C'mon, now, Mehwish,
It's almost time for the nuptials; we can talk later; come!
You didn't tell me
What you do.
You never asked me,
So I thought I'd keep it under wraps.
Why, mate?
The thing is...
Look at what you are, and look what I am...
Why, what are you?
I'm --
An insignificant officer of the local government office.
Oh?
You must be having the time of your life, then!
I get it now.
You haven't brought your car
So one can't know how the times have been for you!
-No, Mr Shehwar...
I don't have a car.
The thing is,
I don't earn anything above my salary.
You're laughing?
I start laughing when I can't believe something.
But, looking at you, I can begin to believe it.
I swear to God I've never taken a bribe.
If I so much as think abou it, Dad shows up.
Your father works there, too?
No.
Dad's no more.
-Oh...
His memory lives on.
When I'd first gone to the office, he told me,
'Do you know'
'Why our country isn't going forward?'
Surely, Mr Danish, it is?
-He used to think it's not.
He'd say,
'One can't march forward'
'In the swamps of bribery'.
'Sometimes, we stop; sometimes, we trip and fall.'
That's what's happening ever since.
I fear the slightest chance to take a bribe.
It feels as if
I'm mired
Up to my ankles.
Don't you believe it?
-No.
For the first time, I'm laughing
When I can believe it.
Your husband is very simple, Mrs Danish.
Meeting him, one grows fond of him.
Anything, really!
No,
I'm honest.
Thank you so much.
Please, pay me a visit sometime.
We'll have dinner together.
Sure.
-9 p.m. tomorrow?
No -- tomorrow --
-What is it tomorrow?
Are you busy?
Why, Mrs Danish?
Are you busy tomorrow night?
No,
We're not busy...
But --
-The night after?
Then, the night after tomorrow?
9 p.m.
Oh, well --
We'll come someday...
Why not the night after tomorrow?
Or is it that
You don't truly accept my friendship?
No, it's nothing like that.
I've accepted your friendship.
If you've accepted my friendship, why not accept this invitation too?
Why don't you say something, Mrs Danish?
Okay, fine.
The night after tomorrow it is.
Just stop here. Our flat's here.
Here?
-Yes.
It's Anoushay.
Hello?
The two of you went in the car with Mr Shehwar?
Yes.
They're friends now.
Danish just couldn't refuse.
Right...
It was just yesterday that it seemed as if he'd grab his collar!
It's quite natural, Anoushay.
Who knows what one's like at first?
It's only after meeting that one realises that one could be like Mr Shehwar!
He's a very nice man.
Is that he saying that, or
Is it just you?
Didn't I tell you they're friends now?
Oh, they talk about such interesting things!
Smiling and laughing all the time.
Yes.
Yes...
But deep down, the poor man's a sad soul.
Why?
His wife, mate...
Good Lord!
That woman's a witch!
The two of them have been separated for 5 years.
Hey!
Alright,
I'm going now.
Good night.
Okay,
She must be asking if we're back.
Yes.
She was a bit surprised too.
Why was she surprised?
She couldn't believe that we'd come back in Mr Shehwar's car.
You should've told her
We're good friends now.
Come, it's 2.30 already.
Yes, just a second.
No, how could I miss the event?
Honestly, I don't like it one bit
That you
Are calling me at 2 a.m.
On the day of your wedding rites.
Go to her, she must be waiting for you.
Good night.
Why are you coming?
Go and rest.
Okay, good night, sir.
-Good night.
Water's dripping from the AC again...
You're up?
I was remembering the wedding celebrations.
I'd seen a lot.
People spend money like they're mad these days.
A hundred gowns for the bride,
15 for the family,
And they also had 5 for the servants.
Splendid.
And guess what,
Even the servants' gowns cost no less than 7,000.
Alright, go to sleep now.
One can't sleep in a moment like that.
I'll doze off, remembering everything...
Don't worry,
You'll get your breakfast on time.
That's not what I meant, Mehwish.
I can cook breakfast myself, too.
You should get some sleep.
I will.
You'd better sleep, now, too.
Why are you laughing?
Nothing really, just...
How innocently you act
To fool someone!
Who have I fooled?
Your friend.
You quickly said, 'Yes',
'We'll be there the night after tomorrow'.
I wasn't lying.
So you're actually going?
What did you think?
I thought you'd just said it to get rid of him.
After all, he was insisting so much, too.
He was insisting, but
I'd actually said
That we'd be there.
What would I wear?
Leave it be.
It's not as if you've signed a deal.
Call him in the morning and excuse yourself.
Why don't you
Wear your black sari?
The one
That exposes my bare waist?
What are you saying!
You have tomorrow, don't you?
Get a new blouse stitched.
So you've got everything planned!
He was insisting so much...
It didn't seem proper
To decline,
But if you say,
I can call him tomorrow
And excuse myself.
As you like it.
It's 2.30, go to sleep now.
Who is it?
Who was it?
No idea.
Rang the bell and made a run for it.
It's 7.30 already, however will I have breakfast in 15 minutes!
I'm coming.
Know what,
This was my favourite hobby.
What hobby?
I'd ring a bell and disappear.
Right up to my college days!
Sometimes, I'd even get caught.
If this bugger gets caught,
I'd punch him right in the face.
Calm down, Danish.
Hey! It's not even been 5 minutes!
Sit and have your breakfast.
I've finished. Give me my lunch.
Where's the lunch box?
Get something for lunch -- yourself.
Alright.
Say goodbye to Rumi from me when he's up.
Hey --
Listen.
You didn't tell me about going.
I'm going.
Is the swelling better now?
I'm asking about going there.
I won't go if you suddenly told me once you're back.
Getting the blouse stitched will take time.
Oh, you mean going there.
We'll be going.
Get your blouse stitched,
And let me know when you're leaving.
Okay.
And be careful -
Not an inch of your waist peeping!
-Not an inch!
Alright.
I'll have tea in a while.
Your tea is in the Boss's room. He's calling you.
May I come in, sir?
Please, come in.
Sit.
Meet Mr Munir Hussain.
Number 5 among the top 10 contractors
In Karachi.
Hi.
Hi, sir...
How are you?
I've heard
Quaid'e Azam [Jinnah] shows up in your dreams.
So he did in mine, too.
But as long as he showed up,
Banknotes with his picture didn't.
No...
Not Quaid'e Azam [Jinnah].
I mentioned my Dad.
You don't believe me, do you, sir?
A very rich friend of mine
Laughs just like that
When he can't believe me.
Finish this quickly, now.
-Give it to me.
Maman will feed you, or you know you make a proper mess here.
Good boy.
Maman's also --
Alright, here. Have this, alright?
Don't drop it somewhere. I'll be back.
Hello?
Good morning.
Who is it?
So, all those who said
That anyone who's heard my voice will remember it
Have been lying to me.
It's Shehwar.
You?
Who gave you my number?
Do you feel bad about it?
I'd asked Anoushay for Mr Danish's number,
And she gave me yours by mistake.
I'm sorry if you feel bad about it.
No --
The thing is,
It's just a bit strange...
Danish had given you his number.
I forgot to save it.
Oh...
How are you?
I'm --
Fine.
And how's Danish?
He's fine too.
He's at the office.
Oh.
I thought he'd be at home.
Well,
Then, that's my excuse to talk to you.
Yes...
May I ask you something?
Sure.
Promise me you won't mind it.
I promise.
Have you ever listened to your voice?
I do every day.
No, not how you're thinking.
Then?
We just know we're speaking when we speak.
We don't listen to our voice.
The others do.
You listen when I speak,
And I listen when you speak.
That's it.
Please,
Never listen to your voice.
Why?
You'll grow to love it.
You're coming tomorrow, aren't you?
Yes, he --
Said we would.
I, too, had said it rather confidently
My heart felt
You'd come if I invited you.
Yes, we'd be coming.
What do you like to eat?
An -- anything -- I'd eat anything.
How can that be?
One who's so selective about what she wears
Could not possibly be so casual about what she eats.
Looking at you, one can never guess that your husband earns so little,
Or is it just that you really know how to dress?
Know what,
I've changed a lot after meeting you.
Yes?
Looking in the mirror,
I take a good look at myself.
Won't you ask why?
Please, go on.
I'd heard that matches are made in Heaven,
But, meeting you,
I'm forced to think
That people just say it to humour themselves,
For the Lord can never be so unjust.
I didn't get it.
If you sew a diamond button to a 400 buck shirt,
The button does not protest,
But the one who looks at it
Does protest, doesn't he?
Leave the dinner up to me.
I have good tastes.
Alright.
9 p.m. tomorrow?
Yes, I remember.
And here
I can't forget my helplessness.
What helplessness?
I have all the riches in the world, so to speak;
People think I can do anything.
But, even if I wish,
I can't
Change today into tomorrow.
See you tomorrow at 9.
I'm waiting for it to be tomorrow...
Bye...
Bye.
Rumi!
You've dropped it again!
I told you I'd feed you.
Lean forward and look at the front seat.
Me?
Yes.
Th -- There's some Rupees here.
Half and half -- that's one...
Speak freely, will you?
One million.
Right.
-It's for you.
For me?
Yes.
I heard
Your lady wants that you should have a car?
Not at all --
I mean, yes --
Everyone talks about such things, you know...
I, too, want that I should have everything,
But no one gets everything.
Someone gets a car; another gets his love.
Why don't you wear a sherwani and Jinnah cap?
Sir?
Let me tell you something about the times.
If you can't keep up with the times,
You'd be left behind,
And nobody will even turn back to look at you.
I say,
Here's 1 million,
Keep it with you for two days,
And give it back to me after that.
In fact,
Call
Your lady right now.
No, I won't tell her.
Why?
If you're so honest, why don't you share everything with your wife?
Why are you insisting, Mr Munir?
I -- won't take a bribe.
Who said I'm bribing you?
Then? This --
What's this million?
A hiring amount.
I'm hiring you for another job.
Another job?
How can I start another job?
It's impossible.
When'd I come to you if I'm here from 8 to 4?
Who said anything about coming anywhere?
Just keep on working,
And collect your salary.
And --
What's the job?
Don't ask about the work.
Ask how much you'd be earning.
How much?
Half a million a month.
And this 1 million is an advance
From the company to buy a car.
When could I get it?
It's 2 right now, Ma'am. You could send someone by around 7.
Alright.
Just a minute.
Yes, Danish?
Why aren't you opening the door?
Are you at the door?
I've been here for 10 minutes, and I've rung the bell three times.
Were you sleeping?
No, I'm at the tailor's.
At the tailor's?
Open the door with your key, will you?
I don't have the key.
I forgot to keep it with me in my hurry.
Splendid, Danish...
Splendid, mate...
Leaving without even telling me...
Why are you arguing like that?
-I'm not arguing.
Come quickly.
I have a --
I have a million Rupees with me.
A mi --
Alright, I'll be there quickly.
Come.
Remember, sir, it shouldn't show an inch of my waist.
-Don't worry, Ma'am.
Come.
Quickly, now.
Mr Munir's given it to me.
Who's Mr Munir?
He's a known contractor.
He said he's hiring me
For a new job.
This is the signing amount.
A million...
We're riding our car tomorrow.
-He was lying, Mehwish.
This is a bribe.
To 'earn' this, I have to write 'Okay' and sign every right and wrong he does.
Just do it! What's it to your father?
It's everything to my father, Mehwish.
Dad would think I've smeared his grave.
Dad's dead, Danish; he won't feel a thing if you smear or bomb his grave.
-Watch what you're saying!
Alright, why have you brought the money, then?
Do you want to show it off or tempt me?
I'd brought this to check my integrity.
Mr Munir thinks
My intentions would change
If I kept this money with me for two days.
But I'm afraid, Mehwish...
If I kept so much money at home,
How would I sleep?
-Alright, then.
Stay awake.
Listen, will you? Why --
Why are you so angry?
You're not returning this money, Danish.
Thank the Lord if He's been kind to us.
Keep this in the cupboard and go to sleep.
And take a bribe?
-It's not a bribe, Danish!
It's a reward for your hard work and integrity.
How hard you work,
Running around on that old bike of yours,
Only to hear a load of guff from one like Monty!
Do you remember that your bike didn't even start the other day?
Rumi's four now and he hasn't started school yet.
If we save something for his admission,
It gets spent somewhere quickly.
You've just got 3 or 4 pairs of trousers,
And some 4 or 6 shirts.
I'm thinking of what you'd wear to dinner tomorrow.
Show it to me for once.
What?
The one million.
Here.
I can't believe it, Danish...
I can't believe it either, Mehwish.
My head's spinning around...
Why don't you take a nap?
Relax, Danish.
No, I'm --
I'm not sleepy.
You're still struggling over Dad, aren't you?
-No.
I'm trying to forget Dad.
Dad's dead.
So,
It's over now, innit?
May he be happy wherever he is.
One can't run a household on this piffling salary.
I'll wash my face and hands.
Dad hasn't the foggiest that petrol now costs 110 Rupees a litre;
Rumi's fees add up to 10,000;
And
A picnic on Sunday drains out every penny one's saved.
When buying a burger, I ask,
'Which one's the cheapest'?
If he showed up in my dream, I'd say to him,
'If one can't even fulfil such piffling dreams, it feels as if one's been kicked in the teeth',
'Which is why I'm sorry, Dad'...
English translation: J. Mir