Teach me your ingenious skill
Of forgetting as you leave;
Efface every trace of your memory
From my life, now that you're leaving.
As nothing more than a formality, if nothing else,
Turn back and glance at me for a moment;
Fulfil the vows of our bond for once
As you break them.
Sometimes, it's nagging me,
And sometimes, making me weep.
Forsake your place in my heart,
Gently and stilly;
Bless you with this parting,
Fare thee well.
Sometimes, it's nagging me,
And sometimes, making me weep.
I had thought that with you by my side,
What else could I ever wish for
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
I had thought that with you by my side,
What else could I ever wish for
My hope in life begins and ends with you;
What does it matter, if I don't have
Anything in this world;
I was under the misbelief
That I had you;
But, from you, I have learnt
That, even in love,
One could rather betray,
One could rather repulse.
Translation: J. Mir
Just until yesterday,
Your hand was in mine,
And your heart beat in mine;
These ebrious eyes
That have altered beyond recognition -
There was a time when I was their ardent devotee.
Should you chance upon me somewhere,
Surreptitiously, turn your gaze the other way, and move away.
I have to live out my days
Without you
I am destined, now, to live out my days without you.